import{_ as g,o as i,c as t,a as n,m as h,t as l,C as b,M as y,U as c,F as w,p,e as v,f,q as j}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},S={class:"review-title"},N={class:"review-content"};function x(e,a,s,m,o,u){return i(),t("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",S,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),h(l(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",N,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),h(l(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const T=g(q,[["render",x],["__scopeId","data-v-b205a3ad"]]),M=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"Алгачкы кыргыз армиясында кимдер болгон?","answer":"Республикадагы алгачкы аскер комиссары, башкача айтканда 53-кыргыз атчандар полкунун тунгуч аскер комиссары (1937-жыл март - сентябрь) - Истамбеков Аден Бекембай уулу (1903 - 37). Ал 1922-жылыь 19 жашында кызыл комиссар наамына ээ болгон. Кыргыздын 1-матросу, 1935 - 39-жылы Балтика флотунда өтөгөн - Н.Жээналиев. Алгачкы кыргыз чек арачыларынын бири - Озоке Лайлиев. Анын ысымы 1994-жылы Нарын чек ара отрядына, 1992-ж. Ысык-Ата районунун Кенбулун айылындагы мектепке берилген. Кыргыз Республикасынын Улуттук гвардиясы 1992-жылы түзүлгөн. Алгачкы командачысы Абдыгул Чотбаева болгон."},{"question":"Tá mé ag méadú meáchain agus ba mhaith liom tosú ag cleachtadh.  Conas ba chóir dom tosú? ","answer":"Tá mé an-sásta go bhfuil tú ag déanamh céim sa treo ceart. Molaim duit rianóir cleachtaíochta a fháil agus do ghníomhaíochtaí a rianú. Nuair a fhaigheann tú bunlíne, is féidir liom cabhrú leat a fháil amach cé mhéad calraí a chaithfidh tú a dhó gach lá chun fanacht sláintiúil. D'fhéadfá tosú le cúpla míle a siúl gach lá. Is féidir leat tosú ag rianú do chalarí a dhó agus do spriocanna sláinte. Chomh maith leis sin, tá damhsa agus siúlóid ina roinnt smaointe éadrom."},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:જમીનની અંદર ગયેલો દરિયાનો ફાંટો","answer":"અખાત "},{"question":"ප්‍රභාසංශ්ලේෂණය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ප්‍රභාසංස්ලේෂණය යනු කාබන්ඩයොක්සයිඩ්, ජලය සහ හිරු එළිය ඔක්සිජන් සහ ග්ලූකෝස් බවට පරිවර්තනය කිරීම සඳහා ශාක, ඇල්ගී සහ සමහර බැක්ටීරියා භාවිතා කරන ක්‍රියාවලියයි. අප හුස්ම ගන්නා ඔක්සිජන් සහ අප ගන්නා ආහාර සපයන බැවින් මෙම ක්‍රියාවලිය පෘථිවියේ ජීවයට ඉතා වැදගත් වේ. ප්රභාසංස්ලේෂණය සඳහා රසායනික ප්රතික්රියාව: 6CO2 + 6H2O + ආලෝක ශක්තිය = C6H12O6 + 6O2."},{"question":"ਵਟਸਐਪ ਦੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਨਿੱਜਤਾ ਨੀਤੀ ਨਾਮਨਜ਼ੂਰ ਕਰਨ 'ਤੇ ਇਹ ਹੋ ਜਾਏਗਾ ਬੰਦ, ਜਾਣੋ ਨਵੀਂ ਨੀਤੀ।ਜੇਕਰ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਹਾਲ ਹੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੈੱਟਫਲਿਕਸ 'ਤੇ ਆਈ ਡਾਕੂਮੈਂਟਰੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ 'ਸੋਸ਼ਲ ਡਾਇਲੇਮਾ' ਦੇਖੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਭੁੱਲੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਵੋਗੇ। 'ਸੋਸ਼ਲ ਡਾਇਲੇਮਾ' ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਫੇਸਬੁੱਕ, ਟਵਿੱਟਰ, ਇੰਸਟਾਗ੍ਰਾਮ ਅਤੇ ਵਟਸਐੱਪ ਵਰਗੇ ਸੋਸ਼ਲ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਪਲੈਟਫਾਰਮ ਅਤੇ ਐਪਸ ਦੇ ਸੰਦਰਭ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਹੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ। ਫੇਸਬੁੱਕ ਅਤੇ ਵਟਸਐੱਪ ਵਰਗੇ ਪਲੈਟਫਾਰਮ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅਸੀਂ ਲਗਭਗ ਮੁਫ਼ਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਪਯੋਗ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਾਂ, ਕੀ ਉਹ ਸਚਮੁੱਖ ਮੁਫ਼ਤ ਹਨ? ਇਸ ਦਾ ਜਵਾਬ ਹੈ-ਨਹੀਂ, ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੋਸ਼ਲ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਪਲੈਟਫਾਰਮ ਯੂਜਰਜ਼ ਦੇ ਯਾਨਿ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਡੇਟਾ ਤੋਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਕਮਾਈ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਵਟਸਐੱਪ ਬਦਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਾਲਿਸੀ ।ਜੇਕਰ ਤੁਸੀਂ 'ਯੂਰਪੀਅਨ ਖੇਤਰ' ਦੇ ਬਾਹਰ ਜਾਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹੋ ਤਾਂ ਇੰਸਟੈਂਟ ਮੈਸੇਜਿੰਗ ਐਪ ਵਟਸਐਪ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਈਵੇਸੀ ਪਾਲਿਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਰਤਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਇੰਨਾ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ, ਜੇਕਰ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਵਟਸਐਪ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕਰਨਾ ਜਾਰੀ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹੋ ਤਾਂ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਲਈ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਤਬਦੀਲੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਵੀਕਾਰ ਕਰਨਾ ਲਾਜ਼ਮੀ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। ਵਟਸਐਪ ਇਸਤੇਮਾਲ ਦੀਆਂ ਸ਼ਰਤਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਦਲਾਅ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਵਟਸਐਪ ਪ੍ਰਾਈਵੇਸੀ ਪਾਲਿਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਰਤਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਦੀ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਐਂਡਰਾਇਡ ਅਤੇ ਆਈਓਐੱਸ ਯੂਜਰਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਨੋਟੀਫਿਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਜ਼ਰੀਏ ਦੇ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਨੋਟੀਫਿਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਫ਼ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜੇਕਰ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਨਵੇਂ ਅਪਡੇਟਸ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਠ ਫਰਵਰੀ, 2021 ਤੱਕ ਸਵੀਕਾਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋ ਤਾਂ ਤੁਹਾਡਾ ਵਟਸਐਪ ਅਕਾਊਂਟ ਡਿਲੀਟ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਵੇਗਾ।  ਯਾਨਿ ਪ੍ਰਾਈਵੇਸੀ ਦੇ ਨਵੇਂ ਨਿਯਮਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਨਵੀਆਂ ਸ਼ਰਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਨਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਅੱਠ ਫਰਵਰੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਟਸਐਪ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ। ਜ਼ਾਹਿਰ ਹੈ ਵਟਸਐਪ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਤੋਂ 'ਫੋਰਸਡ ਕਨਸੈਂਟ' ਯਾਨਿ 'ਜ਼ਬਰਨ ਸਹਿਮਤੀ' ਲੈ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇੱਥੇ ਸਹਿਮਤੀ ਨਾ ਦੇਣ ਦਾ ਬਦਲ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਕੋਲ ਹੈ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ। ਸਾਈਬਰ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਦੇ ਜਾਣਕਾਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੰਨਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਸੋਸ਼ਲ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਪਲੈਟਫਾਰਮ ਜਾਂ ਐਪਸ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਕਦਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਚੁੱਕਦੇ ਹਨ। ਆਮ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਯੂਜਰਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਸੇ ਅਪਡੇਟ ਨੂੰ 'ਸਵੀਕਾਰ' ਜਾਂ ਅਸਵੀਕਾਰ  ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।  ਅਜਿਹੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਟਸਐਪ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਤਾਜ਼ਾ ਨੋਟੀਫਿਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਨੇ ਮਾਹਿਰਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਚਿੰਤਾਵਾਂ ਵਧਾ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇੱਕ ਯੂਜਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਚਿੰਤਤ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਨਵੀਂ ਪਾਲਿਸੀ ਵਿੱਚ 'ਪ੍ਰਾਈਵੇਸੀ' 'ਤੇ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਖ਼ਤਮ ।ਜੇਕਰ 20 ਜੁਲਾਈ 2020 ਨੂੰ ਆਖ਼ਰੀ ਵਾਰ ਅਪਡੇਟ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਵਟਸਐਪ ਦੀ ਪੁਰਾਣੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਈਵੇਸੀ ਪਾਲਿਸੀ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖੀਏ ਤਾਂ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕੁਝ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ।","answer":"\\"ਇਫ ਯੂ ਆਰ ਨੌਟ ਪੇਇੰਗ ਫਾਰ ਦਿ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਕਟ, ਯੂ ਆਰ ਦਿ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਕਟ।\\" ਯਾਨੀ ਜੇਕਰ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਕਟ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਪੈਸੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹੋ ਤਾਂ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਹੀ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਕਟ ਹੋ।"},{"question":"Sheeg aayada kulmisay dhammaan xuruuful hijaa’iga?","answer":"Waa Muxamadu Rasuullulaah. (Suuratul Fatax)."},{"question":"漢数字の１から１０までで画数が一番多いのは？","answer":"四です。"},{"question":"Quel nombre sur l’échelle de Richter un tremblement de terre doit-il atteindre pour être considéré comme majeur ?","answer":"Un tremblement de terre est considéré comme « majeur » lorsqu’il atteint une magnitude de 7,0 ou plus sur l’échelle de Richter. L'échelle de Richter, également connue sous le nom d'échelle de magnitude locale (ML), est utilisée pour mesurer l'énergie libérée par un tremblement de terre. Les tremblements de terre d'une magnitude de 7,0 ou plus sont capables de causer des dommages importants aux bâtiments, aux infrastructures et à l'environnement, en fonction de facteurs tels que la profondeur, la distance par rapport à l'épicentre et les codes du bâtiment locaux."},{"question":"Iza no matanjaka kokoa amin'ny ankapobeny ka mahavita mibata zavatra mavesatra kokoa amin'ny lahy sy ny vavy ?","answer":"Amin'ny ankapobeny dia ny lahy no matanjaka kokoa ary mahavita mibata zavatra mavesatra kokoa noho ny vavy. "},{"question":"د افغان-انګلیس دوهمې جګړې د سیمې په جیو پولیټیکل منظره او د افغانستان او برتانوي امپراتورۍ پر اړیکو څه ډول اغیز وکړ؟","answer":"د افغان-انګلیس دوهمې جګړې د سیمې په جیو پولیټیکل منظرې باندې تلپاتې اغیزې پریښې. په داسې حال کې چې انګرېزانو د کنټرول د رامنځته کولو او د روسیې د نفوذ د مخنیوي په لټه کې وو، جګړې په افغانستان کې د ګوډاګي رژیم د ساتلو ننګونې په ګوته کړې. د ګندمک تړون د افغانستان په بهرنۍ پالیسي باندې د انګلیس کنټرول تضمین کړ خو د افغان مشرانو او د خلکو د احساساتو له مقاومت سره مخامخ شو. جګړې د افغانستان او برتانوي امپراتورۍ تر منځ پیچلې او ډیری وخت ترینګلې اړیکې رامینځته کړې او د راتلونکو کلونو لپاره یې د سیمه ایز سیاست متحرکات رامینځته کړل."},{"question":" 10 sabab oo kugu qasbaya inaad booqatid Soomaaliya","answer":"10 sabab oo kugu qasbaya inaad booqatid SoomaaliyaSedex jeer oo aan booqday Soomaaliya iyo Somaliland, waxaan xaqiiqsaday in dadka Soomaaliyeed ay yihiin kuwo si cadaalad ahayn ama wanaagsaneyn ay ula dhaqmaan warbaahinta caalamka ayagoo sawir qaldan ka gudbiya, waxayna warbaahinta si joogto ah usoo bandhigtaa waxyaabaha xun xun ee dadka Soomaaliyeed . Waana sababta keentay inaan muuqaalkaan sameeyo,   waxaana doonayaa waxyaabaha wanaagsan inaan dadka tuso oo aad arki kartid ama baran kartid marka aad Soomaaliya booqatid. Haddaba waa kuwaan 10-ka sababood ee kugu qasbayo inaad Soomaaliya booqatid:10- Soomaaliya waxay leedahay ama heysataa Tiknoolijiyad horumarsan: Waa macquul inaad arrinkan la yaabtid, balse waxaan mar booqday dalka Japan, waxaana ka waayay ama ku yar nidaamka lacagaha habka Electronic ahaan loogu bixiyo. Laakiin Soomaaliya ma arkeysid qof lacag kaash ah wato qof walbo taleefoonkiisa ayuu lacagta ku sitaa, muhiimna maahan taleefoonkaaga inuu casri yahay, sidoo kalana waxay  lacagaha biilashooda ku bixiyaan hab mobile ah. Xitaa dadka waddooyinka wax ku iibiya ayaa adeegsada habkaan.Sidoo kalena waxay leeyihiin bangiyo lacagta looga bixiyo hab Electronic ah. Weliba 5-sano ka hor xitaa mar aan booqday Soomaaliya sidaan ayay u hormasaneyd.9- Barro waxa nolosha u muhiim ah: madaama aan ku dhashay kuna soo bar baaray reer galbeedka waxaan aaminsanahay dhaqan ahaan haddii aan lacag badan sameeyo inaan farxad badan helaayo. Laakiin Soomaaliya arinkaas muhiim kama ahan waxaa muhiim ah inaa qof wanaagsan tahay, dadka u naxariisto, saaxiib ka dhigto dadka eheladiisa ka warhaayo. Sidoo kalena Soomaalida waxay jecel yihiin kaftanka iyo sheekada madaama aad u jecel yihiin inay qoslaan sidaa darteed dhamaanteen reer galbeed ahaan Soomaaliya waxaan ka baran karnaa waxa nolosha muhiim u tahay.8- Barro in cudurka HIV yahay wax dhaqanka la xariira balse jinsiga la xariirin:Waxaad arki kartaa dalal badan oo Afrikaan ah inuu aad ugu badan yahay qaadista cudurka HIV, waa arrin aad u dhib badan, sidoo kalena Dunida sida guud markaad u fiirisid waxaa arki kartaa dad badan oo maddoow ah oo xanuunkan hayo sida Bahamas iyo Haiti. Sidaa darteed waxaad ku fikiri kartaa in HIV iyo dadka maddow-ga ah la isugu tala galay.Laakiin Soomaaliya arrinka sidaas ma ahan, waxay ka mid yihiin dalalka tirada ugu yar HIV-ga asiibay, haddii aadan ogeyn Soomaaliya waa dad maddow ah sidaa darteed cudurkan jinsiga shaqo kuma lahan ee dhaqanka dadka ayuu la xariiraa, marka dad badan sida Soomaalida camal hadday u dhaqmi lahaayeen HIV dhibaato kuma noqon laheyn dunidan.7- Caawinta Soomaalida: Inta badan waxaad arki kartaa ganacsiyada Soomaaliya ka jira inay maamulaan qoysas iska tababar yar dhaqaale ahaan, laakiin dunida reer galbeedka wey ka duwan tahay, waxaa ka jiraan oo kaliya shirkado waaweyn oo is baheystay. Laakiin Soomaaliya waxaad arkeysaa hooyo ama aabo dukaamo yar yar iska leh shaqaalo yar yar u adeegayaan, marka haddii aan dalxiisayaal nahay dad kala duwan ayaan la fal galnaa. Ganacsi ahaan hotel-ka aad jiifaneysid dad ayaa kaa kireenayo, waardiyayaasha magaalada ku geynaya lacag ayaa siineysaa , dukaamada ayaad wax kasoo gadaneysaa, dhammaan lacagahaas waxay dib ugu laabaneysaa ganacsiyada yar yare ee gudaha Soomaaliya ka jira, waana habka ugu wanaagsan ee wadan faqrinimo kaga bixi karo kadibna dhaqaalaha guud sii caawin kara.Xittaa mid ka mid ah saaxiibadeyda Soomaliya igu soo dhaweeyay wuxuu furtay shirkad dalxiisayaasha soo dhaweyso waana arrin wanaagsan. Sidaa darteed marwalbo oo ay dalxiisayaasha Soomaaliya kusoo bataan waa marwalbo oo dalka sii hagaagayo, waxayna caawinayaan inay dhaqaalaha maalgashi ku sameeyaan6- Baro in Muslimiinta asal ahaan dad kala duwan kasoo jeedaan: Marka aan Mareykanka joogno inta badan waxaan aragnaa ama aan qabnaa aragti ah in Muslimiinta yihiin dadka ku nool Iran, Syria ama bariga dhexe, waana sawirka aan ka heysanay Muslimiinta. Laakiin marka aan Soomaaliya tagay waxaan arkay waddan dhan oo Afrikaan ah dadkiisa dhamaantooda Muslimiin yihiin, marka waxaan ogaaday xaqiiqada ah in Muslimiinta asal ahaan meelo kala duwan kasoo jeedaan oo Bariga dhexe kaliya ku nooleyn.Sidaa darteed Muslimiinta waxay noqon karaan Asian, Maddow, Caddaan ama jinsi kasto, si kooban waxaa loo dhihi karaa qof kasta ayaa Muslim noqon karo.5- Baro in kala duwanaasho weyn u dhaxeyso Afrikaanta: Madaama aan kusoo koray Ameyrika waxaan bartay dhaqamo kala duwan sida dhaqanka reer Yurub, Jarmal, Faransiis, Norway, Switzerland, Talyaani, Greece, waxaana ku baranay inay dhaqamo kala duwan iyo muuqaalo kala duwan leeyihiin. Laakiin Afrika waxaan u baranay Afrika inay tahay hal wadan oo kale dhaqan ahaan, mana aanan soo baranin dalalka kala duwan ee Afrikaanta ah dhaqamada ay leeyihiin, mararka qaar dalalka Afrikaanta waa isku dhaqamo sida Galbeedka Afrika oo kale, balse marka aad Soomaaliya joogtid wey ka duwan yihiin Afrikaanta kale. Dhaqankooda waa gaar Soomaalida, muuqaalkooda Afrikaanta kale uma eko, waxaana ogaaneysaa in Afrika oo idil inaysan isku mid ahayn.4- Cun raashiinka cajiibka badan ee Soomaaliya yaalo: Marka aan Soomaaliya tagay waxaan kasoo helay waaya aragnimo  ku aadan inay jecel yihiin raashin inay isla cunaan, midda labaad ee aan ogaaday waxay tahay inay jecel yihiin inay raashiinka gacantooda ku cunaan, balse reer galbeed ahaan arrinkaas waan la yaabnaa, laakiin waa arrin muhiim ah inaad saaxiibadaada ama qoysaskaaga wax la cuntid oo aad la falgashid, waa labada arrin ee ugu horeyso oo aan rabay inaan ka hadlo ka hor inta aan cunadooda ka sheekeyn.Cuntada Soomaaliya laga cunio waa cunno cajiib ah, waxaan soo qaadan karaa Canjeero, Sambuuska, Hilib Geelka iyo bariiska, ma aqaan si aan u sharxo wax walbo oo aan cunay intaan joogay Soomaaliya balse waxaan dhihi karaa raashiinka Soomaalida waa isku geynta raashiinka laga cuno Bariga Afrika, Yemen, Carabta iyo Hindiyaanka laakiin Soomaaliya raashiinkooda lama gaaro.3- Ogow quruxda Soomaaliya leedahay: Soomaaliya aad ayay u qurux badan tahay waxayna leedahay xeebta ugu dheer Afrika, waxay leedahay dhul saxaro lama dagaan qurux badan ah, dooxooyin, wabiyo iyo buuro wuxuuna u sameysan yahay dhulka Soomaaliya si cajiib badan, marka waa inaad booqataa si aad usoo aragtid.2- Soomaaliya ma ahan meel halis badan: Haddii aad weydiisid qof kasto oo dunida ku nool shanta wadan ee ugu halista badan caalamka waa qasab in liiska Soomaaliya lagu soo daro, ma aysan ku saleynin arrinkaan xog aruurin iyo xaqiiqo dhab ah, balse waxay ku saleenayaan xogaha warbaahinta usoo gudbiso. Laakiin marka aad fiirisid xogaha rasmiga ah ee diiwaan gashan Mareykanka ayaa ka halis badan Soomaaliya.Sidoo kalena kummanaan dalxiisayaal ah ayaa sanad walbo booqda US Virgin Island haddane 10-jeer ayay ka halis badan yihiin Soomaaliya jaziiradahaas. Haddaba maxaa Soomaaliya si qaldan marwalbo loogu eedeeyaa?.Midda kowaad waxay tahay warbaahinta sawirka qaldan oo ay ka gudbiso Soomaaliya. Marka ay wax ka dhacaan Soomaaliya warbaahinta wey buun buunisaa laakiin marka ay wax qaldan ka dhacaan USA, Laatiin Ameerika ama Caribbean-ka cid sheeg sheegto malahan aqbaartooda marka si cadaalad daro ah ayaa Soomaaliya loola dhaqmaa dhanka warbaahinta.Midda labaad waa midib kala sooca la isku sameeyo, waxaa xusid mudan in ka badan 18-wadan oo Caribbean-ka ku yaala ayaa ka halis badan Soomaaliya haddane sidaas oo ay tahay kummanaan dalxiisayaal ah ayaa sanad walbo aada jaziiradaha ku yaalo Caribbeans-ka  haddane wey ka cabsadaan inay Soomaaliya soo aadaan.1- Arag runta Soomaaliya taalla: Inta badan joornaalistayaasha ajaanibta ah ee Soomaaliya soo booqda ma rabo inaan fuquuq sameeyo balse joornaalistayaasha caddaanka ah waxay si gaar ah u baadi goobaan waxa xun ee Soomaaliya ka jiro.Waxaan shaqsiyan aqaan qof Soomaaliya booqday oo aan wax dhibaato ah la kulmin, kadibna wuxuu qoray halista uu la kulmay marka uu halkaas booqday, wuxuuna qof walbo kula taliyay inuusan Soomaaliya aadin, iyadoo aysan jirin wax dhib ah oo qabsaday xataa aniga ma maqlin dalxiise dhibaato ku dhacday, waana arrin ku niyad jebineyso waxa ay joornaalistayaasha sameenayaan.Waxaan ogahay haddii ay wax fiican Soomaaliya ka qoraan inaysan dadka soo jiidan karin, sidaa darteed warbixin xun ayay Soomaaliya ka qoraan si ay lacag badan kaga sameeyaan, sidaa darteed joornaalistayaasha kama fikiraan dadka Soomaaliyeed waxay kaliya ka fikiraan nafsadooda iyo danahooda ganacsi taasoo ku kaliftay inay Soomaaliya ka been sheegaan.Haddii aadan i aamineyn, bal fiiri Muqdisho markii aad Google ku qortid oo Af Ingiriis dooratid kaliya waxaa kuu soo baxayo weeraro argagaxiso iyo waxyaabo badan oo laga naxayo, waa sida ay rabaan dunida reer Galbeedka ah inay Soomaaliya u ekeeto, waana sababta joornaalistayaasha Soomaaliya u imaadaan si ay sawir qaldan kaga bixiyaan.Haddii aad Google ku qortid Muqdisho kadibna luuqadda Af Soomaaliga ah aad dooratid waxaad arkeysaa bilicda magaalada leedahay, dhismo qurux badan, nolol dagan oo caadi ah oo ay kala siman yihiin dalalka kale, waana sida ay dadka Soomaaliyeed dalkooda u arkaan mana ahan doqomo lagu qaldi karo warbixinada been abuurka ah, sababtoo ah maalin walbo ayay ku dhex nool yihiin dalkooda.Dadka ka been sheegaan Soomaaliya waa kuwo aan waligood imaanin ama waa  joornaalistayaasha labo maalin joogeen dalka , marka waxaa wanaagsan inaad dhageysatid dadka ku nool Soomaaliya. Waa dal qurux badan oo wanaagsan waxaana ku ogaan kartaa midaas inaad booqatid gudaha Soomaaliya.Warbixintaan waxaa muuqaal ahaan u diyaariyey Dr. Dustin Pfundheller oo ah dhakhtar u dhashay dalka Mareykanka isla markaasna ku takhasusay Dentist kaasoo booqday dalal badan oo ay ku jirto Soomaaliya, Markii ugu dambeysay oo uu Soomaaliya soo booqday waxay aheyd April 4 2017."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：在物理學中，什麼是熱力學中的「熵」？","answer":"答案：熵是熱力學中的一個物理量，用於描述系統的無序程度或混亂程度。熵增代表系統的無序度增加，熵減代表系統的無序度減少。"},{"question":"Ity misy ampahan-dahatsoratra: \\"Mbola nampiany fa ho averina isaky ny kaominina ihany koa ny vola 52 tapitrisa dolara nomena ireo kaominina andalovan'ny tetikasa Ambatovy \\"Inona no nampiany?","answer":"Nanampy izy fa ho averina isaky ny kaominina ihany koa ny vola 52 tapitrisa dolara nomena ireo kaominina andalovan'ny tetikasa Ambatovy"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'harimau mati meninggalkan belang, manusia mati meninggalkan nama'? Berikan satu contoh ayat peribahase tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang baik meninggalkan nama baik, orang jahat meninggalkan nama jahat. Contoh ayat: Jasa Allahyarham Tuan Haji Kassim tetap dikenang oleh orang-orang kampung kerana beliau banyak berjasa bak kata pepatah harimau mati meninggalkan belang, manusia mati meninggalkan nama."},{"question":"Iyán","answer":"Iyán jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn oúnjẹ ilẹ̀ Yorùbá tó gbajúmọ̀ jùlọ. Iṣu funfun ló dára jù fún iyán gúngún. A lè fi iyán jẹ ọbẹ̀ ẹ̀fọ́, ẹ̀gúsí tàbí ilá. Gbogbo ilẹ̀ Yorùbá ni wọ́n tí máa ń jẹ iyán ṣùgbọ́n iyán jíjẹ wọ́pọ̀ jùlọ láàárín àwọn Ìjẹ̀ṣà, Òndó àti Èkìtì.Iṣu ni ọba èròjà tí wọ́n máa ń fi gúnyán. Lẹ́yìn iṣu, a nílò odó, ó orí-odó àti omi.BÍ A ṢE LÈ GÚNYÁN• A yóò bẹ iṣu• A yóò fọ iṣu náà tónítóní• A yóò dáná láti se iṣu• A yóò bu omi ní ìwọ̀nba tí ó lè se iṣu náà jiná sínú ìkòkò tàbí apẹ tí a fẹ́ fi se iṣu náà• A yóò kó iṣu tí a ti fọ̀ ní àfọ̀mọ́ sínú ìkòkò tí a gbé kaná• A yóò se iṣu náà títí yóò fi jiná dáradára.• Lẹ́yìn tí iṣu bá ti jiná, a yóò wà á sínú odó tí a ti fọ̀ kalẹ̀.• A yóò wá fi omorí odó fi gún un títí yóò fi lẹ̀ dáadáa.• A yóò wá kọ ọ́ sínú abọ́ tàbí àwo tó mọ́ tónítóní fún jíjẹ.Yorùbá bọ̀, wọ́n ní, \\"Iyán loúnjẹ, ọ̀kà logùn, àìrí rárá là ń jẹ̀kọ\\" Yorùbá gbádùn iyán púpọ̀, oríṣiríṣi ọbẹ̀ ni wọ́n fi ń jẹ iyán. Àwọn ni;• Ọbẹ̀ ẹ̀fọ́• Ọbẹ̀ ègúsí• Ọbẹ̀ àpọ̀n• Ọbẹ̀ ata díndín• Ọbẹ̀ ilá abbl."},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકનુ એક લેખન નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે. આજ રીતની \\"માથાફોડ\\" પર આવુ જ બીજુ લેખન લખો. \\"બા: “પણ તું સરખો તો ઊભો રહે ! થનગનથનગન શું કરે છે ?”⁠બાળક: “મને ટાઢ વાય છે; મારાથી ઊભું નથી રહેવાતું.”\\"","answer":"બા: “જોને, ચોરણી પહેરાવી નહિ ત્યાં તો કાઢી નાખી ! છેને પણ કાંઈ ?”⁠બાળક: “બા, એમાં એક કીડી હતી તે કરડતી હતી.”"},{"question":"با توجه به متن زیر به سؤال پرسیده شده پاسخ دهید:  متن: اسکواش یا دیوارتوپ ورزشی راکتی است که به صورت تک‌نفره (۲ بازیکن) و دونفره (۴ بازیکن) در زمینی کاملاً احاطه‌شده با دیوارهای معمولاً شیشه‌ای بازی می‌شود. شیشه‌ای بودن دیوارها تماشای بازی توسط تماشاگران را امکان‌پذیر می‌کند. در مسابقه‌های بین‌المللی دیوارهای بیشتری از جنس شیشه در نظر گرفته می‌شوند.سؤال: اسکواش معمولا چند بازی می‌شود؟","answer":"اسکواش معمولا به صورت تک نفره یا دو نفره بازی می‌شود."},{"question":"ഈ ഖണ്ഡികയ്ക്ക് ഒരു തുടർച്ച എഴുതുക: പാർട്ടിയുടെ പ്രതിച്ഛായ സംരക്ഷിക്കാൻ നെഹ്രുകുടുംബത്തെ ശരണം പ്രാപിക്കുകയെന്ന കോൺഗ്രസ്‌ നേതാക്കന്മാരുടെ കീഴ്‌വഴക്കമാണ്‌ ഇന്ദിരയെ പ്രധാനമന്ത്രിപദത്തിലെത്തിച്ചത്‌. മുതിർന്ന നേതാക്കളിൽ പലർക്കും ഇന്ദിര മികച്ച ഒരു പ്രധാനമന്ത്രിയാകുമെന്ന വിശ്വാസമില്ലായിരുന്നു. എന്നാൽ അധികാരത്തിലെത്തിയ ശേഷം മറ്റുള്ളവരെ അമ്പരിപ്പിച്ച ഒട്ടേറെ നടപടികൾ അവർ സ്വീകരിച്ചു. ദേശവ്യാപകമായ ദാരിദ്ര്യവും ഭക്ഷ്യക്ഷാമവുമായിരുന്നു ഭരണരംഗത്ത് ഇന്ദിരയെക്കാത്തിരുന്ന ആദ്യ വെല്ലുവിളി. 1966 ലെ വിളവെടുപ്പ് മുൻവർഷത്തേതിനേക്കാൾ 12 ദശലക്ഷത്തോളം കുറഞ്ഞു. വികസിത രാജ്യങ്ങളിൽ നിന്നും സഹായം ലഭ്യമാകാതെ നിലനിൽക്കാൻ കഴിയില്ല എന്ന സ്ഥിതിയായിരുന്നു അത്. 1965ലെ ഇന്ത്യ-പാകിസ്താൻ യുദ്ധത്തെ","answer":"തുടർന്ന് അമേരിക്ക ഇന്ത്യക്കു നൽകിയിരുന്ന ധനസഹായം നിറുത്തിയിരുന്നു. ലാൽ ബഹാദൂർ ശാസ്ത്രിയുടെ കാലത്ത് വിയറ്റ്നാം യുദ്ധത്തിൽ അമേരിക്കക്കെതിരേ നിലപാടെടുത്തതുമായി ബന്ധപ്പെട്ട് ഇന്ത്യയുമായുള്ള അമേരിക്കയുടെ ബന്ധത്തിന് ഉലച്ചിൽ തട്ടിയിരുന്നു. എന്നാൽ ഇന്ദിരക്ക് അമേരിക്ക വളരെ സൗഹൃദത്തോടെയുള്ള സ്വാഗതമോതുകയുണ്ടായി. അമേരിക്കയിൽ നിന്നും ഭക്ഷ്യസാധനങ്ങൾ ഇറക്കുമതി ചെയ്യാനും സാമ്പത്തിക സഹായം നേടുവാനും ലിൻഡൻ ബി ജോൺസണുമായി ഇന്ദിര ധാരണയിലെത്തി. 3.5ദശലക്ഷം ടൺ ധാന്യവും, 900 ദശലക്ഷം അമേരിക്കൻ ഡോളർവരുന്ന ധനസഹായവും ലിൻഡൻ ഇന്ത്യക്കു വാഗ്ദാനം ചെയ്തു. എന്നാൽ ഈ ധാരണ പ്രാവർത്തികമാകും മുൻപേ പൊളിഞ്ഞു. വിയറ്റ്‌നാം യുദ്ധത്തിൽ അമേരിക്കയെ പിന്തുണയ്ക്കാൻ ഇന്ദിര തയ്യാറാകാതിരുന്നതാണ്‌ പ്രശ്നമായത്‌. അനേകകോടി ജനങ്ങളെ പട്ടിണിയിലേക്ക്‌ തള്ളിവിട്ടുവെന്ന പഴി ഇന്ദിരയ്ക്കു കേൾക്കേണ്ടിവന്നു. ഇതേത്തുടർന്ന് അധികാരത്തിന്റെ കാര്യത്തിലും അവർക്ക്‌ വിട്ടുവീഴ്ച ചെയ്യേണ്ടിവന്നു. പാർട്ടിയുടെ നിർദ്ദേശത്തിനു വഴങ്ങി മൊറാർജി ദേശായിയെ ഉപപ്രധാനമന്ത്രിയായി നിയമിക്കാൻ അവർ നിർബന്ധിതയായി. എന്നാൽ സുപ്രധാനമായ ആഭ്യന്തര വകുപ്പ്‌ മൊറാർജിക്കു നൽകാതിരിക്കാൻ അവർ ശ്രദ്ധിച്ചു."},{"question":"YDS ne kadar sürede biter?","answer":"ÖSYM'nin YDS başvuru kılavuzu içerisinde verdiği bilgilere göre Yabancı Dil Sınavı sınav süresi 180 dakika yani 3 saat olacak. Sınav günü saat 10.00'a kadar adayların sınav binalarına alınma işlemleri tamamlanacaktır. Adaylar saat 10.00'dan sonra sınav binalarına alınmayacaklardır."},{"question":"Inona no fitoeran-jiro eny amin'ny lanitra?","answer":"Ny fitoeran-jiro eny amin'ny lanitra dia ilay velaran-tany misavovona an-tsaina izay toa mandrakotra ny Tany ary azo jerena na aiza na aiza eto amin'ny planetantsika."},{"question":"60 yaş üstü kart ne kadar basıyor?","answer":"Kayıp, çalıntı yada yıpranma nedeniyle kart yenileme bedeli 75 TL'dir. (02.01.2023 tarihinden itibaren geçerlidir.) Son altı ay içerisinde çekilmiş 1 adet biyometrik fotoğraf istenir."},{"question":"Грамматика — сөз формаларынын өзгөрүшү, курулушу жана сөз айкашы менен сүйлөмжөнүндөгү илим, тил илиминин бир тармагы. Адам баласынын акыл оюнун узак убакыттар боюабстракцияланган ишинин жыйынтыгы тилдин грамматикалык түзүлүшүндө чагылдырылган.Тилдин грамматикалык түзүлүшү кылымдар бою түзүлөт жана жалпы элдик мүнөздө болот.Грамматика аркылуу тил адамдын ой-пикирлерин материалдык тил калыбына салуугамүмкүндүк алат. Грамматика менен лексика өтө тыгыз байланыштуу. Сөз сүйлөмдүн курулушматериалы болуп эсептелет.Суроо: Грамматика эмне үчүн колдонулат?","answer":"Жооп: Адамдын ой-пикирлерин материалдык тил калыбына салууга."},{"question":"Ki i ṣe aisan kindinrin lo n ṣe Ọlaiya Igwe-Owolabi Ajasa","answer":"Latari iṣẹ abẹ ti agba oṣere nni, Ẹbun Oloyede tawọn eeyan mọ si Ọlaiya Igwe, ṣe laipẹ yii, ti ara rẹ si ti n ya daadaa, Aarẹ ẹgbẹ TAMPAN atawọn agba ẹgbẹ kan ṣabẹwo si i niluu Eko lọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, nile rẹ to wa ni Ajao Estate.Ọtunba Bọlaji Amusan, iyẹn Mista Latin to jẹ Aarẹ TAMPAN lo lewaju awọn oṣere yooku bii Yọmi King (Ọpẹbẹ), Ọgbẹni Owolabi Ajasa to jẹ gomina ẹgbẹ naa nipinlẹ Ogun pẹlu awọn alakooso ẹgbẹ ti wọn jọ lọ.Ṣe ni nnkan bii ọsẹ mẹrin sẹyin ni iroyin kan gbode pe Ọlaiya Igwe ti ku lẹyin iṣẹ abẹ kindinrin ti wọn ṣe fun un nileewosan UCH, n’Ibadan. Iroyin naa pada jẹ ofege, nitori Ọlaiya funra ẹ jade sita pe oun ko ku o, alaafia loun wa.Lẹyin abẹwo ọjọ Sannde yii, Mista Latin sọ ọ di mimọ pe oun lọọ ki oṣere ọmọ Abẹokuta naa nile, inu oun si dun pe ara rẹ ti n ya daadaa.Lati fidi ohun ti wọn fi lọọ ki Ọlaiya mulẹ, akọroyin wa pe Gomina TAMPAN nipinlẹ Ogun, Owolabi Ajasa, lori foonu lẹyin ti wọn ti ile Ọlaiya de, o si ṣalaye pe ki i ṣe aisan kindinrin lo n ṣe ọga awọn, bẹẹ ni ko ṣiṣẹ abẹ ti wọn fi n paarọ kindinrin bawọn kan ṣe n gbe e kaye.Ajasa sọ pe kinni kan ti wọn n pe ni ‘Kidney stone’ iyẹn okuta ninu kindinrin lo ṣe Ọlaiya, awọn dokita ri okuta kekere ninu kindinrin rẹ, wọn si ṣiṣẹ abẹ rẹ fun un.O ni iṣẹ abẹ naa lọ nirọwọ-irọsẹ, kinni kan ko ṣe  Ọlaiya lẹyin ti wọn ṣe e tan. O fi kun un pe awọn waa ki i gẹgẹ bo ṣe yẹ keeyan ṣabẹwo si ẹni to ṣẹṣẹ n gbadun ni, ki i ṣe nnkan mi-in, awọn si dupẹ pe alaafia ti n de si ara Igwe awọn onitiata, Ẹbun Oloyede."},{"question":"Bu yazı hangi önemli olay hakkındadır?: 1807 Amerika Birleşik Devletleri ambargosu, Başkan Thomas Jefferson'un ikinci döneminde ABD Kongresi (1806-1808) tarafından kabul edilen bir dizi yasayı içeriyordu. İngiltere ve Fransa dördüncü koalisyon Savaşına katıldılar; ABD tarafsız kalmak ve her iki tarafla da ticaret yapmak istedi, ancak her iki ülke de Amerika'nın diğer tarafla ticaretine itiraz etti. Amerikan politikası, savaştan kaçınmak ve hem Fransa hem de İngiltere'yi Amerikan haklarına saygı duymaya zorlamak için yeni yasaları kullanmayı amaçladı. Ambargo hedeflerine ulaşamadı ve Jefferson Mart 1809'da yasayı yürürlükten kaldırdı.","answer":"Bu yazı, 1807 Amerika Birleşik Devletleri ambargosu hakkındadır."},{"question":"Oṣere tiata, Ṣotayọ Ṣogaga, ṣegbeyawo bonkẹlẹ","answer":"Ọkan ninu awọn oṣerẹ ilẹ wa, Sotayọ Ṣobọla, ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Sogaga, naa ti dara pọ mọ awọn oṣere ilẹ wa ti wọn lade lori bayii, oun naa ti diyawo lọọdẹ ọkọ.Ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, opin ọsẹ yii, ni oṣere naa gbe aworan rẹ, nibi to ti wọ aṣọ igbeyawo, to si fi oruka sọwọ jade,  bo tilẹ jẹ pe ko si ọkọ to fẹ lẹgbẹẹ rẹ.Bi awọn ololufẹ rẹ ti ri aworan naa ni wọn ti n ki i ku oriire, ti wọn si n rọjo adura le e lori pe Ọlọrun yoo fibẹ gba a, yoo si pese ọkunrin abiro, obinrin abiye fun un.Ninu foto ti Ṣotayọ gbe jade yii lo ti kọ ọ pe ki i ṣe pe ayẹyẹ igbeyawo ọhun ṣẹṣẹ waye ni, o ni oun kan pinnu lati gbe aworan naa jade lonii, iyẹ lọjọ Ṣatide, ọjọ kẹfa, oṣu kẹta, yii ni.Ṣugbọn eyi o wu ko jẹ, Sotayọ naa ti kuro ninu awọn oṣere to n wa ọkọ, oun naa ti di iyawo lọọdẹ Mr Somebody ti ẹnikẹni ko ti i mọ bayii. Bẹẹ ni ko sẹni to le sọ ọjọ tabi asiko pẹlu ibi ti igbeyawo naa ti waye, bonkẹlẹ lo fi ṣe.Ṣugbọn pẹlu ẹ naa, adura lawọn ololufẹ rẹ pẹlu awọn oṣere ẹgbẹ ẹ n ṣe fun un."},{"question":"કવિ દલપતરામ લિખીત બે-બે પદ જોડેલાં હોય તેવી કહેવતોના ઉદાહરણ આપો.","answer":"રંડિપુતા શાહાજાદા ન માર મુંડા દોમ પાતશા.રૂપૈયા ભરે ગાગર તારે એક આવે નાગરીય.રાજાએ માંની તે રાણી અને છાંણાં વીનતી આંણી.લાખે લેખાં નેં કોડી ન દેખાં.લપોડ શંખ લાખ તો કે લેને સવા લાખ."},{"question":"\\"Sophie dia tanora mpanoratra manan-talenta izay nanonofy ny ho lasa mpanoratra be mpividy indrindra. Nandany alina tsy nahita tory izy nanoratra tao amin'ny birao keliny.\\"Manomeza tohiny ho an'ny tantara.","answer":"Indro misy tohiny ho an'ny tantara: \\"Indray andro, dia nahita ny sora-tanan’i Sophie ny tompona trano mpamokatra boky iray ary nampiaiky volana azy ny talentany. Nanapa-kevitra ny hamoaka ny bokiny izy, izay lasa boky be mpividy indrindra maneran-tany izany. Nahatanteraka ny nofinofiny ho lasa mpanoratra malaza i Sophie.\\""},{"question":"संसार का सबसे बड़ा फूल कौन-सा है?कमलरेफ्लीसियाकैक्टसरजनीगन्धा","answer":"रेफ्लीसिया"},{"question":"inona no ataon'ny mpivady vao raha vao vita ny fanambadiana?","answer":"ny volan-tantely no ataon'ny mpivady raha vao vita ny fanambadiana"},{"question":"సమన్యాయపాలన అంటే ఏమిటి ?","answer":"సమన్యాయపాలన అంటే చట్టం ఆధిక్యత అని అర్థం. సమన్యాయపాలన అమలులో ఉన్న దేశాలలో ప్రభుత్వాధికారాలు చట్టాల ద్వారా నిర్ణయించబడతాయి. ప్రభుత్వ చర్యలన్నింటికి చట్టసమ్మతి ఉండాలి. చట్టాన్ని ఉల్లంఘించినపుడు మాత్రమే వ్యక్తి శిక్షింపబడతాడు. ధనిక, పేద అనే విచక్షణ లేకుండా చట్టం అందరినీ సమానంగా చూస్తుంది. చట్ట ఆధిక్యత లేదా సమన్యాయ పాలన ఉండటం వలన వ్యక్తులకు స్వేచ్ఛా, స్వాతంత్ర్యాలు లభిస్తాయి."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"banyak tangan\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Ia bermaksud ramai orang yang terlibat dalam menguruskan sesuatu hal. Contoh ayat: Banyak masalah akan timbul jikalau terlalu banyak tangan terlibat dalam projek ini."},{"question":"ಕರ್ನಾಟಕದ ಪ್ರಮುಖ ವಿಮಾನ ನಿಲ್ದಾಣಗಳು ಯಾವುವು? ","answer":"ಕರ್ನಾಟಕದಲ್ಲಿ 8 ವಿಮಾನ ನಿಲ್ದಾಣಗಳು ವಾಣಿಜ್ಯ ವಿಮಾನಸೇವೆ ಒದಗಿಸುತ್ತವೆ. ಬೆಂಗಳೂರು ಮತ್ತು ಮಂಗಳೂರು ಪ್ರಮುಖ ಅಂತರರಾಷ್ಟ್ರೀಯ ವಿಮಾನ ನಿಲ್ದಾಣಗಳಾದರೆ ಹುಬ್ಬಳ್ಳಿ, ಬೆಳಗಾವಿ, ಬೀದರ, ಕಲಬುರಗಿ, ವಿದ್ಯಾನಗರ (ಹಂಪಿ), ಮತ್ತು ಮೈಸೂರು ಇತರ ನಿಲ್ದಾಣಗಳಾಗಿವೆ. "},{"question":"ਫਰਾਂਸ਼ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਸਰਕੋਜ਼ੀ ਨੂੰ ਭ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟਾਚਾਰ ਦੇ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ 3 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਸਜ਼ਾ।ਸਰਕੋਜ਼ੀ 'ਤੇ ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਮਜਿਸਟ੍ਰੇਟ ਨੂੰ ਮੋਨੈਕੋ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਚੰਗੀ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਦੇ ਐਵਜ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਖਿਲਾਫ ਜਾਰੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਮਿਨਲ ਜਾਂਚ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਮੰਗੀ ਸੀ। ਦੋਸ਼ੀ ਮਜਿਸਟ੍ਰੇਟ ਤੇ ਸਰਕੋਜ਼ੀ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਵਕੀਲ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਇਹੀ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਮਿਲੀ ਹੈ। ਸਰਕੋਜ਼ੀ ਇਹ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਭੁਗਤ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ। ਆਪਣੀ ਰੂਲਿੰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੱਜ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਰਕੋਜ਼ੀ ਇਹ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਭੁਗਤ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਇਲੈਕਟ੍ਰੋਨਿਕ ਟੈਗ ਲਾਉਣਾ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। ਸਰਕੋਜ਼ੀ ਇਸ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ ਅਪੀਲ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ।","answer":"ਫਰਾਂਸ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਨਿਕੋਲਸ ਸਰਕੋਜ਼ੀ ਨੂੰ ਭ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟਾਚਾਰ ਦਾ ਦੋਸ਼ੀ ਮੰਨਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਤਿੰਨ ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਸੁਣਾਈ ਗਈ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"බාලදක්ෂ ව්‍යාපාරයේ පියා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"බේඩ්න් පවල් සාමි බාලදක්ෂ ව්‍යාපාරයේ පියා වේ."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Theo đó, tại thông báo số 60/TB-BTST của Ban trị sự GHPGVN tỉnh Vĩnh Phúc về Kết luận phiên họp Tăng sự của Ban thường trực Ban trị sự GHPGVN tỉnh Vĩnh Phúc cho biết phiên họp của Ban trị sự GHPGVN tỉnh Vĩnh Phúc cùng Ban chỉ đạo Công tác Tôn giáo tỉnh, Ban Dân vận tỉnh, UBND tỉnh, Ủy Ban MTTQ tỉnh, Công an tỉnh đã kết luận: Đối với tu sĩ Thích Minh Pháp sẽ chờ cơ quan công an điều tra, xác minh làm rõ khi nào có kết quả mới có hướng giải quyết tiếp theo. Đối với tu sĩ Thích Đạo Phúc giao Ban trị sự GHPGVN huyện Yên Lạc cách hết tất cả các chức vụ. Kết luận cũng thông báo Giao Ban trị sự GHPGVN tỉnh Vĩnh Phúc quản lý điều hành mọi hoạt động Phật sự tại chùa Biện Sơn, thị trấn Yên Lạc và chùa Kim Đường, xã Tam Hồng, huyện Yên Lạc trong thời gian đình chỉ trụ trì. Trường hạ chùa Biện Sơn, huyện Yên Lạc cơ sở Hạ Trường tập trung do Ban thường trực Ban trị sự GHPGVN tỉnh Vĩnh Phúc tổ chức, nay chuyển về Bố tát và Tự","answer":"tứ tại Hạ trường chùa Bầu, phường Liên Bảo, TP. Vĩnh Yên, tỉnh Vĩnh Phúc. Trước đó, sáng 18/7, Báo điện tử Dân Việt đã đăng tải loạt bài Tà dâm nơi cửa Phật tại chùa Biện Sơn. Theo đó, trụ trì chùa Biện Sơn là Thượng tọa Thích Minh Pháp, Uỷ viên Ban Văn hóa - Hoằng pháp Trung ương Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam, Ủy viên Ban trị sự Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam tỉnh Vĩnh Phúc và tu sĩ Thích Đạo Phúc, quản lý chùa Kim Đường đã có hành vi \\"gạ dâm, quấy rối\\". Đây là hiện tượng cá biệt \\"con sâu làm rầu nồi canh\\" làm ảnh hưởng đến uy tín của Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam. Ngày 19/7, Hội đồng trị sự Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam đã có Quyết định số 299 về việc thi hành kỷ luật đối với tu sĩ Thích Minh Pháp, trụ trì chùa Biện Sơn. Chủ tịch Hội đồng trị sự Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam quyết định cách tất cả các chức vụ trong Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam của tu sĩ Thích Minh Pháp, Ủy viên Ban Văn hóa Trung ương, Phó Trưởng ban Ban trị sự Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam tỉnh Vĩnh Phúc, Trưởng ban Ban Trị sự Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam huyện Yên Lạc. Giao Ban trị sự Giáo hội Phật giáo Việt Nam tỉnh Vĩnh Phúc thi hành kỷ luật đối với tu sĩ Thích Minh Pháp. Đồng thời tạm đình chỉ chức vụ trụ trì chùa Biện Sơn, biệt chúng sám hối (lễ Phật sám hối, không được tiếp xúc với mọi người) trong 6 tháng."},{"question":"请解释“邦以民为本”的意思。","answer":"这句话是古代儒家民本思想的一种反映,认为万民百姓是国家的根本。治国应以安民、得民作为根本。"},{"question":"Dame un resumen del libro \\"Las Crónicas de Narnia \\" :","answer":"\\"Las Crónicas de Narnia\\" es una serie de  siete libros de fantasía escritos por C. S. Lewis. Las serie transporta a los lectores  a un mundo mágico lleno de aventuras, criaturas mitológicas y lecciones Morales. Cada libro Narra una historia independiente, pero todos están conectados por el mismo mundo de Narnia y algunos personajes recurrentes "},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity.Fanambarana: \\"Tezitra be dadanay\\"","answer":"Ny fanambarana teo aloha dia manondro tahotra. Matahotra ianao fa tezitra be ny dadanao."},{"question":"Any amin'ny tanàna italiana aiza no misy ny tilikambo mitongilana malaza?","answer":"Any Pise, Italia, ilay tilikambo mitongilana malaza."},{"question":"作中ではゾンビピッグマン、エンダーマン、クリーパーなどが登場する、ドット絵風の立方体ブロックを配置して様々な物を作ることができるサンドボックスゲームは何?","answer":"Minecraft（マインクラフト）です。"},{"question":"Peygamber Efendimizin çiçeğinin adı nedir?","answer":"Peygamber çiçeği bitkisi mavi renkte bulunduğu için mavi kantaron olarak da adlandırılmaktadır."},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng cho câu hỏi sau:Sau Pháp, nước nào có nhiều người giành giải Nobel Văn học nhất?a. Đứcb. Mỹc. Ấn Độ","answer":"Đó là nước MỹĐến nay, Mỹ có 12 tác giả giành giải Nobel Văn học, gồm: Sinclair Lewis, 1930; Eugene O'Neill, 1936; Pearl Buck, 1938; William Faulkner, 1949; Ernest Hemingway, 1954; John Steinbeck, 1962; Saul Bellow, 1976; Isaac Bashevis Singer, 1978; Joseph Brodsky, 1987; Toni Morrison, 1993; Bob Dyland, 2016; Louise Glück, 2020.Theo sách Tóm lược Văn học Hoa Kỳ của GS Kathryn Van Spanckeren, nền tảng của văn học Mỹ được xây dựng từ những câu chuyện thần thoại, truyền thuyết, cổ tích và các bài ca trữ tình được truyền miệng từ các nền văn hóa của người da đỏ. Truyền thống truyền miệng của người Mỹ bản địa tương đối phong phú.Cuộc cách mạng Mỹ chống lại người Anh (1775-1783) là cuộc chiến tranh giải phóng hiện đại đầu tiên chống lại cường quốc thực dân. Chiến thắng quân sự đã thắp sáng niềm hy vọng về chủ nghĩa dân tộc và làm nảy sinh một nền văn học mới. Người Mỹ nhận thấy sự phụ thuộc quá mức của văn học Mỹ vào mô thức văn học kiểu Anh. Họ khát khao tìm kiếm một nền văn học bản địa.Nhà văn lớn đầu tiên của nước Mỹ là James Fenimor Cooper (1789-1851), tiếp đó là Ralph Waldo Emerson (1803-1882), Henry David Thoreau (1817-1862), Walt Whitman (1819-1892), Emily Dickinson (1830-1886).Cuộc nội chiến (1861-1865) là bước ngoặt lớn trong lịch sử Mỹ, những hoạt động sản xuất, kinh doanh buôn bán bùng nổ mạnh mẽ sau đó. Nền công nghiệp hóa lớn mạnh gây ra những ảnh hưởng lớn đến đời sống xã hội. Hai tiểu thuyết gia vĩ đại nhất thời kỳ này là Mark Twain và Henry James.Bước sang thế kỷ 20, nước Mỹ có những tên tuổi văn học lớn khác như: Thomas Stearns Eliot (1888-1965), Robert Lee Frost (1874-1963), Francis Scott Key Fitzgerald (1896-1940), Ernest Hemingway (1899-1961).Đến nay, nước Pháp có 16 giải Nobel Văn học, Mỹ 12 giải, Anh 11 giải. Một số nước có 4-6 giải Nobel Văn học gồm: Đức, Thuỵ Điển, Italy, Tây Ban Nha, Ba Lan, Ireland, Nga."},{"question":"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ |","answer":"ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ (ਉਚਾਰਨ ) (ਜਨਮ 12 ਦਸੰਬਰ 1981) ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਅੰਤਰ-ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਆਲ-ਰਾਊਂਡਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਖੇਡਦਾ ਹੈ। ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਇੱਕ ਖੱਬੂ ਬੱਲੇਬਾਜ਼ ਅਤੇ ਖੱਬੂ-ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ ਹੈ। ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਇੱਕ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ। ਯੂਵੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ, ਤੇਜ਼ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ ਅਤੇ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਯੋਗਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਦਾ  ਪੁੱਤਰ ਹੈ। ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਸੰਨ 2000 ਤੋਂ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਟੀਮ ਦਾ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਟੈਸਟ ਮੈਚ ਅਕਤੂਬਰ, 2003 ਵਿੱਚ ਖੇਡਿਆ। ਯੂਵੀ 2007-2008 ਦੌਰਾਨ ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨਾ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਕਪਤਾਨ ਵੀ ਰਿਹਾ। ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੂੰ ਆਈਸੀਸੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਕੱਪ 2011 ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸਦੇ ਸ਼ਾਨਦਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਲਈ ਮੈਨ ਆਫ ਦ ਟੂਰਨਾਮੈਂਟ ਵੀ ਚੁਣਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ '2007 ਆਈਸੀਸੀ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਟਵੰਟੀ-ਟਵੰਟੀ ਕੱਪ' ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਉਸਦਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਅਹਿਮ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਸੀ। ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਹੀ ਟੂਰਨਾਮੈਂਟ ਭਾਰਤ ਨੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ ਸਨ।2007 ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਕੱਪ ਟਵੰਟੀ-ਟਵੰਟੀ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਹੋਏ ਮੈਚ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਟੂਅਰਟ ਬਰੌਡ ਦੇ ਓਵਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ 6 ਗੇਂਦਾਂ ਤੇ 6 ਛਿੱਕੇ ਲਗਾ ਕੇ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕਦਮ ਹੈਰਾਨ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਦੋ ਟੈਸਟ ਟੀਮਾਂ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ-ਦੂਜੇ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਇਹ ਅੱਜ ਵੀ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਰਿਕਾਰਡ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਟਵੰਟੀ-ਟਵੰਟੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਤੇਜ਼ 50 ਦੌੜਾਂ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਰਿਕਾਰਡ ਵੀ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੇ ਨਾਂਮ ਹੈ। ਯੂਵੀ ਨੇ 2007 ਵਿੱਚ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਸਿਰਫ 12 ਗੇਂਦਾਂ 'ਤੇ 50 ਦੌੜਾਂ ਬਣਾ ਕੇ ਇਹ ਰਿਕਾਰਡ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ।== ਖੇਡਣ ਦਾ ਢੰਗ ==ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਇੱਕ ਖੱਬੂ ਬੱਲੇਬਾਜ਼ ਹੈ ਪਰੰਤੂ ਉਹ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਵੀ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਯੂਵੀ ਆਕਰਾਮਕ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਖੇਡਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਤੇਜ਼ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਬਹੁਤ ਵਧੀਆ ਖੇਡਦਾ ਹੈ। ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੂੰ ਉਸਦੇ ਜਿਆਦਾ ਛੱਕੇ ਲਗਾਉਣ ਕਰਕੇ 'ਸਿਕਸਰ ਕਿੰਗ' ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ ਮੱਧ (ਮਿਡਲ ਔਡਰ) ਵਿੱਚ ਬੱਲੇਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਲਈ ਉੱਤਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਯੂਵੀ ਜਿਆਦਾਤਰ 'ਪੁਆਇੰਟ' ਤੇ ਫੀਲਡਿੰਗ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਚੋਟੀ ਦੇ ਫੀਲਡਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਗਿਣਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।== ਸਵੈ-ਜੀਵਨੀ =='ਦ ਟੈਸਟ ਆਫ਼ ਮਾਈ ਲਾਈਫ਼'- ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਤੋਂ ਕੈਂਸਰ ਅਤੇ ਵਾਪਸੀ।== ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ==12 ਨਵੰਬਰ 2016 ਨੂੰ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਦੀ ਮੰਗਣੀ ਹੈਜ਼ਲ ਕੀਚ ਨਾਲ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ 30 ਨਵੰਬਰ 2016 ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਬੰਧਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੱਝ ਗਏ ਸਨ।== ਬਾਹਰੀ ਕੜੀਆਂ ==ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਦੀ ਟਵਿੱਟਰ ਪ੍ਰੋਫਾਈਲਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੀ ਫੇਸਬੁੱਕ ਪ੍ਰੋਫਾਈਲਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ Archived 2015-04-18 at the Wayback Machine. ਦਾ ਵਿਸਡਨ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਫਾਈਲ ਪੇਜਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਸਿੰਘ Archived 2007-11-26 at the Wayback Machine.== ਹਵਾਲੇ =="},{"question":"صحابي جليل قدم من الحبشة على رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم يوم فتح خيبر فقبل المصطفى بين عينيه والتزقه وقال: ما أدري بأيهما أنا أسَرَّ, بفتح خيبر أم بقدوم..؟","answer":"جعفر بن أبي طالب"},{"question":"வினா: ஒரு பிட் என்பது?","answer":"விடை: 1 அல்லது 0"},{"question":"Кудайдын куттуу күнү дегендин мааниси кандай?","answer":" Күнүгө, ар күнү, күн сайын"},{"question":"Tôi vừa được bố mẹ chia cho một khu đất diện tích 500 m2, mặt tiền 10 m, nằm gần đường lớn, vị trí thuận tiện. Sau khi khảo sát khu vực lân cận, tôi dự định xây kho xưởng cho thuê.Tuy nhiên, với ngân sách 1,5 tỷ đồng, tôi không biết nên phân chia ra sao để quá trình xây dựng được hiệu quả, tiết kiệm, tránh phát sinh chi phí. Ngoài ra, để kinh doanh kho xưởng, thủ tục xin cấp phép cần chuẩn bị những gì, hay nên lưu ý các yếu tố nào khi vận hành.Bây giờ tôi nên làm gì","answer":"Theo mình thì bạn nên cho thuê đất và nhà đầu tư tự xây dựng. Hợp đồng dài hạn (3-5 năm). 1,5 tỷ kia bạn đầu tư vào các kênh khác như mua thêm nhà vùng quen cho thuê, hoặc mua đất, vàng, gửi tiết kiệm để sinh lời. Hoặc trích ra 10% để học hỏi kiến thức từ các chuyên gia. Chưa có kiến thức rất dễ phát sinh những sự cố ngoài mong đợi, ví dụ đầu tư tiền vào xây dựng nhà kho mà chậm có khách thuê thì chôn vốn vào đó, hoặc sau nhiều năm số tiền thu lại có tăng so với số tiền đã bỏ ra hay không?"},{"question":"Напиши продовження: Бразильські–уругвайські відносини - двосторонні відносини між Бразилією та Уругваєм. Бразилія і Уругвай розташовані по сусідству в Південній Америці й мають тісні політичні, економічні та культурні зв'язки. ","answer":"Близькість двосторонніх відносин між двома країнами походить від сильного історичної зв'язку, позначеного важливими подіями: створенням \\"Колонії-дель-Сакраменто\\" в 1680 році, вторгненням Бразилії в \\"Східну полосу\\" в 1815 році і подальшим створенням провінції \\"Сисплатина\\", а також відділенням Уругваю від Бразилії 1828 року. Двосторонні відносини були додатково позначені Громадянською війною в Уругваї(1839-1851) та Війною Потрійного Альянсу (1864-1870)."},{"question":"सर्वात मोठा ग्रह कोणता?उत्तर :","answer":"सर्वात मोठा ग्रह बृहस्पति आहे."},{"question":"வினா: இந்தியாவில் உள்ள மொத்த மாவட்டங்கள்?","answer":"விடை: 748 மாவட்டங்கள்"},{"question":"ਗਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਲਈ ਕੀ-ਕੀ ਯਤਨ ਕੀਤੇ ?","answer":"ਗਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿਚ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਲਈ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੈ-* ਰਾਸ ਬਿਹਾਰੀ ਬੋਸ ਨੇ ਲਾਹੌਰ, ਫ਼ਿਰੋਜ਼ਪੁਰ, ਮੇਰਠ, ਅੰਬਾਲਾ, ਮੁਲਤਾਨ, ਪਿਸ਼ਾਵਰ ਅਤੇ ਕਈ ਹੋਰ ਛਾਉਣੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰਕ ਭੇਜੇ | ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਸੈਨਿਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬਗਾਵਤ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤਾ ।* ਕਰਤਾਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਸਰਾਭਾ ਨੇ ਕਪੂਰਥਲਾ ਦੇ ਲਾਲਾ ਰਾਮਸਰਨ ਦਾਸ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ “ਗਦਰ’ ਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਹਫ਼ਤਾਵਰ ਰਸਾਲਾ ਛਾਪਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ । ਪਰ ਉਹ ਸਫਲ ਨਾ ਹੋ ਸਕਿਆ । ਫਿਰ ਵੀ ਉਹ “ਗਦਰ ਗੂੰਜ ਛਾਪਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ।* ਸਰਾਭਾ ਨੇ ਫਰਵਰੀ, 1915 ਵਿਚ ਫ਼ਿਰੋਜ਼ਪੁਰ ਵਿਚ ਹਥਿਆਰਬੰਦ ਬਗ਼ਾਵਤ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ, ਪਰ ਕ੍ਰਿਪਾਲ ਸਿੰਘ ਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਇਕ ਸਿਪਾਹੀ ਦੀ ਧੋਖੇਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਭੇਤ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹ ਗਿਆ ।"},{"question":"waxaad sheegtaa astaamaha jooniska Ka dhasha Caanaha naaska hooyada ?","answer":"Joonis ama maqaarka iyo indhaha oo huruud u ekaada waa xaalad ku badan ilmaha yar yar ee dhashay ee naaska nuugaya. Dhab ahaantii, ilaa 60 boqolkiiba dhalaanka yar yar  ayuu ku dhacaa jooniskaan dhalashadooda maalmo yar un kadib. Xaaladan waxay dhici kartaa marka ilmaha dhiigooda uu ku jiro xaddi ama tiro badan oo ah dheecaanka loo yaqaan bilirubin. Dheecaanka bilirubin waa shay midabkiisu huruudi ama jaale yahay kaasoo la soo saaro marka la burburinayo unugyada dhiiga cas si loogu badalo unugyo cusub.Caadi ahaan, dheecaanka bilirubin wuxuu soo dhex maraa beerka, kadibna beerku wuxuu kusii shubaa xiidmaha si uu uga qayb qaato dheefshiidka cuntada. Balse, Ilmaha yar yar ee dhawaan dhaladka ah beerkoodu badanaa maahan mid samayskiisu u dhameystiran yahay waxaana dhici karta inuusan awood u yeelan beerku inuu dheecaanka bilirubin ka saaro dhiiga. Hadaba hadii dheecaanka bilirubin uu ku bato dhiiga, wuxuu fariisan karaa maqaarka. Taas ayaana sababaysa in maqaarka iyo indhaha qofka qaba cagaarshowgu ay ugu ekaadaan huruud ama jaale.Jooniska naas nuuga ama jooniska ilmaha dhashay ku dhacaa waa nooc joonis ah oo la xiriira naas nuujinta. Wuxuu badanaa dhacaa hal isbuuc kadib dhalashada ilmaha. Xaaladan waxay badanaa ilmaha sii hayn kartaa ilaa iyo 12 isbuuc, balse nasiib wanaag malahan dhibaatooyin danbe oo caafimaad, mar hadii ilmuhu ka buskoodana khatar kale oo caafimaad malahan.Maxaa sababa jooniska caanaha naaska?Dhakhaatiirtu ma garan wali waxa sababa jooniska caanaha naaska. Balse, waxaa lala xidhiidhin karaa in uu jiro shay kujira caanaha naaska kaas oo diidaya in borotiinada qaarkood ee kujira beerka dhalaanku ay burburiyaan dheecaanka bilirubin. Waxaa kaloo lala xidhiidhin karaa xaaladan arimaha qoyska oo ay macquul noqon karto in ay dhaxal tahay.Saan horay ugu soo sheegnayba jooniska caanaha naaska waa xaalad dhif ah in ay dhacdo, xataa hadii ay dhacdo maahan khatar caafimaad waana wax badanaa iskood iskaga taga. Waa caadi in hooyadu ay naaska sii nuujiso ilmaheeda xataa hadii ay ku aragtay joonis."},{"question":"Suva moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Suva moy péeyu réwum Fidji"},{"question":"Cuba jawab teka-teki berikut: Askar putih dalam gua?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah gigi"},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng:Nhà tù Hỏa Lò được xây dựng năm nào?A. 1896B. 1897C. 1898","answer":"Đáp án đúng là A. 1896Theo thông tin trên website của nhà tù Hỏa lò, cuối thế kỷ XIX, nhằm đối phó với các phong trào đấu tranh của nhân dân Việt Nam, thực dân Pháp đã tăng cường bộ máy đàn áp: bổ sung lực lượng cảnh sát, hoàn chỉnh hệ thống toà án và xây dựng mạng lưới nhà tù.Năm 1896, thực dân Pháp xây dựng nhà tù Hỏa Lò có tổng diện tích 12.908 m2, là một trong những nhà lao lớn và kiên cố bậc nhất Đông Dương bấy giờ.Nhà tù Hỏa Lò được thiết kế thành 4 khu: A, B, C, D với tường bao quanh cao 4 m dày 0,5 m, gia cố thêm mảnh thủy tinh và dây thép điện. Khu A, B là khu vực giam giữ các phạm nhân đang điều tra, phạm nhân không quan trọng hoặc những người vi phạm kỷ cương của nhà tù.Khu C dành cho tù nhân Pháp hoặc ngoại quốc. Khu D dành cho phạm nhân đang chờ thụ án tử hình.Nhà tù Hỏa Lò là địa danh nổi tiếng bởi từng giam giữ hàng nghìn chiến sĩ yêu nước, cách mạng Việt Nam. Ngày nay, di tích này chỉ rộng hơn 2.400 và được Bộ Văn hoá Thể thao và Du lịch công nhận là di tích lịch sử năm 1997."},{"question":"Conas a ghlanann mé scáthán? ","answer":"Is gnách go ndéantar scáthán a ghlanadh le clúdach agus gallúnach. An fuinneog a bhogadh ar dtús. Ansin scrios an salach as. D'fhéadfá táirgí glanta speisialaithe a úsáid freisin. "},{"question":"Аркы-беркини түшүнгөн.","answer":"Ар нерсени билген, көптү көргөн, тажырыйбасы бар."},{"question":"Fale sobre a guerra civil que se desenrolou na Angola após ter adquirido independência.","answer":"A guerra civil pós-independência (1975-2002) foi um conflito devastador entre o MPLA (apoiado pela URSS e Cuba) e a UNITA (apoiada pelos EUA e a África do Sul). Milhares de vidas foram perdidas e muitas infraestruturas danificada, deixando cicatrizes profundas na sociedade e na economia do país."},{"question":"Como é chamada um veado fêmea?","answer":"Corça."},{"question":"شكون هو الأب ديال السيدة مريم ؟","answer":"سيدنا عمران"},{"question":"கேள்வி: தும்பா ராக்கெட் ஏவுதளம் எந்த மாநிலத்தில் உள்ளது? விடை:","answer":"கேரளா. தும்பா கேரளத்தின் தலைநகரான திருவனந்தபுரத்தின் ஒரு புறநகர்ப் பகுதி. 1962-ஆம் ஆண்டு இப்பகுதியில் ராக்கெட் ஏவுதளம் அமைக்கப்பட்டது. 1963 நவம்பர் 21-இல் முதன் முதலில் சவுண்டிங் ராக்கெட்டான நைக்-அப்பாச்சி இதிலிருந்து ஏவப்பட்டது."},{"question":"Кызыктту  фактылар жөнүндө жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Көзүн жумбай туруп чүчкүрө албайт."},{"question":"Awubheke ucishe wona ubuhle nobumnandi bendumezulu yomshado.Eqinisweni njalo ngangingaboni impela ukuthi singasuke silandele isikobese siyathandana. Namanje ungathi ngiyaphupha.Uma ubheka uthi umfowethu ungibeka icala ngalesi senzo sethu?1. Ngubani lo Sipho okukhulunywa ngaye kulesi siqephu?","answer":"Owayengumngani omkhulu kaThenjiwe."},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Kin-in-ni)","answer":"Ẹ jẹ ka ki Adeboye pẹlu OyedepoNibi ti ilu ba ti daa, ki i ṣe awọn baba ọmọ ọgọrin ọdun, aadọrin ọdun, ni wọn yoo tun maa sare kiri lati ta ko ijọba kan. Ṣugbọn Naijiria wa yii ko daa, awọn ti wọn si n ṣejọba ni ko jẹ ko dara. Ṣugbọn ki i ṣe awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba wa nikan ni ika to wa nilẹ wa, awọn eeyan ti wọn n jẹ ijẹkujẹ ninu ijọba ti wọn n ṣe ni Naijiria naa buru pupọ ju iku ti n pa ni lọ. Bi wahala ba ba awọn eeyan, wọn ko ni i sọrọ, wọn si le sọrọ pe ohun ti ijọba n ṣe lo dara ju, bo tilẹ jẹ ninu ọkan wọn lọhun-un, wọn mọ pe ohun tawọn eeyan ti wọn n ṣejọba naa n ṣe ko dara. Nitori ẹ leeyan yoo ṣe ki awọn eeyan bii Pasitọ Adeboye, ati Biṣọọbu Oyedepo, ati awọn pasitọ mi-in loriṣiiriṣii, gbogbo awọn ti wọn ti jade sita pe ohun to n lọ ni Naijiria yii ko dara, ti wọn si n ṣe atilẹyin fun awọn ọdọ ti wọn n fi ẹhonu wọn han kaakiri. Ẹni ti ọrọ ko ba ye yoo ro pe awọn eeyan yii ko fẹran ijọba Buhari ni. Ṣugbọn ẹni to ba mọ idi ipilẹṣẹ ijọba yii, yoo mọ pe gbogbo awọn pasitọ wọnyi ni Buhari de ọdọ wọn, awọn ti ko ba si de ọdọ wọn, o ranṣẹ pataki si wọn lori idi ti oun ṣe fẹẹ gbajọba. Ijọba naa lo si gba ti ko ṣe daadaa to yii. O wa ninu ọrọ Ọlọrun, ninu Bibeli, paapaa lọdọ awọn Musulumi naa, pe nibi ti eeyan ba ti ri ibajẹ to n lọ lawujọ, ki tọhun yi i pada kia ni. Awọn Musulumi tilẹ ta ku pe tọhun ko gbọdọ dakẹ, bi ko ba le fi agbara rẹ yi i, ko fi ọrọ ẹnu rẹ yi i pada, ko ṣaa jẹ ki gbogbo aye mọ pe kinni naa ko dara. Ohun tawọn eeyan Ọlọrun wọnyi n ṣe ree. Ko yẹ ki iru Adeboye maa kanra mọ ijọba Buhari, tabi ko maa wa lẹyin awọn ti wọn fẹẹ doju ijọba naa de, ṣebi igbakeji Buhari, ọkan ninu awọn ọmọlẹyin Adeboye ni. Ṣugbọn Adeboye ri i pe ohun to n lọ ko dara, idi to fi n tẹle awọn ajafẹtọọ gbogbo niyi. Ọmọ rẹ. Leke Adeboye, lo ṣe isin fun awọn ọdọ ni Alausa, bẹẹ ni iyawo rẹ, Pasitọ Adeboye obinrin, ko ounjẹ rẹpẹtẹ fawọn ti wọn n fẹhonu han naa. Ohun to yẹ ki awọn aṣaaju wa ṣe niyi, bi nnkan ko ba dara, ‘Ẹ sọrọ soke,’ nitori ẹni to ba dakẹ, ti ara rẹ yoo ba a dakẹ, bi Naijiria ba si buru ju bayii lọ, awọn olowo, awọn oloṣelu ati awọn eeyan nla awujọ paapaa yoo fara gba a. Ẹ ṣeun o, Pasitọ Adeboye; ẹ ṣe e, Biṣọọbu Oyedepo, ati awọn pasitọ to ku gbogbo.Bẹẹ naa lawọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba gbogboNigba toro yii ba relẹ daadaa, to mu idẹra ati alaafia ti gbogbo ilu n fẹ wa, yoo ṣoro lati gbagbe awọn gomina nilẹ Yoruba, paapaa, Babajide Sanwo-Olu l’Ekoo, Ṣeyi Makinde ni Ọyo, ati Kayọde Fayẹmi paapaa l’Ekiti. Sawoolu ṣe e debii pe o ri awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn pa ninu awọn ọdọ yii ni Surulere mu jade, wọn si darukọ wọn faye gbọ, o si leri pe ijọba oun yoo tẹle ọrọ naa lati ri i pe iya jẹ awọn ọlọpaa yii dọba. Makinde lọ sile awọn ti wọn pa ni Ogbomọṣọ, bẹẹ lo fun wọn lowo, to si sọ pe ni gbogbo ọna ni ijọba oun fi fara mọ ọn pe ki wọn ko SARS kuro ninu awọn ọlọpaa Naijiria, ki wọn pa wọn rẹ pata, nitori iwa wọn ko dara. Awọn ko huwa bii awọn gomina ilẹ Hausa to jẹ gbogbo ohun ti ijọba Buhari ba ti ṣe lo dara, koda ko jẹ ohun ti yoo fi iya jẹ awọn eeyan wọn ni. Ojuṣe akọkọ ti gbogbo ijọba ni ni lati daabo bo awọn eeyan rẹ lọwọ ewu gbogbo: boya iku ojiji ni o, tabi iṣofo ẹmi ati dukia, tabi ifiyajẹni ati ihalẹ gbogbo. Ijọba ti ko ba ti le daabo bo awọn araalu rẹ, ijọba buruku ni, gbogbo eeyan lo gbọdọ kọyin si iru ijọba bẹẹ, koda ki wọn jọ wa ninu ẹgbẹ oṣelu kan naa. Ohun to n mu orilẹ-ede agbaye dara si i lojoojumọ niyi. Ohun ti awọn ọdọ Naijiria wọnyi n beere fun, ohun daadaa ni, ijọba ko si gbọdọ da ọrọ naa si agidi, ki wọn ṣe ohun ti wọn n fẹ fun wọn ni. Ohun ti wọn fẹ yii ki i kuku ṣe pe awọn nikan ni wọn yoo jẹ anfaani ẹ, gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria ni ọrọ naa yoo mu itura ba bo ba ṣẹlẹ, nitori ẹ ni gbogbo ilu ṣe gbọdọ ti wọn lẹyin, titi ti ijọba yii yoo fi ṣe ohun ti wọn n pariwo ẹ yii. Afi ka ṣe e ko yanju, bi a o ba ṣe e ko yanju, awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba wa yoo ro pe awọn ni Ọlorun wa ni. Ẹ ṣeun, ẹyin gomina wọnyi, ẹ tubọ mura si i ko ṣee ṣe!Amọ bi ọrọ ba ti da bayii, ẹnu Lai Mohammed ni kẹ ẹ maa ṣọNigba  tiẹ ba ti fẹẹ mọ bi ijọba Buhari yii ṣe n ronu, ẹnu Lai Mohammed, minista fun eto ikede, ni kẹ ẹ maa ṣọ. Yoo tun wa ṣoro ṣaa o, boya ironu naa jẹ ti Aarẹ Buhayhri ati Lai lasan, pẹlu awọn ti wọn jọ n ṣe wọle-wọde, tabi ironu awọn gbogbo ti wọn n ṣẹjọba. Nibẹrẹ osẹ to kọja yii, Igbakeji Aarẹ, Yẹmi Ọṣinbajo, jade, o ni ijọba Buhari tọrọ aforijin lọwọ gbogbo ọdọ, o ni ki wọn ma binu pe awọn ko tete da si ọrọ awọn SARS yii, awọn gba pe awọn jẹbi, ki gbogbo ọdọ pata fori ji awọn. Gbolohun to ti ẹnu Ọṣinbajo jade yii, gbolohun atunṣe ti awọn eeyan fọkan si pe o le jẹ ki ijọba yii ronupiwada, ki wọn si bẹrẹ si i ṣe ohun to dara ni. Ṣugbọn lojiji ni Lai Mohammded jade, oun ko si ni ọrọ alaafia kan lẹnu ti yoo sọ fawọn ọdọ yii ju pe ko sẹni to le da ijọba ru mọ awọn lori, ẹni to ba fẹẹ gbiyanju ẹ, awọn yoo dẹ awọn aja ijọba si i, ohun ti oju onitọhun ba si ri, ko fara mọ ọn. Ọrọ Lai Mohammed, bii ọrọ aja ti yoo sọnu ti ko ni i gbọ fere ọdẹ ni. Gbogbo ohun to n ṣe yii, ati gbogbo ipo to ro pe oun wa yii, ọdun meji ati diẹ naa lo ku fun un, ka tilẹ sọ pe ijọba Buhari yii lo gbogbo akoko rẹ pe. Lẹyin ti Buhari ba lọ, ti wọn gbajọba kuro lọwọ rẹ, ti wọn da Lai pada sibi to ti lọ, nibo lo ku ti yoo gba. Nibo lo fẹẹ gbe! Awọn nnkan wo lo fẹẹ maa ṣe, ta ni yoo pe e sibi iṣẹ gidi kan pe ko waa sọrọ tabi ko waa gba ẹnikẹni nimọran! Aye yoo pa ọkunrin naa ti bii aṣọ to gbo ni, nitori orukọ rẹ ko dara nigboro raa. Iwọnba awọn ti wọn n lọ si ọdọ rẹ bayii, nitori iṣẹ ati awọn ohun diẹ diẹ ti wọn le ri gba lọwọ rẹ nitori to wa nile ijọba ni, bi ko ba si nile ijọba mọ, aye yoo pada lẹyin rẹ debii pe yoo ro pe oun ko si ninu aye naa mọ ni. Ọrọ naa yoo kan awọn ọmọ rẹ paapaa, nitori wọn yoo maa bu wọn ni, wọn yoo si maa yinmu si wọn ni gbangba pe ọmọ Lai Mohammed, opurọ Naijiria nigba kan, ni wọn. Bi Lai Mohammed ko ba ro ti ara rẹ, ko ro tawọn ọmọ rẹ, ko ma fi asiko tirẹ yii ba aye awọn ọmọ naa jẹ lọjọ ọla. Ẹ sọ fun Lai ko yee purọ, ko si yee halẹ mọ awọn ọmọ Naijiria, ọrọ yii yoo lẹyin bo dọla o.Awọn ti wọn kọlu Oyetọla l’ỌsunIroyin to pada jade yii daa. Iroyin to sọ pe awọn ti wọn ko lu Gomina Adegboyega Oyetọla l’Oṣogbo ki i ṣe awọn ti wọn n fi ẹhonu han, awọn tọọgi oloṣelu ni. Bi iru ọrọ bayii ba ṣẹlẹ, iyẹn iru iwọde to n lọ lọwo yii, awọn meji ni wọn maa n fẹẹ fi kinni naa jẹ anfaani ti ko tọ si wọn. Akọkọ ni awọn oloṣelu, ẹẹkeji ni awọn ọdaran, awọn ọmọọta. Awọn oloṣelu yoo jade lati wa ọna ti wọn yoo fi sọ kinni naa di ti ara wọn, ki i ṣe nitori ohun meji si ni eyi bi ko ṣe ọna ti kinni naa yoo gba di owo fun wọn. Awọn ọmọọta yoo wa ọna ti wọn le fi ja owo ati dukia awọn eeyan gba nibi iru iwọde bayii, nitori iwa ọdaran to ti mọ wọn lara. Ṣugbọn gbogbo ẹni to ba n tẹle awọn ọdọ yii yoo ti ri i pe ko si erongba lati huwa ọdaran ninu ohun ti wọn n ṣe, koda, wọn ko ṣe jagidijagan, bẹẹ ni ko si ẹni to lo ohun ija oloro kankan nibi awọn iwọde wọnyi, ohun ti ko si jẹ ki ọlọpaa tabi ṣọja kankan ri wọn mu niyẹn. Awọn ọdọ wọnyi n ṣe iwọde wọn, nitori wọn mọ ohun ti wọn n wa, wọn si mọ ohun ti wọn fẹ ki ijọba ṣe. Wọn fẹẹ gba agbara lọwọ awọn oloṣelu ati awọn eeyan yẹpẹrẹ ti wọn ti joye arijẹnimadaru ti wọn kun ilẹ wa, ti ko mọ ju ki wọn maa rẹ araalu jẹ lọ. Awọn ọdọ naa ko fi ti pe Musulumi ni wọn tabi pe Kristiẹni ni wọn ṣe, wọn ko si fi ti pe boya Hausa ni wọn tabi Ibo ṣe, koda, wọn ko ni olori kan laarin ara wọn, awọn nikan ni wọn mọ bi wọn ti n ṣe e. Nitori rẹ ni Ọlọrun ṣe tete tu aṣiri awọn ti wọn kọ lu Oyetọla, awọn tọọgi oloṣelu ti wọn fẹẹ dara pọ mọ awọn ọdọ wọnyi, ki wọn le ri wọn sọ lẹnu. Ko si ohun meji ti yoo dara ju ki ijọba ati awọn ọlọpaa wa awọn tọọgi yii ri, ki wọn mu wọn, ki wọn si fi iya ti ko lẹgbẹ jẹ wọn. Bo ba ṣee ṣe lati ri awọn oloṣelu were ti wọn ran wọn niṣẹ yii mu, ki wọn mu awọn naa, ki wọn fi wọn han gbogbo aye, kaye le mọ pe ọbayejẹ ni wọn, lẹyin naa ni ki wọn jẹ ki iya to tọ si wọn jẹ wọn. Awọn ọmọọta ti wọn kọlu gomina naa ko ṣe daadaa rara, iya gidi si gbọdọ jẹ wọn, ki wọn le ti ọwọ ọmọ wọn bọ aṣọ.Iku Ọmọ Awolọwọ n’IbadanRefurẹẹni Tọla Oyediran, akọbi Oloye Ọbafẹmi Awolọwọ lobinrin, naa jade laye lọsẹ to kọja. Iku rẹ ṣe gbogbo aye ni kayeefi, ohun to si fa a ni pe awọn ti wọn ju u lọ ṣi wa laye daadaa. Ninu oṣu kejila, ọdun yii, ni Mama naa iba pe ẹni ọgọrin (80) ọdun, afi bi iku yii ṣe sare mu un lọ. Ko si ohun to mu iku rẹ dun awọn eeyan pupọ ju pe loootọ ni gbogbo aye n ranti, ti wọn si mọ ẹni ti Awolọwọ i ṣe, ọkan ninu awọn ti itan baba naa wa lọwọ rẹ lo ti tun lọ yii, nitori lẹyin oun, ọmọ baba yii kan naa lo tun ku laye. Ati pe iwa bii ti Awolọwọ ati awọn ilakaka lori bi awọn ohun ti baba naa ja fun nigba aye rẹ ko ṣe ni i parẹ lobinrin naa fi ọpọ aye rẹ ṣe, titi di igba to si ku yii naa lo jẹ ọrọ awọn ọdọ ti wọn fẹẹ fi ẹhonu wọn ṣe atunṣe si Naijiria lo n sọ lẹnu. Ẹkọ inu ọrọ yii ni pe ko si ẹni to wa laye yii ti ko ni i ku, ko si ẹni ti yoo lagbara loni-in ti ko ni i di ọlẹ bo ba dọla. Gbogbo ibi yoowu ti eeyan ba le wa laye yii, boya tọhun fẹ o, boya o kọ ni o, yoo fi ipo naa silẹ ni. Awọn oloṣelu ti wọn n ṣe gaugau kiri ilu bayii, meloo meloo ni iru wọn ti wọn ti wa ti wọn ti lọ, ṣugbọn ilu n ranti Awolọwọ ati awọn ọmọ rẹ nitori iṣẹ rere ti baba naa ṣe nidii oṣelu ni. Ẹni to ba wa ni ipo kan ko ṣe e daadaa, ko lo ipo naa lọna rere, ki gbogbo aye le maa ranti rẹ tọmọtọmọ. Ki Ọlọrun da ọmọ Awolọwo kan naa to ku si, ati awọn ọmọọmọ rẹ, ko si ṣe itunu fun Purofẹsọ Oyediran ti i ṣe ọkọ oloogbe, ati awọn ọmọ ti iya naa fi saye lọ. Iku ko loogun, ko si ohun tẹnikan kan le ṣe si i."},{"question":"සංඛ්‍යාත මුර්ජනය හෙවත් එෆ්.එම් ( FM) ක්‍රමය ලෝකයට හඳුන්වාදුන්නේ කවුද ?","answer":"සංඛ්‍යාත මුර්ජනය හෙවත් එෆ්.එම් ( FM) ක්‍රමය ලෝකයට හඳුන්වාදුන්නේ එඩ්වින් අම්ස්ට්රෝන්ග් ‍ය."},{"question":"Які міри довжини стосувалися за часів Київської Русі?","answer":"Основними мірами довжини ще з часів Київської Русі були \\"локоть\\", \\"п'ядь\\", \\"ступня\\", \\"сажень\\" і навіть \\"крок\\". \\"Локоть\\" - відстань між ліктьовим суглобом і кінцем стиснутого улака (\\"п'ястуха\\") людини середнього зросту- становив 45-50 см. \\"Литовський\\" локоть дорівнював 61,6 см і був поширентй на Поліссі. Меншими за величпною були такі міри, як \\"стопа\\" і \\"п'ядь\\". У Карпатах паралельно зі \\"стопою\\" вживався термін німецького походження \\"шух\\" (приблизно 30 см), який ділився на 12 \\"перстів\\", чи \\"пальців\\" (величина великого пальця). "},{"question":"Raha nandeha an-tongotra teny an-tendrombohitra i Marka dia very lalana","answer":"Soa ihany fa nifankahita tamin’ny mpandeha an-tongotra iray hafa izy izay nanampy azy hahita ny lalana sy hody soa aman-tsara."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada akal\\"?","answer":"Cara menyelesaikan sesuatu masalah."},{"question":"Berilah contoh ayat untuk peribahasa \\"bagai bertepuk sebelah tangan\\" dan nyatakan maksudnya.","answer":"Contoh ayat: Hasrat Amir untuk berkahwin dengan Aminah tidak kesampaian apabila cintanya bagi bertepuk sebelah tangan. Ia bermaksud cinta kasih yang tidak berbalas."},{"question":"Кандай ыр-саптарды билесиң?","answer":"ӨЗҮМЫрдап жүрөм, бирок көп эл уга элек Китептерим атак алып тура элек, Кагаз таңгак, бардыгы тең кур турат, Сыя өңдүү калемиме жуга элек.Талант толку, толкун менен кеңешкин, Бир баш тартпай күчү менен ченешкин. Бекеринче бирок такыр мактанба, Жерде жүргөн жеңил кеме эмесмин.Жүрөгүм сен, аптыккандай урбасаң, Бул ишке эми чындап көңүл бурбасам. Ырым менен бүт ааламды эритип, Айга ыракат, жылдызга оюн курбасам.Автору А.Осмонов."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أطول سلسلة جبلية في العالم؟","answer":"الإجابة: جبال الأنديز، وطولها يبلغ 7,000 كيلومتر (4,350 ميل)"},{"question":"දුරේක්ෂ භාවිතා නොකර ගණිතමය අනාවැකි මඟින් සොයාගනු ලැබූ පළමු ග්‍රහලෝකය","answer":"දුරේක්ෂ භාවිතා නොකර ගණිතමය අනාවැකි මඟින් සොයාගනු ලැබූ පළමු ග්‍රහලෝකය නෙප්චූන් ය."},{"question":"Манас менен Алмамбеттин кездешүүсү кандай?","answer":" Манас менен Алмамбеттин кездешүүсү — эпостун эң күрдөөлдүү окуясы бурулушу. Алмамбет кыргыздар менен согушуп жаткан элдин кулуну, анан ошол душман элдин өкүлү, хандарынын бири, атактуу баатыры болуп туруп, кыргыздарга келиши, анын кыргыздар менен кошулуп, кыргыз болуп, кайра өз элине каршы согушка кириши — манасчылардын гениалдуу табылгасы. Ал өз элинен адилеттикти, чындыкты издеп таппай, Күн батыш көздөй жөнөдү, анын адамдык кредосу - \\"Кайыңды көрсөм конормун, кайышпай кайың көтөрсө, как ошо жерде болормун\\", \\"Башымды жөлөр паана жок, баркымды билер даана жок\\" деген сөздөрдө. Ошол издеп-көксөгөнүн Манастан тапты. Манас да Алмамбеттей сыр билги, баатыр жүрөк, акылман доско муктаж эле. Сагымбай Орозбаковдун варианты боюнча, Манас анын келе жатканын Үч-Кошойдун башына чыгып көрөт да, ага мындай баа берет: \\"Кызыл түктүү пил экен, кыраан эрдин бири экен, алыскы ишти ойлогон, акылмандын бири экен, айбатына жан түтпөс, баатырлардын бири экен, кең көкүрөк, сом далы, балбандардын бири экен, кездешкенин мант кылып, алгандардын бири экен, азуусу албарс, уу тырмак, айбаты менен ааламды, баскандардын бири экен\\". Ушул вариантта ал ушул кетип жатышта Мекеге бараткан болот. Манас аны тосуп алып, алдына Сараланы тартуу кылып, үстүнө тон жаап, Ысбахан менен Ындыстандан бери эл чакырып, чоң той берген соң сапарын ушул жерден токтотуп, бир өмүр Манастын эли-жеринде калат. "},{"question":"A partir da segunda metade do século XVIII, o número de escravos recém-chegados cresce no Rio e se estabiliza na Bahia. Nenhum lugar servia tão bem à recepção de escravos quanto o Rio de Janeiro.Na matéria, o jornalista informa uma mudança na dinâmica do tráfico atlântico que está relacionada à seguinte atividade:a) Coleta de drogas do sertão.b) Extração de metais preciosos.c) Adoção da pecuária extensiva.d) Retirada de madeira do litoral.e) Exploração da lavoura de tabaco.","answer":"A resposta correcta é a alternativa: b) Extração de metais preciosos."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన మొదటి పేరా మరియు చివరి పేరా అనుసరించు మధ్య పేరా రాయండి:మొదటి పేరా:ఓ అమ్మా! ఆడపిల్లలు అంటేనే లోకానికి చులకన భావం ఏర్పడింది. ఆడవారు లేకుండా ఈ లోకం ఎక్కడుంది అని సమాజాన్ని నిలబెట్టి స్పష్టంగా అడుగు చెల్లి అని నిసార్ సలహా ఇస్తున్నాడు. పిల్లలు పుట్టాలని పూజలు, వ్రతాలు చేస్తారు. కాని ఆడపిల్ల పుట్టిందని తెలియగానే వెక్కిరిస్తారు. ఆడపిల్ల పడుకుంటే లేపి అంట్లు శుభ్రం చేయిస్తారు. మగపిల్లలను బడికి పంపి చదివిస్తారు. ఆడపిల్లలను పనికి మగపిల్లలను చదువుకు పంపడం అనే భేద భావాలు ఎందుకుండాలి ? ఆడ మగ ఇద్దరూ పరస్పరం సహకరించుకుంటూ ఉండాలి అలా ఉండకుంటే జీవితం సఫలం కాదు అని నిసార్ భావన.చివరి పేరా:ఉదయం లేచింది మొదలు ఇల్లు ఊడ్చడం, వాకిలి ఊడ్చి కల్లాపి చల్లడం, వంటపాత్రలు కడిగి వంటచేయడం, అందరి బట్టలుతకడం, వడ్డించి తినేవరకు ఆగి నీ శరీరం మొత్తం అలిసి పోయేదాక పని చేసినా పని అయిపోదు. రోజులో ఉండే ఇరవైనాలుగు గంటలూ కష్టపడ్డా ఇంకా ఎదో ఒకపని ఉండనే ఉంటది. కాని కేవలం ఎనిమిది గంటలు బయట పనికి వెళ్లి వచ్చిన నీ భర్త మాత్రం నీ మీద ఎగిరి ఎగిరి పడతాడు తల్లి అని నిసార్ ఆవేదన వ్యక్తం చేశాడు. ఇంటికి కావలసిన పనులన్ని చేసి, పిల్లలను పోషించి, అత్త మామలను సరిగా పోషించి, భర్త మెప్పును పొంది కీ వెళ్లి పనిచేసి ఆకలితో ఇంటికి వచ్చి పొయ్యి వెలిగిస్తావు.","answer":"కొత్తగా పెండ్లి కాగానే అత్తగారి ఇంటికి వరకట్నం, కానుకలు తెచ్చే పంటలగా మారి వారి ఇల్లు నింపాలని అనుకుంటారు. నువ్వు కట్నంగా తెచ్చిన డబ్బుతో, బంగారంతో, వాహనంతో, వంట పాత్రలతో ఇల్లు నింపినా ఇంకా సరిపోలేదని అంటారు. ఓ చెల్లెమ్మా! నీవు తెచ్చిన కట్నంలో ఏ కొద్దిగా తగ్గినా నీ మొఖం పాడుగాను, నువ్వేం తెచ్చావని అంటారు. నిన్ను వాళ్ళే చంపేసి వంటింట్లో చచ్చిందని వార్తాపత్రికలకు ఇస్తారని నిసార్ హెచ్చరించాడు."},{"question":"கேள்வி : முசோலினியின் ரகசிய காவல் படையின் பெயர் என்ன? ","answer":"பதில் : ஓவ்ரா"},{"question":"Est-ce que tu peux me raconter une blague ?","answer":"D'accord, voici une blague :Question: Quel est le crustacé le plus léger de la mer ?Réponse: La palourde (pas lourde)."},{"question":"السؤال: بناء على آش كتحسب الفواتير ديال الضو؟","answer":"الإجابة: بناء على الطاقة المستهلكة "},{"question":"පහත පද පෙරළි වලට කෙලිනම් විසඳුම දෙන්න. ගැට පිස්ම","answer":"පිට ගැස්ම"},{"question":"بما كان يُلقب النبي محمد في قومه؟\\t","answer":"\\tالصادق الأمين"},{"question":"Apakah maksud angkat diri? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Maksudnya adalah sombong. Contoh ayat: “Jangan suka angkat diri, nanti orang lain tidak mahu berkawan dengan kamu”, kata Cikgu Ali kepada Shamsul."},{"question":" இசையை ஆதரிக்காத மொகலாய மன்னன் யார்? ","answer":"இசையை ஆதரிக்காத மொகலாய மன்னன்  ஒரௌங்கசீப்.ஔரங்கசீப் (1618-1707) முகலாய பேரரசின் ஒரு குறிப்பிடத்தகுந்த பேரரசர்களில் ஒருவர் ஆவார். ஷாஜகான் மற்றும் மும்தாஜ் தம்பதியர்களின் ஐந்தாவது வாரிசாவார். இவர் ஆலம்கீர் என அழைக்கப்பட்டார் ஆலம்கீர் எனில் (பாரசீக மொழியில் பிரபஞ்சத்தை ஆளப்பிறந்தவன் என பொருள்). இவரது ஆட்சி காலம் பொ.ஊ. 1658 இலிருந்து பொ.ஊ. 1707 வரையாகும். இவரது ஆட்சிகாலத்தில் முகலாயப் பேரரசு காபுலில் இருந்து தமிழ்நாடு வரை பரந்து விரிந்திருந்தது. இந்தியாவை ஒருங்கிணைத்து, திறம்பட ஆட்சி செய்த முதல் பேரரசர் ஆவார். முகலாய மன்னர்களில் அக்பரும் அவுரங்கசீப் ஆகிய இருவர் மட்டுமே 49 ஆண்டுகள் சாகும் வரை நாட்டை ஆண்டவர்கள்."},{"question":"Ìjọba ìpínlẹ̀ mélòó ni ó wà ní gúsù-ìwọ̀-oòrùn ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà?","answer":"Ìjọba ìpínlẹ̀ mẹ́fà ni."},{"question":"ፌቨን 5 እርሳሶች አላት፡፡ ስንት እርሳሶችን ብትጨምር በአጠቃላይ 7 እርሳሶች ይኖራታል?","answer":"ፌቨን 7-5=2 እርሳሶችን ብትጨምር በአጠቃላይ 7 እርሳሶች ይኖራታል።"},{"question":"Lee el siguiente texto y responde la pregunta :La crisis energética provocó un mayor interés en las energías renovables, la energía nuclear y los combustibles fósiles domésticos. Hay críticas de que las políticas energéticas estadounidenses desde la crisis han estado dominadas por el pensamiento de mentalidad de crisis, fomentando soluciones rápidas y costosas y soluciones únicas que ignoran las realidades del mercado y la tecnología. En lugar de proporcionar normas estables que respalden la investigación básica al tiempo que den un amplio margen a la iniciativa empresarial y la innovación, congresistas y presidentes han respaldado repetidamente políticas que prometen soluciones que son oportunas desde el punto de vista político, pero cuyas perspectivas son dudosas. ¿Quién apoyó las políticas que tienen soluciones que suenan bien pero que tienen malas perspectivas?","answer":"El concepto de políticas qué suenan bien pero tienen malas perspectivas es subjetivo y puede variar según las opiniones y creencias de las personas.En la política, diferentes grupos y partidos pueden promover políticas que consideran beneficiosas pero que otros pueden ver como conllevando problemas a largo plazo. "},{"question":"Waa immisa goballada Somaliland?","answer":"Gobalada Somaliland waa 6 gobal oo kala ah Awdal, Maroodi-jeex, Saaaxil, Tog-dheer, Sanaag iyo Sool."},{"question":"नेपालमा विद्यालय क्षेत्र विकास योजना (SSDP) का मुख्य विशेषताहरू के हुन्?","answer":": SSDP ले नेपालमा शिक्षाको समग्र गुणस्तर अभिवृद्धि गर्नमा जोड दिएर पूर्वाधार, शिक्षकको गुणस्तर र विद्यार्थी भर्नामा सुधार गर्छ।"},{"question":"Quelles sont les principales caractéristiques de la Renaissance artistique en Europe et comment elle a influencé l'art et la culture de l'époque ?","answer":"La Renaissance artistique en Europe, au XIVe et au XVe siècle, se caractérise par un intérêt renouvelé pour les arts, la science, la philosophie, et la culture classique de l'Antiquité. Elle a encouragé l'innovation artistique, la perspective linéaire, et l'individualisme, marquant ainsi un tournant majeur dans l'histoire de l'art."},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra ny andian-tantara fantasy \\"Game of Thrones\\"?","answer":"Ny \\"Game of Thrones\\" dia nosoratan'ny mpanoratra amerikana George R.R. Martin."},{"question":"ఒక వ్యక్తి ఆడుకుంటున్నప్పుడు గాయపడ్డాడు. అయితే రక్తం కారడం ఎంత సేపటికీ ఆగలేదు. దీనికి కారణాలు ఏమై ఉండవచ్చో, రాయండి.","answer":"రక్తస్కందనం జరగకపోవటానికిరక్త ఫలకిలకలు తక్కువగా ఉండవచ్చు.విటమిన్ K లోపించి ఉండవచ్చు.హీమోఫీలియా వ్యాధి కల్గి ఉండవచ్చు.రక్త స్కందన ప్రోటీన్స్ లోపించి ఉండవచ్చు."},{"question":"Direksiyon sertliği neden olur?","answer":"Ön lastiklerin havası basıncı azalmışsa, lastiğin biri inmişse veya patlamışsa direksiyon dönmez. Direksiyon bağlantı çubukları, levye kolları gibi parçalarda eğilme ve deformasyon varsa direksiyon sertleşebilir. Lastik rot ayarında sorun varsa direksiyon kilitlendi gibi bir tablo çıkar ortaya."},{"question":"Kodi ku Malawi kuli Shoprite angati?","answer":"Chiyambireni sitolo yathu yoyamba ku Lilongwe mchaka cha 2000, tatsegula masitolo 7 m’Malawi muno, akulemba ntchito anthu oposa 500 m’dziko lonselo."},{"question":"විකිපීඩියාවේ පියා කවුද?","answer":"විකිපීඩියාවේ සම-නිර්මාතෘවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු සිටී: ලැරී සැන්ගර්(Larry Sanger) (උපත 1968), ඇමරිකානු අන්තර්ජාල ව්‍යාපෘති සංවර්ධක. ජිමී වේල්ස්(Jimmy Wales) (උපත 1966), ඇමරිකානු-බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අන්තර්ජාල ව්‍යවසායකයා."},{"question":"'Wenelisekile yizimpendulo zami Zodwa?''Cha, angenelisekanga. Ngaphezu kwalokho, ngisenombuzo owodwawokugcina.''Buza, ngizokuphendula.''Ushadile?''Mina? Cha, cha, cha. Angishadile. Mina? Lutho.' Yimi lowo ngiphika.'Ngiyayibonga impendulo yakho mfowethu.''Ukubuziswa yini lokhu?''Ngikubuziswa wukuthi angifuni sichithelane isikhathi ngento engekho.Yingakho ngifuna isiqiniseko sokuthi uqotho, futhi uthembekile. Phelakukhona amadoda akhohlakele kabi, ashiya abafazi bawo, ahambe enzaukungcola lapha ngaphandle. Umntwana wabantu uhlezi nje laphaya ekhaya,akazi ukuthi iyakhohlakala indoda ngapha. Ihamba icosha wonke udoti lona.Kukhona nabantu besifazane abangcole kabi, abangenandaba noma ngabeumuntu ushadile noma cha. Bayawola nje. Wena ngikubona kahle ukuthiushadile kodwa usenesikhathi sokudlala ngomlilo. Bheka umunwe wakholowo,' washo esukuma, engishiya netafula, nezitsha ezingcolile. Lingcolile lelitafula engihleli kulona, bengingalinakile.Uthini uZodwa? Umunwe? Uyahlanya yini? Umunwe uhlangana ngaphi nalento ebesiyikhuluma? Ngayibukisisa yonke iminwe yami. Ngayibuka sengathiangiyazi kanti ngiyayazi, ngeyami. Awu, uyaqaphela lo muntu madoda! Phelakuyabonakala lapho kuhlala khona indandatho yami yomshado, khona laphaemnweni wami. Isikhumba sithanda ukukhanyakhanya kuleyo ndawo. Phelangivamise ukuyikhipha indandatho lena uma sengisithele emehlwenikaThandi.1. Yisiphi isizathu esasenza ukuthi umunwe walo muntu wesilisaukhanye kakhulu kuneminye?","answer":"Yingoba uhlale ufakwe indandatho yomshado. Yingoba wayekhiphe indandatho yomshado."},{"question":"ニューヨークのグッゲンハイム美術館本館や、東京の帝国ホテルの設計で知られるアメリカの建築家は誰でしょう？","answer":"フランク・ロイド・ライト"},{"question":"Ny Ainga, poeta malagasy malaza, dia ankalazaina noho ny tononkalo mahery vaika sy maneno. Miresaka matetika momba ny fitiavana, ny olana ara-tsosialy ary ny hakanton’ny tontolon’i Madagasikara ny andininy. Iza moa ny poeta malagasy fanta-daza malaza amin'ny tononkalo mihetsiketsika izay maneho matetika ny lohahevitra momba ny fitiavana sy ny olana ara-tsosialy?","answer":"Poeta malagasy malaza i Ny Ainga, malaza amin'ny tononkalo mihetsi-po izay matetika mikaroka lohahevitra momba ny fitiavana sy ny olana ara-tsosialy."},{"question":"Estuvo casado con Elisabeth Young (1854-1932) y era el padre del magnate marítimo N. O. Young Fearnley y del terrateniente Thomas Fearnley.¿La siguiente frase es una paráfrasis de la siguiente oración? Responde Sí o No a la pregunta.Se casó con Elisabeth Young (1854 - 1932) y fue el padre del magnate de navegación Thomas Fearnley y del terrateniente N. O. Young Fearnley.?","answer":"No."},{"question":"¿De qué murió Mac Miller?","answer":"Mac Miller murió de una sobredosis a sus 26 años de edad."},{"question":"Na mitologia nórdica quem é Njord?","answer":"Na mitologia nórdica, Njord (também escrito como Njörðr) é um dos deuses principais associados ao mar, à navegação e à prosperidade. "},{"question":"Hãy viết một bài báo có thể sử dụng tiêu đề sau đây: Tiêu đề: Đảng viên Việt Tân bị bắt vì ‘khủng bố’","answer":"Ông Quân bị cáo buộc kích động biểu tình trong dịp kỷ niệm ngày 30/4Theo đó, cơ quan an ninh - điều tra của công an ra quyết định khởi tố vụ án, khởi tố bị can đối với ông Quân để điều tra về tội danh này theo điều 84 của Bộ luật hình sự.Ông Quân, 59 tuổi, là Việt kiều Mỹ cư trú tại Garden Grove, bang California. Ông có bằng tiến sỹ về toán tại Đại học North Carolina.Ông bị bắt và khám xét khẩn cấp vào ngày 17/4 khi ông làm thủ tục nhập cảnh vào Việt Nam tại sân bay Tân Sơn Nhất dưới tên Richard Nguyễn.Theo Bộ Công an Việt Nam thì ông Quân nhập cảnh vào Việt Nam để thực hiện ý đồ ‘kích động biểu tình, khủng bố nhằm phá hoại lễ kỷ niệm 30/4’ tại thành phố Hồ Chí Minh và các tỉnh khác.Chính quyền Việt Nam cũng thông báo là đã tìm thấy nhiều tài liệu về ‘huấn luyện khủng bố’ trong hành lý của ông Quân.Theo điều 84 Bộ luật hình sự Việt Nam, mức án cao nhất dành cho tội danh ‘khủng bố chống lại chính quyền nhân dân’ lên đến tử hình. Tuy nhiên chính quyền cộng sản Việt Nam chưa từng hành quyết công dân nước ngoài nào về các tội danh chính trị.Tất cả báo chí trong nước đưa tin về ông Quân đều gọi ông là ‘khủng bố’ nhưng đồng thời cũng mô tả ông là người có đường lối ‘đấu tranh bất bạo động’."},{"question":"په افغانستان کې کومې ژبې ویل کیږي؟","answer":"افغانستان تر ۴۲ ډېرې ژوندۍ ژبې لري، چې ويونکې يې په بېلابېلو سيمو کې اوسېږي. خو د اکثريت له اړخه يې د رسمي ژبو پرته نورې ټولې ژبې لږکۍ او سيمه ييزې ژبې دي. پښتو او دري د افغانستان رسمي ژبې دي. د هېواد اکثريت وګړي په دري ژبې خبرې کوي او نور اقوام هم په دې ژبې ښه پوهېږي. خو پښتو ژبه هم د دري ترڅنګ اهمیت لري، چې د ۲۰ څخه تر ۳۰ سلنه وګړي پرې خبرې کوي.په افغانستان کې د پښتو او دري ترمنځ سيالي يو ترټولو مهمو موضوګانو څخه ده، په تېرو څو لسيزو کې د پښتو ژبې ويونکیو تل د هېواد سترې رسمي او ملي ژبې د تخريب هڅه کړې ده. چې تر ډېره د بهرنيانو لاسوهنې هم د پام وړ دي.پښتو د افغانستان په شرق، او جنوب کې د یو قوم یعنی پشتون ژبه ده، چې پکې د هېواد ښارونه؛ کندهار، ننګرهار، لوګر، لغمان، کونړ، پکتيا، پکتيکا، هلمند، غزني، ارزګان، زابل، زابل نور ولايتونه شامل دي.فارسي‌دري ژبه بیا په کابل ، پروان ، کاپیسا، بغلان ، تخار، کندز بدخشان، سرپل، بلخ، فاریاب، جوزجان، بادغیس، غور، هرات، فراه، نیمروز، بامیان، دایکندی، لوگر او پنجشير ولايتونو کې اکثريت وګړي جوړوي."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన వాక్యాన్ని వ్యతిరేకార్థక వాక్యంగా రాయండిఅంబటి రాయడు క్రికెట్ బాగా ఆడగలడు.","answer":"అంబటి రాయుడు క్రికెట్ బాగా ఆడలేడు."},{"question":"Kedu ndị bụ ụfọdụ ndị ama ama dere abụ ndị Igbo?","answer":"Ndị ama ama n'abụ ndị Igbo gụnyere Chinua Achebe, Christopher Okigbo, Gabriel Okara, na Ifeanyi Menkiti, na ndị ọzọ."},{"question":"السؤال: فيمن نزلت الآية “وَالْمُطَلَّقَاتُ يَتَرَبَّصْنَ بِأَنفُسِهِنَّ ثَلَاثَةَ قُرُوءٍ ۚ”؟","answer":"الإجابة: أسماء بنت زيد."},{"question":"Zuretzat, zein da gehiago irakurtzeko motibazioa?","answer":"Niretzat, gehiago irakurtzeko motibazioa da mundu berriak ezagutzea eta gai desberdinetan ezagutza areagotzea."},{"question":"Sooyaalka Qorista Farta somaliga.","answer":"Umad waliba waxay leedahay hido iyo dhaqan soo jireen ah, laakin waxa lagu kala hor maro waa xifdinta hidahaas, iyada oo qoran.Sida dastuurkan cusub ku qoran, dowladda  waa in ururisaa, ilaalisaa waxyaabaha taariikhiga ah ee dalka, iyadoo horumarinaysa aqoonta .Hadaba waa sidee Sooyaalka Qoraalka Farta Soomaaliga:1920-kii ayey ahayd markii la soo bilaabay hindisaha qorista rasmiga ah ee afka Soomaaliga, ilaa xilligaasna waxaa lagu taamayey in si rasmi ah loo qoro, Cusmaan Yusuf Keendiid oo ka mid ahaa dadkii xukumayey beelaha Soomaalida qaarkood, fadhigiisuna ahaa magaalada Hobyo ayaa waxa uu soo saaray far lagu magacaabi jirey Cusmaaniya sanadii  1922-kii, fartaasi meelo kooban ayay ka shaqaysay, mana ahayn mid dalka ku wada baahday.1950-1960-kii, waxaa socdey dood ah sidee loo qori lahaa af-Soomaaliga, waxaa jiray loona badan, rag badan ayaa dadaal sameeyay, waxaa lagu muran sanaa Ma Carabi mise  laatiin?Ragga dadaalka sameeyay waxaa ka mid ahaa Ibaahim Xaashi Maxamud iyo Xuseen Sheekh Axmed Kadare, dhamaan raggaasi waxaa ay soo saareen qoraalo farta ah intii u dhaxeysay sanadihii 1950-1961-dii.July 1,  1961-dii, markii dalka xuriyadda qaatay, Waxaa lasoo bandhigay dhowr qoraal waxaa ka mid ahaa farta Shire Jamaac Axmed oo Laatinahayd  iyo faro kale, tanina waxa ay ka dambeysey kadib markii dowladdii xiligaasi jirtey ee madaxweyne Aadan Cabdulle Cusmaan ay saartey guddi kasoo baaran dega qoraalka farta Soomaaliga.Gudiga ayaa waxaa xubno ka ahaa dadka kala ahMuuse Xaaji Ismaaciil Galaal, Guddoomiye,Yaasiin Cusmaan Yuusuf – xubinMaxamuud Saalex (Ladane)- XubinIbraahim Xaashi Maxamuud – xubinKhaliif Suudi- XubinMustaf Sheekh Xasan- xubinShire Jaamac Axmed- XubinXuseen Sheekh Axmed (Kaddare)- XubinYuusuf Maygaag Samatar- XoghaynGuddigaasi hawshooda waxa ay ka socon weysey isqabqabsi dhexdooda ah maadaamaa rag iyaga ka mid ah ay doonayeen in iyaga fartii ay soo jindiseen la qaato sida Muuse Xaaji Ismaaciil Galaal oo isaga soo saaray far ku qoran alifbeetaha Carabiga sanaddii 1951-diiWaxaa kaloo gudiga xubin ka ahaa Xuseen Sheekh Axmed Kadare oo far uu leeyahay soo saaray 1952-dii, waxay gudiga ku taliyeen in farta Laatiinka la qaato, taasi oo uu soo hindisey Shire Jaamac Axmed sanaddii 1961-dii .Si kartaba ha ahaatee, dowladda Soomaaliya ayaa  keensatay khubaro ka socdey UNESCO, si arintan wax uga qabtaan, taasina ma dhicin in laga miro dhaliyo oo weli waa sii socday is qabqabsi.Markii ay soo ifbaxday in Farta Laatin lagu qorayo Soomaliga Waxaa mudaharaadyo ka dhaceen Soomaaliya oo lagaga soo horjeedey in lagu qoro Laatiinka, waxaana dadka laga dhaadhiciyey in ay ka soo hor jeestaan in lagu qoro laatiinka, taas oo masaajidda laga iclaamiyey in shacabku ka soo hor jeestaan waayo, ayey yiraahdeen, “Laatiin waa Laa-diin” oo micnaheedu yahay “Farta Laatiinta waa Diin La’aan” iyada oo loo tiirinayay in farta Laatiinku tahay tan wadamada islaamka aan ahayd ay wax ku qortaan.October 21, 1969: Markii uu dalka la wareegay  Madaxweyne Maxamed Siyaad waxaa uu dib usoo nooleeyay fikradii qoraalka farta Soomaaliga.21 January 1971:  Waxaa la dhisay guddiga Af-Soomaaliga, gudigan waxaa dhisay golaha sare ee kacaanka si ay u sameeyaan xarfaha ugu haboon ee lagu qoraayo Soomaaliga.Guddigan waxaa uu ka koobnaa 21 oo ah xeeldheerayaal Afafka ah  iyo labo lataliye, Xubnaha Guddiga ayaa kala ahaaSharif Salah Mohamed Ali, GudoomiyeYaasin Cismaan KeenadiidMustaf Sheekh XasanAxmed Cali AbokarYuusuf Xirsi AxmedMsuse Xaaji Ismaaciil GalaalCabdidaahir Affey,Aw Jaamac Cumar CiiseDahabo Faarax XasanCabdulaahi Xaaji AbuubakarCabdullaahi ArdeeyeXasan Sheekh MuuminMaxamed Nuur CaalinMaxamed Xasan Aaden (Gaheyr)Xirsi Magan CiiseCumar Aw NuuxCabdullaahi Xaaji Maxamuud (Insaaniya)Iikar Bannaa XadaadAaqib CabdullaahiXuseen Sheekh Axmed KadareAxmed Cartan XaangeMaxamed Xaaji Xuseen Sheeko XariirCabdiraxmaan Nuur XirsiShire JaamacGuddigan waxaa uu lahaa guddi hoosaadyo sida mid qaabilsan qorista  Qaamuuska, kan Taariikhda ,  Juqiraafiga, Sayniska, diyaarinta kutubta dugsiyada iyo naxwaha.Guddiga Afka Soomaaliga ayaa farta Roman-ka ama Laatiinka in lagu qoro Afka Soomaaliga, sababtun waxay ahayd maadaamaa makiinadihii xafiisyada yiiley ee teebka ay ku qornaayeen fartaasi laatiinka,Muddo  22 Bilood gudahood ah ayaa waxaa lagu diyaariyey  Buugaagta Dugsiga dhexe, xarfaha higgaadda Af-Soomaaligu oo ka kooban 5 Shaqal  iyo 21 Shibbane.Si ka duwan sidii 1961-dii, Ma dhicin wax mudaaharaadyo ah ama cadaadis ku yimid guddigan si farihii tartamayey midkood loo sooco, sababtuna waxay ahayd xukunkii adkaa ee dowladdii Maxamed Siyaad Barre.Markii la sameeyey dhamaan waxyaabihii loogu diyaargaroobayay qorista Afka Soomaaliya, ayaa si rasmi ah loo shaaciyey qoraalka farta sanadii 1972-kii.Hawlaha la qabtay waxaa ka mid ah dajinta naxwaha Afka sida  Magac, fal, Fal-kaab, Magac u yaal, Sifo, laakiin sidaasi oo ay tahay wali naxwaha iyo ebyidda afka waa mid qabyo ah, una baahan hawl badan.Waxaa iyana la qorey qaamuus, hase yeeshee markii uu ku dhamaan waayay xiligii loogu talogalay ayaa wasiirkii hidaha iyo tacliinta sare  waxaa uu sii wadistiisa hawsha dhamaystirka qaamuuska u  xilsaaray Cabdiqaadir Farax Bootaan oo ahaa nin ka tirsan  Akaadeemiyada Fanka iyo Dhaqanka , hase yeeshee waxaa si weyn u caan baxay oo fidey Qaamuuskii uu qorey Yaasiin Cusmaan oo lasoo saaray sanadkii 1976-diiQaraar dowladda Soomaaliya kasoo baxay taariikhdu markii ay ahayd Jaanyi 21 1972-di in afka rasmiga ah ee Jamhuuriyadda Soomaaliya uu yahay Afka Soomaaliga ee “Maxaa Tiri”Markii fartii la dhamaystirey, lana diyaariyey dhamaan agabkii loo baahnaa haddii ay buugaag ahaan lahayd iyo haddii naxwe ahaan lahayd, ayaa waxaa loo baahday in dalka iyo dadka lagu baahiyo, waxaana sidaasi ku biloowdey ololihii Farta sanaddii 1972-dii , Ololahaas oo ay Dawladdii Siyaad Barre  markii dambe ku baahisay  dhammaan deegaamada dalka, dadka reer miyiga ah ama reer guuraagu aad ayey wax u barteen.Warbixino ay hay’ado diyaariyeen waxaa lagu sheegay in Ololahan uu kor u qaaday  aqoonta dadka min 2% ilaa 55%.Xiligii ay jirtay dowladdii kacaanka waxaa dugsiga lagu baran jiray farta Soomaaliya dhamaan maadooyinka manhajka ku jirey sida seyniska, xisaabta iyo wax kasta oo kale.Sanaddii 2012-kii waxaa dalka  Djabuti lagu qabtay xaflad lagu xusay 40-sanno guuraddii qoridda far Soomaaliga, Soomaaliya waxaa ay ku jirtaa marxaladii ugu xumeyd ee xaga midnimada, Qowmidda Soomaalida ayaa u midowday xuska maalintaas.Munaasabaddaas waxaa  lagu daah rogey qaamuuska ugu weyn ee af-Soomaali lagu qoro, kaas oo fikirkiisa uu lahaa madaxweynaha Jabuuti Ismaaciil Cumar Geelle, isla markaana ay wada-jir u diyaariyeen machadka Afafka ee Jabuuti iyo Naadiga Qalinlayda iyo Hal’abuurka Soomaaliyeed (Somali-Speaking PEN Club).January 21, 2015: Madaxweynaha Soomaaliya Xasan Sheekh Maxamuud ayaa  isaga oo ka hadlayay xuska 42 guurada kasoo wareegtey markii la qorey farta Soomaaliga  sheegey in laga bilaabo maalintaas ay mabnuuc tahay in far aan ahayn tan Soomaaliga lagu isticmaalo xafiisyada dowladda, haddii aanan markaasi xiriir lala samaynaynin cid dibadda ah.February 21, 2015: Madaxweynayaasha Soomaaliya iyo Djabuti Ismaciil Cumar Geelle ayaa Muqdisho ku dhagax dhigay xarun goboleed lagu hormarinayo luqadda iyo dhaqanka Somaliweyn, Waxaa loo loogu Magac daray Akaadimiyad Goboleedka Farta Soomalaiga, Xasan Sheekh ayaa maalintaas sheegay in arrintaas lagula tartami doono luqadaha caalamka.Amarka Madaxweynaha ee ahaa in xafiisyada dowladda ay ku shaqeeyaan qoraalka Soomaaliga waxba lagama soo qaadin oo wax walbo waa sidii hore xafiisyada dowladda, inta badan warsaxaafaeedka soo gaaro Goobjoog News waxaa u qoran af Ingiriis iyadoo taasi ay jirto ayaa todobaadkan, maalintii axaddii guddoomiyaha gobolka Banaadir waxaa uu soo saaray amar cusub oo sheegaya in boorarka xayeysiinta ee ku dheggan gobolka Banaadir loo bedelo Farta Soomaaliga, lama oga hadalkaas Yusuf Jimcaale uu dibad baxayaasha niyadda ugu dhisayey iyo si dhab ah loo hirgelin doono."},{"question":"Manomeza ohabolana momba ny vady.","answer":"\\"Ny saka sy ny alika miady ka miady hatramin'ny adala , mpivady miady koa ny zaza ao an-trano no darohana.\\""},{"question":"Lokaci Na Yanzu II shi ne mai manunin lokaciA) -naB) zaC) -keD) -kan","answer":"C.Saboda ana cikin aikin ba a kare ba."},{"question":"Berikan ayat contoh untuk peribahasa \\"abang ipar\\".","answer":"Anwar ialah abang ipar Abdullah."},{"question":"Apakah maksud ulat buku. Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang suka membaca buku. Contoh ayat: Hazirah dikenali sebagai ulat buku kerana sangat rajin membaca pada masa lapang. "},{"question":"நளனின் வரலாறு மகாபாரதத்தில் யார் கூறுவதாக வருகிறது?","answer":"வியாசர் தருமனுக்குக்குத் கூறிய கதை."},{"question":"Inona no adidin'ny velona amin' ny maty araka ny fomba Malagasy?","answer":"Manana adidy amin’ny maty ny velona , mikarakara azy ( manamboatra fasana ho azy, mampody azy any amin’ny fasan-drazany)."},{"question":"請用簡潔的語言回答以下問題：臨床心理學如何應用於文化和多樣性？","answer":"答案：臨床心理學通過關注文化差異、傾聽個體經歷和尊重多樣性，提供文化敏感的心理服務和支持。"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: \\"Đừng bỏ qua 3 dấu hiệu cảnh báo cholesterol xấu trong mắt của bạn\\"","answer":"Cholesterol cao có thể ảnh hưởng đến mắt như thế nào Cholesterol là một chất sáp được tìm thấy trong máu của một người, là chất cần thiết để xây dựng các tế bào khỏe mạnh. Tuy nhiên với cholesterol xấu có thể tăng nguy cơ mắc bệnh tim. Điều quan trọng cần lưu ý là chỉ có hàm lượng cholesterol cao mới làm tăng nguy cơ mắc bệnh tim mạch. Ngoài ra, cholesterol cao không chỉ ảnh hưởng đến tim mà còn có thể tác động tiêu cực đến mắt của bạn. Một trong những cách phổ biến nhất mà cholesterol có thể ảnh hưởng đến mắt là sự hiện diện của xanthelasma, những mảng mỡ nhỏ, màu vàng nhạt ở vùng da quanh mắt của bạn. Dấu hiệu này thường hình thành ở mí mắt. Điều gì xảy ra khi cholesterol xấu tích tụ trong mắt Có 3 dấu hiệu chính báo hiệu cholesterol xấu tích tụ trong mắt của bạn, bao gồm: - Các chất lắng đọng màu trắng, xám và vàng hình thành xung quanh giác mạc. - Mờ mắt. - Nổi mụn vàng quanh mắt. Khi bắt đầu có những dấu hiệu này, các chuyên gia khuyên bạn nên đi kiểm tra ngay lập tức, bởi nó dẫn đến các vấn đề về mắt nghiêm trọng hơn. Thoái hóa điểm vàng do tuổi tác Dịch vụ Y tế Quốc gia của Vương quốc Anh định nghĩa thoái hóa điểm vàng do tuổi tác (AMD) là một tình trạng phổ biến ảnh hưởng đến phần giữa thị lực của bạn. Cơ quan y tế cho biết, tình trạng này phổ biến ở những người trong độ tuổi 50 và 60. AMD không gây mù toàn bộ, nhưng có thể khiến các hoạt động như đọc và nhận dạng khuôn mặt trở nên khó khăn. Các chuyên gia tin rằng thiệt hại có thể do drusen - cặn nhỏ màu vàng của chất béo tích tụ trên võng mạc. Điều này do cholesterol xấu gây ra. Tắc tĩnh mạch võng mạc là gì? Một tình trạng ở mắt khác có thể phát sinh do cholesterol xấu tích tụ trong võng mạc là tắc tĩnh mạch võng mạc. Võng mạc là một lớp mô mỏng nằm ở đáy mắt của bạn. Nó là thứ biến ánh sáng thành tín hiệu đến não, chuyển đổi chúng thành thị giác. Điều đó nói lên rằng, khi tĩnh mạch trên võng mạc bị tắc nghẽn, hình thành cục máu đông sẽ dẫn đến tắc tĩnh mạch võng mạc, dẫn đến mù một phần và tạm thời. Tuy nhiên, một số người có thể bị mù vĩnh viễn. Viêm giác mạc là một tình trạng mắt khác cần chú ý Giác mạc là bề mặt mỏng, trong của mắt bao phủ mống mắt, đồng tử và tiền phòng. Viêm giác mạc, còn được gọi là arcus senilis ở người lớn tuổi hoặc arcus thanh thiếu niên ở những người dưới 40 tuổi. Tình trạng này xảy ra khi cholesterol hình thành xung quanh vành giác mạc. Đó là sự lắng đọng của lipid ở giác mạc ngoại vi. Không chỉ cholesterol cao, những lipid này còn bao gồm phospholipid và triglycerid. Hãy cẩn thận với cholesterol cao khi có các dấu hiệu đau ở chân và tay Hầu hết các trường hợp cholesterol cao đều không có triệu chứng và chỉ được phát hiện khi một người đi khám sức khỏe định kỳ. Cholesterol cao có thể dẫn đến các bệnh khác nhau trong cơ thể, điều này có thể cho thấy sự hiện diện của bệnh. Khi cholesterol cao có thể gây hại cho động mạch của bạn bằng cách thúc đẩy sự tích tụ mảng bám trong động mạch, làm tăng nguy cơ mắc bệnh động mạch ngoại vi (PAD). Quá trình này còn được gọi là xơ vữa động mạch, ảnh hưởng đến các động mạch ở chân và tay của bạn. Một triệu chứng chính của PAD là rung chân không liên tục, gây ra chuột rút ở chân bắt đầu khi bạn di chuyển xung quanh nhưng dừng lại khi bạn nghỉ ngơi. Điều này cho thấy lưu lượng máu giảm do mảng bám ngày càng tăng trong động mạch của bạn.  PAD phổ biến hơn ở chân nhưng cũng có thể xảy ra ở cánh tay. Những gì bạn nên làm Cholesterol xấu có thể được ngăn ngừa bằng một chế độ ăn uống lành mạnh, hydrat hóa tốt và tập thể dục. Do đó, một chế độ ăn uống tốt với nhiều trái cây và rau quả sẽ cung cấp cho chất chống oxy hóa, lutein, zeaxanthin, vitamin C và E, làm giảm chất béo trong máu, áp lực trong tĩnh mạch và khả năng hình thành cục máu đông. Hơn nữa, các chuyên gia khuyên bạn nên tránh các loại thịt đỏ, uống ít nhất 1,5 lít nước mỗi ngày và có thói quen tập thể dục. Ngoài ra, để giảm lượng cholesterol, hãy cố gắng cắt giảm thức ăn béo, đặc biệt là thức ăn có chứa một loại chất béo được gọi là chất béo bão hòa. Bởi chất béo làm tăng cholesterol xấu."},{"question":"Sino ang tinaguriang \\"Ama ng Katipunan\\" sa kasaysayan ng Pilipinas?","answer":"Si Andrés Bonifacio y de Castro ang kinikilala bilang \\"Ama ng Katipunan\\". Isa siya sa mga naging Supremo o pinuno ng sikretong samahan na Katipunan, o Kataas-taasan, Kagalang-galangang Katipunan ng mga Anak ng Bayan at nanguna sa rebolusyon ng mga Pilipino laban sa mga mananakop na Kastila. Itinuturing na bayani ng Pilipinas si Bonifacio dahil sa kanyang dedikasyon sa rebolusyon at pagkamit ng kalayaan para sa bansa."},{"question":"වසර 2013 නම්, Samsung E1200 නිෂ්පාදනය කරන්නේද?","answer":"ඔව්, දුරකථනය 2012 දී නිකුත් කරන ලද අතර 2015 වන තෙක් එය අත්හිටුවා නැත. Samsung E1200 (Samsung Pusha සහ Samsung Keystone 2 ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ) යනු සැම්සුන් විසින් සාදන ලද ජංගම දුරකථනයකි. මෙම දුරකථනය 2012 දී එක්සත් රාජධානියේ ටෙස්කෝ හරහා නිකුත් කරන ලදී. 2015 දී Samsung Guru FM E1202 එහි අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා ලෙස නිකුත් කරන විට එය නතර විය."},{"question":"Mọgaji di alaga ere idaraya ni Kwara","answer":"Ọjọ Aje, Monde, ọṣẹ yii, ni Gomina ipinlẹ Kwara, AbdulRahman AbdulRazaq,  kede Ọgbẹni Bọla Mọgaji, gẹgẹ bii alaga tuntun lẹka ere idaraya nipinlẹ Kwara, to si ni iriri rẹ yoo mu idagbasoke ba ẹka naa.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Akọwe iroyin gomina, Ọgbẹni Rafiu Ajakaye, fi sita lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọṣẹ yii, lo ti kede iyansipo rẹ ati awọn miiran.Mọgaji kẹkọọ jade nile-ẹkọ giga Fasiti ilu Ibadan, o si ti ṣiṣẹ lawọn ileeṣẹ ere idaraya lẹka oriṣiiriṣii jake-jado orile-ede yii. Bakan naa lo ti figba kan jẹ ọkan lara igbimọ ere idaraya nipinlẹ Kwara laarin ọdun 1977 si 1995, gẹgẹ bii akọni mọ-ọn-gba.Gomina tun yan Ọmọwe Ọlarinoye Steve Abiọdun lati ijọba ibilẹ Ifẹlodun, nipinlẹ Kwara, gẹgẹ bii adari agba lẹka ere idaraya nipinlẹ naa. Ọkunrin yii kẹkọọ jade nile-ẹkọ giga Fasiti Ahmadu Bello, nipinlẹ Kaduna.Awọn miiran to tun yan sipo ni : Dele Abubakar; Abdullahi Lade; Lanre Elijah; Makanjuola Monisọla Yẹmisi; Roseline Raphael; Balikis Abọlọrẹ ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ."},{"question":"ලොව වැඩිම උෂ්ණත්වයක් ඇති රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඇමරිකාවේ කැලිෆෝනියාවේ ඩෙත් නිම්නයේ ෆර්නේස් ක්‍රීක් රංචු ප්‍රදේශයේ පෘථිවියේ වාර්තා වූ ඉහළම උෂ්ණත්වය නිරීක්ෂණය විය. 1913 ජූලි 10 වන දින උෂ්ණත්වය 134 ° F (56.7 ° C) දක්වා ළඟා විය. මෙම වාර්තාවේ නිරවද්‍යතාවය පිළිබඳ වාද විවාද පැවති අතර, විවිධ කාලගුණ විද්‍යා සංවිධාන විසින් එය නිල වශයෙන් පිළිගෙන ඇත. කුවේට් සහ ඉරානය වැනි අනෙකුත් රටවල් ද ඩෙත් නිම්නයේ පිහිටුවා ඇති වාර්තාවට ආසන්නව අතිශයින් ඉහළ උෂ්ණත්වයක් වාර්තා කර ඇත."},{"question":"O que é latitude e longitude?","answer":"Latitude e longitude são coordenadas geográficas que permitem especificar a localização de um ponto na superfície da Terra. A latitude mede a distância de um ponto em relação ao equador, enquanto a longitude mede a distância de um ponto em relação ao meridiano de Greenwich, que é usado como referência para marcar o leste e o oeste."},{"question":"महात्मा गांधी ने सविनय अवज्ञा आंदोलन की घोषणा कैसे की?","answer":" 6 अप्रैल को महात्मा गांधी अपने 78 अनुयायियों और कई अन्य लोगों के साथ दांडी तट पर पहुंचे और औपचारिक रूप से समुद्र के पानी को उबालकर नमक का निर्माण करते हुए कानून का उल्लंघन किया।  इसने सविनय अवज्ञा आंदोलन की शुरुआत को चिह्नित किया। "},{"question":"Diniho raha toa ity fanambarana manaraka ity ka maneho fifaliana, alahelo, fahatezerana, na tahotra.Fanambarana: \\"Vao avy nandalo ny fanadinako aho! 😊\\"","answer":"Valiny: Ny fanambarana teo aloha dia maneho fifaliana. Faly ianao fa nahavita ny fanadinanao!"},{"question":"Como é a conjugação do verbo caber na 1ª pessoa do singular do presente do indicativo?a) Eu caibob) Ele cabec) Que eu caibad) Eu caboe) Nenhuma das alternativas","answer":"Alternativa a: Eu caibo.Caber é um verbo irregular da 2ª conjugação. Apesar de estranho, “eu caibo” é a forma correta de conjugá-lo na 1ª pessoa do presente do indicativo."},{"question":"Oviana ny olombelona no heverina fa namboly vary voalohany?","answer":"Tombanana ho eo amin' ny 6 500 hatramin' ny 8 500 taona eo ho eo izay no efa nanaovan' ny zanak' olombelona ny fambolem-bary. Ny tany Azia no efa namboly vary hatramin' ny 8 500 taona, raha hatramin' ny 3 500 taona kosa no namboly vary ny tany Afrika. "},{"question":"Adelé (Regent)","answer":"Adelé (Regent), ní ilẹ̀ Káàárọ́-oò-jíire (Yorùbá) ni ẹni tí a Yàn láti darí ìlú tí Ọba wọ́n bá wàjà tàbí kúrò l'órí oyè tí àṣà wọn kòsì fàyè gbà-á pé kí orí ìtẹ́ Ọba náà ṣòfo. Adelé a máa dárí ìlú tí Ọba wọn bá ń ṣàárẹ̀ tàbí tí kò lè dáńtọ́ ọ́o láàárín ìlú. Adelé kìí pẹ́ l'órí oyè bí Ọba. Ó máa ń ní ìwọ̀nba ìgbà tí Adelé máa fi ń wà l'órí ìtẹ́."},{"question":"Ngoài lĩnh vực thơ ca, Tagore được đánh giá là nhân vật xuất sắc trong vai trò gì?","answer":"Tagore được đánh giá là nhân vật xuất sắc trong vai trò nhạc sĩ, triết gia.Tagore được cả thế giới tôn vinh là một trong số ít nhân tài toàn diện của thế giới với nhiều vai trò như nhà viết kịch, nhà thơ, nhạc sĩ, tiểu thuyết gia, nhà giáo dục, triết gia và nhà nhân văn học.Ngoài hàng nghìn bài thơ, Tagore để lại 12 bộ tiểu thuyết dài và vừa, nhiều luận văn, hàng trăm truyện ngắn, ký, kịch, hơn 2.000 tranh vẽ và hơn 2.000 bài hát. Ngày nay, di sản bài hát của ông được gọi là Rabindra Sangeet và được xem là kho tàng văn hóa Bengal, ở cả Tây Bengal thuộc Ấn Độ lẫn Bangladesh.Các bài hát của ông được chọn làm quốc ca của cả Ấn Độ và Bangladesh. Jana Gana Mana - quốc ca của Ấn Độ - là năm đoạn đầu của một bài thơ của Tagore viết bằng tiếng Bengal. Trong khi đó, Amar Sonar Bangla là quốc ca của Bangladesh với phần lời được Tagore viết năm 1905."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan keperihalan tentang lawatan ke kampung datuk. ","answer":"Pada cuti sekolah yang lalu, bapa membawa kami sekeluarga pergi ke kampung datuk yang terletak di Kluang. Kami bertolak ke sana pada pukul 8.00 pagi dengan menaiki kereta bapa yang baharu.           Dalam perjalanan, kami berbual-bual dengan mesranya sambil menikmati pemandangan yang indah nian. Kami tiba di destinasi pada pukul 9.30 pagi. Kami melihat datuk dan nenek menunggu ketibaan kami sekeluarga dengan perasaan yang gembira. Kami pun terus bersalam dengan datuk dan nenek.          Selepas itu, kami memberikan buah tangan kepada datuk dan nenek. Kemudian, kami bersembang dengan datuk dan nenek di ruang tamu untuk mengeratkan hubungan antara satu sama lain. Bapa pula membaca surat khabar untuk mengetahui berita-berita terkini di dalam dan di luar negara.          Pada pukul 1.00 tengah hari, kami sekeluarga menikmati makanan tengah hari bersama datuk dan nenek. Kami makan dengan berseleranya kerana masakan nenek sungguh lazat. Selepas makan, ibu dan kakak membantu nenek mencuci pinggan mangkuk. Mereka juga membantu nenek mengemaskan dapur sehingga bersih dan kemas.          Pada waktu petang, datuk membawa kami sekeluarga pergi ke dusun buah-buahannya. Dusun datuk terletak berhampiran dengan rumahnya. Terdapat pelbagai jenis pokok buah di dusun datuk seperti durian, mangga, manggis, pisang dan sebagainya. Kami menikmati buah-buahan yang segar dan enak di dusun datuk. Datuk juga membawa saya dan adik pergi memancing ikan di sungai berdekatan dusunnya. Kami memancing ikan dengan sabarnya dan mendapat banyak ikan yang besar.         Pada pukul 6.00 petang, kami pun pulang ke rumah. Saya berasa gembira kerana dapat melawat ke kampung datuk. Saya berharap agar berpeluang ke sana lagi pada masa akan datang."},{"question":"Дати відповідь на наступне питання. Хто співає пісню \\"Тільки любов може розбити твоє серце\\"?","answer":"Ніл Янг"},{"question":"Apakah resipi gulai daging nangka cara kampung?","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 300 gram bawang merah, 5 ulas bawang putih, 50 gram halia, 2 batang serai (dititik), 2 sudu makan kerisik, 2 keping asam keping, 8 biji buah keras (dikisar), 150 gram santan, 200 gram nangka muda, 2 keping daun limau purut, 100 gram cili kering (dikisar), 5 sudu makan rempah kari daging, 1 kilogram dagingLangkah penyediaan1. Tumis bawang merah, bawang putih dan halia bersama serai.2. Masukkan rempah kari daging bersama cili kisar.3. Masak sehingga naik minyak.4. Masukkan asam keping.5. Masukkan daging dan biarkan sehingga lembut.6. Masukkan kerisik dan buah keras yang telah dikisar.7. Seterusnya masukkan santan bersama daun limau purut dan asam keping.8. Masak sehingga daging lembut menggunakan api kecil jika ingin kuah yang lebih pekat.9. Jika suka kuah yang cair, boleh tambahkan air.10. Siap dihidangkan."},{"question":"Nước đóng băng khi nhiệt độ từ 0 oC trở xuống. Trong các phát biểu sau, phát biểu nào đúng, phát biểu nào sai? Vì sao?a) Ở nhiệt độ – 3 °C thì nước đóng băng.b) Ở nhiệt độ 2 °C thì nước đóng băng.","answer":"Nước đóng băng khi nhiệt độ từ 0 oC trở xuống hay nước đóng băng ở nhiệt độ bé hơn (nhỏ hơn) 0 oC.a) Vì – 3 °C < 0 °C (số nguyên âm nhỏ luôn nhỏ hơn 0) Do đó ở nhiệt độ – 3 °C thì nước đóng băng là phát biểu đúng. b) Vì 2 °C > 0 °C (số nguyên dương luôn lớn hơn 0)Do đó ở nhiệt độ 2 °C thì nước chưa thể đóng băng hay phát biểu \\"ở nhiệt độ 2 °C thì nước đóng băng\\" là phát biểu sai. "},{"question":"乔布斯是如何创立苹果公司的？","answer":"答：1976年，乔布斯与斯蒂夫·沃兹尼亚克和罗纳德·韦恩共同创立了苹果公司，推出了苹果 I 电脑。这是个人电脑革命的开始。"},{"question":"Sheeg xilligii uu madaxweynaha ahaa Aadan Cabdulle Cismaan?","answer":"Waxa uu ahaa intii u dhaxeysay 01/07/1960 – 10/07/1967."},{"question":"\\"ڪلائوڊ ڪمپيوٽنگ\\" جو تصور ڇا آهي؟","answer":"ڪلائوڊ ڪمپيوٽنگ جو مطلب آهي ڪمپيوٽنگ سروسز جي ترسيل، بشمول اسٽوريج، پروسيسنگ، ۽ نيٽ ورڪنگ، انٽرنيٽ تي. فزيڪل ڊيٽا سينٽرن ۽ سرورز جي مالڪ ۽ برقرار رکڻ بدران، صارفين ڪلائوڊ فراهم ڪندڙن کان مطالبن تي انهن خدمتن تائين رسائي ڪري سگهن ٿا. فائدن ۾ قيمت جي بچت، اسڪاليبلٽي، ۽ لچڪ شامل آهن. ڪلائوڊ ماڊلز ۾ انفراسٽرڪچر بطور سروس (IaaS)، پليٽ فارم بطور سروس (PaaS)، ۽ سافٽ ويئر بطور سروس (SaaS)، مختلف ضرورتن ۽ ايپليڪيشنن کي پورو ڪرڻ شامل آھن."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaan qaalataa imsaa quraanka ku jirta, iyadoo uu alifka kutaagan yahay?","answer":"2 jeer, (Qaalataa ataynaa dhaa’iciina). (Surat: al-Fussilat).(Qaalataa laa nasqii xattaa yasdura-Rucaa’u). (Surat: al-Qasas).    "},{"question":"Em condições normais, um período de 3 anos pode incluir no máximo quantas Copas do Mundo?","answer":"Em condições normais, um período de 3 anos pode incluir no máximo uma Copa do Mundo. Isso ocorre porque a Copa do Mundo da FIFA é realizada a cada 4 anos. "},{"question":"Магниттик оптика","answer":"Магниттик оптика - бул магнит талаасынын таасири менен заттардын оптикалык касиеттеринин өзгөрүшүн үйрөтүүчү физиканын бөлүмү.Магниттик оптиканын кубулуштарынын басымдуу көпчүлүгү атомдун энергиялык деңгээлдеринин ажыроосу менен байланышкан. "},{"question":"Solve the equation: 3/5x + 1 = 16.","answer":"To solve for 'x', subtract 1 from both sides of the equation: (3/5x) = 16 - 1, which simplifies to (3/5x) = 15. Now, multiply both sides by 5/3: x = 15 * (5/3), which equals 25."},{"question":"ബ്രസീലിന്റെ തലസ്ഥാനം ഏതാണ്?","answer":"1960-ൽ നിർമ്മിച്ചതിനുശേഷം ബ്രസീലിന്റെ ഇപ്പോഴത്തെ തലസ്ഥാനം ബ്രസീലിയയാണ്. 1763 നും 1960 നും ഇടയിൽ റിയോ ഡി ജനീറോ ആയിരുന്നു രാജ്യത്തിന്റെ തലസ്ഥാനം."},{"question":"Apakah laut yang memisahkan antara Semenanjung Malaysia dengan Sabah dan Sarawak?","answer":"Laut China Selatan  memisahkan antara Semenanjung Malaysia dengan Sabah dan Sarawak"},{"question":"Hãy tìm một số chi tiết trong truyện Cô bé bán diêm để chứng tỏ truyện Cô bé bán diêm có đặc điểm của truyện cổ tích (Gợi ý: kiểu nhân vật; cách kết thúc truyện; ý nghĩa;...).","answer":"Một số chi tiết trong văn bản để chứng tỏ truyện Cô bé bán diêm có đặc điểm của truyện cổ tích- Kiểu nhân vật mồ côi, nghèo khổ, khó khăn.- Cách kết thúc truyện tuy là cô bé chết thế nhưng là có “hậu” đối với cô bé. Bởi vì chỉ có cái chết thì mới có thể giải thoát em ra khỏi cảnh ngộ hiện tại.- Ý nghĩa câu chuyện hướng đến lòng nhân ái giữa con người với con người, đồng cảm với những số phận bất hạnh."},{"question":"కింది కర్తరి వాక్యాలను కర్మణి వాక్యాలుగా రాయండి.మహాభారతమును వ్యాసుడు రచించెను. ","answer":"వ్యాసునిచే మహాభారతము రచింపబడింది."},{"question":"வினா: ஹோமோ சேபியன்ஸைத் தவிர, ‘ஹோமோ’ இனத்தின் கீழ் உள்ள மற்ற இரண்டு இனங்கள் யாவை?","answer":"விடை: ஹோமோ ஹாபிலிஸ் மற்றும் ஹோமோ எரெக்டஸ்"},{"question":"प्रश्न : दिइएका अनेकार्थक शब्दलाई फरक फरक अर्थ दिने गरीवाक्यमा प्रयोग गर्नुहोस्‌ :उत्तर, खरी","answer":"उत्तर  :उत्तरउनले मेरा सबै प्रश्नहरुको उत्तर दिइन्‌ ।उत्तर बाट हावा चलिरहेको छ ।खरीम खरीको बोटका चढे ।कालो पाटीमा खरीले राम्ररी लेख ।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਜੇ ਵੇਲਾ ਵਖਤੁ ਵੀਚਾਰੀਐ ਤਾ ਕਿਤੁ ਵੇਲਾ ਭਗਤਿ ਹੋਇ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਨਾਮੇ ਰਤਿਆ ਸਚੇ ਸਚੀ ਸੋਇ ॥ਇਕੁ ਤਿਲੁ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਵਿਸਰੈ ਭਗਤਿ ਕਿਨੇਹੀ ਹੋਇ ॥ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਸੀਤਲੁ ਸਾਚ ਸਿਉ ਸਾਸੁ ਨ ਬਿਰਥਾ ਕੋਇ ॥੧॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇ ॥ਸਾਚੀ ਭਗਤਿ ਤਾ ਥੀਐ ਜਾ ਹਰਿ ਵਸੈ ਮਨਿ ਆਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸਹਜੇ ਖੇਤੀ ਰਾਹੀਐ ਸਚੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਬੀਜੁ ਪਾਇ ॥ਖੇਤੀ ਜੰਮੀ ਅਗਲੀ ਮਨੂਆ ਰਜਾ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਭਾਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਕਾ ਸਬਦੁ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਹੈ ਜਿਤੁ ਪੀਤੈ ਤਿਖ ਜਾਇ ॥ਇਹੁ ਮਨੁ ਸਾਚਾ ਸਚਿ ਰਤਾ ਸਚੇ ਰਹਿਆ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੨॥ਆਖਣੁ ਵੇਖਣੁ ਬੋਲਣਾ ਸਬਦੇ ਰਹਿਆ ਸਮਾਇ ॥ਬਾਣੀ ਵਜੀ ਚਹੁ ਜੁਗੀ ਸਚੋ ਸਚੁ ਸੁਣਾਇ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਮੇਰਾ ਰਹਿ ਗਇਆ ਸਚੈ ਲਇਆ ਮਿਲਾਇ ॥ਤਿਨ ਕਉ ਮਹਲੁ ਹਦੂਰਿ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਸਚਿ ਰਹੇ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਇ ॥੩॥ਨਦਰੀ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਈਐ ਵਿਣੁ ਕਰਮਾ ਪਾਇਆ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ਪੂਰੈ ਭਾਗਿ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਲਹੈ ਸਤਗੁਰੁ ਭੇਟੈ ਜਿਸੁ ਆਇ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਨਾਮੇ ਰਤਿਆ ਦੁਖੁ ਬਿਖਿਆ ਵਿਚਹੁ ਜਾਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸਬਦਿ ਮਿਲਾਵੜਾ ਨਾਮੇ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੪॥੨੨॥੫੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 35 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੇ (ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਕੋਈ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਵੇਲਾ ਕੋਈ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਵਕਤ ਨਿਯਤ ਕਰਨਾ ਵਿਚਾਰਦੇ ਰਹੀਏ, ਤਾਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੇਲੇ ਭੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਹੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਰਿਹਾਂ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਰੂਪ ਹੋ ਜਾਈਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਸੋਭਾ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈਉਹ ਕਾਹਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਹੋਈ ਜੇ ਇਕ ਖਿਨ ਭਰ ਭੀ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿੱਸਰ ਜਾਏ ?ਜੇ ਇਕ ਸਾਹ ਭੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਯਾਦ ਤੋਂ ਖ਼ਾਲੀ ਨਾਹ ਜਾਏ ਤਾਂ ਸਦਾ‑ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਿਆਂ ਮਨ ਸ਼ਾਂਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਸਰੀਰ (ਭੀ) ਸ਼ਾਂਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਭਗਤੀ ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂ (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਵੱਸੇ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਜੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਦਾ‑ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ‑ਬੀ ਬੀਜ ਕੇ (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੀ) ਫ਼ਸਲ ਬੀਜੀਏਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਸਲ ਬਹੁਤ ਉੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਫ਼ਸਲ ਬੀਜਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ (ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰੱਜ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ (ਐਸਾ) ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਹੈ (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਜਲ ਹੈ) ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਪੀਤਿਆਂ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ) ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈਹੈ (ਨਾਮ-ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਪੀਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ) ਇਹ ਮਨ ਅਡੋਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਸਦਾ‑ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਦੀ ਯਾਦ) ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਖਣਾ ਵੇਖਣਾ ਬੋਲਣਾ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਵਾਲੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਜੇਹੜੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਸਦਾ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਮਗਨ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ) ਤੇ ਹਰ ਪਾਸੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ (ਵੇਖਦੇ ਹਨ)ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ (ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਸੁਣਾ ਸੁਣਾ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੋਭਾ (ਸਾਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ) ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਕਾਇਮ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੰੂ ਆਪਣੀ ਯਾਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਹਉਮੈ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਅਪਣੱਤ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜੇਹੜੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਈ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਥਾਂ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ।੩।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉਹ ਮਿਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੰੂ ਵੱਡੀ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਆ ਕੇ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਇਸ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ (-ਰੰਗ) ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਮਾਇਆ (ਦੇ ਮੋਹ) ਦਾ ਦੁੱਖ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ) ਮਿਲਾਪ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੨੨।੫੫।\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"belah hati\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud tidak tetap pendirian dalam mengambil sesuatu keputusan. Contoh ayat: Usahlah berbelah hati untuk meninggalkan keluarga demi mencari masa depan yang lebih baik."},{"question":"Iza ilay mpikaroka italiana nahita an'i Amerika ho an'i Espaina tamin'ny 1492?","answer":" Ny mpikaroka italiana nahita an'i Amerika ho an'i Espaina tamin'ny 1492 dia i Christopher Columbus."},{"question":"මධ්‍යම ආසියානු රටවල් නම් කරන්න.","answer":"මධ්‍යම ආසියාතික රටවල්, බොහෝ විට \\"ස්ටැන්ස්\\" ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලබන අතර, ඒවාට ඇතුළත් වන්නේ:1. කසකස්තානය2. කිර්ගිස්තානය3. ටජිකිස්තානය4. ටර්ක්මෙනිස්තානය5. උස්බෙකිස්තානය6. ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයමෙම ජාතීන්(ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය හැර ) 1991 දී සෝවියට් සංගමය විසුරුවා හරින තෙක් එහි කොටසක් විය. ඔවුන් ඓතිහාසික, සංස්කෘතික සහ භාෂාමය බැඳීම් බෙදා ගන්නා අතර ඔවුන්ගේ විශාල භූ දර්ශන, පොහොසත් සංචාරක සම්ප්‍රදායන් සහ ආසියාවේ සහ යුරෝපයේ බලපෑමේ සම්මිශ්‍රණයක් සඳහා  ප්‍රසිද්ධය.සමහර මූලාශ්‍රවල කසක්ස්ථානයේ ඇතැම් ප්‍රදේශ යුරෝපානු කලාපයට අයත් ලෙස දක්වා ඇත. එමෙන් ම, ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය බොහො අවස්ථාවල දකුණු ආසියාතික රාජ්‍යයක් ලෙස සලකනු පෙනේ."},{"question":"ਜੰਮੁੂ: ਜੰਮੂ ਕਸ਼ਮੀਰ ਦੇ ਰਾਮਬਨ ਜ਼ਿਲੇ ਵਿਚ ਭਾਰੀ ਮੀਂਹ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਢਿੱਗਾਂ ਡਿੱਗਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਜੰਮੂ-ਸ੍ਰੀਨਗਰ ਕੌਮੀ ਮਾਰਗ ਅੱਜ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਤੀਜੇ ਦਿਨ ਵੀ ਬੰਦ ਰਿਹਾ ਅਤੇ 1700 ਦੇ ਕਰੀਬ ਵਾਹਨ ਫਸੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ। 270 ਕਿਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਲੰਮੇ ਇਸ ਕੌਮੀ ਮਾਰਗ ’ਤੇ ਖੂਨੀ ਨਾਲਾ, ਪੰਥਿਆਲ, ਡਿਗਡੋਲ, ਬੈਟਰੀ ਚਸ਼ਮਾ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਰੂਗ ਪੰਜ ਥਾਵਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਢਿੱਗਾਂ ਡਿਗਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਆਵਾਜਾਈ ਬੁੱਧਵਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਬੰਦ ਹੈ। ਰਾਮਬਨ, ਉੂਧਮਪੁਰ, ਜੰਮੂ, ਸਾਂਬਾ ਅਤੇ ਕਠੂਆ ਵਿਚ ਵਾਹਨ ਫਸੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ। ਬਟੋਟਾ-ਡੋਡਾ-ਕਿਸ਼ਤਵਾੜ ਮਾਰਗ ਦੋ ਥਾਵਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਬੰਦ ਪਈ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਮਲਬਾ ਸਾਫ਼ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਚੱਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਜੰਮੂ-ਸ਼੍ਰੀਨਗਰ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਰਾਜਮਾਰਗ 'ਤੇ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਵਾਹਨ ਫਸੇ ਹਨ? ","answer":"ਜੰਮੂ-ਸ਼੍ਰੀਨਗਰ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਰਾਜਮਾਰਗ 'ਤੇ 1700 ਦੇ ਕਰੀਬ ਵਾਹਨ ਫਸੇ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"Complete a frase a seguir utilizando palavras curtas:Ontem a noite eu estava andando pela cozinha de madrugada quando então","answer":"vi uma luz sem cor no teto"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Tonga dia vonona ohatra  ............................. \\" ","answer":"\\"  Tonga dia vonona ohatra ny totohondrim-boka \\" "},{"question":"Theo lời dẫn của tác giả, \\"Sài Gòn tạp pín lù\\" có thể hiểu nôm na, bình dân là gì?","answer":"Bài dẫn mở đầu sách Sài Gòn tạp pín lù (Sài Gòn tả pín lù) tác giả viết: Nếu dịch đúng ra Hán Việt, là \\"Sài Gòn đả biên lô\\" vẫn chưa ai hiểu là gì? Tả là tạp, là đả, đánh. Pín có hai nghĩa: \\"Pín\\" là đuôi sam thằng Chệc đời Mãn Thanh, nhưng đây pín có nghĩa là \\"biên\\" (Hán tự) và \\"bên, gần bên\\" (Nôm). Lù là lò, lò lửa.Tạp pín lù, là \\"đả biên lô\\", tức là món ăn nấu chín gần bên lò lửa cũng như \\"ăn sán lẩu\\" là ăn thịt sống nhúng vào nước sôi bắc trên lò lửa nóng. Số là người Tây bày ra một từ khí làm bằng chì, thiếc, vật kim khí có chân cao giữa khoét lỗ đặt vài cục than cháy, chung quanh là nồi chứa nước thịt ngọt, khách ăn tự lựa từng món ngon: Mề gà, lòng heo, ruột già, ruột non, dồi trường, tự gắp bằng đũa và nhúng vào nước thịt đang sôi, rồi tự gắp qua chén và không cần biết món nhúng đã chín hay còn sống sượng....\\"Sài Gòn tạp pín lù\\", nôm na là \\"Sài Gòn thập cẩm\\", \\"Sài Gòn tào lao\\", \\"Sài Gòn ba lăng nhăng\\", ai muốn hiểu sao thì hiểu. \\"Sài Gòn sán lẩu\\" cũng được. Nếu nói theo Bắc thì \\"Sài Gòn thập cẩm\\"; nếu nói theo Trung thì \\"Sài Gòn tào lao\\", nhưng tác giả sanh tại Sóc Trăng (Nam Kỳ) nên gọi Sài Gòn tạp pín lù là vì vậy."},{"question":"Crie uma pergunta para a categoria Variedades","answer":"Aqui está uma pergunta para essa categoria: Quantos dias tem o mês de dezembro?"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أهم الأمور التي عليك التأكد منها قبل استخدام الطوب؟","answer":"الإجابة: كونه جاف، وغير ماص للماء، وأبعاده منتظمة"},{"question":"Thơ bốn chữ, năm chữ là gì?","answer":"- Thơ bốn chữ: bài thơ có nhiều dòng, mỗi dòng có bốn chữ. Các dòng thơ trong bài thường ngắt nhịp 2/2 hoặc 1/3. Ví dụ nhịp 1/3:Cau / ngày càng caoMẹ / ngày một thấpCau / gần với giờiMẹ / thì gần đất (Đỗ Trung Lai)- Thơ năm chữ: Bài thơ có nhiều dòng, mỗi dòng năm chữ. Các dòng thơ trong bài thường ngắt nhịp 3/2 hoặc 2/3, thậm chí ngắt nhịp 1/4 hoặc 4/1. Ví dụ nhịp 2/3 và 3/2:Mỗi năm / hoa đào nởLại thấy / ông đồ giàBày mực tàu / giấy đỏBên phố / đông người qua.(Vũ Đình Liên)- Các dòng ở cùng một khổ trong bài thơ không nhất thiết phải ngắt nhịp giống nhau.- Bài thơ bốn chữ hoặc năm chữ có thể gieo vần chân (vần được gieo ở cuối dòng thơ), vần lưng (vần được gieo ở giữa dòng thơ), vần liên (vần được gieo liên tiếp ở các dòng thơ), vần cách (vần không được gieo liên tiếp mà thường cách ra một dòng thơ) hay vần hỗn hợp (vần được gieo không trật tự nào). Bài thơ bốn chữ hoặc năm chữ có thể gieo nhiều vần."},{"question":"Fa’idojin Barkwanci?","answer":"Nishaɗantarwa: Akwai nishaɗi a cikin barkwanci, kasancewarsa wasa da ake yi ta hanyar magana kuma a saka juna dariya. Ita kuwa dariya, hanya ce mai matuƙar muhimmanci ta saka nishaɗi.Ƙara Danƙon Zumunci: Barkwanci yana ƙarfafa zumunci tsakanin masu yinsa. Ana kawar da gaba ta hanyar barkwanci. Misali, barkwanci tsakanin ƙabilun da suka yaƙi juna ko kuma masu sana’o’in da kusan suke kishiyantar juna, misali a ce mahauci da masunci. Sukan cirewa junansu ƙyashi ta hanyar barkwanci.Ilimantarwa: Akwai ilimatarwa a cikin barkwanci, saboda ta hanyar barkwanci ake ƙirƙiro wasu gajerun labarurrukan da ake raɓa su da wata ƙabilar wanda a cikin irin waɗannan labaru za a ga akwai hikimomin da za a samu ilimin rayuwa a ciki. Misali, Barebari suna cewa wai wani Bafullace ne mota ta kaɗe shi har ya fita hayyacinsa ta inda har aka kai shi asibiti bai sani ba. To bayan ya farfaɗo daga doguwar sumar da ya yi, sai ya ga likita cikin fararen kaya yana tsaye a kansa, shi kuma bafullacen yana kwance kan gado, ga katifa mai laushi, ga kuma fanka tana firfita shi da sauran kayan alatu. To wai da likita ya tambaye shi sunansa sai ya ce, “Da dai a duniya ana she min Ja’o, amma yanzu Nawakiri (Walakiri) sai abin da ka she (ka ce)”."},{"question":"Apakah nama lagu kebangsaan negara Venezuela? ","answer":"Nama lagu kebangsaan negara  Venezuela ialah Gloria al bravo pueblo."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la relación entre la globalización y la economía mundial?","answer":"La globalización se refiere al proceso de interconexión e interdependencia creciente de países y economías de todo el mundo. En la economía mundial, la globalización implica la expansión del comercio internacional, la inversión extranjera, la transferencia de tecnología y la movilidad de la mano de obra. Esto ha llevado a un mayor acceso a productos y servicios de todo el mundo, pero también ha planteado desafíos como la competencia global y la desigualdad económica."},{"question":"ఒక భవనం యొక్క అడుగుభాగం నుండి ‘d’ మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్న స్థానం నుండి భవనం యొక్క పై భాగంను ‘α’ ఊర్థ్వకోణంను చూస్తే భవనం ఎత్తును కనుగొనే సందర్భంలో ఈ క్రింది త్రికోణమితి నిష్పత్తులలో దీనిని ఉపయోగిస్తారు.A) tan αB) sin αC) cos αD) sec α","answer":"A) tan α"},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 三菱重工業は、客を乗せて飛ぶジェット機を日本で初めてつくるため、2008年に開発を始めました。国も500億円を出して協力していました。しかし、技術が足りなくて、開発は計画のとおりに進みませんでした。航空会社にジェット機を渡す約束にも何度も遅れました。三菱重工業は7日、開発をやめると言いました。開発を続けるために1年に1000億円ぐらいかかることや、ジェット機ができても、売って利益を出すのが難しいことなどが理由です。国も協力して日本の技術でジェット機をつくる計画は、成功することができませんでした。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。"},{"question":"የውጫሌ ውል በስንት ዓ.ም የተደረገ ስምምነት ነው?","answer":"ሚያዝያ ፳፭ ቀን ፲፰፻፹፩ ዓ/ም"},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Ouzbékistan","answer":"Péeyum réwum Ouzbékistan mu ngi tudu Tachkent"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana : « Ranomasom-pifaliana no nikoriana tamin’ny tarehiny rehefa nanaiky ny hanambady ilay lehilahy izy. »","answer":"Maneho hafaliana izany. Hafaliana tokoa no mameno ny fo rehefa hiara-dalana mandra-maty amin’ny tiana."},{"question":"ඔලිම්පික් බොක්සිං තරඟයක් විනිශ්චය කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු කාන්තාව ?","answer":"නෙල්කා  ශිරෝමාලා"},{"question":"Wie is Atia Balba Caesonia?","answer":"Atia Balba Caesonia (85 - 43 v.Chr.) was een Romeinse vrouw van patricische afkomst.Zij was de moeder van keizer Augustus en dochter van Julia Caesaris, de zuster van Gaius Julius Caesar. Haar vader was Marcus Atius Balbus, die in 62 v.Chr. praetor was.Atia trouwde met de senator Gaius Octavius en ze kregen twee kinderen; Octavia Thurina minor en Gaius Octavius Thurinus, die als Octavianus bekend werd en later als Augustus de eerste keizer van Rome werd. Gaius Octavius stierf in 59 v.Chr. toen hij op weg was naar Rome om zich verkiesbaar te stellen voor het consulaat. In hetzelfde jaar hertrouwde Atia met Lucius Marcius Philippus, op dat moment propraetor van de provincie Syria. Philippus bekleedde in 56 v.Chr. het consulaat. Hij voedde de kinderen van Atia op samen met zijn eigen kinderen uit een eerder huwelijk en arrangeerde het eerste huwelijk van Octavia met de consul Gaius Claudius Marcellus minor.Volgens de geschiedschrijver Tacitus was Atia een van de vroomste en eerlijkste vrouwen uit de geschiedenis van de Romeinse Republiek en werd ze alom bewonderd. Na de moord op Caesar in 44 v.Chr. was ze zo bezorgd om Octavianus' veiligheid dat ze hem smeekte om af te zien van zijn rechten als erfgenaam. Zij stierf in 43 v.Chr., in het eerste jaar dat haar zoon consul was. Octavianus eerde haar met een publieke begrafenis. Philippus hertrouwde later met een van haar zusters. "},{"question":"வினா :  பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றைத் தரவும்.","answer":" விடை:பெரியார் தமிழகத்தை சார்ந்த ஒரு முக்கிய சமூக சீர்திருத்தவாதி, செயற்பாட்டாளர், சிந்தனையாளர் ஆவார். அவர் சமூக நீதி, சாதிய எதிர்ப்பு, மூடநம்பிக்கை எதிர்ப்பு, இறைமறுப்பு, பகுத்தறிவு, பெண்கள் முன்னேற்றம், கல்வி ஆகியவை சார்ந்து கொண்டிருந்ததே சிந்தனைகளே பெரியார் கொள்கைகள் அல்லது பெரியார் சிந்தனைகள் என்றழைக்கப்படுகின்றன. இவரின் சமுதாயப் பங்களிப்பைப் பாராட்டி யூனஸ்கோ நிறுவனம் புத்துலக தொலை நோக்காளர், தென்கிழக்காசியாவின் சாக்ரடிஸ், சமூக சீர்திருத்த இயக்கத்தின் தந்தை, அறியாமை மூடநம்பிக்கை, அர்த்தமற்ற சம்பிரதாயங்கள், மட்டமான பழக்கவழக்கங்கள் ஆகியவற்றின் கடும் எதிரி என்று பாராட்டுச் சான்றிதழ் வழங்கியுள்ளது.இவருடைய பகுத்தறிவு, சுயமரியாதைக் கொள்கைகள் தமிழ்நாட்டின் சமூகப் பரப்பிலும், தமிழக அரசியலிலும் பல தாக்கங்களை ஏற்படுத்தியவை.மேற்கோள்: மதம் மனிதனை மிருகமாக்குகிறது, சாதி மனிதனை சாக்கடையாக்குகிறது. "},{"question":"Ndezvipi zvinotevera zvinoratidza basa guru reshongwe yenhepfenyuro munhepfenyuro? Zvisarudzo: a). decoder; b.) encoder; c.) receiver; d.) transmitter;","answer":"d). Transmitter inoratidza basa guru reshongwe yenheofenturo munhepdenyuro. "},{"question":"වෘෂණ වලට කියන හෙළ වදන මොකක්ද?","answer":"කර= අණ්ඩකෝෂකර අඹනවා  කියන්නෙ ඒකනෙ."},{"question":"No contexto da linguagem de programação Go, explique brevemente o termo \\"defer\\".","answer":"Defer é uma declaração usada para adiar a execução de uma função até o final da função atual ou do escopo onde foi definida."},{"question":"Jawablah pertanyaan berikut dengan menggunakan konteks informasi dari artikel yang disediakan di bawah ini.Pertanyaan:Apakah tradisi Balon Lebaran Ponorogo berbahaya? Artikel:Balon Lebaran Ponorogo merupakan salah satu tradisi yang tetap lestari hingga saat ini di Ponorogo , Jawa Timur. Tradisi ini berlangsung pada setiap lebaran Hari Raya Idul Fitri. Masyarakat Ponorogo pada awalnya menyebut tradisi Balon Lebaran dengan \\"umbulan\\" atau \\"ombolan\\" yang berarti menerbangkan seperti bulan, seperti halnya menerbangkan balon udara tanpa awak. Balon Lebaran Ponorogo telah diberlangsung sejak abad ke 15 tepatnya tahun 1496M yang pada awalnya merupakan tradisi masyarakat ponorogo yang kala itu beragama Budha, tradisi menerbangkan balon di wengker telah ada pada abad ke 7 sejak zaman Sriwijaya hingga Medang sebelum masuknya islam di Ponorogo. Batara Katong selaku pendakwah islam dan bupati pertama di Ponorogo kala itu mengubah tradisi tradisi menerbangkan balon yang biasa digunakan umat budha ponorogo menjadi balon yang bernafaskan islami dengan diterbangkannya balon-balon setiap idul fitri, yang pada awalnya sebagai penghormatan kepada Ki Ageng Kutu Surya Alam untuk mengurangi gejolak masyarakat Ponorogo atas gugurnya kepemimpinannya. Balon Lebaran Ponorogo dibuat dari bahan kertas, mengingat ponorogo sejak abad ke 7 sudah mampu membuat kertas sendiri. Kertas-kertas tersebut dirangkai dan disambungkan satu sama lain menggunakan putih kulit telur ataupun nasi, kemudian dirangkai menjulang dan direkatkan pada bambu atau rotan berbentuk lingkaran. Langkah terakhir adalah balon kertas tersebut diberi tali dan tempat untuk menaruh minyak. Balon dibuat dengan ukuran antara 1,5 Meter hingga 4 Meter.Menerbangkan balon lebaran tidak dilakukan seorang diri, melainkan satu balon diterbangkan oleh 5 orang hingga puluhan tergantung kecil besarnya balon yang mencerminkan gotong royong. Sebelum diterbangkannya balon, dibentuk sebuah musyawarah disetiap kekerabatan maupun RT, RW, Kedukuhan, kedusunan, hingga Desa Kelurahan yang tidak terikat dengan kelompok apapun. Kegiatan musyawarah ini bertujuan untuk membahas menerbangkan balon sebelum bulan puasa.Namun, ada beberapa kontroversi terkait tradisi tahunan ini. Dengan hasil kreasi dan inovasi yang tinggi masyarakat Ponorogo terhadap Balon Lebaran, Tradisi Balon Lebaran Ponorogo ini mengkhawatirkan beberapa pihak dengan adanya keluhan dari PT PLN, Bandara Udara, Kepolisian karena dikatakan sangat berbahaya. Dari pihak PT PLN tradisi balon lebaran di Ponorogo sangat berbahaya, karena sangat rawan apabila balon tersebut jatuh dan mendarat di tiang listrik maupun kabel yang melintang karena dapat menyebabkan padamnya listrik. Sedangkan dari Bandara Udara menyebutkan bahwa tradisi masyarakat Ponorogo terkait menerbangkan balon sangat berbahaya bagi penerbangan pesawat terbang karena sangat mengganggu pandangan perjalanan pesawat juga apabila terkena badan pesawat maupun masuk ke dalam turbin, terlebih pernah terjadi mendaratnya balon udara raksasa dari Ponorogo di sekitar bandara udara Adisutjipto Yogyakarta, juga Mendarat di Wonogiri, Madiun, Magetan, Kediri, Nganjuk, Pacitan, Ngawi, Solo, tulungagung, Gresik hingga Malang. Sedangkan dari pihak kepolisian dan pemerintah daerah dibawah bupati Ponorogo Ipong Muchlissoni sudah menerbitkan pelarangan menjalankan tradisi menerbangkan Balon Lebaran Ponorogo yang dinilai berbahaya ini hingga di siarkan di radio setempat dan media masa koran, namun tetap saja masyarakat Ponorogo melakukan tradisi menerbangkan balon lebaran, karena memang tradisi balon lebaran ini sudah ada lebih 500 tahun. Jawaban:","answer":"Ya. Tradisi menerbangkan Balon Lebaran Ponorogo berbahaya, terutama berkaitan dengan jaringan listrik dan penerbangan. Dari laporan pihak PT PLN, penerbangan balon udara tanpa awak membahayakan apabila balon-balon tersebut jatuh dan mendarat di tiang listrik maupun kabel yang melintang, sehingga dapat menyebabkan padamnya atau rusaknya jaringan listrik. Dari pihak Bandara Udara menyebutkan bahwa tradisi masyarakat Ponorogo terkait menerbangkan balon sangat berbahaya bagi penerbangan pesawat terbang karena sangat mengganggu pandangan perjalanan pesawat juga apabila terkena badan pesawat maupun masuk ke dalam turbin."},{"question":"Waxaa sheegtaan saxaabiga kaligii lagu sheegay Quraanka magaciisa? Iyo qofka aanan dhalin oo loogu magacdari jiray?","answer":"Zayd ibnu Muxammad.    "},{"question":"Кандай жаңылмач билесиң ?","answer":"Мына сизге жаңылмач:Бул кайсы оозу май тайлак?Бул кайдагы сары май бал каймак? Бул оозанган оозу май тайлак, Бул сур сары май бал каймак."},{"question":"සිංහල විහිළු කතාවක් කියන්න.","answer":"අගමැති හා චෙක්පතමෙරට අගමැතිවරයා ඔහුට ලැබුණ චෙක්පතක් රැගෙන ප්‍රධාන රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවකට ඇතුළු වූයේ එය මුදල් කරගැනීමට ය. ඔහු ඉතා නිහතමානීව පෝලිමේ සිටියේ තම වාරය එනතුරු ය. ටික වෙලාවකට පසු ඔහු කවුන්ටරය වෙත ළඟා වී ඔහු අත තිබූ චෙක්පත ඉදිරිපත් කළේ ය. අගමැති: \\"මට කරුණාකරලා මේ චෙක්පත මාරු කරලා දෙන්න පුළුවන් ද?\\"කැෂියර්වරිය: \\"මට කරුණාකරලා සර් ගේ හැඳුනුම්පත දෙන්න.\\" අගමැති: \\"ඇත්තටම මට මගේ හැඳුනුම්පත ගේන්න බැරි වුණා. ඒත් මම හිතන්නේ නෑ හැඳුනුම්පත ඕන වෙයි කියල. මාව හැමෝම දන්නවා. මම රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ. මේ රටේ අගමැති.\\" කැෂියර්වරිය: \\"මම සර් කවුද කියලා  දන්නවා. ඒත් බැංකු නීති සහ රෙගුලාසි අනුව හැඳුනුම්පත ඉදිරිපත් කරන්න ඕන.\\"අගමැති: \\"බැංකුවේ ඕනෑම කෙනෙක්ගෙන් අහන්න මම කවුද කියලා. හැමෝම මාව දන්නවා.\\"කැෂියර්වරිය: \\"සමාවෙන්න අගමැතිතුමා, මම බැංකු රෙගුලාසි අනුගමනය කරන්න ඕන.\\"අගමැති: \\"මම ඔයාට කියන්නේ කරුණාකරල මේ චෙක්පත මාරු කරලා  සල්ලි දෙන්න!\\"කැෂියර්වරිය: \\"සර් මේ අහන්න. දවසක් වික්ටර් රත්නායක මහත්තයා ආවා  හැඳුනුම්පත නැතුව චෙක් එකක් මාරු කරන්න. අපි බෑ කිව්වා. ඊට පස්සේ එයා තොටුපල අයිනේ ගීතය ලස්සනට ගායනා කරලා පෙන්නුව. ඒක ගායනා කරපු විදියෙන් අපි අඳුන ගත්තා ඒ වික්ටර් රත්නායකමයි කියල. ඊට පස්සේ අපි චෙක්පත මාරු කරලා එයාට සල්ලි දුන්නා. තව දවසක් අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහත්තයා ආවා හැඳුනුම්පත නැතුව චෙක් එකක් මාරු කරන්න. අපි බෑ කිව්වා. ඊට පස්සේ එයා කට උල් කරලා ඇස් ලොකු කරලා \\"මහින්ද හොරා\\" කියලා තුන් පාරක් කිව්වා. ඒ කියපු විදියෙන් අපි දැන ගත්තා ඒ අනුර කුමාර දිසානායකමයි කියලා. ඊට පස්සේ අපි චෙක්පත මාරු කරලා එයාට සල්ලි දුන්නා. සර්ටත් ඒ වගේ මොනවා හරි කරලා ඔප්පු කරන්න පුළුවන් ද ඔබතුමා තමයි අගමැති කියලා?\\"අගමැතිතුමා දිගු කල්පනාවකට වැටී පසුව කටහඬ අවදි කළේ ය. අගමැති: \\"ඇත්තටම මගේ ඔළුවට කිසිදෙයක් එන්නේ නෑ. මට කරන්න පුළුවන් එක දෙයක් ගැනවත් හිතාගන්න බෑ.\\" කැෂියර්වරිය: \\"සර්ට ඕන 1000 නෝට්ටුවලින් ද 5000 නෝට්ටුවලින් ද ?\\""},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරස්වේත මීදුම් ඉරා දෙනෙත් මඟ ඇහිරුජිවිතේ සීත සෘතුවේ ගිරි දුර්ග අතරින්","answer":"ස්වේත මීදුම් ඉරා දෙනෙත් මඟ ඇහිරුජිවිතේ සීත සෘතුවේ ගිරි දුර්ග අතරින්මා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවිමා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවිමා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවිරළු පොළොව මතින් දිලෙනාවිඩාබර දිගු ගමනේමුදු සිනිදු දෙපා රිදෙනාවේදනා සුසුම් අතරේආදරේ ශේෂ වේවිද චන්න කින්නරාවිමා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවිස්වේත මීදුම් ඉරා දෙනෙත් මඟ ඇහිරුජිවිතේ සීත සෘතුවේ ගිරි දුර්ග අතරින්මා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවිමා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවි…සඳ නිවීගිය රාත්රියේ තාරකා ගොළුව ඝන අදුරේළය මතින් වැතිරි සොඳුරු හීනයකට ඉඩ දීහිනැහෙන්න පුළුවන්ද චන්න කින්නරාවිහිනැහෙන්න පුළුවන්ද චන්න කින්නරාවිහිනැහෙන්න පුළුවන්ද චන්න කින්නරාවිහිනැහෙන්න පුළුවන්ද චන්න කින්නරාවි"},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా ఒక పద్యాన్ని రాయండి:సగం పేగును తడపడానికి సరిపోని అత్యంత తక్కువ ఆహారం కూడా లేని, రక్తాన్ని ఆవిరిగా చేసి, లోకానికి మంచి చేయడానికి ప్రయత్నం చేసి ఈ భూమిని తమ చెమటతో తడిపి కష్టాలతో బాధపడే మానవులకు అత్యంత ప్రేమతో మంచి మొదటి పంటగా సీతాఫలాలను ఇచ్చే నీ కారుణ్యాన్ని మెచ్చుకుంటాను.","answer":"మ|| అరప్రేవుం దడుపంగజాలని నిర ల్పాహారమై, రక్త మావిరిగా, లోకహితార్థమై కడగు చుర్విం జెమ్మట న్ముంచి, కష్టరతిం గుందెడు మానవాళికి గరిష్ఠప్రేమ “సీతాఫలో”త్కరమున్ మేలొలిపంటగా నొసగు నీకారుణ్యమగ్గించెదన్."},{"question":"MOTHER'S CURSEChapter 10","answer":"MOTHER'S CURSEChapter 10Izunna!!!! Cassandra screamed, throwing her phone away.Mum, it's Izunna, mum. I've fucked up, hei chimm .. she cried.You and your loud mouth; sort it out yourself. Her mom went to her and went in.She picked up her phone and dialled the number, but it wasn't connecting. She kept on trying until he picked up.Izunna!! She called.Cassy!! He answered.Izunna, I'm sorry for everything; I've learned my lessons. Please forgive me; this child is really yours.That child can't be mine. I left the village seven months ago, so I don't know what you're talking about. Izunna replied, \\"Okay, can I come over so as to see my children?\\" she askedYou can't. It's so painful that your kids don't even miss you. They don't talk about you and they don't even know if you really exist because you're a disgrace to womanhood. Izunna said, \\"I want my kids. I want to see them. Bring back my kids.\\"Well, when you're done screaming at the top of your voice, you can rest. My kids now have a mom who's taking care of them, unlike you who will abandon her children to starve. Izunna said that and ended the call.Izunna Wait for me; I'm coming to Abuja, Izunna. I'll deal with that girl. I'll deal with that husband snatcher. Wait for me, Izu. She cried, tearing her clothes apart.Ara agbala gi oooo,stay there while another woman takes your place, go to Abuja, and make sure you locate him. Don't allow that husband snatcher to reap where she didn't sow. Her mom saidWait ... mum, you're the cause of all this. You're the one doing this to me. I don't even know what to do again. If Izunna doesn't take me back, I won't forgive you, mom. You made me go astray.Shut that mouth, madam. Don't you know marriage is for better or worse? Why didn't you stay with him when he had nothing? Her mom bellowedCassandra raised her head.Mum, you misled me; you made me leave Izunna; you introduced me to Martins; now Martins has nothing again; you now want me to go back to Izunna."},{"question":"Tafiditra amin’ny sehatra ara-javakanto hafa ankoatra ny literatiora ve i Marc Levy?","answer":"Tsia"},{"question":"கேள்வி: தேசிய நவீன கலைக் கூடத்தின் அமைவிடம்","answer":"பதில்: ஜெய்ப்பூர் இல்லம் , ராஜ்பாத், புது தில்லி"},{"question":"Wes Gurnee සහ Max Tegmark විසින් Large Language Models (LLMs) සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද පත්‍රිකාවේ ප්‍රධාන අවධානය කුමක්ද?","answer":"Wes Gurnee සහ Max Tegmark විසින් ලියන ලද පත්‍රිකාව අවධානය යොමු කරන්නේ LLMවරුන් ඔවුන් පුහුණු කර ඇති දත්ත කෙතරම් සත්‍ය වශයෙන්ම තේරුම් ගන්නේද යන්න විශ්ලේෂණය කිරීම, අවකාශය සහ කාලය වැනි මූලික මානයන් පිළිබඳ ඔවුන්ගේ ග්‍රහණය විශේෂයෙන් පරීක්ෂා කිරීම සහ ඒවා සරල සංඛ්‍යාන රටාවන්ගෙන් ඔබ්බට යන්නේද යන්නයි."},{"question":"شكون أسس مدينة القسطاط بمصر ؟","answer":"عمرو بن العاص"},{"question":"स्वास्थ्य सेवाहरूमा पहुँचले समग्र स्वास्थ्य परिणामहरूलाई कसरी असर गर्छ?","answer":"स्वास्थ्य सेवाहरूमा पहुँचले स्वास्थ्य परिणामहरूलाई धेरै प्रभाव पार्छ। पर्याप्त पहुँचले समयमै चिकित्सा हस्तक्षेपहरू, रोग रोकथाम उपायहरू, र स्वास्थ्य अवस्थाहरूको उचित व्यवस्थापन सुनिश्चित गर्दछ, जसले समग्र स्वास्थ्य सुधार गर्न योगदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Men hvad der gør mere ondt i S-toppen, er, at en række socialdemokratiske borgmestre nu også angriber de planlagte skattelettelser","answer":"og de gør det med den meget konkrete begrundelse, at de lige nu må skære i udgifterne til børn, syge og ældre. S-toppen mener derfor at skattelettelserne forværre det danske velfærdssystem."},{"question":" විකිරණය ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"රත් වූ වස්තුවක් තරංග ආකාරයෙන් ශක්තිය පිට කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය විකිරණයයි .රත් වූ වස්තුවක ට ඕනෑම දිශාවකින් අත කිට්ටු කළ විට රස්නය දැනේ .සංවහනය ඉහලට පමණක් දැනෙන අතර වාතය තුළ සන්නයනය ඉතා අඩු නිසා තාප සංක්‍රමණය ට තවත් ක්‍රමයක් තිබිය යුතුය.තවද හිරුගෙන් පොළොවට විශාල තාප ශක්ති ප්‍රමාණයක් ලැබෙනුයේ රික්තයක් හරහාය.සංවහනය, සන්නයනය රික්තයක් හරහා සිදුවිය නොහැක.රත් වූ වස්තුවක පෘෂ්ඨවල අණු පරමාණු කම්පනය වෙමින් තරංග ලෙසින් ශක්තිය මුදා හරියි.තාප විකිරණ විද්‍යුත් චුම්බක තරංග වේ.මේවා විද්‍යුත් චුම්බක වර්ණාවලිය තුළ පාරජම්බුල ,දෘශය ආලෝක හා අධෝරක්ත යන කලාප තුනක ඇත.වස්තුවක් ඕනම උෂ්ණත්වයකදී තාප විකිරණ පිට කරයි.ඕනම උෂ්ණත්වයකදී තාප විකිරණ අවශෝෂණය කරයි.වස්තුවක් තාප විකිරණ පිට නොකරන්භන් 0K දී පමණි.මේ අනුව අඩු උෂ්ණත්වයකදී පිටකරන්නේ IR විකිරණ පමණි.උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩි වන විට දෘශ්‍ය ආලෝකය මෙන්ම පාරජම්බුල විකිරණ ද පිට කරයි.වස්තුවක් තාප විකිරණ පිට කිරීමේ සීඝ්‍රතාව පහත සාධක මත රඳා පවතී.පෘෂ්ඨයේ උෂ්ණත්වයපෘෂ්ඨයේ වර්ගඵලයපෘෂ්ඨයේ ස්වභාවයකළු රළු පෘෂ්ඨ වැඩිම ශීඝ්‍රතාවයකින් තාප විකිරණ පිට කරයි.සුදු ඔපදැමූ පෘෂ්ඨ අඩුම ශීඝ්‍රතාවයකින් තාප විකිරණ පිට කරයි.එසේම කළු රළු පෘෂ්ඨ වැඩිම ශීඝ්‍රතාවයකින් තාප විකිරණ අවශෝෂණය කරයි.සුදු ඔපදැමූ පෘෂ්ඨ අඩුම ශීඝ්‍රතාවයකින් තාප විකිරණ අවශෝෂණය කරයි.මේ අනුව හොඳ විකිරකයක් සෑම විටම හොඳ අවශෝෂකයක් ද වේ."},{"question":"\\"Nihamaizina ny lanitra, ary nanomboka nilatsaka ny ranonorana voalohany.\\"Inona no mety ho fiafaran'ny tantara teo aloha:A. Tsapako fa nanadino ny elo tao an-trano aho.B. Nihazakazaka nitady fialofana izahay talohan'ny nisian'ny oram-be.","answer":"B. no fiafarana mety indrindra ho an'ny tantara."},{"question":" 文1: \\" 俳優のアルジュン・サージャの娘は 俳優のラジェシュとニヴェディタと結婚している \\". 文2: \\"俳優のラジェシュの娘のニヴェディタは俳優のアルジュン・サージャと結婚している\\". 質問:第1文と第2文は同じ意味を表しているのですか. そうか,いやか?","answer":"文1と文2は異なる意味を表しています。文1の内容:アルジュン・サージャの娘はラジェシュという俳優とニヴェディタという人物と結婚している。これは、アルジュン・サージャの娘がラジェシュとニヴェディタの2人と結婚しているように読めます（これは現実的ではありませんが、文としてはそう読めます）。文2の内容:ラジェシュの娘であるニヴェディタはアルジュン・サージャと結婚している。これは、ラジェシュには娘がおり、その娘の名前はニヴェディタで、彼女はアルジュン・サージャと結婚しているという意味になります。したがって、2つの文は異なる内容を伝えています。答えは「いや」です。"},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity : “Vady tsy tiana ...................”","answer":"“Vady tsy tiana be-tsiny.”"},{"question":" Apakah resipi untuk ayam percik Kelantan? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: 1 ekor ayam, 2 cawan santan pekat, 10 biji bawang merah, 2 ulas bawang putih, 1 inci halia, 2 batang serai, 1 sudu besar tepung beras/jagung (untuk memekatkan kuah), ½ keping asam gelugor, 1 sudu kecil lada sulah, 1 sudu besar gula, 1 cawan air, Garam secukup rasaCara penyediaan:1. Kisar bawang merah, bawang putih, halia, serai, lada sulah, garam dan gula dengan sedikit air.2. Potong ayam kepada empat bahagian atau lebih kecil. Bersihkan, kelar dan tuskan.3. Gaulkan ayam dengan bahan kisar dan perapkan selama sekurang-kurangnya setengah jam.Cara memasak:1. Masukkan ayam bersama perapan ke dalam periuk. Tambah secawan air, kacau, tutup periuk dan rebus dengan api sederhana.2. Bila ayam masak, keluarkan ayam dari periuk untuk dipanggang.3. Masukkan santan, asam keping dan tepung beras ke dalam periuk berisi perapan tadi dan masak dengan api kecil sehingga kuah pekat. Sentiasa kacau supaya santan tidak berketul dan pecah minyak.Perasakan dengan garam dan gula sebelum diangkat. Keluarkan asam keping kalau dah cukup rasamasam.4. Panggang ayam di atas bara api, dalam oven atau menggunakan pemanggang ajaib. Bila ayam dahkeperangan, lumurkan kuah percik pada ayam dan teruskan memanggang hingga garing. Terbalikkanayam dan ulangi proses melumur kuah dan memanggang beberapa kali sehingga kuah melekat padaayam dan ia masak sekata.5. Angkat dan hidangkan."},{"question":"Iguta ripi muRajasthan rine mabhurugwa akatumidzwa zita raro?","answer":"Guta riri muRajasthan rine mabhurugwa anotasva anonzi Jodhpur. Iwo akasarudzika \\"Jodhpurs\\" mabhurugwa aya anoratidzwa nezvidya zvawo zvakatsva uye makumbo ezasi anotsvedza."},{"question":"පර්යේෂණ පත්‍රිකා ඵලදායි ලෙස අවබෝධ කර ගෙන මතක තබා ගන්නේ  කෙසේද?","answer":"පර්යේෂණ පත්‍රිකා ඵලදායි ලෙස මතක තබා ගැනීමට සහ තේරුම් ගැනීමට, පහත පියවර සලකා බලන්න:1. දිනකට පත්‍රිකා දෙකක් පමණක් සෙමින් කියවන්න: එක් එක් පත්‍රය කියවා රස විඳීමට ඔබේ කාලය ගන්න. ඔවුන් හරහා ඉක්මන් වීමෙන් වළකින්න. දිනකට සම්පූර්ණ පත්‍රිකා 2-4ක් කියවීම සැලකිය යුතු ප්‍රමාණයකි.2. උද්දීපනය(Highlight) නොකරන්න; මතක තබා ගැනීමට ලියන්න: සරලව උද්දීපනය කරනවා වෙනුවට, ඔබේම වචනවලින් කඩදාසි අන්තර්ගතයේ සාරාංශ ලියන්න. මෙම ක්‍රියාවලිය ඔබගේ අවබෝධය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමට උපකාරී වේ.3. සාරාංශ සාරාංශ කරන්න: ඔබේම වචනවලින් පත්‍රිකාව සාරාංශ කිරීමෙන් පසුව, ඔබේ සාරාංශය තවදුරටත් සාරාංශ කරන්න. මෙය පත්‍රයේ ප්‍රධාන අදහස් වාක්‍ය 1-2 කට ආසවනය කිරීමට උපකාරී වේ.4. කතුවරුන්ගේ අභිප්‍රාය විකේතනය කරන්න: කතුවරුන් පත්‍රිකාව ලිව්වේ මන්දැයි තේරුම් ගෙන ඔවුන්ගේ අභිප්‍රායන් සංක්ෂිප්තව සාරාංශ කරන්න. පත්‍රිකාවේ සන්දර්භය සහ අරමුණ අවබෝධ කර ගැනීම සඳහා මෙම පියවර අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ."},{"question":"कोरोना विषाणूचा मानवी शरीरावर थेट परिणाम कुठे होतो?","answer":" श्वसन प्रणालीवर"},{"question":"Inona no tokony hotenenina raha toa ka te hankahery olona mandalo fotoan-tsarotra amin'ny teny Malagasy?","answer":"Raha toa ka te hankahery olona mandalo fotoan-tsarotra, dia afaka miteny azy hoe \\"Mahereza foana!\\""},{"question":"WHO ඇකඩමිය යනු කුමක්ද සහ එය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කොහේද?","answer":"ප්‍රංශයේ ලියොන් හි පිහිටා ඇති WHO ඇකඩමිය, ගෝලීය සෞඛ්‍යය සඳහා වැඩිහිටි ඉගෙනීමේ නවතම නවෝත්පාදනයන් සපයන  මධ්‍යස්ථානයකි. සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින් සහ ලොව පුරා සිටින අනෙකුත් අය වෙත ළඟා වීමට මාර්ගගත, පුද්ගලික සහ මිශ්‍ර ඉගෙනුම් වැඩසටහන් සැපයීම එහි අරමුණයි."},{"question":"Cuál es la categoría de esta pregunta: ¿Son 5 los continentes?.","answer":"La categoría de esta pregunta es geografía "},{"question":"Inona avy ny soa azo avy amin'ny fanatanjahantena?","answer":"Manolokolo ny vatana ny fanantanjahantenamanolokolo ny saina ny fanatanjahantenamanolokolo ny fanahy ny fanatanjahantena"},{"question":"ネパール語ではサガルマーター、チベット語ではチョモランマと呼ばれる、標高8850メートルで世界最高峰となっている山は何でしょう？","answer":"エベレスト山 (Mount Everest)"},{"question":"زيت الوقود الذي يستخدم في حرقه لتوليد بخار الماء المستخدم في إدارة محركات وتوربينات بخارية في محطات توليد الكهرباء يسمى…؟","answer":"-المازوت"},{"question":"సహకార సంఘాల ప్రయోజనాలను, లోపాలను వివరించండి.","answer":"సహకార సంఘాల వలన ప్రయోజనాలు:1. స్థాపనా సౌలభ్యము: సహకార సంస్థలను స్థాపించుట సులభము. పదిమంది కలసి తమ ఆర్థిక ప్రయోజనాల కోసము ఒక సంస్థగా ఏర్పడవచ్చు. నమోదుచేయుటకు అవలంబించవలసిన చట్టబద్ధమైన లాంఛనాలు చాలా తక్కువ.2. ప్రజాస్వామ్య పరిపాలన: సంస్థల నిర్వహణ ప్రజాస్వామిక సూత్రాలపై ఆధారపడి ఉంటుంది. వ్యాపార నిర్వహణలో పాల్గొనే హక్కు ప్రతి సభ్యునకు ఉంటుంది. ఒక మనిషికి ఒకే ఓటు. అతనికి ఎన్ని వాటాలు అయినా ఉండవచ్చు.3. నిర్వహణ ఖర్చులు తక్కువ: సహకార సంస్థలలో పరిపాలన ఖర్చులు తక్కువ. పాలక మండలి సభ్యులు వేతనము తీసుకోకుండా నిర్వహణ పనులు చేపడతారు.4. సేవాశయము: సహకార సంస్థల ముఖ్య ఉద్దేశము సేవలను అందించుట. సభ్యులకు చౌక ధరలకు వస్తువులను అందజేస్తుంది. తక్కువ వడ్డీలకు ఋణాలను అందిస్తుంది. సభ్యుల మధ్య సహకార భావనను కలుగజేస్తుంది.5. పరిమిత ఋణబాధ్యత: సభ్యుల ఋణబాధ్యత వారు చెల్లించిన వాటా మూలధనానికే పరిమితమై ఉంటుంది.6. స్థిరత్వము: సభ్యుల మరణము, విరమణ లేదా దివాలా తీయడంవలన సంస్థ మనుగడకు భంగముకలగదు.7. పన్ను రాయితీలు: సహకార సంఘాల ఆదాయముపై కొంత పరిమితి మేరకు పన్ను మినహాయింపు ఉంటుంది. అంతేగాక నమోదు రుసుములోను, స్టాంపు డ్యూటీలోను మినహాయింపు ఉంటుంది.8. ప్రభుత్వ ఆదరణ: ప్రభుత్వము సహకార సంఘాలకు అప్పులు, గ్రాంట్ల రూపములో ఆర్థిక సహాయం అందిస్తుంది. సమాజములో ఆర్థికముగా, సాంఘికముగా వెనుకబడిన వర్గాలకు సహాయపడే ధ్యేయముతో ఈ సంఘాలకు ఉదారముగా ధన సహాయం అందిస్తుంది.9. వాటాలలో స్పెక్యులేషన్ ఉండదు: ఈ సంఘాలలో సభ్యుడు ఎప్పుడైనా వాటాలను కొనవచ్చు కాబట్టి వాటాలలో స్పెక్యులేషన్ ఉండదు.10. సాంఘిక ప్రయోజనాలు: ఈ సంస్థలు ప్రజాస్వామ్యములో విద్య, శిక్షణ, స్వయం పరిపాలన, స్వయం సహాయం, పరస్పర సహాయము మొదలైన సూత్రాలను ప్రతిపాదిస్తుంది.11. వ్యాపారాలపై నియంత్రణ: ఇతర వ్యాపారసంస్థలు అధిక ధరలతో వినియోగదారులను దోచుకుంటున్నప్పుడు, ఇవి తక్కువ ధరలకు వస్తువులను అందజేస్తుంది.12. మధ్యవర్తులు ఉండరు: సహకార సంస్థలు వస్తువులను నేరుగా ఉత్పత్తిదారుల నుంచి కొనుగోలుచేసి వాటిని వినియోగదారులకు అందజేస్తాయి. మధ్యవర్తుల బెడద ఉండదు.13. సభ్యుల మధ్య సుహృద్భావము: ఒకరి కోసము అందరూ, అందరికోసం ఒకరు అనే సూత్రముపై సహకార సంఘాలు పని చేస్తాయి. కాబట్టి సభ్యుల మధ్య సోదరభావం, సంఘీభావము పెంపొందిస్తాయి.సహకార సంఘాల వలన లోపాలు:1. అసమర్థ నిర్వహణ: పాలకవర్గ సభ్యులకు గౌరవ వేతనము మాత్రమే లభిస్తుంది. కాబట్టి వారు నిర్వహణలో పూర్తి ఆసక్తిని చూపరు. ఆదాయ వనరులు స్వల్పముగా ఉంటాయి. కాబట్టి సమర్థవంతులైన, వృత్తి నిపుణులైన నిర్వాహకులను నియమించుట కష్టము.2. పరిమిత ఆర్థిక వనరులు: డివిడెండ్ల పరిమితి మరియు ఒక వ్యక్తికి ఒక ఓటు అనే సూత్రము వలన ధనవంతులు ఈ సంఘాలలో చేరడానికి ఇష్టపడరు. పరిమితమైన వనరుల వలన విస్తృతికి అవకాశముండదు.3. సభ్యులమధ్య సంఘీభావము లోపించుట: సభ్యుల మధ్య మనస్పర్థలు, తగాదాల వలన సహకార సంస్థలు విఫలమవుతాయి..4. కష్టపడేవారికి ప్రోత్సాహము ఉండదు: సంఘాలకు ఎక్కువ లాభాలు వచ్చినా వారి సేవలకు చెల్లింపు జరగదు కాబట్టి మేనేజ్మెంట్ కమిటీ సభ్యులు నిర్వహణలో ఎక్కువ ఆసక్తిని చూపరు.5. వాటాల బదిలీ ఉండదు: ఏ సభ్యుడు తన వాటాలను బదిలీచేయడానికి, వీలులేదు కాని మూలధనాన్ని వాపసు తీసుకోవచ్చు.6. కఠినమైన ప్రభుత్వ నియంత్రణ: సహకార సంఘములు చట్టములోని నియమ నిబంధనలను మరియు ప్రభుత్వ నిబంధనలు పాటించవలెను.7. అన్ని సంస్థలకు వర్తించకపోవడం: ఇవి చిన్న, మధ్యతరహా వ్యాపారాలకే అనువుగా ఉంటుంది.8.. రహస్యాలు దాగవు: సంస్థ వ్యవహారాలు సభ్యులందరికి తెలుస్తాయి కాబట్టి వ్యాపార రహస్యాలు దాగవు.9. నిస్వార్థ సేవకులు దొరుకుట కష్టము: సంస్థ విజయానికి నిస్వార్థ సేవకులు, నాయకుల ఆవశ్యకత ఉన్నది. కాని అటువంటివారు లభించుట అరుదు.10. రాజకీయాల జోక్యము: మేనేజ్మెంట్ కమిటీలో ప్రభుత్వము సభ్యులను నామినేట్ చేస్తుంది. ప్రతి ప్రభుత్వము -తమ సొంతపార్టీ సభ్యులను ఈ సంఘాలకు పంపుతుంది.11. పోటీతత్వము లేకపోవుట: సహకార సంస్థలకు పరిమిత వనరులు ఉండటము వలన పెద్ద సంస్థల పోటీని తట్టుకోలేవు. అవి భారీ ఉత్పత్తి ద్వారా ఓవర్హెడ్ ఖర్చులను తగ్గించుకోగలవు."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Henri Cartan para a matemática?","answer":"Henri Cartan teve contribuições significativas para a topologia e a teoria dos feixes, além de desempenhar um papel fundamental na fundação da Escola Francesa de Matemática."},{"question":"Quem é o atual Presidente dos Estados Unidos (em 2023)?","answer":"O atual Presidente dos Estados Unidos é Joe Biden"},{"question":"Sino ang kilala bilang “Grandmother of the Philippine Revolution”?","answer":"Si Mechora Aquino na binansagan ring \\"Tandang Sora\\""},{"question":" Sheeg asxaabtii uu Rasuulka (NNKH) u doortay inay quraanka soo dagaya uruuriyaan?","answer":" Wuxu u doortay Sayid Bin Thaabid, Ubaya Bin Kacab, Mucaad Bin Jabal, MucaawiyeBin Abuu Sufyaan, Iyo Afartii Khaliif"},{"question":"Felix Abidemi Fabunmi","answer":"Felix Abidemi Fabunmi je ojogbon (Professor) ninu imo eda-ede (Linguistics) ati ede Yoruba (Yoruba Language) ni Eka-Eko Imo Eda-ede ati Awon Ede Adulawo (Department of Linguistics and African Languages) ni Yunifásítì Ọbáfẹ́mi Awólọ́wọ̀ ni Ile-Ife , Nigeria. Ni odun 2006 ni o gba oye ijinle omowe (PhD). Apileko re da lori Mofoli, eka-ede Yoruba kan ti won n so ni ile Bene (Benin Republic). Akori iwe apileko akogboye naa ni \\"Asiko ati Iba-Isele ninu Eka-ede Yoruba Mofoli\\" (Tense and Aspect in the Mofoli Dialect of Yoruba). Opolopo ise ni o ti se lori ede Yoruba. O gba oye imo ijinle akoko (BA Yoruba) lodun 1992, oun lo gbegba oroke ju: First Class Honours. Lodun 1998 lo gba oye imo ijinle keji (MA Yoruba Language); bakan naa lo tun gba oye imo ijinle keji miiran (MA Linguistics) lodun 2004 ni Yunifasiti ilu Ibadan. Obafemi Awolowo University lo ti gba oye omowe (PhD Yoruba Language & Linguistics) ni 2006. Lodun 2013 ni Felix Abidemi Fabunmi di ojogbon ni Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Nigeria. O tun gba oye imo ijinle miiran lori eko Tiologi (Theology) - (M.Div.Th) lodun 2018 lati ile-eko giga ti awon oniwaasu: the Nigerian Baptist Theological Seminary, Ogbomoso, Nigeria. Oun naa lo tun gbegba oroke ju lo laarin awon akekoo kilaasi re. Akori ise apileko M.Div.Th re ni: \\"Contemporary Evangelistic and Church Growth Strategies in Ebenezer Baptist Church, Ile-Ife.\\"Lodun 1993 ni Ojogbon Felix Abidemi Fabunmi bere ise oluko ni OAU Ile-Ife. O di Olori Eka-Eko (HoD) Imo Eda-ede ati Ede Adulawo (Acting Head, Department of Linguistics and African Languages) OAU Ile-Ife lodun 2007. Die lara awon ise to ti fi koni niwonyi: YOR 105-Introduction to the Study of Language; YOR 106-General Phonetics; YOR 207-Phonology of Yoruba; YOR209-Introduction to Morphology; YOR301-Yoruba Syntax II; YOR 305-Grammar of the Yoruba Language from the Earliest to the Present; YOR407-Dialects of the Yoruba Language; YOR 402-Topics in the Structure of Yoruba; LIN 101-Language & Linguistics; LIN 103-Basic Grammatical Concepts; LIN 105-The Production of Speech I; LIN 102-Languages in Nigeria; LIN 104-Language Use & Language Attitudes; LIN 106-The Production of Speech II; LIN201-Basic Grammar; LIN207-Introduction to Sociolinguistics; LIN303-Semantics; LIN305-Transformational Grammar; LIN307-Morphology; LIN309-Phonology; LIN405-Transformational Grammar III; LIN302-Linguistics for Students of Literature; LIN304-Linguistics and Languages Teaching; LIN310-Linguistics and Translation; LIN204-The Production of Speech IV; LIN206-Basic Grammar II; LIN102 Languages in Nigeria; LIN402-Pidgin & Creole Languages; LIN408-Lexicography; LIN601 General Phonetics; LIN603-Syntactic Descriptions; YOR601-The Phonology of Yoruba;YOR602-Yoruba Verb Phrase; etc.Ojogbon Felix Abidemi Fabunmi ti sise iwadii lori ede Yoruba, imo eda-ede Yoruba; o tun n sise lori awon eka-ede Yoruba paapaa ju lo awon eka-ede Yoruba to wa leyin-odi Naijiria. Die lara awon ise re to ti te jade niwonyi:2001.\\"Notes on Ijesa Tense and aspect Marking\\", Studies in African Linguistics, 30,1:113-1142002. \\"Contextualised Theory of Beauty as a Pivot in Yoruba Oratures\\", Journal of languages and Literatures, 2,1&2:106-1172003.\\"A GPSG Appraisal of Sequential Distribution of Auxiliary Verbs in Ijesa Dialect of Yoruba\\", Nordic Journal of African Studies, 12,3:337-348.2004. \\"The Status of Yoruba Dialects in Communicative Conpetence and Language Proficiency\\", Africa Development, xxix, 3:103-113.2005. (Fabunmi & Salawu). \\"Is Yoruba an Endangered Language?\\", Nordic Journal of African Studies, 14, 3:391-408. http://www.njas.helsinki.fi/pdf-files/vol14num3/fabunmi.pdf2006. \\"Various Grammar of the Yoruba Language From Earliest to the Latest\\", An Encyclopaedia of the Arts, 12, 1:14-27.2007. \\"A Linguistic Introduction to the Mofoli Dialect of Yoruba\\", Nigerian Languages, Literatures, Culture and Reforms, No 6:487-504.2008. \\"The Syntax of Auxiliaries in the Yoruba Proverbs\\", Languages and Linguistics in Nigeria, 7:89-109.2009a. \\"A GPSG Strcuture of Aspect in Yoruba-Akoko\\", in Current Perspectives in Syntax and Dialectology, pages 156-191.2009b. A Grammatical Analysis of Mofoli Dialect of Yoruba. Plumstead, Cape Town, South Africa: The Center for Advanced Studies of African Society (CASAS). ISBN: ISBN 978-1-920447-22-9 (223 pages).2009c.Current Perspectives in Phono-Syntax and Dialectology. Edited by Gordon S.K. Adika, Felix Abidemi Fabunmi & Akeem Segun Salawu. A Publication of the Department of Gur-Gonja, Faculty of Languages, University of Education, Winneba, Ghana. ISBN: ISBN 978-9988-8489-1-0 (457 pages).2010a. Negation and the Scope of Negation in Yoruba Mofoli. Germany: VDM Verlag Dr. Muller. ISBN: ISBN 978-3-639-25527-0 (192 pages).2010b. \\"Vigesimal Numerals in Ife (Togo) and Ife (Nigeria) Dialects of Yoruba.\\" Lingistik Online 43, 3/2010 http://www.linguistik-online.de/43_10/fabunmi.html2011. \\"On the Formation of Questions in Ekegusii and Yoruba Mofoli.\\" Papers in English and Linguistics, vol. 11:78-942012. Asèrànwó Òrò-ìse Nínú Yorùbá Ìjèsà (Auxiliary Verbs in Ìjèsà Dialect of Yorùbá). Ile-Ife, Nigeria: Obafemi Awolowo University Press. ISBN: 978-136-057-7 (189 pages).2013a. Readings in African Dialectology and Applied Linguistics. Edited by Felix Abidemi Fabunmi & Akeem Segun Salawu. Munchen, Germany: LINCOM EUROPA Academic Publishers (GmbH). ISBN: ISBN 9783862884179 (542 Pages).2013b. \\"Negation in Sixteen Yorùbá Dialects.\\" Open Journal of Modern Linguistics. Vol.3, No.1, 1-8 Published Online March 2013 in SciRes (http://www.scirp.org/journal/ojml) DOI:10.4236/ojml.2013.31001Fabunmi, F. A. (ed.) 2014. Journal of African Culture and Languages. Vol 1, No. 1. Co-edited and published by the Department of Ghanaian Languages Education (Gur), University of Education, Winneba, Ghana.  Vol. 2, No. 1 (208 pages).Fabunmi, F. A. (ed.) 2016. Ifè̩ Journal of Languages and Literatures. Edited and published by the Department of Linguistics and African Languages, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife. Vol. 2, No. 1 (292 pages).Fabunmi, F. A. 2017. (ed.) Ifè̩ Journal of Languages and Literatures. Edited and published by the Department of Linguistics and African Languages, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife. Vol. 3, No. 1 (202 pages).Fabunmi, F. A. 2018. (ed.) Ifè̩ Journal of Languages and Literatures. Edited and published by the Department of Linguistics and African Languages, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife. Vol. 4, No. 1 (203 pages).Fabunmi, F. A. 2019. (ed.) Ifè̩ Journal of Languages and Literatures. Edited and to be published by the Department of Linguistics and African Languages, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife. Vol. 5, No. 1 (in press)."},{"question":"Il colibrì ali di zaffiro è l'unica specie nota del genere Pterophanes: vero o falso?","answer":"Vero."},{"question":"¿Por qué la Luna no se cae?.","answer":"La Luna no se cae hacia la Tierra debido a  un equilibrio entre fuwrzas fundamentales la gravedad y la velocidad orbital de la luna ,combinación de su movimiento. Aquí están los factores clave que evitan que la Luna se precipite hacia la Tierra:1. Movimiento orbital: La Luna está en constante movimiento alrededor de la Tierra en una órbita elíptica. Este movimiento es similar a cómo un objeto en caída libre sigue una trayectoria curva a medida que cae. Sin embargo, debido a la velocidad tangencial de la Luna y su inercia, continúa moviéndose horizontalmente en lugar de caer directamente hacia la Tierra.2. Fuerza centrífuga: A medida que la Luna se mueve en su órbita alrededor de la Tierra, experimenta una fuerza centrífuga debido a su movimiento en dirección opuesta a la gravedad. Esta fuerza equilibra parcialmente la atracción gravitatoria y contribuye a mantener la Luna en su órbita.3. Equilibrio gravitatorio: La gravedad de la Tierra ejerce una fuerza de atracción sobre la Luna, y esta fuerza tiende a atraerla hacia la Tierra. Sin embargo, debido a la inercia de la Luna y su movimiento orbital, estas fuerzas gravitatorias y centrífugas están en equilibrio, lo que resulta en una órbita estable.4. Velocidad orbital adecuada: La Luna tiene una velocidad orbital adecuada que le permite mantener su distancia de la Tierra y no caer hacia ella. Si la Luna fuera demasiado lenta, caería hacia la Tierra, y si fuera demasiado rápida, escaparía de la órbita.En resumen, la Luna no se cae hacia la Tierra debido a una combinación de su movimiento orbital, la fuerza centrífuga generada por este movimiento y la gravedad de la Tierra. Estos factores trabajan en conjunto para mantener la Luna en una órbita estable alrededor de nuestro planeta."},{"question":"Aşağıdaki cümleyi tamamlayın: Ancak, durum çok geçmeden radikal bir şekilde kötüleşti. 1648'den itibaren Kazak Khmelnytsky Ayaklanması güneyi ve doğuyu kapladı ve kısa bir süre sonra Polonya'nın merkezine yayılan İsveç istilası. Kazaklar ve Rusya ile savaş,","answer":"Ukrayna'yı bölünmüş, doğu kısmı ise Devletler Birliği tarafından kaybedilerek Çarlık'ın bağımlısı haline geldi. Osmanlı İmparatorluğu ile uzun süren savaşlarda savaşan III. John Sobieski, 1683'te Viyana'yı bir Türk saldırısından kurtarmak için kararlı bir şekilde yardımcı olan süreçte Birliğin askeri gücünü bir kez daha canlandırdı."},{"question":"Mubvunzo: Chivako chipi chakareba kupfuura zvimwe zvose munyika muna 2018 Mhinduro:","answer":"Burj Khalifa ku guta guru re Dubai"},{"question":"*ما عاصمة منغوليا ؟","answer":"أولا باتور"},{"question":"मी चेंडूने खेळतो. या वाक्याचा काळ ओळखा.चालू वर्तमानकाळसाधा वर्तमानकाळचालू व पूर्णवर्तमानकाळपूर्ण वर्तमानकाळ","answer":"Option 2 : साधा वर्तमानकाळकाळ: वाक्यात दिलेल्या क्रियापदावरून जसा क्रियेचा बोध होतो, तसेच ती क्रिया कोणत्या वेळी घडत आहे याचा जो बोध होतो त्यास काळ असे म्हणतात.काळाचे तीन मुख्य प्रकार पडतात.वर्तमानकाळ- क्रियापदाच्या रूपावरून क्रिया 'आता' घडते असे जेव्हा कळते तेव्हा तो वर्तमानकाळ असतो.उदा. मी अभ्यास करतो.भूतकाळ- क्रियापदाच्या रूपावरून क्रिया 'पूर्वी' घडली असे समजत असेल तर तेव्हा तो भूतकाळ असतो.उदा. मी अभ्यास केला.भविष्यकाळ-  क्रियापदाच्या रूपावरून क्रिया 'पुढेे' घडत असेल असे कळते तेव्हा तो भविष्यकाळ असतो.उदा. मी अभ्यास करीन.‘मी चेंडूने खेळतो’ या वाक्याचा काळ साधा वर्तमानकाळ हा आहे. वर्तमानकाळाचे इतर तीन प्रकार पडतात. अपूर्ण वर्तमानकाळ- क्रियापदावरून एखादी क्रिया वर्तमानकाळात चालू आहे किंवा ति अपूर्ण आहे असे जेव्हा समजते तेव्हा त्याला ‘अपूर्ण वर्तमानकाळ’ असे म्हणतात.उदा. तो मुलगा खेळत आहे.पूर्ण वर्तमानकाळ- ज्या क्रियापदांवरून क्रिया ही वर्तमानकाळात पूर्ण झाली आहे हे समजते तेव्हा त्याला ‘पूर्ण वर्तमानकाळ’ असे म्हणतात.उदा. मधूने लाडू खालला आहे.रीति वर्तमानकाळ- वर्तमानकाळात एखादी क्रिया सतत करीत असण्याची रीत समजली तर त्याला ‘चालू/रीति वर्तमानकाळ’ असे म्हणतात.उदा. मधू लाडू खात असतो."},{"question":"14 मिटरको आधार र 8 मिटरको उचाइ भएको समानान्तर चतुर्भुजको क्षेत्रफल गणना गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"समानान्तर चतुर्भुजको क्षेत्रफल उचाइले गुणन गरिएको आधार बराबर हुन्छ। त्यसैले, क्षेत्रफल १४ मिटर * ८ मिटर = ११२ वर्ग मिटर हो।"},{"question":"Inty misy fehezanteny:Hoy i Nalisoa RAVALITERA: “Matoa voatendry izy dia efa volahatra, ary miafanaraka ami’ny vintana ny fanendrena azy, tsy mety ho lasan’olon-kafa ny anjarany na dia ao anaty vahoaka maro aza izy.”Inona no fanontaniana azo apetraka momba io fehezanteny io?","answer":"Indro misy fanontaniana azo apetraka momba io fehezanteny io: inona no voalazan'i Nalisoa RAVALITERA momba ny lahatra?"},{"question":"એક પદ અથવા વાતા જેવી કહેવતોના ઉદાહરણ આપો.","answer":"એક પદ અથવા વાતા જેવી કહેવતોના નીચે મુજબ છે:- બીબી થાઅ મીઆં જોગ તારે થાઅ ઘોર જોગ- બીલાડી ઊંદરને પકડે છે અને બચોલીઆંનેઅ પકડે છે. તેમાં ફેર છે.- બુધે નાર પાંસરી ને બુધે ડોબું દોવા દે ને બુધે છોકરૂં રોતું રેહે.- બુઢો વઈદ ને જુવાંન જોશી.- બે પઈશા હોઅ તેનાં છોકરાં ઘુઘરે રમે.- ભણી ગણીને પોપટ થઓ.- ભણા પણ ગણા નહીં.- ભભુત લગાવે ભાગ્ય ન છપે.- ભગત જગતને આદ વેર.- ભાગ્યશાલીને ભુત રળે.- ભાવતું ઓશડ વઈદે કીધું.- ભાજી મુળા તે ઝાડમાં લેખું. (નથી)- ભાત મેલીએ પણ સાથ ન મેલીએ.- ભાગું ભાણું કંસારે જાએ નેં રૂઠું છોરૂં માવતરે જાઅ.- ભાગ્યની પીડામાં ભાગ ન થાઅ.- ભીખ તેને શું ભુખ.- ભુખે મરતાં ને છોકરાં ઘણાં- ભુતનું ઠેકાણું આંબલી."},{"question":"Inona no manara-pitsipi-piteny amin’ireto :1. Voro-damba2. Vori-damba3. Rovi-damba","answer":"Voalohany 1 sy Fahatelo 3 - Voro-damba sy Rovi-damba no manara-pitsipi-piteny, satria « vorotra + lamba », « rovitra + lamba »."},{"question":"Miliọnu mọkanla naira lawọn Fulani to ji awọn iyalọja gbe loju ọna Ọwọ n beere fun","answer":"Titi di ba a ṣe n kọ iroyin yii ni wọn ṣi n wa iyalọja Isua Akoko, nijọba ibilẹ Guusu Ila-Oorun Akoko, Oloye Edward Helen, atawọn ọlọja mẹfa mi-in tawọn Fulani agbebọn ji gbe lọsan-an ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ to kọja.Ibi ipade awọn iyalọja ti wọn n ṣe loṣooṣu niluu Akurẹ lawọn iyalọja naa ti n bọ ki wọn too bọ sọwọ awọn ajinigbe ọhun laarin oju ọna marosẹ Ọgbẹṣẹ si Uṣo.Awakọ to gbe wọn nikan lo raaye sa lọ ninu gbogbo wọn, oun naa lo si sare lọ siluu Isua lati lọọ royin ohun toju rẹ ri fawọn eeyan.Awakọ ọhun to n jẹ Jimi ṣalaye f’ALAROYE pe awọn Fulani bii mẹwaa ni wọn deedee jana mọ ọkọ bọọsi awọn lẹnu lojiji pẹlu ibọn AK47 ti wọn gbe lọwọ, eyi ti wọn n yin leralera lati fi dẹruba awọn eeyan.Awọn ọkọ akero meji mi-in to rin sasiko ti wọn n sọṣẹ lọwọ lo ni awọn ajinigbe naa tun da duro, ti wọn si fipa ko gbogbo ero to wa ninu wọn wọ inu igbo lọ.O ni ṣe lawọn ajinigbe naa mọ-ọn-mọ fi oun nikan silẹ lẹyin-o-rẹyin la ti lọọ royin ohun to sẹlẹ fawọn eeyan nile.A gbọ pe awọn ajinigbe naa ti pe awọn ẹbi Oloye Edward sori aago, tí wọn si n beere fun miliọnu mọkanla naira ki wọn too tu u silẹ.Iroyin awọn ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ ji gbe naa ni wọn lo ti da ibẹru sọkan awọn eeyan ilu Isua ati gbogbo awọn arinrinajo to n kọja loju ọna marosẹ Akurẹ si Ọwọ.Ọkan ninu awọn agbaagba ilu Afin Akoko, Alaaji Ibrahim Kilani, ni tọsan-toru lo ku tawọn onisẹẹbi naa fi n ṣiṣẹ lawọn oju ọna marosẹ to wa lagbegbe naa lati igba tawọn ọlọpaa ti jokoo pa si tesan latari rogbodiyan to su yọ lasiko iwọde SARS ti wọn ṣe kọja.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ondo, Tee-Leo Ikoro, ni awọn oṣiṣẹ awọn ti ri awọn mẹwaa gba pada ninu awọn ti wọn ji gbe naa.O ni igbesẹ si n tẹsiwaju la ti ri awọn yooku tu silẹ ninu igbekun awọn to ji wọn gbe."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਬੀਜ ਮੰਤ੍ਰੁ ਸਰਬ ਕੋ ਗਿਆਨੁ ॥ਚਹੁ ਵਰਨਾ ਮਹਿ ਜਪੈ ਕੋਊ ਨਾਮੁ ॥ਜੋ ਜੋ ਜਪੈ ਤਿਸ ਕੀ ਗਤਿ ਹੋਇ ॥ਸਾਧਸੰਗਿ ਪਾਵੈ ਜਨੁ ਕੋਇ ॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਉਰ ਧਾਰੈ ॥ਪਸੁ ਪ੍ਰੇਤ ਮੁਘਦ ਪਾਥਰ ਕਉ ਤਾਰੈ ॥ਸਰਬ ਰੋਗ ਕਾ ਅਉਖਦੁ ਨਾਮੁ ॥ਕਲਿਆਣ ਰੂਪ ਮੰਗਲ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਮ ॥ਕਾਹੂ ਜੁਗਤਿ ਕਿਤੈ ਨ ਪਾਈਐ ਧਰਮਿ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਤਿਸੁ ਮਿਲੈ ਜਿਸੁ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਧੁਰਿ ਕਰਮਿ ॥੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 274 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਨਾਮ (ਹੋਰ ਸਭ ਮੰਤ੍ਰਾਂ ਦਾ) ਮੁੱਢ ਮੰਤ੍ਰ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਸਭ ਦਾ ਗਿਆਨ (ਦਾਤਾ) ਹੈ ।ਬ੍ਰਾਹਮਣ, ਖਤ੍ਰੀ, ਵੈਸ਼, ਸ਼ੂਦਰ) ਚਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਜਾਤੀਆਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਭੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ) ਨਾਮ ਜਪ (ਕੇ ਵੇਖ ਲਏ), ਜੋ ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਉੱਚੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, (ਪਰ) ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ (ਰਹਿ ਕੇ) (ਇਸ ਨੂੰ) ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਜੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਉਸ ਦੇ) ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ (ਨਾਮ) ਟਿਕਾ ਦੇਵੇ ।ਪਸ਼ੂ, ਚੰਦਰੀ ਰੂਹ, ਮੂਰਖ, ਪੱਥਰ (-ਦਿਲ) (ਕੋਈ ਭੀ ਹੋਵੇ ਸਭ) ਨੂੰ (ਨਾਮ) ਤਾਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਾਰੇ ਰੋਗਾਂ ਦੀ ਦਵਾਈ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਉਣੇ ਚੰਗੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਤੇ ਸੁਖ ਦਾ ਰੂਪ ਹੈ ।(ਪਰ ਇਹ ਨਾਮ ਹੋਰ) ਕਿਸੇ ਢੰਗ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਰਸਮ ਰਿਵਾਜ ਦੇ ਕਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ; ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਇਹ ਨਾਮ) ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ (ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਤੇ) ਧੁਰੋਂ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ) ਮੇਹਰ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੫।\\""},{"question":"Manomeza ohatra amin'ny fadin-tany.","answer":"Ireto misy ohatra amin'ny fadin-tany: tongolo, kisoa, osy, ondry, alika."},{"question":"Berikan saya resipi untuk hidangan pulut kelapa rendang kerang.","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 2 kilogram kerang (rebus sekejap dan ambil isinya), 1 biji kelapa (dikisar dengan 2 1/2 cawan air, perah dan ambil santan), 5 helai daun limau purut, 3 paket kecil kerisik (kalau dibuat sendiri guna tiga ke empat sudu besar), 2 helai daun kunyit (hiris), 1 1/2 keping asam keping, 2 sudu besar gula pasir, 1/2 sudu besar garam, 1 sudu teh perasa, 2 senduk minyak masakBahan kisar: 15 hingga 18 tangkai cili kering (tambahkan jika mahu pedas), 2 biji bawang besar, 5 hingga 6 ulas bawang putih, Halia, Lengkuas, 6 batang seraiCara penyediaan:1. Panaskan minyak dan tumis bahan kisar.2. Masukkan asam keping dan gula, tumis hingga naik minyak.3. Masukkan kerisik, daun limau purut dan santan.4. Apabila kuah mulai pekat (sentiasa kacau, jangan sampai pecah santan), masukkan kerang.5. Letak garam dan peras, di samping tabur daun kunyit jika kuah sudah pekat.6. Tutup api dan sedia untuk dihidang bersama pulut."},{"question":"आर्टिफिशियल इंटेलिजेंस के अवश्यकता और इसके विभिन्न उद्योगों पर प्रभाव की विवरण करें।","answer":"आर्टिफिशियल इंटेलिजेंस प्रोग्राम एक ऐसा प्रोग्राम है जो सीखने और सोचने में सक्षम है। किसी भी चीज़ को कृत्रिम बुद्धिमत्ता मानना ​​संभव है यदि इसमें कोई ऐसा कार्य करने वाला प्रोग्राम शामिल हो जिसे हम आम तौर पर मानते हैं कि एक इंसान करेगा।जहां कृत्रिम बुद्धिमत्ता के कई फायदे हैं, वहीं कुछ कमियां भी हैं। एआई के लाभों में कार्य स्वचालन के माध्यम से दक्षता, सूचित निर्णयों के लिए डेटा विश्लेषण, चिकित्सा निदान में सहायता और स्वायत्त वाहनों की उन्नति शामिल है। एआई की कमियों में नौकरी में विस्थापन, पूर्वाग्रह और गोपनीयता के बारे में नैतिक चिंताएं, हैकिंग से सुरक्षा जोखिम, मानव जैसी रचनात्मकता और सहानुभूति की कमी शामिल है।आइए कृत्रिम बुद्धिमत्ता के फायदों से शुरुआत करें।हेल्थकेयर में ए.आईनिदान और उपचार को बढ़ाने की क्षमता। एआई एल्गोरिदम सटीक और समय पर निदान करने में स्वास्थ्य पेशेवरों की सहायता के लिए रोगी रिकॉर्ड, प्रयोगशाला परिणाम और चिकित्सा छवियों सहित बड़ी मात्रा में चिकित्सा डेटा का विश्लेषण कर सकता है। एआई उन पैटर्न और विसंगतियों की पहचान कर सकता है जिनका पता लगाना मानव चिकित्सकों के लिए मुश्किल हो सकता है, जिससे बीमारियों का पहले ही पता चल जाता है और उपचार के परिणाम बेहतर हो जाते हैं। मार्केटिंग में एआईविपणन अभियानों के लक्ष्यीकरण और वैयक्तिकरण को बढ़ाने की क्षमता। एआई एल्गोरिदम दर्शकों को विभाजित करने और अत्यधिक लक्षित और वैयक्तिकृत विपणन संदेश देने के लिए जनसांख्यिकी, प्राथमिकताएं, ब्राउज़िंग व्यवहार और खरीद इतिहास सहित बड़ी मात्रा में ग्राहक डेटा का विश्लेषण कर सकता है। एआई का लाभ उठाकर, विपणक अपने अभियानों को विशिष्ट ग्राहक खंडों के अनुरूप बना सकते हैं, जिससे उनके विपणन प्रयासों की प्रासंगिकता और प्रभावशीलता बढ़ जाती है। लक्ष्यीकरण और वैयक्तिकरण के इस स्तर से उच्च रूपांतरण दर, बेहतर ग्राहक संतुष्टि और विपणन अभियानों के लिए निवेश पर रिटर्न (आरओआई) में वृद्धि हो सकती है।शिक्षा में ए.आईवैयक्तिकृत शिक्षण अनुभव प्रदान करने की क्षमता। एआई-संचालित सिस्टम अनुरूप शैक्षिक सामग्री और अनुकूली शिक्षण पथ बनाने के लिए छात्र के प्रदर्शन, प्राथमिकताओं और सीखने की शैलियों पर बड़ी मात्रा में डेटा का विश्लेषण कर सकते हैं। यह वैयक्तिकरण छात्रों को अपनी गति से सीखने, उन क्षेत्रों पर ध्यान केंद्रित करने, जहां उन्हें अधिक समर्थन की आवश्यकता है, और ऐसी सामग्री से जुड़ने की अनुमति देता है जो उनके लिए प्रासंगिक और दिलचस्प है।"},{"question":"آیا زمانی در دریاچه ارومیه کشتیرانی می‌شده است؟","answer":"کشتیرانی در دریاچه ارومیه سابقه دیرینه دارد و رونق آن به پیش از حمله مغول بازمی‌گردد. نخستین گزارش‌هایی که از قرن نوزدهم در باب کشتیرانی در دریاچه در دست است، نشان می‌دهد که شناورهایی هرچند تکامل نیافته و با خدمه‌های فاقد مهارت‌های دریانوردی در دریاچه وجود داشت. به گفته اگوست بن تان، افسر فرانسوی که به دربار عباس میرزا در تبریز اعزام شده بود، کشتیرانی در دریاچه ارومیه به علت طوفان‌های ناگهانی با مخاطره همراه بود. ملک قاسم میرزا، پسر فتحعلی‌شاه که در دوران عباس میرزا و محمد شاه حاکم ارومیه بود امتیاز انحصار کشتیرانی در این دریاچه ارومیه را از محمدشاه گرفت و برای بهره‌برداری از این حق، تعدادی از قایق‌های ابتدایی روستاییان سواحل دریاچه را نابود کرد و به صنعتگران روسی که از بنادر دریای مازندران به شیشوان آورده بود، سفارش ساخت کشتی کوچکی را داد که در دریاچه به آب انداخته شد. سپس با استخدام یک استاد کشتی ساز از باکو و تعدادی نجار، کشتی بزرگی با ظرفیت یکصد تن در شیشوان ساخت تا برای حمل کالا به کار رود. ملک قاسم میرزا یک کشتی بادی اختصاصی با کابینی مجلل داشت که فاصله شیشوان تا ارومیه را در سه روز می‌پیمود."},{"question":" الجيش هو القوة النظامية لجمهورية العراق، وتتألف فُروعه من القوة البرية والقوة البحرية والقوة الجوية. ويَرجع تاريخ الجيش العراقي إلى العام 1921، حيت تأسَست أولى وحَدات القوات المسلحة خلال الإنتداب البريطاني للعراق، حَيثُ شُكل فوج الامام موسى الكاظم واتخذت قيادة القوات المسلحة مَقرها العام في بغداد، تبع ذلك تشكيل القوة الجوية العراقية عام 1931م ثم القوة البحرية العراقية عام 1937م، ووَصل تعداد الجيش إلى ذروته مع نهاية الحرب العراقية الإيرانية ليبلغ عدد أفراده 1.000.0000 فرد. بحلول عام 1990م نمت القوة العراقية إلى 56 فرقة مما جعل الجيش العراقي في المرتبة الأولى عربياً والخامسة بين جيوش العالم. وبعد غزو الكويت تقلصت القوة البرية إلى 23 فرقة بالإضافة إلى قوات الحرس الجمهوري. استخرج موضوع النص مما سبق:","answer":"الجيش العراقي"},{"question":"Айтылуучу маалыматка 18 мүнөт көңүл бөлгөн окуучулар.а)4-класстар б)5-класстар в)9-класстарг)10-класстар","answer":"Тураа жообу:б)5-класстар "},{"question":"Mitovy ve ny hevitrin'ny teny \\"mioty\\" amin'ireto fehezanteny roa manaraka ireto?Fehezanteny voalohany: Ny zaza dia tokony mioty ny zavatra rehetra ilainy amin'ny ray aman-dreniny.Fehezanteny faharoa: Mioty voankazo ao an'ala i Tahina.","answer":"Tsia, ny hevitry ny teny mioty amin'ny fehezanteny voalohany dia misitraka tombon-tsoa ary amin'ny fehezanteny faharoa kosa dia mitango na maka voankazo."},{"question":"คอมพิวเตอร์สามารถใช้ทำอะไรได้บ้าง","answer":"- ทำงานเอกสารออนไลน์- ดูหนัง- เขียนโปรแกรม- เล่นเกม"},{"question":"Siyah saç boyası abdest geçirir mi?","answer":"Boya, saç üzerinde kimyasal bir tabaka oluşturup suyun temasına engel olmadıkça guslü ve namaz abdestini engelleyici bir unsur değildir.\\" denildi."},{"question":"Ity misy ampahan-dahatsoratra: \\"Misy ny milaza fa olona efa maty tamin'ny 5 taona mahery no mbola tafiditra ao anaty lisitry ny mpifidy\\" .Olona efa maty oviana no mbola tafiditra anaty lisi-pifidianana?","answer":"Olona efa maty tamin'ny 5 taona mahery no mbola tafiditra ao anaty lisitry ny mpifidy ."},{"question":"တိုက်တန်းနစ် ( Titanic ) ရဲ့ ပိုင်ရှင်အစစ်က ဘယ်သူလဲ။","answer":"RMS Titanic သင်္ဘောကို ဗြိတိန်သင်္ဘောအဖြစ် မှတ်ပုံတင်ထားသော်လည်း ၎င်းကို အမေရိကန်သူဌေးကြီး John Pierpont (J.P.) Morgan က ပိုင်ဆိုင်ထားပြီး ကုမ္ပဏီသည် White Star Line ၏ ပိုင်ဆိုင်မှုကို ထိန်းချုပ်ထားကာ ယုံကြည်စိတ်ချမှုကို ဆက်လက်ထိန်းသိမ်းထားသည်။ သူ့ရဲ့ US Steel၊ General Electric နှင့် ကမ္ဘာလုံးဆိုင်ရာဘဏ္ဍာရေးဝန်ဆောင်မှုလုပ်ငန်း JP Morgan Chase & Co တို့မှာလည်း ယနေ့ ( ၂၀၂၃ ) အထိ ကြီးထွားနေဆဲဖြစ်သည်။"},{"question":"Qui était le peintre Rembrandt van Rijn ?","answer":"Rembrandt van Rijn, peintre néerlandais du Siècle d'Or, est célèbre pour son talent exceptionnel à capturer la lumière et les ombres et à transmettre la profondeur émotionnelle de ses sujets. Sa « Ronde de nuit » est un portrait de groupe monumental qui met en valeur sa maîtrise de la composition et de l'éclairage dramatique. Les autoportraits et les études de personnages intimes de Rembrandt révèlent sa capacité à dépeindre l'expérience humaine avec empathie et authenticité."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari uku da arba'in da biyu a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 342"},{"question":"野球でスコアと言ったら得点のこと。ではオーケストラでスコアと言ったら何のことでしょう？","answer":"楽譜（譜面）です。"},{"question":"Tính giá trị của biểu thức: 15 + (39 : 3 – 8) . 4","answer":"Khi biểu thức có chứa dấu ngoặc, ta thực hiện các phép tính trong dấu ngoặc trước.15 + (39 : 3 – 8) . 4= 15 + (13 – 8) . 4 = 15 + 5 . 4 = 15 + 20 = 35. "},{"question":"من القائل:نالت على يدها ما لم تنله يدي * نقشا على معصم وأوهت به جلدي؟","answer":"جمهوريجمهوري"},{"question":"Кыргызстандык кайсы программисттерди тааныйсың?","answer":"Тилек МамутовТилек Мамутов учурда Google’да иштебейт. Бирок ал алгачкы кыргызстандыктардан болуп 2006-жылы Google’га жумушка кирген. Ал жакта 11 жыл эмгектенген.  Бул жылдар аралыгында Google’дын бир нече кызматтарын кыргыз тилине которууну демилгелеп, “орус хакерлери” менен күрөшкөн, Wi-Fi тараткан аба шарларын учуруу долбоорун жетектеген. Тилек Мамутов кыргыз тилинин Google котормочуга киргизилишине салым кошкондордун бири.Бирок ал иштегенге бардык шарттары бар, маянасы жакшы жумуштан өзүнүн стартапын баштоо үчүн 2018-жылы кетип калган. Ошондон тарта ал Google, Microsoft, Facebook, Bloomberg, Amazon жана башка ири компанияларда иштегиси келген КМШ өлкөлөрүнүн таланттуу адистерине көмөктөшүп келет. Учурда ал Америкада иштөөнү калагандар үчүн маекке даярданууга жана жумушка кирүүгө жардам берет."},{"question":"Awọn ṣofin ogun fọwọ si ki wọn yọ igbakeji olori wọn, Kadiri,  l’Ogun","answer":"Nitori awọn ẹsun iwa jagidijagan ati dida omi alaafia ilu ru ti wọn fi kan Igbakeji abẹnugan ile-igbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ Ogun, Ọnarebu Dare Kadiri, ile naa ti gbe igbimọ ti yoo ri si awọn ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an dide.Mẹrindinlọgbọn ni awọn ọmọ ile igbimọ aṣofin Ogun, ogun ninu wọn lo ti fọwọ si i pe ki wọn yọ Dare Kadiri nipo to wa.Eyi lo fa a ti Akọwe ile naa, Ọgbẹni Deji Adeyẹmọ, fi jẹ ko ye igbimọ lọjọ Iṣẹgun ọsẹ yii ti wọn jokoo lọfiisi wọn l’Oke-Mosan, pe oun ti fi iwe ẹsun wọn ranṣẹ si Kadiri, o si ti da esi pada, igbimọ ti yoo si jokoo lori ẹsun naa ati esi rẹ ti wa nikalẹ.Awọn igbimọ ti yoo ṣiṣẹ lori ọrọ yii gẹgẹ bi Ọlakunle Oluọmọ, olori ile naa ṣe ka a ni: Olori ọmọ ẹgbẹ to pọ ju lọ;Yusuf Sheriff (Alaga)AbdulBashir Ọladunjoye, Bọlanle Ajayi, Adeyẹmi Ademuyiwa, Modupẹ Mujọta ati Temitọpẹ Hokon to jẹ akọwe wọn.Ṣe lọsẹ to kọja yii ni awọn ọlọpaa lati Kọmandi l’Abẹokuta, mu Dare Kadiri ti i ṣe Igbakeji  ile-igbimọ aṣofin Ogun, wọn lo ko danjuku lẹyin lọọ ba ile Ọgbẹni Tokunbọ Talabi jẹ, iyẹn Akọwe ijọba fun Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun.Wọn fi kun un pe awọn eeyan mẹta mi-in lọkunrin yii tun kọ lu, to ba dukia wọn jẹ nitori awọn nnkan eelo iforukọsilẹ ẹgbẹ APC to n wa kiri.Kadiri ko ti i ba ile naa jokoo ipade latigba naa, iwadii ṣi n lọ lori rẹ latọdọ awọn ọlọpaa. Bẹẹ ni ile-igbimọ paapaa n ṣiṣẹ tiwọn lati mọ ootọ to wa nidii iṣẹlẹ naa, ati pe boya yiyọ ni yoo gbẹyin ọkunrin yii, boya wọn yoo si fi i silẹ ko maa ba iṣẹ rẹ lọ ni."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਃ ੫ ॥ਜੋ ਧੁਰਿ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਲੇਖੁ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਮੇਟਣਾ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ਰਾਮ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਨੁ ਵਖਰੋ ਨਾਨਕ ਸਦਾ ਧਿਆਇ ॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 315 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੁਢ ਤੋਂ (ਕੀਤੇ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ) ਜੋ (ਸੰਸਕਾਰ-ਰੂਪ) ਲੇਖ (ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਉੱਕਰਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਿਟਾਇਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ।(ਪਰ ਹਾਂ) ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਤੇ ਸੌੋਦਾ (ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰੋ), ਨਾਮ ਸਦਾ ਸਿਮਰੋ (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪਿਛਲਾ ਲੇਖ ਮਿਟ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੨।\\""},{"question":"世界の高峰ベスト10のうち、実に８つもの山が位置している国はどこでしょう？","answer":"ネパール"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو وقت صلاة الضحى؟","answer":"الإجابة: من ارتفاع الشمس قدر رمح إلى الاستواء"},{"question":"Kí ni orúkọ Ààrẹ Ọ̀nà Kakaǹfò ilẹ̀ Yorùbá?","answer":"Iba Gàní Adams ni."},{"question":"Wọn ti fun Ṣoworẹ atawọn ẹgbẹ ẹ ni beeli ogun miliọnu","answer":"Ifa ajafẹtọ-ọmọniyan nni, Ọmọyele Ṣoworẹ, ti fọ’re bayii, ileejọ ti fun un ni beeli to beere fun, miliọnu lọna ogun naira lo maa fi duro lati le maa tile waa jẹjọ.Owurọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, nile-ẹjọ Majisreeti kan niluu Abuja fọwọ si ẹbẹ oludasilẹ ati alakooso ileeṣẹ iroyin ori atẹ ayelujara, Sahara Reporters, to ti kọkọ wa lahaamọ awọn agbofinro, kile-ejọ too fi i ṣọwọ sẹwọn lọsẹ to kọja.Yatọ si miliọnu ogun naira beeli ti wọn bu fun un yii, o tun gbọdọ wa oniduuro meji ni iye owo kan naa, ti wọn si ni dukia to jọju bii ile tabi ilẹ l’Abuja, bẹẹ ni ko gbọdọ ṣere kọja origun mẹrin ilu Abuja, titi ti ẹjọ to n jẹ lọwọ yoo fi pari, aijẹ bẹẹ, awọn agbofinro yoo tun un gbe.Bakan naa ni wọn fun awọn ẹlẹgbẹ ẹ mẹrin, Juwọn Sanyaolu, Damilare Adenọla, Peter Williams ati Emmanuel Bulus ni beeli, miliọnu kan naira niye owo ti ọkọọkan wọn maa fi duro, wọn si gbọdọ wa oniduuro kọọkan ni iye owo kan naa.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, alẹ aisun ọdun tuntun, lọjọ kọkanlelọgbọn, oṣu kejila, ọdun 2020 to kọja yii, lawọn agbofinro mu Ṣoworẹ atawọn ẹgbẹ ẹ niluu Abuja, nibi ti wọn ti lawọn n ṣe iwọde alaafia kan.Ẹyin naa ni wọn foju wọn bale-ẹjọ, lara ẹsun tijọba ka si wọn lẹsẹ ni igbimọ-pọ lati dalu ru, apejọ ti ko bofin mu ati riru awọn araalu soke lati dẹyẹ sijọba. Latigba naa nile-ẹjọ ti paṣẹ ki wọn wa lọgba ẹwọn Wuse, l’Abuja."},{"question":"Quel est le 59ème élément du tableau périodique ?","answer":"Le 59ème élément du tableau périodique est le praséodyme (Pr). Faisant partie de la série des lanthanides, le praséodyme possède des propriétés uniques qui le rendent important dans diverses applications. C'est un métal mou et argenté qui peut rapidement ternir lorsqu'il est exposé à l'air. Le praséodyme est utilisé en combinaison avec le néodyme pour créer de puissants aimants de terres rares, appelés aimants en néodyme, qui font partie intégrante de nombreuses technologies modernes, notamment les moteurs électriques, les écouteurs et les disques durs d'ordinateurs. Le praséodyme est également utilisé dans certains types de lasers, où ses propriétés contribuent à produire une lumière cohérente et intense. Ses composés sont utilisés pour colorer les verres et les émaux, ce qui donne une teinte jaune ou verte distincte. De plus, le praséodyme est envisagé pour une utilisation potentielle dans les matériaux de stockage d’hydrogène en raison de sa capacité à absorber et à libérer de l’hydrogène gazeux. Ses applications polyvalentes en magnétique, en optique et en science des matériaux soulignent son rôle dans le développement technologique dans diverses industries."},{"question":"En una de sus obras (poema épico en Skanderbeg) un tema subordinado fue Nikola Jurišić. Pregunta : ¿En una de sus obras (poema épico sobre Nikola Jurišić), Skanderbeg era un tema subordinado?.","answer":"La respuesta es falso. "},{"question":"Tohizo izao : 'Izay adala no ..... '","answer":"'Izay adala no toa an-drainy '"},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Suíça?","answer":"A capital da Suíça é Berna."},{"question":"inona no biby mampiavaka an'i Madagasikara?","answer":"Miavaka tokoa i  Madagasikara raha samy firenena afrikanina, ny \\"Maki\\" no biby mampiavaka an'i Madagasikara"},{"question":"Shade Okoya","answer":"Fọláṣadé Noimat Ọkọ́ya (bíi ni ọjọ́ kẹẹ̀ẹ́dọ́gbọ̀n, oṣù kẹrin ọdún 1977) jẹ́ aláàkóso fún ilé-iṣẹ́ Eleganza Group èyí tí okọ rẹ̀ gbé kalẹ̀.Wọ́n bí Folashade ní ọjọ́ kẹẹdọgbọn, oṣù kẹrin ọdún 1977 sí ìdílé Àlhájì Tajú àti Àlhájà Nimosat Adeleye sí ìlú Èkó. Ó jẹ́ Mùsùlùmí, ó sì wá láti Ìjẹ̀bú òde ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn. Ó gboyè nínú ìmò ìfowópámọ́ jáde ilé ẹ̀kọ́ Lagos State Polytechnic. Ó tẹ̀ síwájú sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ gíga tí University of Lagos níbi tí ó tí gboyè nínú ìmọ̀ Sociology.Folashade fẹ́ Razaq Okoya nígbà tí ó wà ní ọmọ ọdún mọ́kànlélógún, ní àkókò tí ọkọ rẹ̀ sì jẹ́ ọmọ ọdún mokandinlọ́gọ́ta. Ó tí bí ọmọ mẹ́rin. Folashade ní olùdásílẹ̀ ìdíje Folashade Okoya kids cup. Ní ọjọ́ kẹtàlélógún, oṣù kẹjọ ọdún 2014, ilé ẹ̀kọ́ gíga tí European American University fún ní ìwé ẹ̀rí nínú ìmò Business Management and Corporate Leadership. Ó gbà àmì Inspiring Executive Woman of the Year Award ní oṣù kẹjọ ọdún 2018."},{"question":"Dapọ Abiọdun gbe iṣuna ọdun 2021 kalẹ fawọn aṣofin","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ogun, Ọmọọba Dapọ Abiọdun ti gbe aba eto iṣuna ipinlẹ yii fọdun to n bọ lọ siwaju ile igbimọ aṣofin Ogun.Ọjọruu, ọjọ keji oṣu kejila yii lo gbe bọjẹẹti onibiliọnu ọ̀ọ́dúnrún le mọkandinlogoji (339bn) naa lọ sọdọ awọn igbimọ naa lati buwọ lu.Akọle ti wọn fun bọjẹẹti naa ni ‘Budget of Recovery and Sustainability’, eyi ti itumọ rẹ jẹ iṣuna ti yoo da ikolo pada ti yoo si gbe awọn eto to wa nilẹ ro.Ọgọrun-un kan ati mẹtadinlọgọrin (177bn) nijọba ya sọtọ fun awọn iṣẹ olowo nla ti yoo da wọle. Biliọnu ọgọrun-un kan le mejilelọgọta (162bn) ni wọn yoo si naa lori awọn owo iṣẹ tawọn eeyan ba ṣe funjọba.Biliọnu mọkanlelọgọta(61bn)  ni yoo ba eto amayedẹrun lọ, awọn eto bii ilera, ile gbigbe, aato ilu ati ayika pẹlu ọrọ awọn obinrin yoo si jẹ biliọnu mẹtadinlọgọrun-un (93bn).Gẹgẹ bi Gomina Abiọdun ṣe wi, biliọnu mejidinlọgọta (58bn) nijọba yoo na lori eto ẹkọ lọdun to n bọ."},{"question":"What was the name of the Franco-British supersonic commercial plane that operated from 1976–2003?","answer":"The Concorde was the Franco-British supersonic commercial plane that operated from 1976–2003. Built in the 1960s as part of a joint venture between the United Kingdom and France, the Concorde was the first commercial aircraft of its kind. Only 14 Concorde aircraft went into service before it was retired by both countries in 2003."},{"question":"Wat zijn AirPods?","answer":"AirPods zijn een in-ear koptelefoonproduct dat gemaakt en verkocht wordt door Apple. "},{"question":"महाराणी ताराबाई व छत्रपती शाहू यांच्यामध्ये 23 वर्ष चाललेल्या संघर्षाला काय म्हणतात ?","answer":"महाराणी ताराबाई व छत्रपती शाहू यांच्यामध्ये 23 वर्ष चाललेल्या संघर्षाला यादवी युध्द म्हणतात."},{"question":"Ала жипти аттабаган.","answer":"Бирөөгө кара санабаган, жамандык ишке барбаган, бирөөнүн бир нерсесин албаган, арамдык кылбаган."},{"question":"Nhà thơ Xuân Quỳnh là ai?","answer":"Xuân Quỳnh tên thật là Nguyễn Thị Xuân Quỳnh, sinh năm 1942 tại thị xã Hà Đông, tỉnh Hà Tây (nay là quận Hà Đông, Hà Nội). Bà xuất thân trong gia đình công chức, mẹ mất sớm, bố thường xuyên công tác xa nên được bà nội nuôi dạy từ nhỏ.Tháng 2/1955, Xuân Quỳnh vào Đoàn văn công Trung ương và được đào tạo thành diễn viên múa. Bà đã nhiều lần đi biểu diễn ở nước ngoài. Năm 20 tuổi, Xuân Quỳnh bắt đầu học Trường bồi dưỡng những người viết văn trẻ của Hội Nhà văn Việt Nam. Học xong, bà làm việc tại báo Văn nghệ, báo Phụ nữ Việt Nam.Xuân Quỳnh kết hôn lần thứ hai với nhà viết kịch, nhà thơ Lưu Quang Vũ năm 1973. Họ mất trong trong một tai nạn giao thông ở Hải Dương cuối tháng 8/1988.Trong suốt sự nghiệp, Xuân Quỳnh xuất bản nhiều tập thơ như Chồi biếc (1963); Hoa dọc chiến hào (thơ, in chung, 1968); Gió Lào, cát trắng (1974); Lời ru trên mặt đất (1978); Sân ga chiều em đi (1984); Tự hát (1984) và một số tập thơ khác được in sau khi bà qua đời.Nhà thơ Xuân Quỳnh được truy tặng giải thưởng Nhà nước về Văn học nghệ thuật năm 2001, giải thưởng Hồ Chí Minh về văn học nghệ thuật năm 2017."},{"question":"'Eshu! Ngafa mina kababa!' ezikhalela ngaphansi uChule. 'Ngilekelele Daffo!'UDaffo wayemxwayisa ngemuva kwendaba uJamu owathi uyasukuma, laliduma lidlaumunge nomtholo. Zangquzulana izimoto, isinqe sikaChule simhlanganisa nekhalalemoto yabo. Zampaqaza isifuba nezimbambo, wavela ngekhanda kuphela phakathikwekhala nesinqe.'Ngafa! Ngisize sho ...! Gudluza imoto!''KaMazibuko! Nomvula mntakwethu! Ngilekelele mkami! Ngafa sithandwa!' ebubulangaphansi kwemoto uNkosiyaphakade.UNomvula wamuzwa, wabuza edidekile wathi, 'Ngenzenjani Chule njengoba nonkenifuna ukungibulala nje?' Wavula ifasitela walunguza, walibona igazi ligeleza nomyeniejanduza ngaphansi kwemoto. Wavula isivalo waphuma endiza ethi, 'Phuma Chule!Kodwa Nkosi yami ngizothini ezweni?1. Phawula ngempumelelo yombhali ekuphetheni le ndaba. ","answer":"Le ndaba iphetha ngopholavuthondaba ngoba kuba nokuxolelananokubuyisana. UNomvula ushada noGenyeza bathenga umuzi omkhulueThusini. Abenzi bobubi bayajeza, uChule uyafa, uDaffo uyagwetshwangesenzo sokuzama ukubulala uNomvula."},{"question":"女性漫画家で初のコミックス100巻到達を果たし、同時に最終巻となった（その後2016年に続編コミックス発売）室山まゆみ原作の長寿まんがは何ちゃんでしょう?","answer":"あさりちゃんです。"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:వ. ‘ఇట్టి లోకవిరుద్ధంబుల కే మూడుదు, మయుక్తంబు లయిన పలుకులు పలుకక నీయాశ్రమంబునకుం బొమ్మనిన శమంతల యత్యంత సంతా వికాంఈ కరణమై.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :ఇట్టి = ఇటువంటిఇటువంటి లోక విరుద్దంబులకున్ . : వాస్తవానికి వ్యతిరేకంగా ఉండేవాటికిఏము = మేముఓడుదుము = భయపడతాం / అంగీకరించంఅయుక్తంబులు + అయిన = తగనివి అయినపలుకులు = మాటలుపలుకక = మాట్లాడకనీ ఆశ్రమంబునకున్ = నీ ఆశ్రమానికిపొమ్ము + అనినన్ = తిరిగి వెళ్ళిపో అని చెప్పగాశకుంతల = శకుంతలఅతి + అంత = మిక్కిలిసంతాపిత + అంతఃకణ + ఐ = తపింపబడిన హృదయం కలిగినదైతాత్పర్యం :ఇటువంటి లోక విరుద్ధమైన అంశాలను మేం అంగీకరించం. తగని మాటలు మాట్లాడకుండా నువ్వు నీ ఆశ్రమానికి తిరిగి వెళ్ళిపో, అని దుష్యంతుడు చెప్పగా శకుంతల మనస్సులో -మిక్కిలి సంతాపాన్ని పొందినదని తాత్పర్యం."},{"question":"Suaal: Foomalka loo helo degaanka saddex jarrasaad waa sidee?","answer":"Jawaab: Foomalka loo helo degaanka saddex jarrasaad waa A = (1/2)bh, halka b ay tahay xiridda jarrasaadka iyo h ay tahay dhererka ugu sareeya"},{"question":"පැන්ඩෝරා  පත්‍රිකා  හෙළිදරව් කළේ කුමන සංවිධානය මඟින්ද ?","answer":"ගවේෂණාත්මක පුවත් සඳහා  සහයෝගීව කටයුතු කරන ගවේෂණාත්මක මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ගේ ගෝලීය ජාලයක් වන \\"ජාත්‍යන්තර ගවේෂණාත්මක මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ගේ සංගමය\\" (ICIJ: International Consortium of Investigative Journalists) විසින් පැන්ඩෝරා  පත්‍රිකා  හෙළිදරව් කරන ලදී."},{"question":"\\"දාර්ශනිකයෝ\\" යන පදය අයත් තද්ධිතය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"'ඉක 'ප්‍රත්‍යදර්ශන + ඉක + ඕ --- ' ඒ පිළිබඳ දන්නා ' යන අර්ථය"},{"question":"Atsakykite į šį klausimą. Persijos įlankos srovė yra greičiausia pasaulyje vandenynų srovė, kuri teka šito vandens telkinio vakarinėje pusėje. Koks tai vandens telkinys?","answer":"Atlanto vandenynas"},{"question":"வினா:அன்றாட வாழ்வில் நீ காணும் ஒளியின் நேர்க்கோட்டு பண்பு நிகழ்வுகள் இரண்டினை கூறுக.","answer":"விடை:மரங்களின் கிளைகளின் வழியே சூரிய ஒளி நேராக செல்லுதல்பைஞ்சுதைக் கலவை கிரிலின், சிறு துளைகளின் வழியே சூரிய ஒளி நேராக செல்லுதல்.கிளர்கதிர் மற்றும் மின்விளக்கின் ஒளி நேராக செல்லுதல்"},{"question":"เหตุการณ์สำคัญที่เกี่ยวข้องกับข้อความนี้คืออะไร: สรุปเหรียญพาราลิมปิกฤดูร้อน 2012 เป็นรายชื่อของจำนวนเหรียญประเภทต่าง ๆ ที่ชาติต่าง ๆ ที่เข้าร่วมโอลิมปิกชนะระหว่างการแข่งขันพาราลิมปิกฤดูร้อน 2012 ณ กรุงลอนดอน สหราชอาณาจักร ตั้งแต่ 29 สิงหาคม ถึง 9 กันยายน พ.ศ. 2555 นักกีฬาเข้าร่วมการแข่งขันทั้งหมด 4,302 คนจาก 164 ประเทศ ในการแข่งขัน 503 รายการใน 20 ชนิดกีฬา","answer":"พาราลิมปิกฤดูร้อน 2012"},{"question":"සාහිත්‍යය සඳහාවූ නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය මෙවර දිනාගත් ඇමෙරිකානු ජාතික කිවිඳිය කවුද ?","answer":"සාහිත්‍යය සඳහාවූ නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය මෙවර දිනාගත් ඇමෙරිකානු ජාතික කිවිඳිය ලුවිස් ග්ලූක්  (Louise Glück) ය."},{"question":"¿Qué es y en que consiste el aprendizaje por refuerzo?","answer":"El aprendizaje por refuerzo o aprendizaje reforzado (en inglés: reinforcement learning) es un área del aprendizaje automático (AA) inspirada en la psicología conductista, cuya ocupación es determinar qué acciones debe escoger un agente de software en un entorno dado con el fin de maximizar alguna noción de \\"recompensa\\" o premio acumulado. Si bien se ha usado principalmente para resolver tareas en robótica y juegos, se ha vuelto popular a la hora de entrenar modelos del lenguaje ya que, dada la calificación de una persona, el modelo puede ser optimizado para generar mejores respuestas "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸ੍ਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਭਗਤ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀਉ ਕਾ ॥ਅਚਰਜ ਏਕੁ ਸੁਨਹੁ ਰੇ ਪੰਡੀਆ ਅਬ ਕਿਛੁ ਕਹਨੁ ਨ ਜਾਈ ॥ਸੁਰਿ ਨਰ ਗਣ ਗੰਧ੍ਰਬ ਜਿਨਿ ਮੋਹੇ ਤ੍ਰਿਭਵਣ ਮੇਖੁਲੀ ਲਾਈ ॥੧॥ਰਾਜਾ ਰਾਮ ਅਨਹਦ ਕਿੰਗੁਰੀ ਬਾਜੈ ॥ਜਾ ਕੀ ਦਿਸਟਿ ਨਾਦ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਗੈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਭਾਠੀ ਗਗਨੁ ਸਿੰਙਿਆ ਅਰੁ ਚੁੰਙਿਆ ਕਨਕ ਕਲਸ ਇਕੁ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਮਹਿ ਧਾਰ ਚੁਐ ਅਤਿ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਰਸ ਮਹਿ ਰਸਨ ਚੁਆਇਆ ॥੨॥ਏਕ ਜੁ ਬਾਤ ਅਨੂਪ ਬਨੀ ਹੈ ਪਵਨ ਪਿਆਲਾ ਸਾਜਿਆ ॥ਤੀਨਿ ਭਵਨ ਮਹਿ ਏਕੋ ਜੋਗੀ ਕਹਹੁ ਕਵਨੁ ਹੈ ਰਾਜਾ ॥੩॥ਐਸੇ ਗਿਆਨ ਪ੍ਰਗਟਿਆ ਪੁਰਖੋਤਮ ਕਹੁ ਕਬੀਰ ਰੰਗਿ ਰਾਤਾ ॥ਅਉਰ ਦੁਨੀ ਸਭ ਭਰਮਿ ਭੁਲਾਨੀ ਮਨੁ ਰਾਮ ਰਸਾਇਨ ਮਾਤਾ ॥੪॥੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 92 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਭਗਤ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਪੰਡਤ ! ਉਸ ਅਚਰਜ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਇਕ ਕੌਤਕ ਸੁਣੋ (ਜੋ ਮੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਜੋ) ਐਸ ਵੇਲੇ (ਜਿਉਂ ਕਾ ਤਿਉਂ) ਕਿਹਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਨੂੰ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ) ਤੜਾਗੀ ਪਾ ਕੇ ਦੇਵਤੇ, ਮਨੁੱਖ , ਗਣ ਅਤੇ ਗੰਧਰਬਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੋਹ ਲਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।੧। ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ (ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਇੱਕ-ਰਸ ਤਾਰ ਵੱਜ ਰਹੀ ਹੈਉਹ ਅਚਰਜ ਕੌਤਕ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਜਿਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼-ਰੂਪ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਾਲ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਲਿਵ ਲੱਗਦੀ ਹੈ, ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। ਮੇਰਾ ਦਿਮਾਗ਼ ਭੱਠੀ ਬਣਿਆ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ, (ਭਾਵ, ਸੁਰਤ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ); ਮੰਦੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ ਸੰਕੋਚ, ਮਾਨੋ, ਵਾਧੂ ਪਾਣੀ ਰੱਦ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਨਾਲ ਹੈ; ਗੁਣਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਗ੍ਰਹਿਣ ਕਰਨਾ, ਮਾਨੋ, (ਨਾਮ ਰੂਪ) ਸ਼ਰਾਬ ਕੱਢਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਨਾਲ ਹੈ; ਤੇ ਸ਼ੁੱਧ ਹਿਰਦਾ, ਮਾਨੋ, ਸੋਨੇ ਦਾ ਮੱਟ ਹੈ; ਹੁਣ ਮੈਂ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈਮੇਰੇ ਸ਼ੁੱਧ  ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ (ਨਾਮ- ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਦੀ) ਬੜੀ ਸਾਫ਼ ਧਾਰ ਚੋ ਚੋ ਕੇ ਪੈ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਸਭ ਰਸਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸੁਆਦਲਾ (ਨਾਮ) ਰਸ ਖਿੱਚਿਆ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।੨। ਇੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਸੁਆਦਲੀ ਗੱਲ ਬਣ ਪਈ ਹੈ (ਉਹ ਇਹ) ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਸੁਆਸਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਨਾਮ-ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਪੀਣ ਲਈ) ਪਿਆਲਾ ਬਣਾ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਮੈਂ ਸੁਆਸ ਸੁਆਸ ਜਪ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ)(ਇਸ ਸੁਆਸ ਸੁਆਸ ਜਪਣ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ) ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹੀ ਵਿਆਪਕ (ਦਿੱਸ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ) । ਦੱਸ, (ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ ! ਮੈਨੂੰ) ਉਸ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਹੋਰ ਕੌਣ ਵੱਡਾ (ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ) ਹੈ ? ।੩। (ਜਿਵੇਂ ਉੱਪਰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਹੈ) ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਪਛਾਣ (ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਪਰਗਟ ਹੋ ਪਈ ਹੈ । ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਤੇ ਹੋਏ, ਹੇ ਕਬੀਰ ! (ਹੁਣ) ਆਖ ਕਿਹੋਰ ਸਾਰਾ ਜਗਤ ਤਾਂ ਭੁਲੇਖੇ ਵਿਚ ਭੁੱਲਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ) ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਰਸਾਂ ਦੇ ਸੋਮੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਮਸਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।੪।੩।\\""},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه موضوعی صحبت می‌کند؟چند روزی است که لیونل مسی اعلام کرده که قصد خروج از بارسلونا را دارد. در ابتدا این خبر توسط برخی از منابع رد شد اما اکنون هیئت مدیره تیم بارسلونا خبر از برگزاری یک جلسه فوری داده و به طور رسمی اعلام کرده است که مسی قصد خروج از این تیم را دارد و او در پیش فصل جاری حضور نخواهد داشت. ","answer":"متن در مورد تصمیم لیونل مسی برای خروج از تیم فوتبال بارسلونا صحبت می‌کند. ابتدا برخی منابع این خبر را تکذیب کرده‌اند، ولی سپس هیئت مدیره بارسلونا این خبر را تایید و اعلام کرده‌اند که مسی در فصل آماده‌سازی تیم حضور نخواهد داشت."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Бардык пандалар өтө кичинекей төрөлүшөт, салмагы болгону 85 граммды түзөт. Алар жай өсүүчү сүт эмүүчүлөрдүн катарына кирет."},{"question":"Độ mặn của Biển Chết là bao nhiêu?","answer":"Nước Biển Chết cực kỳ mặn, với nồng độ muối tăng dần từ bề mặt xuống dưới, tạo ra hai khối nước khác nhau trong cùng một thời gian. Hồ có độ mặn 34,2%, khiến nơi đây trở thành một trong 10 vùng nước mặn nhất thế giới. Nó mặn hơn khoảng 9,6 lần so với nước biển và có mật độ muối là 1,24 kg/lít, giúp con người có thể nổi trên mặt nước. Tuy nhiên, vào cuối thế kỷ 19 và đầu thế kỷ 20, hồ không bị nhiễm mặn như bây giờ. Vào thế kỷ 19, độ mặn là khoảng 19%."},{"question":"De maneira concisa, defina a palavra \\"aprendizado\\".","answer":"Aprendizado significa adquirir conhecimento e habilidades por meio do estudo e da experiência."},{"question":"De Witt Wallace akatanga chii","answer":"De Witt Wallace akatanga Reader's Digest. Akatanga magazini iyi muna 1922 aine chinangwa chekupfupisa zvinyorwa kubva kwakasiyana-siyana kuti zvive nyore kugaya kune vaverengi."},{"question":"Completa la frase seguente:\\"Successivamente la divisione fu inviata a Budapest ... \\"","answer":"\\" ... (Operazione Frühlingserwachen), insieme ad altre sei divisioni delle Waffen-SS (la \\"Leibstandarte SS Adolf Hitler\\", la \\"Das Reich\\", la \\"Wiking\\", la \\"Hohenstaufen\\", la \\"Hitlerjugend\\" e la \\"Reichsführer SS\\"), per cercare di aprire un varco alle forze tedesche rimaste intrappolate nella città. Dopo aver lanciato un attacco nella zona dell'aeroporto, la divisione combatté duramente nel settore di Stuhlweißenburg, ma ormai le difese russe si erano fatte invalicabili, e le divisioni SS furono costrette a sospendere l'attacco.\\""},{"question":"බුදු දහමේ එන  කර්මාදි ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයන් ගෙන් උපදනා රූප ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"අවිනිර්භෝග රූප අට ය, පරිච්ඡේද රූපයය, ප්‍ර‍සාද රූප පස ය, ජීවිත රූපය ය, භාව රූප දෙක ය, හෘදය රූපය ය යන මේ රූපයෝ අටළොස් දෙන කර්මයෙන් උපදවන රූපයෝ ය.අවිනිර්භෝග රූප අට ය, පරිච්ඡේද රූපයය, ශබ්ද රූපය ය, විකාර රූප තුන ය, විඥප්ති රූප දෙක ය යන මේ රූපයෝ පසළොස් දෙන චිත්තයෙන් උපදවන රූපයෝ ය.අවිනිර්භෝග රූප අට ය, පරිච්ඡේද රූපයය, ශබ්ද රූපය ය, විකාර රූප තුන ය යන මේ රූප තෙළෙස සෘතුවෙන් උපදවන රූපයෝ ය.අවිනිර්භෝග රූප අට ය, පරිච්ඡේද රූපයය, විකාර රූප තුන ය යන මේ දොළොස් දෙන ආහාරයෙන් උපදවනු ලබන රූපයෝ ය.ඒකාන්ත වශයෙන් කියත හොත් පරිච්ඡේද රූපය යම් කිසි හේතුවකින් උපදනා රූපයක් නොවේ. කර්මාදියෙන් උපදනා රූප කලාප පිණ්ඩයන් තුළ ඒවා එකිනෙක වෙන් කරමින් පවත්නා වූ ආකාශ ධාතුව, පර්‍ය්‍යාය වශයෙන් ඒ ඒ රූප කොට්ඨාසයට ඇතුළත් කොට ගණන් ගන්නා බැවින් පරිච්ඡේද රූපය, හේතූන් ගෙන් හටගන්නා රූපයක් සැටියට දක්වනු ලැබේ.ලක්ෂණ රූපයෝ වනාහි පෘථිවි ධාත්වාදි රූපයන් ගේ ඉපදීම්, දිරීම්, බිඳීම් වූ ලක්ෂණයේ ය. ඒවායේ වෙන් වූ ඉපදීමක් නැත. ඉපදීමේ තවත් ඉපදීමක් ඇතය යි ගත හොත් කෙළවරක් නැති ඉපදීම් ඇති සේ ගන්නට සිදු වන්නේ ය. දිරීම් බිඳීම්වල ඉපදීමක් ඇතයයි ගැනීම ද නුසුදුසු ය. එබැවින් පෘථිවි ධාත්වාදීන්ගේ උත්පාදාදි ලක්ෂණ වූ ලක්ෂණ රූපයෝ කර්මාදි ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෙන් නො හට ගන්නා රූපයෝ යයි කියනු ලැබෙත්.තවත් ක්‍ර‍මයකින් ජාතිරූපය හෙවත් උපචය සන්තති දෙක කර්මාදි ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෙන් හටගන්නා බව ද කියනු ලැබේ. ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වනාහි ජනක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ය, උපස්ථම්භක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය, අනුපාලක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය යයි තෙවැදෑරුම් වේ. ජනක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය යනු යම්කිසි ධර්මයක් උපදවන ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ය. උපස්ථම්භක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය යනු යම්කිසි ධර්මයකට අනුබල දෙන යම්කිසි ධර්මයක් බලවත් කරන ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ය. අනුපාලක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය යනු යම්කිසි ධර්ම පරම්පරාවක් ආරක්ෂා කරන ප්‍රත්‍යය ය. ජනක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයාගේ ශක්තිය, ජනක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයා ගේ ආනුභාවය පැමිණෙන්නේ රූපයා ගේ උත්පාදක්ෂණයට ය. ස්ථිති භංග අවස්ථාවන්ට එය නො පැමිණේ. උපස්ථම්භක අනුපාලක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයන් ගේ ආනුභාවය ස්ථිතික්‍ෂණයට ද පැමිණේ. එක ම ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයක ආනුභාවයකුදු භංගක්ෂණයට නො පැමිණේ. උපචය සන්තති රූප දෙක පවත්නේ ජනක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයා ගේ ආනුභාවය රූපයට ලැබෙන අවස්ථාවෙහි ය. එබැවින් ඒ දෙක කර්මාදි රූපජනක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයන් ගෙන් හට ගන්නා රූප දෙකක් හැටියට ද සලකනු ලැබේ. තවද යම්කිසි ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයකින් හටගන්නා ධර්මයක හටගැනීම වන්නේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයා ගේ සමායෝගය ඇති කල්හි ය. ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යසමායෝගය නුවුවහොත් එතෙක් ඒ ධර්මයා ගේ ඉපදීමක් නො වේ. ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයන් ගේ සමායෝගයක් නො වූයේ ය කියා උපන් ධර්මයක දිරීම් බිඳීම් දෙක නො වන්නේ නො වේ. ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යාපේක්ෂාවක් නැතිව ම උපන් ධර්ම සියල්ල ම දිරීමට හා බිඳීමට පැමිණේ. එබැවින් ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ලද කල්හි ම ඇති වන, නො ලද හොත් ඇති නො වන, උපචය සන්තති රූප දෙක කර්මාදි ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයන් හටගන්නා රූප සැටියට ද, ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ලාභයක් නැතිව ම ඇති වන ජරතා අනිච්චතා රූප දෙක කර්මාදි ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෙන් නො හටගන්නා රූප සැටියට ද සලකනු ලැබේ. උපචය සන්තතීන් ද ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෙන් හටගන්නා රූප සැටියට ගන්නා කල්හි කර්මජ රූප විස්සක් ද, චිත්තජ රූප සතළොසක් ද, සෘතුජ රූප පසළොසක් ද, ආහාරජ රූප තුදුසක් ද වේ. ජරතා අනිච්චතා රූප දෙක කර්මාදි ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයන් ගෙන් හටන්නා රූපයන්ගේ දිරීම් බිඳීම් වන බැවින් පර්‍ය්‍යායයෙන් ඒ දෙක ද කර්‍මාදි ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයන්ගෙන් හටගන්නා රූප සැටියට ගණන් ගනු ලැබේ. ජරතා අනිච්චතා දෙක ද ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෙන් හටගන්නා රූප සැටියට ගන්නා කල්හි කර්මජ රූප දෙවිස්සක් ද චිත්තජ රූප එකුන් විස්සක් ද, සෘතුජ රූප සතළොසක් ද ආහාරජ රූප සොළොසෙක් ද වේ.මෙතෙකින් කියන ලදුයේ කර්මාදීන්ගේ ජනක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යතාවය ය. එක් කර්මයක් අන් ක්‍ර‍මයකින් හට ගන්නා වූ ද, චිත්තාදි ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයන් ගෙන් හටගන්නා වූ ද රූපයනට උපස්ථම්භන වශයෙන් හා අනුපාලන වශයෙන් ද ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වේ. බොහෝ සූත්‍ර‍ ධර්මයන්හි කර්මයේ උපස්ථම්භන ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යතාව හා අනුපාලන ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යතාව දක්වා තිබේ.“සුවණ්ණතා සුස්සරතා - සුසණ්ඨාන සුරූපතාආදිපච්ච පරිවාරෝ - සබ්බමෙතෙන ලබ්භති”යන නිධිකණ්ඩ සූත්‍රයෙහි එන මේ ගාථාවෙන් ශරීරයාගේ යහපත් පැහැය හා ශරීරාවයවයන් ගේ යහපත් බව ද, ශරීරයා ගේ ශෝභාව ද, මිහිරි කටහඬ ද කුශල කර්මයෙන් ලැබෙන බව දක්වා තිබේ. ශරීරයෙහි උස මහතට ඇති ඇසට පෙනෙන කොටස, සෘතුජ රූප සමූහය ය. ගාථාවෙහි දැක්වෙන පැහැය හා යහපත් බව ද ශෝභනත්වය ද ඇත්තේ ඒ සෘතුජ රූප සමූහයෙහි ය. සෘතුජ රූපයන්ට අයත් ඒ යහපත් බව කර්මයෙන් වන දෙයක් සැටියට දක්වන්නේ සෘතුජ රූප සමූහයට කුශල කර්මය උපස්ථම්භන වශයෙන් ප්‍ර‍ත්‍ය වන හෙයිනි. ගාථාවෙහි දැක්වෙන මිහිරි කටහඬ චිත්තජ රූපයෝ ය. කුශල කර්මයා ගේ උපස්ථම්භනයෙන් හා පාලනයෙන් මිහිරි හඬ ඇති වීමට බාධක වූ සෙම් ආදියෙන් තොර ව උගුර යහපත් වේ. එයින් කථා කිරීමේ දී ඇතිවන චිත්තජ ශක්තිය වූ හඬ මිහිරි වේ. ශරීර වර්ණාදිය චක්ෂුඃ ප්‍ර‍සාදාදිය සේ කර්මයෙන් ම ඇති කරවන රූප වශයෙන් ගෙන කාරණය අවුල් නො කර ගත යුතුය.“දීඝායුක සංවත්තනිකා එසා මානව පටිපදා යදිදං පාණාතිපාතං පහාය පාණාතිපාතා පටිවිරතො හොති” යනුවෙන් චූලකම්ම විභංග සූත්‍රයෙහි ප්‍රාණඝාතයෙන් වැළකීම වූ ශීලමය කුශලයෙන් දීර්ඝායුෂ්ක වන බව දක්වා තිබෙන්නේ ද කර්මයාගේ උපස්ථම්භක අනුපාලක භාවය සඳහා ය. ප්‍රාණඝාතයෙන් වැළකීම නමැති ශීලමය කුශලය කර්මාදි සතර හේතුවෙන් ම හටගන්නා වූ රූප පරම්පරාවට අනුබල දීම් වශයෙන් හා පාලනය කිරීම් වශයෙන් රූපසන්තතියි චිර කාලයක් පවත්වයි. එසේ නොව ප්‍රාණඝාත විරමන කුශලයෙන් ද දීර්ඝායුෂ්ක ශරීරයක් උපදවනු ලැබේ යයි ගත හොත් එය වරදවා ගැනීමෙකි.දෙවියනට පහළ වන වස්ත්‍රාභරණ විමානාදිය ද සෘතුජ රූපයෝ ම ය. ඒවා පහළවීමට කුශල කර්මය උපනිඃශ්‍ර‍ය වේ.කර්මාදි ප්‍රත්‍යය සතරෙන් ම හටගන්නා රූප කලාපයන්හි ඇත්තා වූ තේජෝ ධාතුව හෙවත් සෘතුව ස්ථිතියට පැමිණි කල්හි සෘතුජ අෂ්ටක කලාපයන් උපදවයි. කර්මජ කලාපයක ඇති තේජෝ ධාතුව ස්ථිතියට පැමිණි කල්හි එක් අෂ්ටක කලාපයක් උපදවයි. එහි තේජෝ ධාතුව ද ස්ථිතියට පැමිණ තවත් අෂ්ටක කලාපයක් උපදවයි. මෙසේ එක කර්මජ කලාපයක් නිසා පරම්පරා වශයෙන් සෘතුජ රූප සතරක් හෝ පසක් උපදී. චිත්තජ කලාපයක ඇති තේජෝ ධාතුව ස්ථිතියට පැමිණි කල්හි එක් අෂ්ටක කලාපයක් උපදවයි. එහි තේජෝ ධාතුව ද ස්ථිතියට පැමිණ තවත් අෂ්ටක කලාපයක් උපදවයි. මෙසේ එක් චිත්තජ රූපයක් නිසා සෘතුජ රූප පරම්පරා දෙකක් හෝ තුනක් ඇති වේ. මෙසේ ආහාරජ රූප කලාප සම්බන්ධයෙන් උපදනා සෘතුජ රූප පරම්පරාව කලාප දශයක් හෝ දොළොසක් වන්නේ ය. සෘතුවෙන් ම හටගන්නා රූපයන් හි ඇති තේජෝ ධාතුව නිසා පරම්පරා වශයෙන් බොහෝ රූප කලාප උපදී. ඒවායේ සංඛ්‍යා නියමයක් නැත."},{"question":"હોળી કયા કારણ થી અને કેમ ઉજવીએ છીએ?","answer":"હોળી સાથે પૌરાણીક કથાઓ સંકળાયેલી છે. વૈષ્ણવ માન્યતા અનુસાર, હિરણ્યકશ્યપ એ દાનવોનો રાજા હતો. અને તેમને બ્રહ્માજીનું વરદાન હતું કે તે 'દિવસે કે રાત્રે, ઘરની અંદર કે બહાર, ભુમિ પર કે આકાશમાં, માનવ દ્વારા કે પ્રાણી દ્વારા, અસ્ત્ર કે શસ્ત્ર દ્વારા કોઇપણથી તેનું મૃત્યુ થશે નહીં', આ વરદાનને કારણે તે લગભગ અમર બની ગયો કે તેને મારવો તે લગભગ અસંભવ થઇ ગયું. આથી તે અભિમાની અને અત્યાચારી બની ગયો, તથા સ્વર્ગ અને પૃથ્વી પર બધેજ હાહાકાર મચાવી દીધો. તેમણે ઇશ્વરને પૂજવાનું પણ બંધ કરાવ્યું અને પોતાની પૂજા કરાવવાનું શરૂ કર્યું.હોળી રમતાં રાધા કૃષ્ણ અને ગોપ-ગોપીઓઆ દરમિયાન, હિરણ્યકશ્યપનો પોતાનો દિકરો, પ્રહલાદ, જે ભગવાન વિષ્ણુનો ભક્ત હતો. તેને કંઇ કેટલાં પ્રલોભનો તથા બીક બતાવી તેમણે ઇશ્વર ભક્તિથી દુર કરવાના પ્રયત્નો કર્યા પરંતુ પ્રહલાદ ડગ્યો નહીં અને પોતાની ભક્તિ ચાલુ રાખી. તેણે પ્રહલાદને મારવા માટે પણ કંઇ કેટલા ઉપાય કર્યા, પરંતુ ઇશ્વરકૃપાથી તે દરેક નિષ્ફળ રહ્યા. અંતે પ્રહલાદને મારવાનાં ઉદ્દેશથી હિરણ્યકશ્યપે પ્રહલાદને, પોતાની બહેન હોળીકાનાં ખોળામાં બેસી, અગ્નિપરિક્ષા આપવાનો આદેશ આપ્યો. હોળીકા, કે જેની પાસે એક એવી ઓઢણી (સ્ત્રીઓ એ માથે ઓઢવાનું કાપડ) હતી કે જે તેને ધારણ કરે તેનાથી અગ્નિ પણ બાળી શકે નહીં. પ્રહલાદે પિતાની આજ્ઞાનું પાલન કર્યું અને વિષ્ણુને પોતાનો જીવ બચાવવા માટે પ્રાથના કરી. અંતે જ્યારે અગ્નિ પ્રગટાવવામાં આવ્યો ત્યારે પેલી ઓઢણી હોલિકાનાં માથા પરથી ઉડી અને પ્રહલાદને વીંટાઈ ગઈ, આથી હોળીકા અગ્નિમાં બળીને ભસ્મ થઇ અને પ્રહલાદ સાજો સારો બહાર આવ્યો. આમ હોળીકાનું દહન થયું તે ઘટના હોળી ઉત્સવનું કારણ બની.પછીથી ભગવાન વિષ્ણુ દ્વારા હિરણ્યકશ્યપના વધની કથા આવે છે, જેમાં વિષ્ણુએ નૃસિંહ અવતાર ધારણ કરી (જેમાં ભગવાનનું અડધું શરીર મનુષ્યનું અને અડધું સિંહનું છે) અને બરાબર સંધ્યા સમયે, ઘરનાં ઉંબરા વચ્ચે, પોતાનાં ખોળામાં પાડીને, પોતાનાં નખ દ્વારા ચીરી નાખી, હિરણ્યકશ્યપનો વધ કર્યો. આમ આસુરી શક્તિઓ પર દૈવી શક્તિઓના વિજયનું આ પર્વ છે.આ ઉપરાંત અન્ય કથાઓ પણ પ્રચલિત છે. જેમાં રાધા અને કૃષ્ણનાં દિવ્ય પ્રેમની કથા તથા શિવજી દ્વારા કામદહનની કથા પણ છે.હોળી બ્રહ્માંડમાં તેજનો તહેવાર પણ છે. આ તહેવાર દરમિયાન, બ્રહ્માંડમાં અલગ અલગ તેજકિરણો પ્રસરે છે, જે વાતાવરણમાં અલગ અલગ રંગો અને આભાઓ પ્રકાશિત કરે છે"},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk Biskut Coklat Chips Crunchy sebagai biskut raya? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan A : 1 cawan buttercup, 3/4 cawan gula perang, 1 biji telur, 1 sk esen vanillaBahan B 2 cawan tepung gandum, 1sk soda bikarbonat (Satukan tepung + soda bikarbonat, ayak terlebih dahulu), 1 cawan coklat chips, 1/2 cawan coklat riceCara Membuat Biskut Coklat Chips :1. Satukan kesemua bahan A dalam bekas. Pukul bagi sebati.2. Jika sudah sebati, masukkan tepung gandum yang telah diayak. Gaul sebati. (Adunan memang lembik, jangan tambah tepung pulak, nanti keras biskutnya, Kalau rasa lembik sangat, tambah 2 sb tepung)3. Bila tepung sudah sebati, masukkan coklat chips + coklat rice, gaul sebati.Kalau sudah siap, boleh sudukan adunan dalam tray, tak perlu sapu butter. (Guna sudu kecil saja, mahu cubit-cubit pon boleh.4. Buat kecil-kecil saja, nanti bila bakar dia akan kembang/leper.5. Bakar selama 20min-25min suhu 170’C, api atas bawah.6. Selepas bakar keluarkan tray, biasanya biskut tu dia akan nampak macam tak masak, kalau kita tekan dia macam lembik, biarkan dia sejuk dulu, baru biskut akan elok. Selamat mencuba."},{"question":"Awa nawa ake ɗauka don tafiya ta jirgin sama zuwa Berlin daga Faransa?\\t","answer":"Awa ɗaya da rabi"},{"question":"ద్రవ్యోల్బణ నివారణ చర్యలు గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"దీర్ఘకాలంలో సాధారణ ధరల స్థాయిలో నిరంతరమైన పెరుగుదలను ద్రవ్యోల్బణం అని అంటారు. పరిమిత ద్రవ్యోల్బణం ఆర్థికాభివృద్ధికి దోహదం చేస్తుంది. అతి ద్రవ్యోల్బణం ఆర్థికాభివృద్ధిని నిరోధిస్తుంది. ద్రవ్యోల్బణాన్ని నివారించడానికి ప్రభుత్వం అనేక చర్యలను చేపడుతుంది. అవి:1) ద్రవ్యపరమైన చర్యలు: ద్రవ్యపరమైన చర్యలు ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థలో ద్రవ్య సప్లయ్న క్రమబద్ధం చేస్తాయి. బ్యాంకులు పరపతిని క్రమబద్ధం చేయటం ద్వారా ద్రవ్య సప్లయిని నియంత్రణ చేయటం జరుగుతుంది. కేంద్ర బ్యాంకు పరిమాణాత్మక, గుణాత్మక పరపతి నియంత్రణ సాధనాల ద్వారా ద్రవ్యం సప్లయ్న నియంత్రణ చేయవచ్చు.2) కోశ విధానాలు: ద్రవ్యోల్బణ కాలంలో ప్రభుత్వం మిగులు బడ్జెట్ను ప్రవేశపెట్టడానికి పన్ను రేట్లను పెంచటం, కొత్తగా పన్నులను విధించడం మొదలగువాటిని కోశపరమైన చర్యలు అంటారు.3) ద్రవ్యేతర అంశాలు:a) ఉత్పత్తిని పెంచటం: వస్తుత్పత్తిని పెంచటం ద్వారా ద్రవ్యోల్బణాన్ని అరికట్టవచ్చు. ఉత్పత్తిని పెంచటానికి ఈ క్రింది చర్యలు చేపట్టాలి.ఉత్పాదక వనరులను సక్రమంగా కేటాయించడం.దేశీయంగా ఉన్న వస్తూ కొరతను దిగుమతుల ద్వారా ద్రవ్యోల్బణాన్ని అరికట్టవచ్చు.b) వేతనాలు: వేతనాల పెరుగుదలకు, వస్తు ధరల పెరుగుదలకు దగ్గర సంబంధం ఉంది. సక్రమమైన వేతన విధానాలను అమలు చేయాలి.c) రేషనింగ్: ద్రవ్యోల్బణాన్ని నివారించే ప్రత్యక్ష చర్య వస్తువు ధరలను అమలు చేయటం, అదుపులో ఉంచటం. చట్టబద్ధంగా ప్రతి వస్తువుకు గరిష్ఠ ధరను నియంత్రించి ఆ ధర కంటే ఎక్కువ ధరకు అమ్మకుండా చర్యలు తీసుకోవాలి.d) బ్లాక్ మార్కెటింగ్ను అరికట్టుట: అక్రమ వస్తు నిల్వలను అదుపు చేయుట ద్వారా వస్తువుల ధరలను అదుపు చేయవచ్చు. ప్రభుత్వ నియమ, నిబంధనలకు వ్యతిరేకంగా నిల్వచేసే వ్యాపారస్తులను కఠినంగా శిక్షించాలి."},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Một hình chữ nhật có chiều dài là 6 cm, chiều rộng là 5 cm. Biểu thức nào sau đây dùng để biểu thị chu vi của hình chữ nhật đó?a) 2 . 6 + 5 (cm).b) 2 . (6 + 5) (cm).","answer":"Biểu thức biểu thị chu vi của hình chữ nhật có chiều dài là 6 cm, chiều rộng là 5 cm là2 . (6 + 5) (cm)."},{"question":"පුරාණ දඹදිව \\"වංග දේශය\\" වර්තමානයේ හඳුන්වන නම කුමක්ද?","answer":"පුරාණ දඹදිව \\"වංග දේශය\\" වර්තමානයේ හඳුන්වන නම බෙංගාලයයි. තවද මෙ​හි කොටස​ක් බංග්ලාදේශයටද අයත්වේ."},{"question":"Chọn phát biểu Sai dưới đây:A. Nước cất (nước không lẫn tạp chất) luôn sôi ở 100 độ CB. Thêm ít muối vào nồi nước thì nhiệt độ sôi của nước tăng lênC. Nước trong nồi áp suất có thể sôi ở 140 độ C","answer":"Đáp án A. Nước cất (nước không lẫn tạp chất) luôn sôi ở 100 độ CGiải thích Điểm sôi là điểm nhiệt tại đó nhiệt độ và áp suất đủ để chất lỏng biến thành hơi. Thêm nhiệt hoặc giảm áp suất sẽ khiến biến đổi hơi do áp suất hơi của chất lỏng sẽ lớn hơn áp suất tác dụng lên chất lỏng. Điểm sôi được xác định bởi hai thuộc tính chính: nhiệt độ và áp suất.Nhiệt độ làm tăng áp suất hơi của chất lỏng hoặc tác dụng lực lên bề mặt nước khiến chất lỏng bay hơi. Áp suất xung quanh là áp suất tác động lên chất lỏng. Điểm sôi của chất lỏng đạt được khi áp suất hơi và áp suất xung quanh bằng nhau. Tại thời điểm đó, chất lỏng có thể được đun sôi bằng cách tăng nhiệt độ, giảm áp suất xung quanh.Ở điều kiện bình thường, áp suất không khí là 1 atm thì điểm sôi của nước là 100 độ C. Càng lên cao áp suất không khí càng giảm, các phân tử nước dễ bay hơi hơn. Trung bình cứ lên cao 1000 m thì nhiệt độ sôi của nước giảm ba độ, như vậy đỉnh núi Everest với độ cao khoảng 8.848 m thì nước sẽ sôi ở nhiệt độ khoảng 73,5 độ C. Vì vậy, nếu sử dụng nồi bình thường để nấu ăn trên núi thì thức ăn sẽ khó có thể chín.Nồi áp suất có hệ thống ngăn không cho hơi nước thoát ra ngoài. Nếu áp suất hơi nước bão hòa trong nồi duy trì ở mức khoảng 4 atm thì nhiệt độ sôi của nước có thể đạt 140 độ C.Khi đun nước, bỏ thêm một ít muối vào nồi có thể làm tăng nhiệt độ sôi của nước. Tùy vào lượng muối bỏ vào mà nhiệt độ sôi có thể tăng một vài độ."},{"question":"问题：气体的危险性如何？","answer":"回答：某些气体具有毒性、易燃或爆炸性质，使用和储存时需要谨慎，确保安全操作。"},{"question":"පහත  නාම පදයට අදාළ ස්ත්‍රී ලිංග නාම පාදක කුමක්ද?සාන්තුවරයා","answer":"සාන්තුවරිය "},{"question":"翻译下面的文言文：范仲淹二岁而孤，母贫无依，再适常山朱氏。既长，知其世家，感泣辞母，去之南都入学舍。昼夜苦学，五年未尝解衣就寝。或夜昏怠，辄以水沃面。往往饘粥不充，日昃始食，遂大通六经之旨，慨然有志于天下。常自诵曰：“当先天下之忧而忧，后天下之乐而乐。”","answer":"范仲淹二岁时死了父亲，母亲贫穷无依无靠，又嫁给常山姓朱的人。范仲淹长大以后知道了自己的身世，含泪告别母亲，离开去应天府的南都学舍读书。他白天、深夜都认真读书。五年里睡觉几乎都没有解开衣服，有时夜晚疲倦了，就用冷水洗脸。他常常是白天苦读，什么也不吃，直到太阳偏西才吃一点东西。就这样，他精通了六经的主旨，后来立下造福天下的志向。他常常自己吟诵说：“应当在天下人忧愁之前先忧愁，在天下人都享乐之后才享乐。”"},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر الطويل. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"لَئِن قَرَّبَ اللَهُ النَوى بَعدَ هَذِهِوَكانَ لِرَوحاتِ المَطيِّ بَلاغُشَغَلتُ بِكُنَّ النَفسَ عَن كُلِّ حاجَةٍوَهَيهاتَ مِن شُغلٍ بِكُنَّ فَراغُوَليسَ لِبَردِ الماءِ لَم تَشرَبي بِهِإِلى القَلبِ مِنّي يَأُمَيمَ مَساغُ"},{"question":"வினா : பண்டைய எகிப்தியரின் எழுத்து என்ன?","answer":"விடை :  ஹெய்ரோகிளிபிக்ஸ்"},{"question":"ما هو عدد مخارج الحروف","answer":"مخرجًا17"},{"question":"Roslyn ane makore 36 ekuberekwa, anorema 74 kg, akareba 165 cm, uye ane 35% mafuta emuviri. Baba vake vakarwara nechirwere chemoyo pazera ramakore makumi matanhatu nemasere uye mukoma wake akaita angioplasty pazera ramakore makumi mana. Vese vari kurarama uye vakagwinya. Makemikari eropa rake anoyera cholesterol yakazara pa195 mg% uye HDL cholesterol pa42 mg%. Kutsanya kwake shuga yeropa ndeye 105 mg%. Roslyn anongogara uye haana kuita chirongwa chekutsungirira kubva kukoreji. Funga nezvechirongwa chakakodzera chekudzidzisa maekisesaizi kubatsira Roslyn kuvandudza kusimba kwake kweC-R (cardiorespiratory). Iva nechokwadi chekuverenga chinongedzo chekuyerwa kwemoyo neRPE inoenderana.","answer":"Isu tinogona kunyora chirongwa chekurovedza muviri kuburikidza nelenzi yeFITT: frequency, kusimba, nguva, uye mhando. Zvenguva zhinji, isu tinofanirwa kuvavarira kwemazuva 3-5 pasvondo, nekukwirira kuri nani kuvandudzwa kweCR kusimba. Kana zviri zvekusimba, tinoda kuvavarira 60-90% HRR (kupora kwemoyo), chero kubva ku4-8 RPE (chiyero chekufungidzira kusimba). Sezvo Roslyn aine makore makumi matatu nematanhatu ekuzvarwa, kurova kwemoyo wake kwaakafanotaura kuri 184bpm, uye tinopihwa kuti RHR yake (kurova kwemoyo wekuzorora) i64bpm. Nekudaro, isu tirikuvavarira chinangwa chemoyo wepakati pe136 BPM kusvika 172 BPM. Kwenguva, nguva yacho inoenderana nekusimba, asi zvakanyanya, tinoda kuve tichishanda kunze kwemaminetsi makumi maviri uye kazhinji awa. Kana iri rudzi rwemaekisesaizi, tinogona kuongorora sarudzo dziripo uye dzinogoneka kuti Roslyn aite, uye tosarudza pakati pemaekisesaizi ekutakura uremu (sekufamba kana kumhanya) uye maekisesaizi asingaremi akadai sekushambira kana kukwasva. Chimwe chinhu chekufunga nezvacho ndechekuti Roslyn anongogara, uye angangoda kufambira mberi zvishoma nezvishoma kuita kurovedza muviri kwakanyanya. Muenzaniso wechirongwa chekudzidzisa maekisesaizi cheRoslyn ungatanga nekuita zvine mwero-kusimba aerobic chiitiko kwemaminitsi makumi matatu pazuva, katatu pasvondo (Muvhuro, Chitatu, neChishanu). Sezvo iye anowedzera kujaira kune nhanho yekurovedza muviri, isu tinoda kufambira mberi kune yakasimba maekisesaizi. Maererano naDavid P. Swain, kurovedza muviri kwakasimba kunogona kuguma ne \\"zvikomborero zvakawanda kupfuura kurovedza muviri kune mwero\\", izvo zvinosanganisira asi zvisingagumiri pakuvandudzika kukuru muhutano hweaerobic uye kuderedza kukuru kwechirwere chemwoyo. Saka, tinogona kuwedzera mamwe mazuva maviri ekurovedza muviri kwakasimba kwaRoslyn, sekumhanya kwemaminetsi makumi maviri neChipiri neChina. Chimwe chinhu chinokosha chokufunga nezvacho kukurudzira, kwatinogona kubatsira Roslyn kuti arambe achiita nokuchinja maekisesaizi ake kuti arambe achifarira. Semuyenzaniso, tinogona kushandura kumhanya nekuchovha bhasikoro, kana kukwira makomo."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Kepentingan Menerapkan Semangat Cinta akan Negara dalam Kalangan Rakyat.","answer":"Sejak negara kita menikmati arus kemerdekaan daripada penjajahan asing, pelbagai kemajuan yang telah dikecapi. Siapa sangka, negara yang terdiri daripada berbilang kaum mampu untuk mencapai kemerdekaan dan seterusnya melangkah maju ke hadapan bersaing dengan negara membangun yang lain. Namun begitu, kita acapkali tersentak dengan pelbagai permasalahan yang dicetuskan oleh masyarakat kita sendiri yang mempu mengganggu gugat kemakmuran negara kita. Oleh itu, sebagai warganegara yang cinta akan tanah air, kita seharusnya menyemai sifat patriotisme di dalam setiap peringkat umur masyarakat agar kemerdekaan yang dicapai tidak disia-siakan. Saya yakin rakyat Malaysia mengenali peribahasa rambut sama hitam tetapi hati masing-masing lain. Walaupun kita berbeza dari pelbagai sudut, dengan sifat toleransi dan keterbukaan, kita mampu menjadi negara yang bersatu padu dalam mencapai kemajuan sejagat. Mari kita bincangkan kepentingan menerapkan semangat cinta akan negara kepada nusa bangsa.Umum mengetahui, Malaysia mempunyai masyarakat majmuk yang terdiri daripada bangsa Melayu, Cina, India, Orang Asli dan pelbagai lagi golongan bumiputera yang berada di Sabah dan Sarawak. Pada tanggal 16 September 1963, Persekutuan Malaysia telah diisytiharkan oleh Tunku Abdul Rahman menjadi bukti penyatuan rakyat yang berbilang bangsa, kaum dan agama ini. Justeru itu, dalam mengekalkan keharmonian dan keamanan negara, semangat cinta akan negara mampu menjadi penyumbang perpaduan antara masyarakat tempatan. Dengan iltizam dan semangat yang dikongsi bersama iaitu memajukan negara dan memartabatkan masyarakat di persada anatarabangsa, ia dapat melahirkan sebuah negara yang berwibawa. Persis kata mutiara, bersatu teguh, bercerai roboh. Anggota masyarakat pada hari ini seharusnya bersikap inteligensia dan terbuka dalam meraikan perbezaan serta mencari kesatuan dalam setiap situasi yang dihadapi oleh kita. Janganlah kita bersikap seperti gajah berjuang sama gajah, palanduk mati di tengah-tengah. Nescaya perjuangan yang memecah-belahkan perpaduan akan merugikan kita.Di samping itu, semangat cinta akan negara juga dapat membentuk masyarakat yang berdaya saing. Konsep ini kita dapat lihat di negara-negara maju seperti Jepun dan Korea Selatan. Kita dapat lihat bahawa masyarakat di negara tersebut memartabatkan negara mereka dengan mengetengahkan elemen lokal atau tempatan dengan jayanya. Sebagai contoh penggunaan bahasa tempatan mereka dan pemerkasaan teknologi tempatan diberikan tumpuan yang lebih berbanding elemen asing. Misalnya, jenama automotif negara Jepun, Honda yang terkenal di seantero dunia dengan produk dan kemampuan mereka. Kita sebenarnya sudahpun mempunyai jenama yang berjaya diperingkat antarabangsa seperti Petronas tetapi kita perlu lebih banyak lagi jenama atau industri tempatan yang bersaing di peringkat antarabangsa. Berbekalkan semangat cinta akan negara, mungkin pada satu hari nanti jenama Proton akan menjadi salah satu jenama automotif yang terkenal di dunia. Ia bergantung kepada kehendak dan kemampuan tenaga professional tempatan sama ada untuk maju ke peringkat lebih tinggi atau kekal di takuk yang sama.Pada sudut pandang yang lain, semangat cinta akan negara adalah penting bagi mengekalkan tradisi dan budaya masyarakat tanah air kita. Dewasa ini, generasi muda kita lebih terdedah dan terpengaruh dengan anasir dari negara luar sehingga melupakan tradisi dan budaya yang kita miliki. Keunikan seni budaya tempatan semakin dilupakan dan pengamalnya mencari-cari pengganti yang akan mewarisi budaya atau tradisi tempatan ini. Jika tidak dijumpai maka, ia akan pupus dan hilang dek ditelan kealpaan masyarakat kita menghargai dan memelihara keunikan nenek dan moyang kita yang terdahulu. Kemodenan hari ini merupakan cabaran yang perlu kita tempuh tetapi ia tidak sepatutnya menjadi alasan untuk kita melupakan tradisi dan budaya kita. Bak kata pepatah Melayu, hidup dikandung adat, mati dikandung tanah. Mungkin generasi hari ini perlu menyelami budaya dan tradisi yang diamalkan oleh masyarakat terdahulu supaya muncul kembali perasaan atau semangat cinta akan negara.Semangat cinta akan negara juga penting supaya menjadi teladan kepada generasi akan datang dalam mengekalkan kemakmuran dan keamanan negara. Terdapat segelintir daripada masyarakat kita yang intelek dan menyambung pelajaran ke luar negara. Seterusnya mereka menetap di sana dan menjadi tenaga kerja professional di sana. Hal ini tidak menjadi isu yang besar tetapi alangkah baiknya jika kemampuan mereka dugunakan untuk manfaat masyarakat tempatan. Situasi ini perlu diberi perhatian oleh golongan pemimpin negara dan pembuat polisi dalam memastikan setiap ahli masyarakat kita mempunyai peluang dalam kerjaya serta pendidikan. Dengan mengutamakan dua agenda ini, negara kita pasti dapat menghasilkan tenaga kerja professional tempatan yang akan melonjakkan ekonomi dan status negara kita. Namun disebabkan kurangnya peluang dan lebih banyak manfaat yang ditawarkan di negara luar, maka ramai ahli masyarakat yang berkhidmat di negara asing. Sebagai pengajaran kepada generasi muda, pihak berwwajib harus mencari solusi terbaik dalam menerapkan semangat cinta akan negara kepada semua rakyat di negara ini dan tidak bersikap seperti kacang lupakan kulit.Konklusinya, pelbagai kepentingan yang dapat kita bincangkan terhadap topik semangat cinta akan negara. Perkara ini adalah mustahak dalam menjamin kebolehan sesebuah negara untuk duduk sama rendah dan berdiri sama tinggi dengan negara-negara lain. Janganlah kita bersikap terlalu meraikan kehadiran pelabur atau pendatang asing tanpa memastikan masyarakat di negara kita mendapat manfaat yang terbaik yang boleh diberikan oleh negara kita sendiri. Persis kata peribahasa Melayu, hujan emas di negeri orang, hujan batu di negeri sendiri, baik lagi di negeri sendiri. Oleh yang demikian, setiap di antara kita perlu memanifestasikan fikiran dalam mencari mekanisma terbaik untuk memajukan negara di samping mengangkat elemen-elemen tempatan yang dimiliki oleh kita. Kekitaan yang kita tunjukkan mampu menjadi ejen penyatuan masyarakat dunia yang kerap kali dicabar dengan perang saudara atau kuasa di mana pengakhirannya hanyalah merugikan tamadun manusia."},{"question":"Yintoni umgqakwe? Cacisa ngesiXhosa kwakilunye nangeSingesi.","answer":"NgesiXhosa: Ngumntana ozalwe ngphandle kwase-mtshatweni ngokunga ziwayo nangokunga fanelekanga.In english: A bastard of unknown parentage."},{"question":"Mahasalama ve ny fihinànana voankazo ? Valio eny na tsia.","answer":"Eny, mahasalama ny fihinànana voankazo satria misy otrik'aina natoraly."},{"question":"Macnaha Magac","answer":"Magac waaxa uu u taaganyahay dhir, dad, meel, walax, ama fikrad."},{"question":"பாரதியாரின் சுதந்திரப் பள்ளு பாடலை குறிப்பிடுக.","answer":"ஆடுவோமே - பள்ளுப் பாடுவோமேஆனந்த சுதந்திரம் அடைந்து விட்டோ மென்று.பார்ப்பானை ஐயரென்ற காலமும் போச்சே - வெள்ளைப்பரங்கியைத் துரையென்ற காலமும் போச்சே - பிச்சைஏற்பாரைப் பணிகின்ற காலமும் போச்சே - நம்மைஏய்ப்போருக் கேவல்செய்யும் காலமும் போச்சே.எங்கும் சுதந்திரம் என்பதே பேச்சு - நாம்எல்லோரும் சமமென்பது உறுதியாச்சுசங்கு கொண்டே வெற்றி ஊதுவோமே - இதைத்தரணிக்கெல் லாமெடுத்து ஓதுவோமே.எல்லோரும் ஒன்றென்னும் காலம் வந்ததே - பொய்யும்ஏமாற்றும் தொலைகின்ற காலம் வந்ததே - இனிநல்லோர் பெரியரென்னும் காலம் வந்ததே - கெட்டநயவஞ்சக் காரருக்கு நாசம் வந்ததே.உழவுக்கும் தொழிலுக்கும் வந்தனை செய்வோம் - வீணில்உண்டுகளித் திருப்போரை நிந்தனை செய்வோம்.விழலுக்கு நீர்பாய்ச்சி மாய மாட்டோ ம் - வெறும்வீணருக்கு உழைத்துடலம் ஓய மாட்டோ ம்.நாமிருக்கும் நாடு நமதுஎன்ப தறிந்தோம் - இதுநமக்கே உரிமையாம் என்ப தறிந்தோம் - இந்தப்பூமியில் எவர்க்கும்இனி அடிமை செய்யோம் - பரிபூரணனுக் கேயடிமை செய்து வாழ்வோம்."},{"question":"Àlìmájìrín","answer":"Àlìmájìrín jẹ́ ìlànà ikẹ́kọ̀ọ́ tí àwọn ará ilẹ̀ Hausa ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà ń lò láti kọ́ àwọn ọmọ wọn lẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ẹ̀sìn Islam. Wọ́n ṣe àfàyọ orúkọ ìlànà ikẹ́kọ̀ọ́ yí láti ara ọ̀rọ̀ Lárúbáwá \\"al-muhajirun\\" tí ó túmọ̀ sí \\"A rìn rìn-àjò\\".Wọ́n bẹ̀rẹ̀ ìlànà ìkẹ́kọ̀ọ́ yí ìlú Kanem Borno, níbi tí pupọ̀ nínú àwọn adarí wọn jẹ́ onímọ̀ nípa Alùkùránì tí ó jẹ́ ìwé mímọ́ ẹ̀sìn Islam. Lẹ́yìn ọgọ́rin mẹ́rin ọdún ó dìn mẹ́wá (700), tí wọ́n dá ìlú Sokoto sílẹ̀ ni wọ́n pọọ́n ní dandan láti máa lo ìlànà ìkẹ́kọ́ ẹ̀sìn Islam. Àwọn Ọba ilẹ̀ Sokoto àti Borno ni wọ́n wa ń ṣàkóso ẹ̀kọ́ Al-májìrín. Lásìkò yí, àwọn ọmọ akẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ma ń wa lọ́dọ̀ àwọn òbí wọn ni, tí àwọn ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ wọn gbogbo si wà ní ìtòsí ìletò wọn gbogbo. Àwọn olùbẹ̀wò aṣojú Ọba si ma wà ń ṣèbẹ̀wò, tí wọ́n si ń jábọ̀ fun Ọba. Àwọn ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ wọ̀nyí ni ó jẹ́ wípé owó àpò ìlú, òbí, ọrẹ àtinúwá (sadaqqah) , owó orí (Zakat) ni wọ́n fi ń tọ́jú ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ náà.Ní ọdún 1904, àyípadà dé bá ètò ẹ̀kọ́ Almájìrín nígbà tí àwọn Gẹ̀ẹ́sì fi agbára wọ ilẹ̀ Hausa tí wọ́nnsì fipá gbàjọba lọ́wọ́ àwọn Emir. Fífipá gbàjọba yí mú kí àwọn Gẹ́ẹ̀sì ó pa ọ̀pọ̀ nínú àwọn Emir, tí púpọ̀ wọ́n si pàdánù ìjọba ilẹ̀ wọn sí ọwọ́ àwọn Gẹ̀ẹ́sì, fúndí èyí ètò ẹ̀kọ́ àlìmájìrín kò ri ìtọ́jú to péye mọ́. Lẹ́yìn èyí, wọ́n dá Bókò sílẹ̀, tí ó túmọ̀ sí \\"ìmọ̀ ẹ̀kọ́ èdè Gẹ̀ẹ́sì\\". ÌjọbaGẹ̀ẹ́sì tuntun fòpin sí ìnáwó sí ètò ẹ̀kọ́ Almájìrín láti àpò ìjọba tí kò sì sí ìrànwọ́ kankan mọ́ fún ètò ẹ̀kọ́ àlìmájìrín mọ́. Èyí ni ó mú kí àwọn olùkọ́ àti akẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní gba bárà láti fi jẹun."},{"question":" Sheeg asxaabigii dhimashadiisa dartiis uu carshiga  la gil gishay ?","answer":"Saxaabigi dhimashadiisa carshiga la gilgishay waxa u ahaa Sacad Bin Mucaad"},{"question":"问：如何维持一段健康的恋情？","answer":"答：维持健康恋情需要诚实、沟通、尊重和理解。每个人都需要有自己的空间和时间，同时也要共享彼此的生活。"},{"question":"Escríbeme todos las indicaciones y precauciones que hay que tener cuando hay una tormenta eléctrica, considerando todos los escenarios posibles, por ejemplo, estar en una piscina, en el campo, salir de casa, etc...","answer":"Aquí tienes algunas indicaciones y precauciones generales que debes tener en cuenta durante una tormenta eléctrica en diferentes escenarios:En casa:1. Permanece en el interior de tu casa y evita usar dispositivos electrónicos conectados a la corriente.2. Evita el uso de teléfonos fijos con cable durante la tormenta.3. Mantén las ventanas cerradas y evita tocar superficies metálicas.4. Desenchufa los electrodomésticos y dispositivos electrónicos para prevenir daños por sobretensión.5. Evita el contacto con grifos y agua corriente, ya que la electricidad puede viajar a través de las tuberías.En la calle:1. Busca refugio en un edificio sólido o un vehículo cerrado tan pronto como escuches truenos.2. Evita refugiarte debajo de árboles altos, postes eléctricos y estructuras metálicas.3. Mantente alejado de cuerpos de agua, como piscinas, lagos y ríos.4. No utilices paraguas ni objetos metálicos largos.5. Mantén una distancia segura de otras personas para evitar el riesgo de una descarga lateral.En el campo o áreas abiertas:1. Busca refugio en un edificio o en un vehículo cerrado tan pronto como escuches truenos.2. Evita quedarte en áreas elevadas, colinas o campos abiertos.3. Si no hay refugio cercano, agáchate en posición de cuclillas manteniendo los pies juntos y las manos cubriendo las orejas.4. Mantén una distancia segura de árboles altos, postes eléctricos y objetos metálicos.Recuerda que durante una tormenta eléctrica, es importante priorizar tu seguridad. Mantén la calma, sigue las indicaciones anteriores y asegúrate de estar bien informado sobre cómo actuar en caso de emergencia."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai minyak dengan air\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang bermusuhan atau yang tidak sehaluan mustahil dapat dicampur jadi satu."},{"question":"په ادب او ډرامه کې د شکسپیر د ونډې اهمیت څه دی؟","answer":"ویلیم شیکسپیر، چې اکثرا په انګلیسي ادب کې ترټولو لوی ډرامه لیکونکی ګڼل کیږي، د ډرامې او ژبې په برخه کې دوامداره مرسته کړې. د هغه اثار، لکه \\"هېملېټ\\" او \\"رومیو او ژولیت\\" د انساني پېچلو احساساتو سپړل او د انګلیسي ادبیاتو او تیاتر په لاره کې اغېزمن پاتې کېدل."},{"question":"«Көпөлөк эффектиси» деген түшүнүк кандай?","answer":"Көпөлөк эффектиси – бул хаос теориясынын концепциясы, ал кичинекей өзгөрүүлөр чоң, күтүүсүз кесепеттерге алып келиши мүмкүн дегенди түшүндүрөт."},{"question":"వరి, వేరుశనగ, చెరకు","answer":"తలారివెట్టు గ్రామంలో అధికంగా పండే పంట ఏది?"},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, awọn meji ku nibi ti wọn ti n ṣewọde SARS l’Akurẹ","answer":"Iwọde SARS to n lọ lọwọ kaakiri awọn ilu nipinlẹ Ondo gbọna mi-in yọ l’Ọjọbọ, Tosidee, ọsẹ ta a wa yii, pẹlu bi meji ninu awọn olufẹhonu han ọhun ṣe ku sinu ijamba ọkọ to waye niwaju ile ijọba to wa  l’Alagbaka, niluu Akurẹ.AKEDE AGBAYE gbọ pe ọkọ Toyota Camry kan ti nọmba rẹ jẹ LND 778 GL to sọ ijanu rẹ nu lo ṣeesi kọlu awọn mejeeji ọhun lori ọkada ti wọn wa, ti wọn si ṣe bẹe ku loju ẹsẹ.Akurẹ ti i ṣe olu ilu ipinlẹ Ondo ati ilu Ondo, ni wọn kọkọ berẹ ifẹhonu han yii l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee.Aarọ kutukutu Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, lawọn to n ṣe iwọde naa tun ti ko ara wọn jọ si agbegbe Adegbenle, niwaju ileesẹ to n ri sọrọ aṣa ati iṣe l’Akurẹ, lati bẹrẹ ifẹhonu mi-in lakọtun.Oju ọna Fiwaṣaye si Ọja-ọba ti wọn di pa lasiko iwọde naa lo ṣokunfa bi awọn onimọto ati ọlọkada ṣe wa ọna mi-in gba, ọna onibeji to gba iwaju ile ijọba kọja si wa lara awọn ọna tawọn ọlọkọ wọnyi n gba ki wọn le raaye de ibi ti wọn n lọ lasiko.Wọn ni loju ẹsẹ ni wọn ti gbe oku awọn mejeeji lọ si mọsuari ileewosan ijọba to wa l’Akurẹ, nibi ti wọn wa ni gbogbo asiko ta a fi n kọ iroyin yii lọwọ."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe sakramentan' ny filaharana na ôrdinasiôna?","answer":"Ny sakramentan' ny filaharana na ôrdinasiôna dia fihetsika sy teny araka ny litorjia izay ampidirana ao amin' ny filaharan' ny mpanao ny asam-pisoronanana kristiana, izay ankalazain' ny eveka. Ahitana ôrdinasiôna koa ny ao amin' ny fiangonana anglikana sy ny fiangonana loterana nefa tsy mihevitra azy io ho sakramenta.Ao amin' ny fiangonana katôlika sy ôrtôdôksa dia ny eveka sy ny pretra ary ny diakra no afaka mandray ny sakramentan' ny filaharana.Amin' ny Katôlika, ny Filaharana dia sakramenta izay mahatonga ny fanirahana nankinin’ i Kristy tamin’ ireo apôstôliny hitohy ka ho ampiasaina ao amin’ ny Fiangonana mandra-pahatongan’ ny farandro: ny Filaharana izany no sakramentan’ ny andraiki-panompoana maha-apôstôly. Misy ambaratonga telo izy: ny maha-eveka, ny maha-pretra ary ny maha-diakra."},{"question":"ما الشئ الذي يقتلك اذا اكلت نصفه ويفيدك اذا اكلته كله؟","answer":"السمسم "},{"question":"Ọba Ogiyan ni ki Oyetọla yi orukọ ileewe ti Arẹgbẹṣọla fi sọri Wọle Ṣoyinka niluu Ejigbo pada","answer":"Ogiyan ti ilu Ejigbo, nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Ọba Ọmọwọnuọla Oyesọsin, ti ke si Gomina Gboyega Oyetọla lati ba wọn yi orukọ ileewe Wọle Ṣoyinka Government High School, pada si Akinjole Government Secondary School.Ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu kọkanla, ọdun 2015, ni Ọgbẹni Rauf Adesọji Arẹgbẹṣọla ṣi ileewe nla kan to fi miliọnu lọna ọtalelaaadọrin o din mẹwaa naira (#750m) kọ siluu Ejigbo, to si pe orukọ rẹ ni Wọle Ṣoyinka Government High School.Ṣugbọn lasiko ipade kan ti ọfiisi oludamọran pataki fun Gomina Oyetọla lori ibaṣepọ awọn araalu ṣe pẹlu awọn eeyan ilu Ejigbo ninu gbọngan ilu naa ni Ọba Oyesọsin ti sọ pe awọn fẹ kijọba yi orukọ naa pada si orukọ baba-nla awọn to tẹ ilu naa do, Akinjole.Kabiyesi ṣalaye pe yatọ si bi mimu ayipada ba orukọ naa yoo ṣe mu inu awọn eeyan ilu naa dun, o tun jẹ ọna lati bu ọla ati iyi fun awọn alalẹ ilu ọhun.Ogiyan fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe titi lae ni ilu Ejigbo yoo maa ranti Gomina Oyetọla fun ipa ribiribi to ti ko ninu idagbasoke ilu naa lẹnu iwọnba asiko to ti de ori aleefa.O ni “Aimọye awọn iṣẹ idagbasoke ni gomina ti ṣe ninu ilu wam eleyii to si ti mu ki aye tun gbẹdẹmukẹ si i fun awọn eeyan wa. Lara wọn ni oju-ọna ninu ilu yii to ti mu ki irinajo kaakiri rọrun fun wa.“Inira ti a la kọja latari irinajo laarin Ejigbo si Oṣogbo fọpọ ọdun ti dohun itan bayii. A ko le gbagbe atunṣe ileewosan General Hospital ati Primary Health Center wa, bẹẹ naa si ni atunṣe ileeṣẹ panapana ti ilu Ejigbo, to fi mọ atunṣe biriiji Sagan ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ.’’Oludamọran pataki fun gomina lori ọrọ ibaṣepọ awọn araalu, Ọgbẹni Ọlatunbọsun Oyintiloye, tẹnu mọ ọn pe eredi ipade tileeṣẹ naa n ṣe kaakiri ni lati mọ ẹdun ọkan awọn araalu, ati ki awọn araalu naa le nipa lori ọrọ idagbasoke ipinlẹ Ọṣun.O dupẹ lọwọ awọn araalu Ejigbo fun aduroti wọn fun iṣejọba Gomina Oyetọla, o si ṣeleri pe gbogbo ibeere wọn nijọba yoo gbe yẹwo."},{"question":"Berikan saya jawapan untuk soalan teka-teki ini: Kereta rosak perlu carinya.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah mekanik"},{"question":"what important event is this text about: Amerikan Bağımsızlık Savaşı'nın patlak vermesiyle, Dük bir saha komutanlığı umdu, ancak George reddetti. Bavyera Veraset Savaşı (1777-1779) sırasında Prusya Kralı II . Frederick'in güçlerinde hizmet etmek için bir talepte bulundu - George kabul etti, ancak Frederick'in kendisi teklifi reddetti. Daha sonra 1. Piyade Alayı'na geçti ve 18 Ekim 1793'te mareşal oldu. 1796'da Kuzey Bölgesi Komutanlığı Genel Subayı olarak , 1802'ye kadar elinde bulundurduğu bir komutanlığa devam etti.","answer":"Belirtilen bilgiler doğrultusunda bu olau “Bavyera Veraset Savaşı” olmalı."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: \\"Lãnh đạo Cơ quan Hàng không vũ trụ Mỹ (NASA) Bill Nelson chỉ trích Trung Quốc vì không cung cấp thông tin về quỹ đạo cụ thể của mảnh vỡ để xác định khu vực rơi xuống. Tên lửa Trường Chinh 5B được Trung Quốc phóng lên hôm 24.7, mang theo mô đun Vấn Thiên lên quỹ đạo để xây Trạm không gian Thiên Cung. Giới quan sát đã bày tỏ lo ngại về việc bộ phận chính của tên lửa nặng khoảng 22,5 tấn rơi tự do xuống trái đất.\\"","answer":"Nhiều mảnh vỡ nhỏ có thể bị cháy hết khi đi vào khí quyển nhưng những mảnh lớn vẫn có thể còn lại và gây nguy hiểm cho mặt đất. Trung Quốc nói vẫn theo dõi kỹ phần tên lửa rơi xuống và nhấn mạnh không gây nguy cơ cho cư dân trái đất."},{"question":"ایک دلچسپ The Wolf and the Kid پڑھیں اردو میں | Read an interesting The Wolf and the Kid In Urdu","answer":"ایک دلچسپ The Wolf and the Kid پڑھیں ۔ ایک بار ایک چھوٹا بچہ تھا جس کے بڑھتے ہوئے سینگوں نے اسے یہ سوچنے پر مجبور کیا کہ وہ ایک بڑا بلی بکرا ہے اور اپنی دیکھ بھال کرنے کے قابل ہے۔چنانچہ ایک شام جب بھیڑ چراگاہ سے گھر جانے لگا اور اس کی ماں نے پکارا تو بچے نے کوئی دھیان نہیں دیا اور نرم گھاس کو چھلنی کرتا رہا۔ تھوڑی دیر بعد جب اس نے سر اٹھایا تو گلہ جا چکا تھا۔وہ بالکل اکیلا تھا۔ سورج غروب ہو رہا تھا۔ لمبے لمبے سائے زمین پر رینگنے لگے۔ ایک ٹھنڈی سی ہوا ان کے ساتھ گھاس میں خوفناک آوازیں نکالتی ہوئی آئی۔ خوفناک بھیڑیا کے بارے میں سوچتے ہی بچہ کانپ گیا۔ اس کے بعد وہ اپنی ماں کے لیے بلکتے ہوئے میدان کے اوپر وحشیانہ انداز میں چلنے لگا۔ لیکن آدھے راستے پر نہیں، درختوں کے جھنڈ کے قریب، وہاں بھیڑیا تھا!بچہ جانتا تھا کہ اس کے لیے بہت کم امید ہے۔\\"براہ کرم مسٹر وولف،\\" اس نے کانپتے ہوئے کہا، \\"میں جانتا ہوں کہ آپ مجھے کھانے والے ہیں۔ لیکن پہلے براہ کرم مجھے ایک دھن لگائیں، کیونکہ میں جب تک ہو سکتا ہوں ناچنا اور خوش رہنا چاہتا ہوں۔بھیڑیا کو کھانے سے پہلے ایک چھوٹی سی موسیقی کا خیال پسند آیا، اس لیے اس نے ایک خوشگوار دھن بجائی اور بچہ چھلانگ لگا کر خوشی سے جھک گیا۔اس دوران ریوڑ آہستہ آہستہ گھر کی طرف بڑھ رہا تھا۔ اب بھی شام کی ہوا بھیڑیا کی پائپنگ بہت دور تک لے گئی۔ چرواہے کتوں نے ان کے کان نوچ لیے۔ انہوں نے اس گیت کو پہچان لیا جو بھیڑیا ایک دعوت سے پہلے گاتا ہے اور ایک لمحے میں وہ چراگاہ کی طرف دوڑ رہے تھے۔ بھیڑیا کا گانا اچانک ختم ہو گیا اور جب وہ کتوں کے ساتھ اپنی ایڑیوں پر بھاگ رہا تھا تو اس نے اپنے آپ کو ایک بیوقوف کہا کہ ایک بچے کو خوش کرنے کے لیے پائپر کا رخ موڑتا ہے، جب اسے اپنے قصاب کی تجارت میں پھنس جانا چاہیے تھا۔کسی چیز کو آپ کے مقصد سے ہٹانے نہ دیں۔"},{"question":" kuma ayuu ahaa hogaamiyihii daraa wiishta? ","answer":" Waxa uu ahaa sayid maxamed cabdule xasan. "},{"question":"චීටාට වඩා වේගවත් මාළුවෙක් නම් කරන්න ?","answer":"චීටා පෘථිවියේ වේගවත්ම සත්වයා නේද? හොඳයි, ඉක්මන් බළලා ගොඩබිම සිටින වේගවත්ම සත්වයා බව සත්‍යයකි, නමුත් ජලයේදී රුවල් මාළු ත්‍යාගය ලබා ගනී. විද්‍යාඥයන් ඇස්තමේන්තු කරන්නේ චීටා කෙනෙකුට දුවන්න පුළුවන් තරම් වේගයෙන් එය පැයට සැතපුම් 68 ක වේගයෙන් ජලයෙන් පැන යා හැකි බවයි!"},{"question":"නිලූක කරුණාරත්න යනු කවුද, ඔහුගේ බැඩ්මින්ටන් ක්‍රීඩාවේ ඔහු ලැබූ සුවිශේෂී ජයග්‍රහණ මොනවාද?","answer":"නිලූක කරුණාරත්න යනු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කීර්තිමත් බැඩ්මින්ටන් ක්‍රීඩකයෙකි, ඔහු වසර 17 ක් අඛණ්ඩව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික ශූරයා ලෙස කිරුළු දැරූ අතර ලෝක ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්වල 34 වැනි ස්ථානයට පත්විය. ඔහුගේ කීර්තිමත් වෘත්තීය ජීවිතයට ඔලිම්පික් තරග තුනක් සහ රන් පදක්කම් 9ක් සමඟින් ජාත්‍යන්තර ඉසව්වලින් පදක්කම් 21ක් ඇතුළත් වේ."},{"question":"ලොව ප්‍රථම එක්දින ශතකය සහ ළකුණ ලබාගත් ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"චාල්ස් බැනරිමන්"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en la categoría: geografía. ","answer":"¿Cuántas islas principales tiene Japón? La respuesta es cuatro. "},{"question":"Raha dinihina ity andinin-tsoratra ity :\\"Soa sy Vao dia mpinamana hatramin'ny sekoly ambaratonga faharoa, nizara traikefa tsy tambo isaina ary nifanohana tamin'ny fihoaram-pefy teo amin'ny fiainana. Tsy tapaka ny fatoran'izy ireo, porofon'ny tanjaky ny tena fisakaizana. Nankalaza ny fitsingerenan'ny andro nahaterahany izy ireo, niara-nihomehezana, ary samy namaoka ny ranomasony. Amin'izao fotoana izao, rehefa nijoro teo amin'ny sisin'ny olon-dehibe izy ireo, dia niatrika fanamby vaovao ny fisakaizan'izy ireo.\\" ary ny fehezanteny tanjona: \\"Nitodika tany amin’i Soa i Vao ary niteny hoe: ‘Na aiza na aiza hitondran’ny fiainana antsika, dia fantatro fa hitoetra ho mafy orina foana ny _-ntsika.\\" Vinavinao ny teny banga.","answer":"Ny teny banga teo dia fisakaiza."},{"question":"සෝවියට් සංගමය විසුරුවා හැරීම ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"1991 අගෝස්තු කුමන්ත්‍රණය -කුමන්ත්‍රණය දියත් කළ පිරිසට අවශ්‍ය වුනේ සොවියට් දේශය තුළ සිදු වෙමින් පැවති ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ නවතා දමා දැඩි මතදාරී පාලනයක් ආරම්භ කිරීමයි.නමුත් කුමන්ත්‍රණයේ ප්‍රතිඵලය වුනේ සොවියට් දේශය වේගයෙන් කඩා වැටීමයි..1985 බලයට පැමිණි මිහායිල් ගොර්බචොව් නව ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ඇරඹුවා නමුත් ඔහුට නිරන්තරයෙන් සොවියට් සාම්ප්‍රදායික කණ්ඩායම්වල අභියෝගයන්ට මුහුණ දීමට සිදු වුනා.මේ ආකාරයට පාලන තන්ත්‍රයේ බැමි ලිහිල්වත්ම ජනතාවගෙන් වැඩි දෙනෙක් නිදහස වෙනුවෙන් නැගී සිටියා.. මේ කාලය තුළ ජාතිවාදීන්ගේ වර්ධනයක් දක්නට ලැබුනා..1991 අගභාගය වන විට මෙම බල අරගලය යටතේ සොවියට් දේශය දරුණු ලෙස බිද වැටෙමින් තිබුනා.මේ කාලය වන විට බෝල්ට්ක් සමුහාණ්ඩු වු ලැත්වියාව,ලිතුවේනියාව,එස්තෝනියාව, මෝල්ඩෝවාව,ආර්මේනියාව සහ ජෝර්ජියාව යන ප්‍රාන්ත තමන්ට අවශ්‍ය පරිසි ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු ආරම්භ කලා.අනෙක් ප්‍රාන්ත නවය මිහායිල් ගොර්බචොව්ගේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණයන් සදහා සහය පලකර සිටියා.කුමන්ත්‍රණකරුවන් සිතුවේ මිහායි ගොර්බචොව් සේවයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වේ යැයි කියාය, සිදු වුනේ නොසිතූ දෙයකි මිහායිල් ගොර්බචොව් කුමන්ත්‍රණකරුවන්ට අවස්ථාවාදීන් ලෙස බැන වැදුණේය..කුමන්ත්‍රණය ටිකෙන් ටික වැඩි දියුණු විය.රාජකීය හමුදාව පවා අණ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන්නට විය,සති කිහිපයක් ගත වීමට පෙර මිහායිල් ගොර්බචොව් කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂයද තහනම් කරන ලදී.1995 දෙසැම්බර් 8 වෙනිදා ඉතිරි ප්‍රාන්තද විසිරැවා හරින ලදී.දෙසැම්බර් 25 මිහායිල් ගොර්බචොව් ජනාධිපතිධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් විය.රුසියාව ඇතුළු අනෙක් සියලු ප්‍රාන්ත රටවල් බවට පත්විය.සීතල ලෝක යුද්දය නිමා විය..සොවියට් දේශය විනාශ කළ මිහායිල් ගොර්බචොව් නම් වු නපුරැ අතකොලුවට ධනවාදී රටවල් වගකිව යුතුය.කෙසේ වෙතත් අද රුසියාව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයට හිස නමා ආචාර කරයි."},{"question":"Saan natagpuan ang pinakamalaking buwaya sa mundo?","answer":"Natagpuan si Lolong, ang pinakamalaking buwayang nahuli sa mundo, sa isang sapa sa bayan ng Bunawan sa Agusan del Sur. Nahuli siya noong Setyembre 3, 2011 sa tulong ng mahigit-kumulang 100 na katao at dinala sa Bunawan Ecopark and Wildlife Reservation Center. Kinilala bilang pinakamalaking buwaya si Lolong na may haba na 6.17 na metro ng Guinness Book of World Records noong Hunyo 2012."},{"question":"Agir en tant qu'intervieweur pour un poste de stagiaire en apprentissage automatique. Posez-moi une question et attendez ma réponse avant de poser la question suivante. Ne leur posez pas toutes les questions en même temps.","answer":"Bien evidemment ! Commençons par l'entretien :Question 1 : Pouvez-vous vous présenter brièvement ? Ensuite parlez-moi de votre expérience avec le machine learning et des projets sur lesquels vous avez travaillé dans ce domaine ?"},{"question":"හොට් ඩෝග් නිර්මාණය කළ බව කියන යුරෝපීය රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"ජර්මනියහොට් ඩෝග්, ෆ්‍රෑන්ක්ෆර්ටර්, වීනර් හෝ සොසේජස් ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ, බොහෝ විට ජර්මනිය සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වේ. ෆ්‍රැන්ක්ෆර්ට් නගරය ෆ්‍රෑන්ක්ෆර්ටර්ගේ උපන් ස්ථානය යැයි පවසන අතර \\"වීනර්\\" යන පදය ආරම්භ වන්නේ ඔස්ට්‍රියාවේ වියානා (ජර්මානු භාෂාවෙන් වයින්) වෙතින් ය. \\"හොට් ඩෝග්\\" ලෙස බොහෝ දෙනා සිතන බනිස් ගෙඩියක සොසේජස් පිරිනැමීමේ සංකල්පය 19 වන සියවසේ ජර්මානු සංක්‍රමණිකයන් විසින් එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ප්‍රචලිත කළ බව කියනු ලැබේ. කෙසේ වෙතත්, හොට් ඩෝග්ගේ නියම මූලාරම්භය මෙන්ම එය බනිස් ගෙඩියක සේවය කිරීමට මුලින් අදහස් කළේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න විවාදයට භාජනය වන අතර නිශ්චිතවම එක් රටකට හෝ පුද්ගලයෙකුට ආරෝපණය නොවේ."},{"question":"Que língua é falada no Brasil?","answer":"Português."},{"question":"Rongedza chimwe nechimwe chezvinotevera sechiratidziro cheterevhizheni kana bhaisikopo: The Wire, The Sopranos, Game of Thrones, Mad Men, Harry Potter, Westworld, Iron Man.","answer":"\\"The Wire chirongwa cheterevhizheni chakaburitswa paHBO.Iyo Sopranos iratidziro yeterevhizheni yakabuda paHBO.Mutambo weZvigaro zvoumambo iratidziro yeterevhizheni yakabuda paHBO.Mad Men chirongwa cheterevhizheni chakaburitswa paShowtime.Harry Potter firimu rakaburitswa neWarner Brothers Studios.Westworld chirongwa cheterevhizheni chakaburitswa paHBO.Iron Man ifirimu rakaburitswa neMarvel Studios."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਜਿਨੑਾ ਚਖਾਇਓਨੁ ਰਸੁ ਆਇਆ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਭਾਇ ॥ਸਚਾ ਵੇਪਰਵਾਹੁ ਹੈ ਤਿਸ ਨੋ ਤਿਲੁ ਨ ਤਮਾਇ ॥੧॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਸਚਾ ਵਰਸਦਾ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਾ ਮੁਖਿ ਪਾਇ ॥ਮਨੁ ਸਦਾ ਹਰੀਆਵਲਾ ਸਹਜੇ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਸਦਾ ਦੋਹਾਗਣੀ ਦਰਿ ਖੜੀਆ ਬਿਲਲਾਹਿ ॥ਜਿਨੑਾ ਪਿਰ ਕਾ ਸੁਆਦੁ ਨ ਆਇਓ ਜੋ ਧੁਰਿ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਸੋੁ ਕਮਾਹਿ ॥੨॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਬੀਜੇ ਸਚੁ ਜਮੈ ਸਚੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਾਪਾਰੁ ॥ਜੋ ਇਤੁ ਲਾਹੈ ਲਾਇਅਨੁ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੇਇ ਭੰਡਾਰ ॥੩॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਦਾ ਸੋਹਾਗਣੀ ਭੈ ਭਗਤਿ ਸੀਗਾਰਿ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਰਾਵਹਿ ਪਿਰੁ ਆਪਣਾ ਸਚੁ ਰਖਹਿ ਉਰ ਧਾਰਿ ॥੪॥ਜਿਨੑਾ ਪਿਰੁ ਰਾਵਿਆ ਆਪਣਾ ਤਿਨੑਾ ਵਿਟਹੁ ਬਲਿ ਜਾਉ ॥ਸਦਾ ਪਿਰ ਕੈ ਸੰਗਿ ਰਹਹਿ ਵਿਚਹੁ ਆਪੁ ਗਵਾਇ ॥੫॥ਤਨੁ ਮਨੁ ਸੀਤਲੁ ਮੁਖ ਉਜਲੇ ਪਿਰ ਕੈ ਭਾਇ ਪਿਆਰਿ ॥ਸੇਜ ਸੁਖਾਲੀ ਪਿਰੁ ਰਵੈ ਹਉਮੈ ਤ੍ਰਿਸਨਾ ਮਾਰਿ ॥੬॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਘਰਿ ਆਇਆ ਗੁਰ ਕੈ ਹੇਤਿ ਅਪਾਰਿ ॥ਵਰੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਸੋਹਾਗਣੀ ਕੇਵਲ ਏਕੁ ਮੁਰਾਰਿ ॥੭॥ਸਭੇ ਗੁਨਹ ਬਖਸਾਇ ਲਇਓਨੁ ਮੇਲੇ ਮੇਲਣਹਾਰਿ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਆਖਣੁ ਆਖੀਐ ਜੇ ਸੁਣਿ ਧਰੇ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥੮॥੧੨॥੩੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 428 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ) ਆਪ ਚਖਾਇਆਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਆ ਗਿਆ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਭੀ ਸਮਝ ਆ ਗਈ ਕਿ) ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਬੇ-ਮੁਥਾਜ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਰਤਾ ਭਰ ਭੀ (ਕਿਸੇ ਕਿਸਮ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ) ਲਾਲਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਤੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ (ਹਰ ਥਾਂ) ਵਰ੍ਹ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ । ਪਰ ਇਹ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਵਿਚ ਜੋ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾ ਗਾ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਸਦਾ ਖਿੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀਆਂ ਸਦਾ ਮੰਦ-ਭਾਗਣਾਂ ਰਹਿੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਖਲੋਤੀਆਂ (ਭੀ) ਵਿਲਕਦੀਆਂ ਹੀ ਹਨ । ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਦਾ ਕਦੇ ਸੁਆਦ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਇਆ ਉਹ ਉਹੀ ਮਨਮੁਖਤਾ ਵਾਲੇ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਰਹਿੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਧੁਰ ਦਰਗਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਤੇ ਲਿਖੇ ਪਏ ਹਨ ।੨।ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਦਾ ਕਦੇ ਸੁਆਦ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਇਆ ਉਹ ਉਹੀ ਮਨਮੁਖਤਾ ਵਾਲੇ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਰਹਿੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਧੁਰ ਦਰਗਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਤੇ ਲਿਖੇ ਪਏ ਹਨ ।੨।ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਲਾਭਵੰਦੇ ਕੰਮ ਵਿਚ ਲਾਇਆ ਹੈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੇ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਦੇ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀਆਂ ਸਦਾ ਚੰਗੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਆਪਣਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਬਣਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨਉਹ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦਾ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਮਾਣਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।੪।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਮੈਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਮਾਣਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਸਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜੀਆਂ ਰਹਿੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।੫।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਤੇ ਹਿਰਦਾ ਠੰਢਾ-ਠਾਰ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ (ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ) ਰੌਸ਼ਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਹਉਮੈ ਨੂੰ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਹਿਰਦਾ-ਸੇਜ ਸੁਖਦਾਈ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ (ਉਸ ਸੇਜ ਉਤੇ) ਸਦਾ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਅਪਾਰ ਮੇਹਰ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਜਿਸ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ-ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸੁਭਾਗਣ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਆਪਣੇ ਵਰਗਾ ਇਕ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਹੈ ।੭।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕੀਤੀ, ਉਸ ਨੇ (ਪਿਛਲੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਆਪਣੇ) ਸਾਰੇ ਪਾਪ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਵਾ ਲਏ, ਮੇਲਣ ਦੀ ਸਮਰੱਥਾ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾ ਲਿਆ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦਾ) ਬੋਲ ਹੀ ਬੋਲਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਣ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਸਾਡੇ ਨਾਲ) ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰੇ ।੮।੧੨।੩੪।\\""},{"question":"Cad iad na barráin is féidir leat a chur ar pizza? ","answer":"Is feidir leat fónaicí a chuir ar. Mar shampla peitrealanna buí, oinniúin, meisce, trátaí, olive, spinéas, srl.Tá an-tóir ar fheoil a chur ar pizza, mar shampla pioróiní, sicín, muiceoil, béic, sicín, srl.Nó is feidir lear mara a chuir ar, ar nós muiríní, ainseabóit, srl.Tagann seo caite ach ní a laghad luibheanna agus spíosraí: Oregano, basil, luibheanna piobar dearga, srl."},{"question":"اكتب سؤال عن العاب الفيديو مع الإجابة","answer":"كم عدد ألعاب ماريو كارت التي طورتها NDCube؟ 7"},{"question":"Magbigay ka ng isang Pilipinong kanta na ang tema ay tungkol sa Pasko.","answer":"Isa sa mga sikat na kanta tungkol sa Pasko ay ang \\"Ang Pasko ay Sumapit\\". Ang liriko niya ay ang susunod:Ang Pasko ay sumapitTayo ay mangagsiawitNg magagandang himigDahil sa Diyos ay pag-ibigNang si Kristo'y isilangMay tatlong haring nagsidalawAt ang bawat isaAy nagsipaghandog ng tanging alayBagong taon ay magbagong-buhayNang lumigaya ang ating bayanTayo'y magsikap upang makamtan natin ang kasaganahanTayo'y mangagsiawitHabang ang mundo'y tahimikAng araw ay sumapitSa sanggol na dulot ng langitTayo ay magmahalanAting sundin ang gintong aralAt magbuhat ngayon kahit hindi pasko ay magbigayanBagong taon ay magbagong-buhayNang lumigaya ang ating bayanTayo'y magsikap upang makamtan natin ang kasaganahanTayo'y mangagsiawitHabang ang mundo'y tahimikAng araw ay sumapitSa sanggol na dulot ng langitTayo ay magmahalanAting sundin ang gintong aralAt magbuhat ngayon kahit hindi pasko ay magbigayan"},{"question":"A mistura das cores vermelho e branco forma qual cor?","answer":"A mistura da cor vermelha com branco é igual a cor rosa."},{"question":"س192- في أي سنة هجرية توفي صلى الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"ج192- في السنة11 للهجرة"},{"question":"¿Cómo se llama la compañía que desarrolló el popular juego Baldur's Gate 3? ¿Me puedes dar un resumen de su historia? Ah, y también, ¿es cierto que es una compañía muy querida entre sus usuarios?","answer":"Se trata de Larian Studios, un equipo independiente de desarrollo de videojuegos belga con subsidiarias en Barcelona,  Dublín, Guilford, Kuala Lumpur y Quebec. El estudio fue fundado en 1996 por Swen Vincke, quien junto con su esposa es dueño del 70 por ciento de las acciones de la compañía.​ Este estudio se especializa en el desarrollo de juegos de rol, aunque anteriormente también desarrolló juegos educativos. Entre 1997 y 2013 sacó a la venta varios juegos, principalmente de rol con combate en tiempo real dentro de su saga original Divinity, con una entrega de estrategia en tiempo real en 2013. El estudio pasó por problemas financieros a comienzos de la década de 2010, por lo que optó por la financiación por mecenazgo en Kickstarter para desarrollar Divinity: Original Sin sin necesitar financiación externa. A diferencia de sus anteriores juegos, Divinity: Original Sin tuvo un sistema de combate por turnos y fue recibido muy bien por la crítica y el público. Vincke asegura que era el juego que quería desarrollar desde que fundó la compañía, pero que las presiones de financiadores externos lo llevaron a incluir un componente de acción similar al de la franquicia Diablo. En 2017, tras otra campaña de financiación en Kickstarter, sacan a la venta Divinity: Original Sin II, el cuál fue un éxito aún mayor, pues cosechó mejores críticas y vendió más de 7 millones de copias en PC, PlayStation 4, Xbox One y Nintendo Switch. El juego más exitoso de la compañía es Baldur's Gate 3, otro juego de rol por turnos que salió en 2023 para PC, macOS, PlayStation 5 y Xbox Series X/S. Baldur's Gate 3 no fue financiado mediante Kickstarter, pero la compañía utilizó el mecanismo de \\"acceso temprano\\" en las plataformas Steam y GOG para permitir a los jugadores interesados jugar parte del juego durante su desarrollo. Este es sin duda el juego más exitoso de la compañía hasta 2023, pues superó en tan solo unos meses las ventas totales de su anterior juego y se llevó la mayoría de premios al mejor juego del año de 2023, incluyendo eventos como The Game Awards y The Golden Joystick Awards, entre otros. Respecto a tu última pregunta, Larian tiene una buena reputación entre sus usuarios. Esto se debe no solo a la calidad de sus juegos, también tiene una política de desarrollo de contenidos descargables en la que prefieren no hacer a los compradores pagar por contenido adicional. En lugar de eso, suelen desarrollar versiones mejoradas de los juegos que desarrollan y dan acceso gratuito a estas a los jugadores que ya hubieran comprado la versión original. Este fue el caso, por ejemplo, con Divinity: Original Sin II, que recibió en 2018 una \\"edición definitiva\\" gratuita y con numerosas mejoras."},{"question":"问题：机器学习和深度学习有何区别？","answer":"答案：机器学习是一种基于数据的算法模型训练方法，而深度学习是机器学习的一种特定形式，使用多层神经网络进行模式识别和学习。"},{"question":"Какой металл является самым распространенным на Земле? A) ЗолотоB) СереброC) ЖелезоD) Медь","answer":"Правильный ответ: C) Железо. Железо - это один из наиболее распространенных металлов на Земле и широко используется в различных отраслях промышленности, включая строительство, производство автомобилей и многие другие. Его богатые рудные залежи находятся в разных частях мира, и железо служит основным строительным материалом для многих инфраструктурных проектов."},{"question":"Wat is het verschil tussen tennis en pickleball?","answer":"Het zijn vergelijkbare sporten. Ten eerste is de grootte van het pickleball-veld ongeveer de helft van de grootte van een tennisveld. Ten tweede wordt pickleball gespeeld met een bal die lijkt op een plastic bal. Ten derde wordt pickleball gespeeld met peddels in plaats van rackets. Ten slotte is het scoresysteem heel anders omdat je punten speelt die alleen gescoord kunnen worden wanneer jij of jouw team serveert."},{"question":"బొద్దింకలోని మూడు కోటరాలు పరిమాణంలో సమానంగా లేవు. ఎందుకు?","answer":"బొద్దింకలోని మూడు కోటరాలు పరిమాణంలో సమానంగా ఉండవు. వీటిలో మధ్య కోటరం పెద్దది. ఎందుకంటే దీనిలో చాలా అంతరాంగ అవయవాలు ఉంటాయి. పృష్ఠ, ఉదర కోటరాలు చిన్నవి. వీటిలో గుండె, నాడీదండం మాత్రమే ఉంటాయి."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸ੍ਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖੁ ਮੋਹਿ ਵਿਆਪਿਆ ਬੈਰਾਗੁ ਉਦਾਸੀ ਨ ਹੋਇ ॥ਸਬਦੁ ਨ ਚੀਨੈ ਸਦਾ ਦੁਖੁ ਹਰਿ ਦਰਗਹਿ ਪਤਿ ਖੋਇ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਖੋਈਐ ਨਾਮਿ ਰਤੇ ਸੁਖੁ ਹੋਇ ॥੧॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਅਹਿਨਿਸਿ ਪੂਰਿ ਰਹੀ ਨਿਤ ਆਸਾ ॥ਸਤਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਿ ਮੋਹੁ ਪਰਜਲੈ ਘਰ ਹੀ ਮਾਹਿ ਉਦਾਸਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਵੈ ਬਿਗਸੈ ਹਰਿ ਬੈਰਾਗੁ ਅਨੰਦੁ ॥ਅਹਿਨਿਸਿ ਭਗਤਿ ਕਰੇ ਦਿਨੁ ਰਾਤੀ ਹਉਮੈ ਮਾਰਿ ਨਿਚੰਦੁ ॥ਵਡੈ ਭਾਗਿ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਪਾਈ ਹਰਿ ਪਾਇਆ ਸਹਜਿ ਅਨੰਦੁ ॥੨॥ਸੋ ਸਾਧੂ ਬੈਰਾਗੀ ਸੋਈ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਸਾਏ ॥ਅੰਤਰਿ ਲਾਗਿ ਨ ਤਾਮਸੁ ਮੂਲੇ ਵਿਚਹੁ ਆਪੁ ਗਵਾਏ ॥ਨਾਮੁ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ਸਤਗੁਰੂ ਦਿਖਾਲਿਆ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਪੀਆ ਅਘਾਏ ॥੩॥ਜਿਨਿ ਕਿਨੈ ਪਾਇਆ ਸਾਧਸੰਗਤੀ ਪੂਰੈ ਭਾਗਿ ਬੈਰਾਗਿ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖ ਫਿਰਹਿ ਨ ਜਾਣਹਿ ਸਤਗੁਰੁ ਹਉਮੈ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਲਾਗਿ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸਬਦਿ ਰਤੇ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਰੰਗਾਏ ਬਿਨੁ ਭੈ ਕੇਹੀ ਲਾਗਿ ॥੪॥੮॥੪੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 29 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਨਾਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਲਗਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਨਾਹ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲੋਂ ਉਪਰਾਮਤਾਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਵਿਚਾਰਦਾ, (ਇਸ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ) ਸਦਾ ਦੁੱਖ (ਘੇਰੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ) ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਦਰਗਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਗਵਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦੱਸੇ ਰਾਹ ਤੇ ਤੁਰਿਆਂ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਜਾਈਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਸੁਖ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! (ਤੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਤਾਂ) ਦਿਨ ਰਾਤ ਸਦਾ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ) ਆਸ ਭਰੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ (ਹੇ ਮਨ !) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰ (ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ) ਮੋਹ ਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਸੜ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ) ਗ੍ਰਿਹਸਤ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿੰਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ (ਮਾਇਆ ਤੋਂ) ਉਪਰਾਮ ਹੋ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦੱਸੇ) ਕਰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ (ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਖਿੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਸੁਖ ਹੈਉਹ ਦਿਨ ਰਾਤ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਹਉਮੈ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਬੇ-ਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈਵੱਡੀ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਥੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ (ਟਿਕਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ) ਸੁਖ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਅਸਲ) ਸਾਧੂ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਬੈਰਾਗੀ ਹੈ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਵਸਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਾਲਖ ਕਦੇ ਭੀ ਅਸਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦੀ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਗਵਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ (ਉਸਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਹੀ) ਵਿਖਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਉਹ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਰੱਜ ਕੇ ਪੀਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਜਿਸ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੇ ਲੱਭਾ ਹੈ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਵੱਡੀ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਲੱਭਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦੇ (ਬਾਹਰ ਜੰਗਲਾਂ ਅਦਿਕ ਵਿਚ) ਤੁਰੇ ਫਿਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ (ਦੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ) ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਮਝਦੇ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਹਉਮੈ (ਦੀ ਮੈਲ) ਲੱਗੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਪਰ ਪਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਪੱਕਾ ਰੰਗ ਨਹੀਂ ਚੜ੍ਹਦਾ, ਤੇ ਨਾਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ) ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਪਾਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਦੀ ।੪।੮।੪੧।\\""},{"question":"બાંધણી વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"બાંધણીની કળા એ અત્યંત કુશળ પ્રક્રિયા છે. આ ટેકનીકમાં ફેબ્રિકને રંગવાનું સામેલ છે જેને ઘણા બિંદુઓ પર દોરડાથી ચુસ્ત રીતે બાંધવામાં આવે છે, આમ ચંદ્રકલા, બાવન બાગ, શિકારી વગેરે જેવી વિવિધ પેટર્ન ઉત્પન્ન થાય છે; કાપડને કઈ રીતે બાંધવામાં આવે છે તેના આધારે. બંધનમાં વપરાયેલ મુખ્ય રંગ પીળો, લાલ, વાદળી, લીલો અને કાળો છે. દરેક રંગ પરંપરાગત રીતે ચોક્કસ સાંસ્કૃતિક અર્થ સાથે જોડાયેલો છે. લાલ એ લગ્નનું પ્રતીક છે અને વિવાહિત સ્ત્રીઓની ધાર્મિક વિધિઓ સાથે જોડાયેલું છે, પીળો રંગ વસંતનો અર્થ છે અને તે ઋતુ અને બાળજન્મ બંને સાથે જોડાયેલો છે, કેસર એ વિશ્વના ત્યાગીનો રંગ છે અને યુદ્ધમાં પોતાનો જીવ આપવા માટે તૈયાર યોદ્ધાઓ સાથે જોડાય છે. અથવા સંસારિક જીવનનો ત્યાગ કરનારા યોગીઓ માટે, કાળો અને લાલ રંગનો ઉપયોગ શોક માટે થાય છે. [8]બાંધણી એ ટાઇ અને ડાઇ પ્રક્રિયા હોવાથી, ડાઇંગ હાથથી કરવામાં આવે છે અને તેથી બાંધણીમાં શ્રેષ્ઠ રંગો અને સંયોજનો શક્ય છે. રંગોની ટકાઉપણું અનુસાર પરંપરાગત રીતે બે પ્રકારના ડાઈંગને વર્ગીકૃત કરવામાં આવે છે - પક્કા, જેમાં રંગો સરળતાથી ઉતરતા નથી અને કાચા, જેમાં રંગો સરળતાથી ઝાંખા પડી જાય છે અથવા ધોવાઈ જાય છે. ઐતિહાસિક રીતે, કાચાની ટેકનિક વધુ પ્રાધાન્યવાળી હતી કારણ કે રંગોને ફરીથી અને ફરીથી તાજું કરી શકાય છે જ્યારે પુક્કા ટેકનિકને વૃદ્ધ લોકો માટે યોગ્ય માનવામાં આવતી હતી. ઉત્કૃષ્ટ અને સૌથી જટિલ પેટર્ન, પછી ભલે તે પુરુષોની પાઘડી હોય કે સ્ત્રીઓની ઓઢણીઓ માટે, હંમેશા કચ્છના રંગોમાં રંગવામાં આવતી હતી."},{"question":"સુનામી એટલે શું?","answer":"સુનામી એ પાણીના મોટા પ્રમાણમાં પાણીના વિસ્થાપનને કારણે પાણીના શરીરમાં તરંગોની શ્રેણી છે, સામાન્ય રીતે સમુદ્ર અથવા મોટા તળાવમાં.ભૂકંપ, જ્વાળામુખી વિસ્ફોટ અને પાણીની ઉપર અથવા નીચે પાણીની અંદરના વિસ્ફોટો બધામાં સુનામી ઉત્પન્ન કરવાની સંભાવના છે.સામાન્ય સમુદ્ર તરંગોથી વિપરીત, જે પવન અથવા ભરતી દ્વારા ઉત્પન્ન થાય છે, જે બદલામાં ચંદ્ર અને સૂર્યના ગુરુત્વાકર્ષણ ખેંચાણ દ્વારા ઉત્પન્ન થાય છે, એક સુનામી મોટી ઘટનામાંથી પાણીના વિસ્થાપન દ્વારા ઉત્પન્ન થાય છે."},{"question":"*إلى أي قوم أرسل سيدنا صالح ؟","answer":"قوم ثمود"},{"question":"A que categoría corresponde la siguiente pregunta : ¿Luke Skywalker fue un personaje de Star Trek?.","answer":"La categoría corresponde a películas. "},{"question":"பரம்பரை மரபணு சிறுநீரகக் கட்டி நோய் பற்றி விளக்கம் தருக.","answer":"இவ்வியாதியில் மரபணுக்களில் இருந்த கோளாறு காரணமாக சிறுநீரகத்தின் அமைப்பு மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி பாதிக்கப்பட்டு சிறுநீரகங்களில் பல நீர் நிரம்பிய கட்டிகள் உருவாகின்றன.  இவ்வியாதி உள்ளவர்கள் இக்குறையுள்ள மரபணுக்களோடுதான் பிறக்கின்றார்கள்.  இக்கட்டிகள் கருவாக இருக்கும் காலம் தொட்டு 40 வயது வரை எப்போது வேண்டுமானாலும் வெளியே தெரிய ஆரம்பிக்கலாம்.  பெரும்பாலும் 35 வயதிற்கு பின்பே தெரிய ஆரம்பிக்கின்றது. இவ்வியாதி உள்ளவர்களில் சிலருக்கு பிற்காலத்தில் சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு வரலாம். இவ்வியாதி பெரும்பாலும் முதன்முதலாக அவருக்கு மட்டுமே அவர் குடும்பத்தில் வரலாம். ஆனால் இவ்வியாதி உள்ளவரின் குழந்தைகளுக்கும் இவ்வியாதி வர அதிக வாய்ப்பு உண்டு.இந்த வியாதியை பொறுத்த வரை வரும் கட்டிகள் நீர் நிரம்பிய சாதாரண கட்டிகள்தான்.  பார்ப்பதற்கு ஒரு திராட்சை கொத்து போல தோன்றும்.  இரண்டு சிறுநீரகங்களையும் பாதிக்கும்.  சில சமயம் இக்கட்டிகளில் இரத்தக் கசிவு, கிருமித் தாக்குதல், கல் வளர்ச்சி ஆகியன உண்டாகலாம். அப்போது மட்டுமே இதனால் வலி காய்ச்சல் போன்ற கஷ்டங்கள் வரும். இன்னும் சிலருக்கு இக்கட்டிகள் படிப்படியாக வளர்ந்து நல்ல சிறுநீரக திசுக்களை அழுத்துவதால் சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு உண்டாகலாம். சிலருக்கு சிறுநீரகங்கள் பெரியதாக வீங்கி வயிறே பெரியதாகக் கூட தெரியலாம். இன்னும் சிலருக்கு இக்கட்டிகள் படிப்படியாக வளர்ந்து நல்ல சிறுநீரக திசுக்களை அழுத்துவதால் சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு உண்டாகலாம். சிலருக்கு சிறுநீரகங்கள் பெரியதாக வீங்கி வயிறே பெரியதாகக் கூட தெரியலாம்.இக்கட்டிகள் சீரகங்களை எவ்வாறு பாதிக்கின்றன?இக்கட்டிகள் வரக்கூடிய வாய்ப்பு உள்ளவர்களுக்கு 35 வயதிற்குள் வந்துவிடும். இக்கட்டிகள் வளர வளர அருகிலுள்ள நன்றாக வேலை செய்து கொண்டிருக்கும் சிறுநீரகத் திசுக்களை அழுத்துவதால் அவை அழிந்து விடுகின்றன. இதனால் படிப்படியாக சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு உண்டாகின்றது அப்படியும், இவ்வியாதி உள்ளவர்களில் 1/3 பேருக்கு 70 வயது வரை சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு ஆரம்பிக்காமல் இருக்கலாம்.  பெரும்பாலானவர்களுக்கு இக்கட்டிகள் சிறுநீரக இரத்தக் குழாய்களை அழுத்துவதால் உயர் இரத்த அழுத்தம் ஏற்படுகின்றது. மேலே சொல்லியிருந்தது போல சிலருக்கு இக்கட்டிகளில் இரத்தக் கசிவு, கிருமி தாக்குதல், கல் வளர்ச்சி போன்ற காரணங்களால் வலி, காய்ச்சல், வாந்தி போன்ற தொந்தரவுகள் உண்டாகலாம்.இதனால் சிலருக்கு (பிறக்கும் போதே இக்குறையுடன் பிறக்கின்றார் என்ற போதும்) பல வருடங்கள் கழித்தே கட்டிகள் தோன்றவும் பின்னர் வளரவும் ஆரம்பிக்கின்றன.இது பிறவிக் குறைபாடு என்றபோதும் பல வருடங்கள் கழித்தே இக்கட்டிகள் வருவது எதனால் என்று இன்னும் முழுமையாக தெரியவில்லை. அதனால் மரபணுக்களை பரிசோதிப்பதன் மூலம் இவ்வியாதி உள்ளதாக கட்டிகள் தோன்று முன்னரே கண்டு பிடித்தாலும் கட்டிகள் வராமல் தடுக்கவும் வந்த பின் வளராமல் தடுக்கவும் இன்னும் வைத்தியம் கண்டு பிடிக்கப்படவில்லை.அறிகுறிகள்  மற்றும் கண்டுபிடிக்கும் முறை:இவ்வியாதி உள்ள சிலருக்கு எந்த வகை தொந்தரவும் இருக்காது இவர்கள் வேறு காரணங்களுக்காக வயிற்று ஸ்கான் செய்த போது இந்த சிறுநீரக கட்டிகள் கண்டு பிடிக்கப்பட்டிருக்கலாம் அல்லது குடும்பத்தில் வேறு ஒருவருக்கு உதாரணமாக அப்பா, அம்மா, சகோதரர், சகோதரி ஆகியோருக்கு இருந்து தனக்கும் உள்ளதா என்று மருத்துவரின் அறிவுரையின் பேரில் ஸ்கான் செய்த போது கண்டு பிடிக்கப்பட்டிருக்கலாம்.  சிலருக்கு சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு வந்த பிறகு அதனுடைய தொந்தரவுகளால் இந்த வியாதி கண்டு பிடிக்கப்படலாம்.  வேறு சிலருக்கு உயர் இரத்த அழுத்தம் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டு அதன் காரணத்தை ஆராயும் போது இந்த வியாதி கண்டு பிடிக்கப்பட்டு இருக்கலாம். மிகச் சிலருக்கு ஏற்கனவே கூறியிருந்தது போல கட்டிகளில் இரத்தக்கசிவு, கிருமித்தாக்கம், கற்கள் இவற்றால் வரும் தொந்தரவுகள் முதலில் வெளியே தெரிய வரலாம்.  சிலருக்கு சிறுநீரகங்கள் உள்ள விலா எலும்பிற்கு கீழான பகுதியில் தொடர்ந்து ஒரு வித கனமான வலி இருக்கலாம். சிலருக்கு சிறுநீரில் இரத்தம் கலந்து அடிக்கடி வெளியேறலாம்.  இந்த வலி, சிறுநீரில் இரத்தம் ஆகியன பொதுவாக விட்டு விட்டு வரும். மேலும் இந்த வியாதி உள்ளவர்களுக்கு சிறுநீரக கட்டிகளில் மட்டும் இல்லாமல் சிறுநீரகத் தாரையிலும் கிருமிகள் வர வாய்ப்பு அதிகம். சிறுநீர் கழிக்கையில் எரிச்சல் வலி, காய்ச்சல் என்ற அறிகுறிகள் இதன் அடையாளங்கள். எனவே சிறுநீரக கட்டிகள் வியாதி இவ்வாறாக பல விதமாக கண்டு பிடிக்கப்படலாம்.பரம்பரையாக வருவது எப்படிஇவ்வியாதி சிறுநீரகங்களின் உருவாக்கத்தையும் அமைப்பையும் நிர்ணயிக்கும் மரபணுக்கள் மாறிப்போவதால் வருகின்றது.  இவ்வியாதி உள்ள நபர்கள் பெரும்பாலும் அவரது குடும்பத்தில் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட முதல் நபராக இருப்பார்.  ஆனால் அவரது குழந்தைகளுக்கு இந்த வியாதி வர 50 சதவிதம் வாய்ப்பு உண்டு.  சிலருக்கு பரம்பரை பரம்பரையாக இந்த வியாதி ஒவ்வொரு தலைமுறையிலும் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட நபர்கள் இருக்கலாம். சமீப காலத்தில் இந்நோயை கருவிலேயே கண்டறியக் கூடிய மரபணு பரிசோதனைகள் வந்துள்ளன.  இந்தியாவில் இது இன்னும் வரவில்லை.  இச்சோதனையல்லாது இவ்வியாதியை கண்டுபிடிக்க சிறுநீரகங்களுக்கு அல்ட்ரா சவுண்ட் ஸ்கான் செய்வதன் மூலம் மட்டுமே முடியும். அதிலும் பெரும்பாலானவர்களுக்கு ஸ்கானில் கட்டிகள் 30 வயதிற்கு முன்பு தெரிவதில்லை. எனவே குடும்பத்தில் சிறுநீரகக் கட்டி வியாதி உள்ளவர்கள் தங்களுக்கு அதே வியாதி உள்ளதா என்று தெரிந்து கொள்ள 30 வயதிற்கு மேல் வருடம் ஒருமுறை ஸ்கான் செய்து கொள்ள வேண்டும். அபூர்வமாக சிறுநீரக கட்டி வியாதி கருவிலிருக்கும் குழந்தையிலிருந்து பெரியவர் வரை எப்போது வேண்டுமானாலும் தெரிய வரலாம்.மருத்துவம் முறை:ஒருவருடைய தாய் அல்லது தந்தை அல்லது சகோதரர், சகோதரி அவர்களில் யாரேனும் ஒருவருக்கு இந்த வியாதி இருந்தால் அந்த நபருக்கு இவ்வியாதி வர 50 சதவிதம் வாய்ப்பு உண்டு. 30 வயதிற்கு மேல் ஸ்கான் செய்து இந்த வியாதி வந்துள்ளதா? என்று தெரிந்து கொள்ளலாம். ஒருவருக்கு இவ்வியாதி இல்லை என்றால் அவரின் குழந்தைகளுக்கு கண்டிப்பாக இவ்வியாதி வராது. அது தவிர வியாதி வராமல் தடுக்கவோ அல்லது வியாதி வந்த பிறகு அது முன்னேறாமல் தடுக்கவோ இது வரை மருந்துகள் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்படவில்லை. அதற்கான ஆராய்ச்சிகள் நடந்து கொண்டிருக்கின்றன. இன்னும் சில வருடங்களில் அதனுடைய பலன்களை நாம் எதிர் பார்க்கலாம்.பாதிப்பின் விளைவுகள்:இவ்வியாதியில் சிறுநீரகங்கள் தான் முக்கியமாகவும் அதிகமாகவும் பாதிக்கப்படுகின்றன. சிலருக்கு இதே போன்ற கட்டிகள் ஈரல், மண்ணீரல், கணையம், பெருங்குடல் ஆகிய உறுப்புக்களில் வருவதுண்டு சிலருக்கு இருதய வால்வுகளில் பாதிப்புகள் வருவதுண்டு. இன்னும் சிலருக்கு மூலையில் உள்ள இரத்த குழாய்கள் வீங்கி வெடிக்கக் கூடியதொரு வித வாய்ப்பும் உண்டு இதனால் இந்த வியாதி உள்ளதாக கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் சில உத்தியோகங்களுக்கு செல்லும் போது மூளையின் இரத்த நாளங்களை ஆய்வு செய்யும் ஏஞ்சியோ பரிசோதனை செய்து ஏதும் பாதிப்பில்லை என்று தெரிந்த பிறகே வேலையில் பணியாற்ற அனுமதிக்கப்படுவர். ஆனால் இத்தகு பாதிப்புகள் ஒரு சிலருக்கே வர வாய்ப்பு உண்டு.மருந்துகள்:இவ்வியாதி எப்படி தெரிய வந்தாலும் தெரிந்த பிறகு அந்நபர் தொடர்ந்து சிறுநீரக மருத்துவரின் கண்காணிப்பில் இருக்க வேண்டியது அவசியம். இவர்களுக்கு வரும் உயர் இரத்த அழுத்தம், சிறுநீரக தாரையில் கிருமித்தாக்கம் போன்றவற்றை ஆரம்பித்திலேயே கண்டுபிடித்து சரியாக அவற்றை கட்டுப்படுத்தி வைப்பதன் மூலம் சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு வரும் சமயத்தை வெகு காலம் தள்ளிப் போடவும். வந்த பிறகு சிறுநீரகங்களின் ஆயுளை பலவருட காலம் நீட்டிக்கவும் முடியும். தவிர சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு தொடங்கி படிப்படியாக முன்னேறும் காலக் கட்டங்களில் அதற்குரிய சில வைத்தியங்களை சிறுநீரக மருத்துவரின் ஆலோசனைப்படி செய்ய வேண்டி வரும்.  சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு படிப்படியாக முன்னேறி கடை நிலை சிறுநீரக செயலிழப்பு என்று ஆகும் போது கூட இரத்தச் சுத்திகரிப்பு சிகிச்சை அல்லது சிறுநீரக மாற்று அறுவை சிகிச்சை ஆகியவற்றின் மூலம் மேலும் பல வருடங்கள் ஆரோக்கியமாக வாழ முடியும்.  இவ்வியாதி உள்ளவர்கள் சிறுநீரக மாற்று அறுவை சிகிச்சை செய்து கொள்வதில் எந்த கூடுதல் சிக்கலும் வருவதில்லை."},{"question":"දුටුගැමුණු රජතුමා විසින් ඉදි කරවන ලද , පළමුවැනි චෛත්‍යය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"මිරිසවැටිය "},{"question":"A = {x : x అనేది ASSISTANCE పదంలోని అక్షరం}B= {x : x అనేది ASSISTANT పదంలోని అక్షరం} అయినA) A ∪ B =AB) A ∩ B = BC) B ⊂ AD) పైవన్నీ","answer":"D) పైవన్నీ"},{"question":"Zer da kriptografia, eta nola erabiltzen da datuen segurtasuna bermatzeko?","answer":"Kriptografia da mezuen edo datuen ezkutatzearen teknika, matematika erabiliz. Datuen segurtasuna bermatzeko, kriptografia erabiltzen da datuak zifratu eta deskifratzeko, komunikazio seguruak bermatuz."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai api dalam puntung hanyut\\"?","answer":"Cerita yang sudah tamat"},{"question":"السؤال:  في لعبة كرة السلة بالمدرسة الإعدادية ، لوحظ خطأ في سجل نقاط الفريق المضيف: لا يتم تضمين لاعب واحد في تشكيلة الفريق المضيف. وما الحكم الصحيح؟","answer":"الإجابة: يتلقى الفريق تقريرًا فنيًا: على الرغم من أن المسؤولين لا يتبعون دائمًا هذه القاعدة ، إلا أن هذا هو الحكم الصحيح."},{"question":"オーストラリアの国旗に星は６つありますが、ニュージーランドの国旗には星がいくつあるでしょう？","answer":"４つ"},{"question":"Telegram有什么特点？","answer":"Telegram的特点包括：安全性：Telegram使用了端到端加密技术，保证了用户的信息安全。支持大型群组和频道：Telegram支持超过20万人的群组，用户还可以创建公开或私有的频道来发布信息。支持发送各类文件：Telegram支持发送各种类型的文件，无论是图片、视频还是文档，都可以轻松发送。自定义和扩展性：用户可以自定义Telegram的界面，开发者也可以使用Telegram的API进行开发和扩展。"},{"question":"රසායනික සංයෝග බෙදිය හැකි කාණ්ඩ දෙක නම් කරන්න.","answer":"රසායනික සංයෝග කාබනික සහ අකාබනික ලෙස බෙදිය හැකිය."},{"question":"සයනොබැක්ටීරියා ප්‍රජනනය වන්නේ කොහොමද?","answer":"සයනොබැක්ටීරියාවන්ගේ ලිංගික ප්‍රජනනයක් තවමත් සොයා ගෙන නැත. අලිංගික ප්‍රජනන ක්‍රම කිහිපයක් පමණක් පෙන්වයි. ඒවා පහත දැක්වේ.1. ද්වි කණ්ඩනය - සෛලය දෙකට බෙදී යාම මගින් නව සාමාජිකයින් බිහිවීම.2. කඩ කඩ වීම - සූත්‍රිකාකාර සාමාජිකයන්ගේ දේහය ඕනෑම තැනකින් කඩවීම මගින් නව සාමාජිකයින් බිහිවීම.3. හෝමගෝනියා මගින් - සූත්‍රිකාකාර සාමාජිකයන්ගේ දේහයේ බෙදුම්මඩල් ඇති ස්ථාන වලින් බෙදී යාම (එසේ බෙදී ගිය කොටස් හෝමගෝනියා ලෙස හැඳින්වෙයි) මගින් නව සාමාජිකයින් බිහිවීම."},{"question":"வினா: கரிசலாங்கண்ணியின் மருத்துவக் குணங்களைக் குறிப்பிடுக","answer":"விடை: கரிசலாங்கண்ணியின் மருத்துவக் குணங்கள் :-கரிசலாங்கண்ணி ஒரு மருத்துவ மூலிகைச் செடியாகும். இதில் இருவகை உண்டு. மஞ்சள் கரிசலாங்கண்ணி, வெள்ளை கரிசலாங்கண்ணி. மஞ்சள் கரிசலாங்கண்ணியை, அதன் மஞ்சள் நிற பூக்களை வைத்து அடையாளம் காணலாம். வெள்ளை கரிசலாங்கண்ணியை, அதன் வெள்ளைநிற பூக்களை வைத்து  அடையாளம் காணலாம்.கல்லீரல் செயல்பாட்டின் குறைவினால் ஏற்படும் இரத்த சோகை நோய்க்கு கரிசலாங்கண்ணிச்சாற்றை 100 மில்லியளவு தினந்தோறும் சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் சில  தினங்களில் இரத்த சோகை நீங்கி விடும். இரத்தத்தில் உள்ள அமிலத்தன்மை சீராகச் செயல்படும். குழந்தைகளுக்கு கரிசலாங்கண்ணிச்சாறு இரண்டு சொட்டில் எட்டு சொட்டு தேன் கலந்து கொடுத்தால் சளித்தொல்லை நீங்கிவிடும். அடிக்கடி சளி ஏற்படுவது  குறைந்து குழந்தை ஆரோக்கியமாக இருக்கும். பல கொடிய வியாதிகளில் இருந்து பாது காத்துக் கொள்ளலாம். மஞ்சள் காமாலை முதல் அனைத்து வகையான காமாலை நோய்களுக்கும் மிக முக்கியமானது  கரிசலாங் கண்ணிக் கீரையாகும்.கரிசலாங்கண்ணி இலையைப் பறித்து சுத்தம் செய்து நன்றாக அரைத்து இரண்டு சுண்டைக்காய் அளவில் எடுத்து பாலில் கலந்து வடிகட்டி காலை, மாலை சாப்பிட வேண்டும். சிறுவர்களுக்கு மூன்று நாட்கள் கொடுத்தால் போதுமானது. பெரியவர்களுக்கு ஏழு நாட்கள் கொடுக்க வேண்டும். மருந்து சாப்பிடும் காலத்தில்  உப்பில்லாப் பத்தியம் இருக்க வேண்டும். நோய் நீங்கிய பின், ஆறு மாதம் வரை எளிதில் செரிக்கும் உணவு சாப்பிட வேண்டும்.சிறுநீரகம் பாதிப்படைந்து வெள்ளை, வெட்டை நோய் ஏற்பட்டால், இந்நோய்க்கு கரிசலாங்கண்ணி தான் முதன்மையான மருந்தாகும். கரிசலாங்கண்ணிச் சூரணத்தை நான்கு மாசத்துக்கு ஒரு பாகம் திப்பிலிச்சூரணம் சேர்த்து காலை, மாலை ஒரு தேக்கரண்டி தேனில் குழைத்து ஒரு மாத காலம்  சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் ஆஸ்துமாவின் தொல்லை குறையும். கரிசலாங்கண்ணி கரிசாலை, அரிப்பான் பொற்கொடி போன்ற பெயர்களால் வழங்கப்படுகிறது. கரிசலாங்கண்ணிக் கீரையில் தங்கச் சத்து, இரும்புச்சத்து,  வைட்டமின் ‘ஏ’ அதிகம் உள்ளன.  கரிசலாங்கண்ணியை எளிய முறையில் உபயோகித்தாலே பல நன்மைகளை அடையலாம். வாரத்துக்கு இரண்டு நாள், கீரையைச் சமையல் செய்து  சாப்பிட்டாலும் இதன் சாற்றை 100 மில்லியளவு சாப்பிட்டு வந்தாலும், உடலுக்கு எந்த நோயும் வராமல் நோய் எதிர்ப்புத் தன்மை உண்டாகும்."},{"question":"音楽記号で、ヘ音記号のもととなったアルファベットはFですが、ト音記号のもととなったアルファベットは何でしょう？","answer":"Ｇ"},{"question":"வினா:ஒரு தலைமுறை சுமார் எத்தனை ஆண்டுகளை குறிக்கும்?","answer":"விடை: 33"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity.Fanambarana: \\"Tsy nahomby fanintelony tamin'ny fanadinana mitondra fiara aho.\\"","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia maneho alahelo. Diso fanantenana tamin'ny tsy fahafahany fanadinana fitondrana fiara izy."},{"question":"Yaya sunan tsohon mataimakin gwamnan jihar kano?","answer":"Sunansa Dr. Nasiru Yusuf Gawuna"},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng cho câu hỏi sau:Các số La Mã XV, XXI được đọc lần lượt là: A. mười lăm, hai mốtB. mười năm, hai mốtC. mười lăm, hai mươi mốtD. mười bốn, mười chín","answer":"Lời giảiCác số La Mã XV, XXI biểu diễn các số tự nhiên 15, 21 và được đọc lần lượt là: mười lăm, hai mươi mốt. Chọn đáp án C. "},{"question":"今年秋に開幕する、ラグビーの社会人１２チームによる全国規模のリーグ戦を何というでしょう？","answer":"（ジャパンラグビー）トップリーグ"},{"question":"Good morning","answer":"Good morningTHIS IS THE REALITY!.A mature lady does not care about your height, your money,your complexion and your job.A mature lady wants a man who will love her truly and giveher happiness and peace of mind..A girl who is not mature wants to date a tall, handsome, andrich man.Even if you beat and insult her, she doesn't care as long asYou are handsome, rich, work for an oil company, and are tall.You are her dream man.She will never leave you..SOME OF OUR WOMEN NEED TO AGE..They are still kids..This is why they will always suffer heartbreak.because many handsome and rich guys are looking for girls.to use and dump..Ladies, PLEASE CHANGE!.Money is not everything!.YOU BETTER BE IN LOVE WITH A MAN WHO TRULYLOVES YOU THAN LOVING A RICH AND HANDSOME GUYWHO BREAKS YOUR HEART EACH AND EVERYDAY! YOUR MAN CAN NEVER REMAIN THE WAY HE IS; MAYBE HE'S BROKE AND STILL STRUGGLING TO SURVIVE. YOU CAN CHOOSE YOUR MAN NO MATTER WHAT THE WORLD SAYS OR KNOWS ABOUT HIM, MAKE HIM, BUILD HIM, HELP HIM, AND TOGETHER YOU CAN BUILD AN EMPIRE..BE WISE AND GROW UP, LADIES!!"},{"question":"Imisa jeer ayaa qur'anka lagu xusay  magaca Nabiyullahi Muxamed SCW ?","answer":"Waxaa lagu xusay 4 jeer ."},{"question":"පැරණි ඊජිප්තුවේ පාරාවෝ වරුන් අතර අවසන් පාලකයා කවුද?","answer":"පුරාණ ඊජිප්තුවේ අවසාන පාරාවෝ වූයේ ක්ලියෝපැට්රා VII තියා ෆිලෝපේටර්(Cleopatra VII Thea Philopator) ය. ඇය ක්‍රිස්තු පූර්ව 51 සිට ක්‍රිස්තු පූර්ව 30 දක්වා පාලනය කළාය. ක්ලියෝපැට්රා යනු පුරාණ ඉතිහාසයේ වඩාත් ප්රසිද්ධ චරිතයක් වන අතර ජූලියස් සීසර් සහ මාර්ක් ඇන්ටනි සමඟ ඇති සබඳතා සඳහා ප්රසිද්ධය. එවකට ඔක්ටේවියන් ලෙස හැඳින්වූ ඔගස්ටස් විසින් ඇයගේ පරාජයෙන් පසු, ඊජිප්තුව රෝම අධිරාජ්‍යයේ පළාතක් බවට පත් වූ අතර, ටොලමියානු රාජධානියේ අවසානය සහ ස්වාධීන ඊජිප්තු පාරාවෝවරුන්ගේ යුගය සනිටුහන් කළේය."},{"question":"Nderipi zuva rekuzvarwa risinganyanyozivikanwa muUnited States? MuUnited States pakati pa1973 na1999, Gunyana 16 ndiro zuva rekuzvarwa rinonyanyozivikanwa muUnited States uye Zvita 25 zuva rekuzvarwa risinganyanyozivikanwa (kunze kwaKukadzi 29, nekuda kwemakore akawanda). Muna 2011, Gumiguru 5 ne6 akashumwa semazuva ekuzvarwa anowanzoitika.","answer":"Zuva rekuzvarwa risinganyanyozivikanwa muUnited States pakati pa1973 na1999 raive Kukadzi 29 nekuda kwemakore ekusvetuka."},{"question":"Bu metin hangi önemli olayla ilgilidir: 1914'te Londra'da Lyceum Tiyatrosu'nda bir pantomimde başrolde sahneye çıktı. Bu başarısının sevinci, babasını Somme Muharebesi’nde kaybetmenin üzüntüsü ile gölgelendi. Bale eğitimini Enrico Cecchetti, Edouard Espinosa gibi tanınmış öğretmenlerle devam etti. Pantomim, revü ve operalarda dansçı olarak deneyim kazandıktan sonra, 1923'te Diaghilev topluluğunun konuk sanatçısı oldu. Üç yıl boyunca çalıştığı bu toplulukta solist olarak dans etti ve o sıralarda henüz bir çocuk olan geleceğin ünlü İngiliz balerini Alicia Markova'yı yetiştirdi. Çocukken atlattığı ve o zamanlar teşhis konmamış olan çocuk felci nedeniyle bale çalışmaları sırasında ağrıları olsa da solo kariyerine sürdürdü.","answer":"Somme Muharebesi"},{"question":"Quem era a loira do verso \\"And you're probably with that blonde girl\\" da música Drivers License da Olivia Rodrigo?","answer":"De acordo com os fãs, a Olivia Rodrigo se referia à cantora Sabrina Carpenter."},{"question":"س155- ماذا كانت ديانة الفرس قبيل الإسلام ؟","answer":"ج155- النار ويسمون المجوس"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Efa ho lava toy ny laingan'ny faritra sasany,  ....................\\" .","answer":"\\"Efa ho lava toy ny laingan'ny faritra sasany, avekeo mierina hoy izy nefa any izy dia tsy hita.\\""},{"question":"മനുഷ്യരിൽ, ഒരു സ്വഭാവം ഒരു ജോഡി അല്ലെങ്കിൽ നിരവധി ജോഡി മൂലകങ്ങളാൽ നിർണ്ണയിക്കാവുന്നതാണ്. താഴെ പറയുന്നവയില് നിന്ന് തെരഞ്ഞെടുക്കുക. [1] ജീനുകൾ; [2] സൂക്ഷ്മാണുക്കൾ; [3] സെല്ലുകൾ; [4] അവയവങ്ങൾ","answer":"ഓപ്ഷൻ [1] ജീനുകളാണ് ഉത്തരം"},{"question":"താഴെ പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം തരൂ. ഡിസ്കിൽ നിന്നും മെമ്മറിയിലേക്ക് പ്രോഗ്രാം ലോഡ് ചെയ്യുന്നയാൾ? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"ലോഡർ"},{"question":"Tôi chuẩn bị xây nhà phố 4 tầng, diện tích 5x16 m. Trong đó, tầng một dự kiến là khu sinh hoạt chung gồm phòng khách, bếp, chỗ để xe. 3 tầng còn lại chia thành 3 phòng ngủ và một phòng thờ. Tôi không muốn xây nhiều phòng ngủ, vì thực tế chỉ có hai vợ chồng và hai con nhỏ nên nhu cầu không nhiều.Nhờ chuyên gia tư vấn giúp, bố trí công năng như vậy liệu có lãng phí? Ngoài ra, quy mô nhà như trên cần tối thiểu bao nhiêu phòng vệ sinh và phòng tắm, nên thiết kế ở vị trí nào?","answer":"Với trường hợp của bạn, bố trí mỗi tầng một phòng ngủ sẽ hơi lãng phí. Ngoài thiết kế sảnh thang bộ rộng khoảng 14-15 m2 ở mỗi tầng, với phần diện tích còn lại, bạn có thể lựa chọn một trong hai phương án dưới đây:- Một, mỗi tầng bố trí 2 phòng gồm: một ngủ và một phòng chức năng sử dụng cho các mục đích như: đọc sách, học tập, tập gym - yoga, hay khu vui chơi nếu nhà có trẻ nhỏ...Trong đó, diện tích phòng ngủ nên để 35-40 m2, phòng chức năng khoảng 20-25 m2. Tùy vào nhu cầu, bạn có thể bổ sung thêm các không gian xanh như giếng trời, ban công... Riêng tầng 4, có thể bố trí phòng thờ, một phòng ngủ, khu giặt và sân phơi.- Hai, nếu vẫn muốn bố trí một phòng ngủ mỗi tầng cho rộng rãi theo đúng sở thích, bạn có thể bổ sung khu vực thay đồ riêng, đồng thời thêm các không gian xanh như giếng trời, ban công...Tùy vào nhu cầu lưu trữ đồ nhiều hay ít, khu vực thay đồ có thể làm thành một phòng riêng hay gộp chung với phòng tắm. Trường hợp này, cần chừa lại một khoảng diện tích đủ rộng cho khu đệm phía trước phòng vệ sinh để tiện đi lại.Ngoài ra, với diện tích nhà của bạn, nên thiết kế 4 phòng vệ sinh ở các vị trí như sau: Một phòng vệ sinh chung không bao gồm tắm dưới tầng một, 3 phòng vệ sinh bao gồm tắm ở 3 tầng còn lại. Diện tích mỗi phòng vệ sinh cơ bản có phân khu khô và ướt cần tối thiểu khoảng 4-6 m2. Trường hợp phòng vệ sinh lắp thêm bể sục hoặc bồn tắm có thể tăng lên 10 m2. Tùy theo sở thích và công năng, phòng vệ sinh có thể bố trí ở cuối nhà hoặc giữa nhà đều hợp lý."},{"question":"Eyi le o, ajinigbe lawọn gende meji kan fẹẹ mu ti wọn fi ku sodo n’llọrin","answer":"Ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, opin ọsẹ to kọja yii, ni iṣẹlẹ kayeefi kan ṣẹ niluu Ilọrin, nipinlẹ Kwara. Ajinigbe kan ti ko sẹni to mọ orukọ rẹ lo ji ọmọ kekere kan gbe ni agbegbe Amilẹgbẹ, nijọba ibilẹ Ila-Oorun Ilọrin, wọn gba a mu, wọn si gba ọmọ naa lọwọ ẹ. Ṣugbọn ni kete ti wọn fẹẹ maa fiya jẹ ẹ lo fere ge e, lawọn gende meji ti a o ti i mọ orukọ wọn ba gba tẹle e, nise ni ajinigbe naa bẹ sinu odo Amilẹgbẹ to wa ni agbegbe naa, lawọn ọkunrin meji ọhun ba bẹ tẹle e, ṣugbọn niṣe ni wọn dawati ninu odo.Lẹyin ọpọlọpọ wakati ti wọn ti n wa wọn ninu odo ni wọn pada yọ oku wọn jade. ALAROYE gbọ pe ọdaran ajinigbe naa mọ odo o wẹ daadaaa, eyi lo fa a ti wọn ko fi ri i mọ."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو خاتم الأنبياء والرسل؟","answer":"الإجابة: محمد صلى الله عليه وسلم"},{"question":"Sino ang unang babaeng pangulo ng Pilipinas?","answer":"Si Maria Corazon \\"Cory\\" Sumulong Cojuangco-Aquino ang unang babaeng pangulo ng Pilipinas. Siya ang oposisyon ni Ferdinand Marcos Sr., ang pangulo ng bansa sa eleksyon noong Pebrero 1986. Si Marcos ang inulat na panalo ng eleksyon noon, ngunit hinamon ito ng kampo ni Aquino dahil umano sa pandaraya. Maraming mamamayan at opisyal na gobyero rin ang tumuligsa sa resulta ng eleksyon at nag-alsa sa Epifanio de los Santos Avenue o EDSA sa Metro Manila. Umalis si Marcos at ang kanyang pamilya ng bansa noong Pebrero 25, 1986 at niluklok si Aquino bilang opisyal na pangulo ng bansa."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Bé gái 7 tuổi ở Bình Phước bị bạo hành: Căm phẫn và cảm ơn","answer":"Hãy chấm dứt tình trạng bạo hành trẻ em vì trẻ em là đối tượng được pháp luật bảo vệ nhiều nhất, đồng thời phải đưa ra pháp luật kẻ hành hạ trẻ em để xử thật nặng. Đó là một trong nhiều ý kiến của bạn đọc gửi đến Báo Người Lao Động liên quan đến việc bé gái D.Y 7 tuổi bị cha dượng là Trần Thanh Tú (ngụ tại xã Tân Hòa, huyện Đồng Phú, Bình Phước) và mẹ ruột là Lầu Y Lầu bạo hành với nhiều vết thương chi chít trên cơ thể. Bạn đọc Nguyễn Văn Thế viết: \\"May cho cháu đã gặp người tốt cứu giúp. Hãy xử lý tận gốc những kẻ thủ ác tội bạo hành trẻ em. Thực sự trẻ em vô tội, không có khả năng tự vệ, cần được yêu thương, che chở... Vậy mà vẫn có những người ác độc có thể tra tấn trẻ. Phải xử thật nghiêm\\". Bạn đọc Nguyễn Song Giang bức xúc cho rằng trẻ thơ hiếu động, quậy phá chứ nào có tội tình gì mà cha dượng, mẹ ruột hành hạ dã man vậy. \\"Vô cùng căm giận. Thời gian gần đây nhiều mẹ ghẻ, cha dượng hành hạ con vợ, con chồng dã man gây thương tích trầm trọng, thương vong\\" - Song Giang lên tiếng. Trong khi đó, Lành Bình An cho rằng những kẻ làm ác với bé gái 8 tuổi ở TP HCM bị cả xã hội chê cười khinh bỉ, căm thù thì cặp cha dượng, mẹ đẻ này cũng tương tự. Hãy nghiêm trị để làm gương cho xã hội Bạn đọc Lý Hải Trung cũng đồng tình phải trừng trị kẻ hành hạ trẻ em và cảm ơn người tố giác; bạn đọc Bùi Văn Dũng kêu gọi chấm dứt tình trạng bạo hành trẻ em vì trẻ em là đối tượng được pháp luật bảo vệ nhiều nhất. Liên quan đến 2 đối tượng bạo hành bé gái 7 tuổi, ngày 29-7, cơ quan Công an Bình Phước ngoài khởi tố, bắt tạm giam cha  dượng để điều tra về hành vi trên, công an cũng khởi tố người mẹ và áp dụng biện pháp ngăn chặn cấm rời khỏi nơi cư trú do người này đang mang thai, nuôi con nhỏ. Cùng ngày, bà Trần Tuệ Hiền, Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh Bình Phước cũng đã ký công văn khẩn chỉ đạo các ngành và các địa phương trên địa bàn tăng cường phòng chống xâm hại, bạo lực trẻ."},{"question":"En güvenilir burç hangisi?","answer":"Astrolojideki en güvenilir burçlar arasında Oğlak burcu da yer alır. Oğlak burçları sonucu ne olursa olsun asla yalan söylemez. Dürüstlük onlar için önemlidir. Başak burcu, Zodyak'ın en güvenilir burçlarından biridir."},{"question":"Eeyan mẹfa padanu ẹmi wọn nibi ijamba ọkọ epo bẹntiroolu to gbina niluu Jẹbba","answer":"Eeyan mẹfa lo padanu ẹmi wọn, ti ọpọlọpọ dukia ṣofo laaarọ Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, nibi ijamba ọkọ epo bẹntiroolu to ṣẹlẹ niluu Jẹbba, nijọba ibilẹ Moro, nipinlẹ Kwara.ALAROYE gbọ pe gbugburu lawọn eeyan jona nibi iṣẹlẹ ọhun, ti awọn ile ati ṣọọbu bii ọgbọn si ba a lọ pẹlu ọja inu ẹ.Lara awọn tiṣẹlẹ naa ṣoju wọn ṣalaye pe lasiko ti ọkọ epo naa n gba igboro ilu Jẹbba kọja lo lọọ ya wọ ile tawọn eeyan wa, to si fọn bẹntiroolu si gbogbo adugbo naa, ki awọn eeyan si too mọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ, ina buruku ti ṣọ.Ẹwẹ, Gomina ipinlẹ Kwara, AbdulRahman AbdulRazaq, ti ba mọlẹbi awọn to padanu ẹmi ati dukia wọn nibi ijamba naa kẹdun, o ṣapejuwe iṣẹlẹ naa bii eyi to ba ni lọkan jẹ gidi.Atẹjade lati ọwọ akọwe iroyin rẹ, Rafiu Ajakaye, ni ijọba ti n gbe igbesẹ lati mọ bi adanu naa ṣe to ati ọna lati ran awọn to fara gba ijamba naa lọwọ.“Gomina ti ran ajọ to n mojuto iṣẹlẹ pajawiri nipinlẹ Kwara, State Emergency Management Agency (SEMA), lọ sibẹ lati ba ẹbi awọn to ku kẹdun, ati lati mọ ọna tijọba fi le ran awọn to padanu dukia wọn lọwọ.”"},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هو الحق في القانون؟","answer":"الإجابة: الحق هو واحد الميزه كايمنحها القانون لواحد الشخص اللي كاتحميه لما خاصو يتواجه مع ناس اخرين وكاتمكنوا باش يستاثر بواحد الشيء ويتصرف به."},{"question":"खालील गोष्ट वाचून त्यावरून काय धडा घेता येईल ते सांगा --प्राचीन ग्रीकमध्ये मिडास नावाचा एक राजा होता. त्याच्याकडे खूप सोनं आणि आवश्यक ते सर्व होते. त्याला एक सुंदर मुलगीही होती. मिदास यांना त्यांच्या सोन्यावर खूप प्रेम होते, पण तो त्याच्या मुलीवर त्याच्या संपत्तीपेक्षा जास्त प्रेम करायचा.एके दिवशी सिलेनस नावाचा सत्यर प्रवास करत असताना त्याने मिडसच्या गुलाबाच्या बागेत थोडा वेळ विश्राम करायचं ठरवलं. सिलेनस आपल्या बागेत विश्राम करत आहे हे मिडास राजाला कळालं. सिलेनस हा डायऑनससचा मित्र आहे, जो वाइन आणि उत्सवाचा देवता आहे हे मिडास या माहिती होता. मिडास राजाने सिलेनसला आपल्या महालात विश्राम करण्याचं आमंत्रण दिले आणि त्याचा चांगला पाहुणचार केला. त्यानंतर मिडास राजा सिळेनास या डायऑनसस कडे घेऊन गेला. मिडसचा आपल्या मित्राबद्दल दयाळूपणा आणि आदर कळल्यानंतर, डायऑनिससने केगला पुरस्कार देण्याचा निर्णय घेतला.जेव्हा डायऑनसस मिडासला त्याची कोणतीही एक इच्छा पूर्ण करण्याचा वरदान देतो, तेव्हा मिडस म्हणतात “मी जे काही स्पर्श करेन ते सोन्याचं होईल अशी माझी इच्छा आहे”. डीओनिससला माहित होतं की ती चांगली कल्पना नाही, परंतु तो मिडसची इच्छा पूर्ण करतो.आपली इच्छा मंजूर झाल्याबद्दल मिडसला भरपूर आनंद होतो, मिडास बागेत आणि राजवाड्यातील यादृच्छिक वस्तूंना स्पर्श करीत त्या सर्वांना सोन्यात बदलत जातो. तो एका सफरचंदला स्पर्श करतो आणि ते चमकदार सोन्याच्या सफरचंदात बदलते. राजवाड्यात इतके सोने पाहून त्याचे लोकं चकित होतात, पण आनंदी होतात.त्याच्या आनंदात, मिडास जाऊन आपल्या मुलीला मिठी मारतो आणि काही समजण्यापूर्वी तिचे निर्जीव सोन्याच्या पुतळ्यामध्ये रुपांतर होते! हे बघितल्यावर मिडास भरपूर निराश होतो, आणि परत बागेत जाऊन डायओनिससला बोलावतो. आपली शक्ती काढून घ्या आणि आपल्या मुलीला वाचवा अशी तो डायओनिससला विनवणी करतो. डायओनिसस मिडास या सांगतो की, त्याची शक्ती काढून घेतल्यावर त्याने आत्तापर्यंत जे काही सोन्यामध्ये बदलले ते सर्व आर्त त्याच्या मूळ रूपात परत येईल. मिडास यासाठी तयार असतो कारण त्याला त्याची मुलगी परत हवी असते जिच्यावर त्याचे खूप प्रेम असते. डायओनिसस त्याची सर्व शक्ती काढून घेतो आणि परत सगळं जसा होता तसं करतो. मिडासला त्याने केलेल्या कृत्याचा धडा मिळतो आणि आयुष्यभर जे काही आहे त्यामध्ये समाधानी राहून जगतो.या गोष्टीमधून काई शिकायला मिळते?","answer":"या गोष्टीमधून आपल्याला शिकायला मिळते की, लोभी होऊ नका. आपल्याकडे जे आहे त्यात आनंदी आणि समाधानी रहा."},{"question":"Gàn gëbla moo tegu ci diggante ñaar i dex bu baxa bi ak bu weex bi?","answer":"Xartuum"},{"question":"ఖచ్చిత సంభవ ఘటన యొక్క సంభావ్యత ఎంత ?","answer":"ఖచ్చిత సంభవ ఘటన యొక్క సంభావ్యత = 1"},{"question":"Inona no fototeny amin’ny matoanteny hoe \\" mifanena \\" ?","answer":"Ny fototeny amin'ny matoanteny hoe \\" mifanena \\" dia  \\" tsena \\"."},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Baba vaLatifun Nisan, Mohammad Jamal ibn Muhammad Adam ibn Zainuddin ibn Moinuddin ibn Qazi Fatehullah aive mwanakomana waHusain Mohammad weTijara. Mutsara 2: Baba vaLatifun Nisan, Mohammad Jamal ibn Mohammad Adam ibn Zainuddin ibn Moinuddin ibn Qazi Fatehullah aive mwanakomana waHusain Mohammad weTijara. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hongu kana kuti kwete?","answer":"Hongu"},{"question":"டிடி கோசாம்பியின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"நாவின் சுவைக்காக இல்லாமல் மதத்தின் அடிப்படையில் இந்திய உணவுப் பழக்கங்கள் நிலவுகின்றன."},{"question":"معي مثل صعب ، اشرحه: إبليس ما خلاش لحد حاله","answer":"إي ما ترك إبليس أحداً من الناس سالماً من المتاعب."},{"question":"Imvelo iyasifundisaIbhalwe nguNonkululeko MjajiNjengabantu sinenhlanhla enkulu ngoba saphiwa imiqondo yokwazi ukwenza izinto eziningi.Imvelo nje iyodwa ingasifundisa okuningi njengabantu. Lo mcabango ungifikele ngesikhathi kadengivakashele esiqiwini saseHluhluwe ngempelasonto edlule. Leli holide besililangazelela kakhulu.Kuhle ukuthola ithuba lokuphuma esiphithiphithini sedolobha kwesinye isikhathi. Lokhu kukunikanethuba lokuchitha isikhathi nomndeni wakho ngaphandle kokuphazamiseka. Kulokhu, besifisaukuba neholide elisendaweni ethule.Sahamba usuku lonke ngemoto nomndeni wami ukuya eHluhluwe. Safika selizoshona ilanga okwenzaukuthi kungabikhona lutho esalwenza ngalolu suku. Sajabulela ukuthola indlu esasilungiselwe yonangoba sasikhathele kakhulu. Amadodana ami afikelwa ukwesaba uma sekushone ilanga ngobakwakumnyama kakhulu. Phela abantwana bami bajwayele impilo yasedolobheni lapho kuhlalekunomsindo futhi kukhanya. Ukuba sendaweni emnyama lapho kukhanyisa inyanga nezinkanyezibabengakujwayele.Ngosuku olulandelayo ngavuka ekuseni kakhulu ngoba ngangizwile ukuthi izilwane zasendlezithanda ukuya edamini ziyophuza amanzi. Ilanga laphuma sengingasedamini. Ukuphumakwelanga kulesi siqiwi kuhle ngendlela emangalisayo. Abanye abantu bayathanda ukubuka ilangalishona. Kodwa, emva kokubona ilanga liphuma kulesi siqiwi, ngicabanga ukuthi lokhu sekuyikhonaengikuthanda kakhulu. Ngakhumbula ukuthi noma bungaba mnyama kangakanani ubusuku kodwaukukhanya okunamandla kuyavela ekuseni. Nasempilweni siyafikelwa ubumnyama obuhlukenekodwa kumele sazi ukuthi izinsuku ezingcono ziyafika.Khona lapho ngisabuka izilwane ngasedamini ngabona izindlovu ziphuza amanzi zihambaziyiqembu. Ngabuza uThemba, umsebenzi wasesiqiwini, ukuthi izindlovu ziyizilwane ezinjanikahle kahle. Ngiyajabula ukuthi ngambuza lokhu ngoba impendulo engayithola kuye yangifundisaebengingakwazi ngezindlovu. Ngokusho kukaThemba, izindlovu ezihamba nezindlovu ezindalazesifazane ziphila isikhathi eside. Izindlovu ezindala ziyakwazi ukubona uma kuzoba nesomiso nomanezinye izinkinga zemvelo. Izindlovu ezisakhula zisizakala ngokuhlakanipha kwezindlovu ezindala.Lokhu kuyinto ebalulekile nakithi njengabantu. Siyadinga ukuhlakanipha kwabantu abangaphambilikunathi empilweni. NesiZulu siyasitshela ukuthi indlela ibuzwa kwabaphambili. Akumele sicabangeukuthi ngoba sesinobuchwepheshe besimanje asisabudingi ubuhlakani babantu abadala noma laboabebekhona ngaphambi kwethu. Abantu abadala banolwazi nesipiliyoni esiningi abangasikhulisangaso futhi basisize singangeni ezinkingeni ebesingazigwema ngokubalalela.Okunye engakuqaphela khona ngasemfuleni ukuthi zonke izilwane zazithatha isikhathi sazo.Ngafikelwa umcabango wokuthi imvelo ayijahi. Yonke into yenzeka ngendlela nangesikhathi esifanele.Thina njengabantu siphila esikhathini lapho sizama ukuthi yonke into yenzeke ngokushesha. Umakunokwenzeka, kumele sehlise isivinini esihamba ngaso. Ngesikhathi sisendleleni eya kulesi siqiwi,sama endaweni ethize ukuze sithole ukudla futhi abantwana bami babekhononda ngokuthi uhamboluthatha isikhathi eside. Nami futhi angehlukile kubantwana bami ngoba ziningi izindawo laphongifuna izinto zenzeke ngokushesha noma kungakabi yisikhathi.Lolu hambo lwangenza ngafikelwa umcabango wokuthi ukuya endaweni efana nale kuyasizakakhulu. Ukuvakashela isiqiwi kusifundise okuningi siwumndeni okwedlula amaqiniso ambalwangezilwane. Bekumnandi ngendlela emangalisayo futhi angeke sikhohlwe kalula. Ngempela imveloinguthisha omkhulu.1. Ngokusho kukaThemba, yini eyenza izindlovu ziphile isikhathi eside endle?A Ezincane zifunda kulezi ezindala.B Zihamba ngamaqembu uma zizophuza amanzi.C Zivikelwa ngabantu.","answer":"A"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai apung di tengah laut, dipukul ombak jatuh ke tepi\\"?","answer":"Melarat di tempat asing"},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Kepentingan Sektor Industri Pelancongan kepada Rakyat dan Negara.","answer":"Industri pelancongan merupakan antara sektor utama dalam ekonomi negara Malaysia. Pembukaan Lapangan Terbang Antarabangsa Kuala Lumpur (KLIA) serta penganjuran Sukan Komanwel pada tahun 1998 telah membuka mata dunia terhadap negara Malaysia. Sejak dari tahun itu, kerajaan Malaysia bersama-sama sektor swasta telah menyemarakkan industri pelancongan negara dengan jayanya. Kedudukan Malaysia yang terletak di garisan khatulistiwa dan beriklim panas dan lembap telah membentuk pelbagai kekayaan alam semulajadi yang menjadi penarik utama para pelancong. Daripada puncak Gunung Kinabalu kepada keindahan terumbu karang di Pulau Tioman, Malaysia menerima kunjungan yang amat ramai saban tahun, maka adalah penting untuk mengekalkan konsistensi dalam pembangunan dan pelaksanaan industri pelancongan negara.Antara kepentingan ulung industri pelancongan adalah ekonomi. Ekonomi negara bergantung kepada industri pelancongan. Sebagai contoh, sosio-ekonomi di luar bandar dapat berkembang apabila mendapat peluang pekerjaan seperti pemandu pelancong atau membuka rumah inap dan restoran untuk menampung kehadiran pelancong. Dalam kawasan bandar pula, pelancongan kesihatan dapat dijana oleh hospital-hospital swasta sekaligus menambah bilangan pengunjung dan hotel di kawasan sekitar. Hal ini kerana perkhidmatan kesihatan di negara adalah berpatutan berbanding di negara asal pelancong dan mereka melakukan aktiviti pelancongan kesihatan untuk menjimatkan kos perkhidmatan yang mereka inginkan.Selain itu, industri pelancongan secara tidak langsung telah menggalakkan penambah-baikan infrastruktur di dalam negara kita di mana rakyat juga mendapat tempias manfaatnya. Hari ini, hampir setiap negeri sudah mempunyai lapangan terbang dan beberapa diantaranya menawarkan penerbangan antarabangsa seperti di Lapangan Antarabangsa Langkawi. Pelancong mendapat akses yang mudah untuk ke tempat yang ditujui tanpa perlu mengharungi perjalanan yang jauh seperti dahulu kala. Infrastruktur seperti jalan raya dan pengangkutan awam juga menjadi semakin baik apabila kawasan luar bandar yang mempunyai kawasan tarikan pelancong seperti pantai atau air terjun dan gua memerlukan tahap ketersampaian oleh pelancong-pelancong.Kepentingan industri pelancongan yang lain adalah keunikan budaya dan alam semula jadi negara dapat dikongsi serta dihargai. Eko-pelancongan merupakan antara pendekatan yang berjaya dan diraikan oleh semua dimana pelancong akan melawat kawasan-kawasan semula jadi seperti Taman Negara Endau- Rompin dan Taman Laut Terengganu di samping usaha pemeliharaan kawasan tersebut berjalan seiring. Pelancong dapat menyaksikan pusat konservasi gajah atau menikmati keindahan hidupan laut dengan menyelam di sekitar pulau-pulau di Malaysia. Seperti peribahasa Melayu berkata,”Yang dikejar tidak dapat, yang dikendong berciciran” yang bermaksud kita perlulah menyelaraskan usaha pembangunan seiring dengan memelihara apa yang kita miliki.Tambahan pula, industri pelancongan telah menarik pelbagai pelabur asing untuk melabur di dalam negara kita. Antaranya adalah dari segi hospitaliti dimana pelabur berminat untuk mengusahakan hotel, pusat membeli belah dan juga membina taman tema. Sebagai contoh, pembukaan Legoland di negeri Johor telah menarik minat ramai pelancong terutamanya dari negara luar kerana ia merupakan taman tema berjenama Lego yang pertama di Asia tenggara. Kehadiran pelabur asing dapat membantu kerajaan mengurangkan kos yang digunakan dalam sektor pelancongan sekaligus memberi lebih faedah kepada rakyat dan negara khususnya.Konklusinya, pelbagai manfaat dapat dinikmati oleh rakyat serta negara sekiranya industri pelancongan di Malaysia berjaya dan diuruskan dengan efisien. Justeru, penggubal undang-undang dan polisi negara seharusnya mnyusun rangka terbaik dalam membentuk formula dalam industri pelancongan negara supaya dapat memberi pulangan maksima kepada rakyat dan negara. Industri pelancongan adalah industri yang sihat dan wajar untuk diteruskan dan disandarkan pada ekonomi negara sekiranya diurus dengan baik. Maka, promosi pelancongan negara perlu dilaksanakan dengan lebih jitu dan berkesan agar seluruh pelusuk dunia tahu dan berminat untuk melawat negara kita suatu hari nanti. Bak kata pepatah,”tidak kenal maka tidak cinta” yang bermaksud kita perlulah memperkenalkan negara kita sehingga perasaan minat dan cinta akan Malaysia itu timbul kelak."},{"question":"Mark Knowles နဲ့ Daniel Nestor တို့ဟာ Jonathan Erlich နဲ့ Andy Ram တို့ကို 5 - 3, 5 - 4 နဲ့ အနိုင်ယူပြီး ချန်ပီယံဆုကို ရရှိခဲ့ပါတယ်။ Jonathan Erlich နဲ့ Andy Ram တို့ဟာ Mark Knowles နဲ့ Daniel Nestor တို့ကို 5: 3, 5: 4 နဲ့ အနိုင်ယူပြီး အနိုင်ရခဲ့ပါတယ္။ မေးခွန်း၊ ပထမဝါကျနဲ့ ဒုတိယဝါကျက တူညီတဲ့ အဓိပ္ပါယ်ကို ဖော်ပြလား? ဟုတ်လား၊ မဟုတ်ဘူးလား။","answer":"No... အဓိပ္ပါယ်တွေက တူမနေပါဘူး။ လုံးဝဆန့်ကျင်ဘက်ဖြစ်နေတာပဲ"},{"question":"కొల్లేరు సరస్సు యొక్క ప్రాధాన్యత ఏమిటి?","answer":"1999 నవంబరులో భారత ప్రభుత్వం కొల్లేరు సరస్సును పక్షి సంరక్షణ కేంద్రంగా ప్రకటించింది. ఇక్కడ 193 రకాల పక్షి జాతులు, వివిధ రకాల జంతు వృక్షజాలానికి ఆవాసంగా ఉండడంతో పాటు ఎన్నో రకాల మందు మొక్కలు కూడా పెరుగుతున్నాయి. ఆసియా, తూర్పు ఐరోపా దేశాల నుండి అక్టోబర్, మార్చి నెలల మధ్యకాలంలో ప్రతి ఏటా దాదాపు, 20 లక్షల పక్షులు ఈ సరస్సుకు వలస వస్తాయి. సరస్సుపై ఆధారపడి దాదాపు 20 మిలియన్ల ప్రజలు జీవిస్తున్నారు."},{"question":"Doc to summarize: Joseph Maina ti yi kilaasi ikẹkọ rẹ pada di ile adiẹIyara ikẹkọ ileewe Mwea Brethren to ṣe pe ariwo awọn akẹkọ lo maa n gbalẹ nibẹ, ti di ibudo ti igbe awọn adìẹ ti gbalẹ kan.Kaka ki wọn kọ iṣẹ iṣiro (Maths) si oju patako ikọwe, ohun to wa nibẹ ni alaye asiko tawọn adiyẹ yoo gba abẹrẹ ajẹsara.Joseph Maina to ni ileẹkọ Central Primary School naa ti sọ kilaasi di ibudo ọsin adìẹ, ko ba le ri owo gbọ bukata to wa nilẹ.'Ọna ọfun lọna ọrun''Nkan ko rọgbọ fun Jonathan paapa julọ ni oṣu Kẹta ti wọn paṣẹ ki wọn ti awọn ileewe. Lasiko taa n sọ yìí, o ni owo kan to ya lọwọ ile ifowopamọ, to si ni lati tun ijoko jokoo pẹlu wọn lori bi yoo ṣe da owo wọn pada.O kọkọ da bii ẹni pe ko si ireti kankan fun ṣugbọn o pada pinu pe oun gbọdọ wa nkan ṣe pẹlu ileewe to wa nilẹ la ṣe nkankan.Niṣe ni wọn sun aga ati tabili ijoko sẹgbẹ kan lati le gba nkan ọgbinNitori pe awọn ileewe aladani a maa fi owo tawọn obi ba san lati fi san owo oṣu olukọ wọn, bi wọn ṣe ti awọn ileewe pa ṣe akoba fawọn to da iru ileewe bẹ silẹ.Gẹgẹ bi ẹgbẹ awọn ile ẹkọ aladani ni Kenya ti ṣe sọ, diẹ ninu awọn ileewe aladani lo n gbiyanju lati maa kọ awọn akẹkọ loju ayelujara ṣugbọn owo ti wọn n ri nibẹ ko to lati san owo oṣu awọn oṣiṣẹ.Nkan bi ida marundinlogorun awọn olukọ bii egberun lọ́nà oodunrun to n ṣiṣẹ pẹlu ileewe aladani ni wọn ti ni ki wọn lọ isinmi nile lai gba owo oṣu.Peter Ndoro to jẹ alakoso ẹgbẹ yii fikun pe, ileewe metalelaadoje ni wọn sọ agadagodo si, ti wọn ko si mọ igba ti wọn yoo ṣi wọn pada.'Ko buru to bayi ri'Ki ọrọ baa ma di pe awọn naa yoo ti ileewe wọn pa, ileẹkọ Roka Preparatory ti tete yi ọgba wọn naa si oko.James Kung'u to da ileewe naa silẹ ni ọdun mẹtalelogun sẹyin sọ fun BBC pe ''Nkan ko buru to bayi ri fun wa''Ni ọgbà iṣere awọn akẹkọ ewebẹ ni wọn gbin sibẹ bayi.O tun n sin adiyẹ nibẹ naa.''Ọrọ mi ko yatọ si ti ọpọ awọn ileewe mii.Tipa ni mo fi n ri epo ra si ọkọ mi. Awọn olukọ ati akẹkọ ko si nibi mọ. Ki ni naa ba wa gidi gan''Oṣiṣẹ meji pere ni Mwea Brethren ati Roka gba ṣiṣẹ ti wọn n ran...nSummary in the same language as the doc:","answer":"ìgbésẹ̀ ìjọba Kenya tó ti àwọn ilé ẹ̀kọ́ pa di ọdún tó n bọ̀, ti mu ki ọpọ olùkọ́ di alainiṣẹ lọ́wọ́ gẹ́gẹ́ bi BBC ti ṣe iwadii rẹ."},{"question":"Duok man pavyzdį trivia šioje kategorijoje: muzika","answer":"Klausimas: Kuris ZZ Top narys neturi barzdos? Atsakymas: Frank Beardas"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: കേരളത്തിൽ നെൽകൃഷിക്ക് ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന പരമ്പരാഗത രീതികൾ ഏതൊക്കെയാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: കേരളത്തിലെ പരമ്പരാഗത നെൽകൃഷി രീതികളിൽ ജൈവ വളങ്ങൾ, കൈവേല, \\"പൊക്കാളി\\" സമ്പ്രദായം പോലുള്ള പരമ്പരാഗത ജലസേചന വിദ്യകൾ എന്നിവ ഉൾപ്പെടുന്നു."},{"question":"この段落の続きを書くー今後も、先入観や苦手意識を持たずに、","answer":"新しいことに挑戦しようと気持ちを切り替えたのでした。"},{"question":"\\"ලා ඉරෙන් ඉල්ලා රම්‍ය ගී මාලා \\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න ","answer":"ලා ඉරෙන් ඉල්ලා රම්‍ය ගී මාලාසීතලේ පින්නේ පීදිලාමාලතී සේනා මල් ලන්දේ ගම් මැද්දේතාම මට සුවඳයි සේ එදාමාල ගිරවුන්නේ අතු පතරේ හැංගීබාල වසුපැටියෝ නාඬන්නේනීල රළ රැල්ලේ මුතුලැල්ලේ පාවෙලාමා කෙසේ ඉන්දෝ ඉතින් අනේඅම්මේ ඔබ තුරුලෙන් වෙන් වෙලායන්නේ සිත ඔබ ළඟ රඳවලාමා රෑ සිහිනෙන් සෑමදාගම් පියසේ ගී ගයාඔබ නින්දෙන් ඇහැරවාසැඟැවී යන්නේලා ඉරෙන් ඉල්ලා රම්‍ය ගී මාලාසීතලේ පින්නේ පීදිලාමාලතී සේනා මල් ලන්දේ ගම් මැද්දේතාම මට සුවඳයි සේ එදානාඬන් දූ ගැන කඳුලැල් සලාසීනෙන් ඈ ඔබ ළඟමයි සදාමා එනතුරු හෙට ගම් බලාඅම්මා ඇත මග බලාසියොතුනි නොරැඳී කැලේඈ සනසන්නේනීලා වික්‍රමසිංහ"},{"question":"ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਦੀ ਪਰਿਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਦਿਓ ।","answer":"ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ (Biosphere) – ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ ‘‘ਜੀਵ ਦਾ ਖੇਤਰ\` । ਧਰਤੀ ਤੇ ਸਥਲ, ਜਲ ਅਤੇ ਹਵਾ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਪੌਦਿਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਜੰਤੂਆਂ ਦਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਬਣਾਈ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਧਰਤੀ ਤੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਬਣਾਈ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਇਹ ਖੇਤਰ ਆਪਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਧਰਤੀ ਤੇ ਸਥਲ-ਮੰਡਲ, ਜਲਮੰਡਲ ਅਤੇ ਵਾਯੂ-ਮੰਡਲ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪੌਦਿਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਜੰਤੂਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿਚ ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ (Biosphere) ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"UFC (англ. Ultimate Fighting Championship-аралаш мушташ өнөрү боюнча уюм)  уюмуна биринчи болуп чыккан кыргыз улутундагы адам ким ?","answer":"Мыктыбек Оролбай уулу UFC уюмуна чыккан биринчи кыргыз улутундагы адам."},{"question":"इंद्राच्या पत्नीचे नाव काय होते?उत्तर -","answer":"शची"},{"question":"ما إسم الصحابي الذي استضاف الرسول صلى اللهعليه وسلم بعد الهجرة إلى يثرب ؟","answer":" سيدنا أبو أيوب الأنصاري"},{"question":"කෙනෙකුගේ බුද්ධිය පටු වූ තරමට ඔහුගේ දේශනාව දිගය","answer":"ටෙට් කුක්"},{"question":"\\"Describe a personal achievement that you are proud of.\\"","answer":"One personal achievement that I am particularly proud of was completing a marathon. The journey to this accomplishment was both physically and mentally challenging, requiring months of disciplined training, diet management, and mental preparation.Initially, I was not a long-distance runner, and the idea of running 26.2 miles seemed almost insurmountable. However, I was motivated by a desire to push my limits and achieve something that I had previously thought impossible. I started with shorter distances, gradually increasing my mileage each week. This incremental approach helped me build endurance and confidence.Along with running, I focused on improving my overall fitness. This involved adopting a healthier diet, incorporating strength training and flexibility exercises into my routine, and ensuring adequate rest and recovery. Balancing this rigorous training schedule with other life responsibilities was a challenge in itself.One of the key aspects of this journey was learning to overcome mental barriers. There were days when I felt exhausted or demotivated, but I learned to push through these moments, drawing on inner reserves of strength and determination. This mental fortitude became invaluable, especially during the latter stages of the marathon.On the day of the marathon, despite the nerves and excitement, I felt prepared. The race itself was a test of endurance, resilience, and mental toughness. Crossing the finish line was an overwhelming experience, filled with a sense of accomplishment and elation. It was not just about the physical achievement of running the marathon, but also about the journey of personal growth that came with it.This achievement taught me valuable lessons about setting goals, the importance of persistence and hard work, and the incredible capability of the human body and spirit. It was a reminder that with dedication and the right mindset, what seems impossible can become achievable. The experience has since been a source of motivation in other areas of my life, encouraging me to take on new challenges with confidence and determination."},{"question":"isaky ny inona no nifanatitra jaka ny mpianakavy?","answer":"isaky ny fety fandroana no nifanatitra jaka ny mpianakavy"},{"question":"Gear Box (වාහනයක) කියන වචනයට සිංහලෙන් මොකක්ද කියන්නෙ?","answer":"Gear Box = පන්න පෙට්ටිය,ගියර පෙට්ටිය"},{"question":"پوښتنه:کیګل څه شی دی؟","answer":"کیګل د ډیټا ساینس مشهور پلیټ فارم دی1. کورسونه2. د معلوماتو سیټونه3. سیالۍدا د خلکو لپاره د نړۍ مشهور پلیټ فارم دی چې د عامه ډیټاسیټونو په اړه د دوی ډیټا تحلیلونه یا د ماشین زده کړې مهارتونه تمرین کړي. په دې سیالیو کې د نړۍ له ګوټ ګوټ څخه لوړ انجینران او ساینس پوهان راځي او د دوی جایزه ملیونونه ډالره ده. کیګل څه موده وړاندې د ګوګل لخوا اخیستل شوی و.کیګل تاسو ته وړیا GPUs هم درکوي."},{"question":"Kedu ihe bụ akụkọ ifo Igbo?","answer":"Akụkọ ọdịnala ndị Igbo na-ezo aka n’ọtụtụ akụkọ ọdịnala, akụkọ ifo, akụkọ ifo na akụkọ ọdịnala ndị e bufere ọgbọ n’obodo Igbo."},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపుగా ఒక పేరా రాయండి:గగుర్పాటుతో ఆయన వెంట్రుకలు నిక్కపొడుచుకొనెను. ఆయన కన్నుల నుండి ఆనంద బాష్పములను స్రవించెను. అంతేకాదు – శ్రీకృష్ణుని భార్యామణియగు రుక్మిణీ దేవి స్వయముగా చామరములు వీచుచుండెను. ఈ విధముగా రుక్మిణీ కృష్ణులు చేయు సపర్యలను అందుకొనుచున్న ఆ కుచేలుని భాగ్యమునకు ఆశ్చర్యపోయి అంతఃపుర కాంతలు ఇట్లు ప్రశంసించిరి.","answer":"ఈ బ్రాహ్మణుడు పూర్వ జన్మమునందు ఎటువంటి తపస్సు చేసెనో గదా ! యోగులచే ఉపాసింపబడు జగత్ప్రభువు, లక్ష్మీదేవి ప్రియుడైన శ్రీకృష్ణుని తల్పముపై కూర్చుండినాడు ఎటువంటి మునీశ్వరులైనను ఈ మహనీయమూర్తికి సాటియగునా ?"},{"question":"டிடி கோசாம்பியின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"புராணங்கள் கட்டுக்கதைகள் ஆகியவற்றைத் தவிர வேறு உயர்வான வரலாற்றுச் சான்றுகள் கிடையாது. முழுமையாக மன்னர்களின் பட்டியல் ஒன்றைக் கூடத் தயாரிக்க இயலாத நிலையில் உள்ளோம். சில சமயங்களில் முழு அரச வம்சங்கள் கூட நமக்குத் தெரியவில்லை. முகமதியர்கள் ஆட்சிக்காலம் வரையில் இந்திய வரலாற்றில் முக்கியத்துவம் பெற்ற பெரியோர் எவரைப் பற்றியும் உறுதியாகக் காலத்தைக் கூற முடியாது."},{"question":"یک نظر منفی در مورد یک فیلم بنویس.","answer":"فیلم بسیار خسته کننده بود و اصلا فیلمنامه خوبی نداشت. با اینکه از بازیگران مطرحی در فیلم استفاده شده بود، ولی به دلیل ضعف فیلمنامه، اصلا مخاطب را جذب نمی‌کرد."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي علامة نصب جمع المؤنث السالم؟","answer":"الإجابة: الكسرة "},{"question":"Суроо: Математикада көбөйтүү деген эмне?","answer":"Жооп: Көбөйтүү – математикадагы негизги арифметикалык амалдардын бири жана эки же андан көп сандардын көбөйтүндүсүн табуу үчүн колдонулат. Көбөйтүү операциясы \\"×\\" же \\"*\\" белгиси менен көрсөтүлөт жана көбөйтүлгөн натыйжаны алуу үчүн факторлор деп аталган сандарды бириктирүү аркылуу аткарылат."},{"question":"வினா : கான்வா போர் நடந்த ஆண்டு எது ? ","answer":"விடை : கி.பி.1527"},{"question":"వాక్యాల్లో అవ్యయాన్ని గుర్తించడం :1. ఆహా ! తెలుగు భాష ఎంత బాగుందో !2. ఎక్కడ పేదవారు ఉండరో అదే సంపన్న రాజ్యం .3. పొయ్యి మీద పిల్లి కూర్చుంది.4. అయ్యయ్యో ! ఆ సంబంధం తప్పి పోయిందా ?5. వాడు తెలివైనవాడే కానీ పొగరు ఎక్కువ.","answer":"లింగ, వచన, విభక్తులు లేని పదాలను అవ్వయాలంటారు. వీటికి స్త్రీ, పురుష భేదం ఉండదు. ఏక బహువచనాలు ఉండవు. డు, ము, వు, లు, యొక్క చేత, కొఱకు, వలన మొదలైన విభక్తి ప్రత్యయాలు చేరవు. యథా, తథా, ఎక్కడ, మీద, క్రింద, ప్రక్కన, నుండి, మరియు, కూడా, ఓహో, అయ్యయ్యో మొదలైనవి.1. ఆహా ! 2. ఎక్కడ3. మీద4. అయ్యయ్యో ! 5. కానీ"},{"question":"Ngiyafisa ukuba qothoNgishumayele ngobuqotho,Ngibe qotho ezindleleni zamiUlimi lwami lube qotho,Ngibe qotho nanxa ngikhuluma.Ngiyafisa ukuba qothoEmisebenzini yami,Nanxa ngikhandlekaImisebenzi yami ibe qothoIziphambeko zami zisulwe.Ngiyafisa ukuba qothoKubazali bamiNgihloniphe omdala nomncaneUkuze ngitshal' imbewuYobuqotho esizweni sakithi.Ngiyafisa ukuba qothoEziphiweni zami enginazoUkuze ngisebenzise zonkeNgokukhulu ukwethembekaUkuze ngijabulise abantu.Ngiyafisa ukuba qothoNakuSomandla uqobo!Ngiziveze ngimsulwa kuyeNgikhale kuye angizweYen' owazi ngempokophelo yami.1. Imbongi iphumelele ukudlulisa umyalezo wayo ngokusebenzisa lenkulumo; Ukuze ngitshal' imbewu, Sekela lo mbono ngamaphuzuAMABILI.","answer":"Iphumelele imbongi ngoba: Ukutshala kusho ukwandisa lokhu umuntu anakho. Lokhukusho ukuthi ubuqotho ngeke buphele uma imbongiibutshalile.  Ukutshala kungaba ukufundisa abantu abancanengokubaluleka kokuba qotho, ngaleyo ndlela imfundisoyobuqotho iqhubeke."},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara tamin'ny 29 marsa 1947?","answer":"Ny 29 marsa 1947 dia nisy ny tolom-panoherana notarihan’ny JINA sy ny PANAMA tao Moramanga, Fianarantsoa, Sahasinaka, Ambohimanga atsimo, Antananarivo ary Diego Suarez. Araka ny filazan’ny mpikaroka dia miisa 550 any ho any ny Frantsay maty voavono tamin’izany. Narahina famaizana mahery vaika naharitra 21 volana izany tolom-panoherana izany, ary Malagasy an’arivony maro no namoy ny ainy tamin’izany."},{"question":"ما هي الهندسة الداخلية؟ أجب على السؤال السابق.","answer":"الإجابة هي: مجموع التخطيط والتصميم للفراغات الداخلية,والتي تهدف لتسخير الاحتياجات المادية والروحية والاجتماعية للناس ,والتي بدورها تضمن سلامة المبنى."},{"question":"Gözü açık ne demek TDK?","answer":"Gözü açık TDK sözlük anlamı şu şekildedir: sıfat,mecaz Uyanık, becerikli (kimse)"},{"question":"ሩማንያ የቀለም የቴሌቭዥን ስርጭት የተጀመረው መቼ ነው?","answer":"በ1977 ዓም"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి పర్యాయ పదాలని ఇవ్వండి: భాగీరథి","answer":"గంగానది, జాహ్నవి, పావని"},{"question":"Sheeg Ileyska Imisa Nooc Ayuu U Kala Baxaa?","answer":"Ileyska Wuxu U Kala Baxaa,1. Mid Dabiica Ah.2. Mid Aan Dabiici Eheen."},{"question":"Quem disse a frase \\"O que é aiorriu?\\"","answer":"Mari Gonzales durante sua passagem no BBB20."},{"question":"\\"Inaugura-se hoje, às 18h30, no Centro de Arte Moderna da Gulbenkian, a instalação de Doris Salcedo, \\"Plegaria Muda\\". A artista nasceu em Bogotá, Colômbia, em 1958, e sente-se uma artista do Terceiro Mundo: herança que diz ser o seu maior privilégio. Este sítio de onde vê o mundo obriga-a a uma incessante procura pelo modo como os outros vivem, pensam e sentem.\\"Quem se sente uma artista de terceiro mundo? ","answer":"Doris Salcedo"},{"question":"Klausimas: Kieno pažangos dėka XIX a. reiškiniu tapo serijiniai romanai? Atsakymas labai konkretus ir trumpas.","answer":"Spausdinimo technologijų pažanga"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe sodina?","answer":"Ny sodina dia zavamaneno tsofina amin' ny vava, toy ny fantsona mahitsy, misy lavaka milahatra manaraka ny halavany izay tampenana manontolo amin' ny rantsan-tanana afa-tsy ny iray izay avela hivoha mba hivoahan' ny haavompeo tiana ho heno. Amin' ny teny indôneziana dia atao hoe suling ny sodina."},{"question":"Wọn le olukọ-agba ti ko wa sileewe lọjọ Isinmi kuro lẹnu iṣẹ lEkiti","answer":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Ekiti ti le Olukọ-agba (Principal) ileewe girama, Methodist Girls High School, Ifaki Ekiti kuro lẹnu iṣẹ o. Wọn ni ko lọọ jokoo sile na ti awọn yoo fi mọ ijiya ti yoo tọ si i gan-an. Ohun to ṣe ni pe ko lọ sileewe ọhun ni ọjọ Isinmi, iyẹn ọjọ Aiku,  Sannde ijẹta, bẹẹ ọjọ naa ni Gomina Kayọde Fayẹmi ṣe abẹwo ojiji sibẹ.Kọmiṣanna eto ẹkọ l’Ekiti, Foluṣọ Daramọla, lo kede ijiya yii funra rẹ, to si paṣẹ pe ki igbakeji olukọ-agba naa nibẹ maa gba iṣe rẹ ṣe lẹsẹkẹsẹ. Eto ti wọn ni wọn ṣe silẹ tẹlẹ ni pe Fayẹmi yoo bẹ awọn ileewe kan wo lati mọ bi awọn ileewe naa ti gbaradi to fun iwọle awọn ọmọ ti wọn fẹe ṣedanwo oniwee mẹwaa nibẹ, ko le foju ara rẹ ri i bi wọn ti tẹ le ofin korona yii to. Ana, ọjo Aje, Mọnde, yii lawọn akẹkọọ naa pada sileewe wọn lati bẹrẹ imurasilẹ fun idanwo aṣejade. Ṣugbọn ijọba ti ṣekilọ pe gbogbo ileewe gbọdọ tẹ le ofin korona, ohun ti Fayẹmi n tori rẹ ṣe abẹwo ojiji kiri ree.Ileeṣẹ eleto-ẹkọ nibẹ ni awọn ti fi ọrọ ranṣẹ si gbogbo ileewe pe gomina naa yoo maa jade kaakiri. Boya olukọ-agba yii ko waa mọ pe gomina yii le de adugbo awọn ni o, tabi boya nnkan mi-in lo ṣẹlẹ, ohun to sa han ni pe nigba ti Fayẹmi de, ko si oluko-agbba nileewe naa, abẹwo ibẹ ko si ṣee ṣe. Ohun to fa ibinu ree, ni wọn ba da ọga naa duro ko ma de ileewe mọ, titi ti ijọba yoo fi mọ ohun ti wọn yoo ṣe fun un."},{"question":"भौगोलिक छ्येत्रले मनाइने चाडपर्वहरुमा कसरी प्रभाव पार्छ ?","answer":"जलवायु, भूभाग, र ऐतिहासिक सन्दर्भ जस्ता भौगोलिक कारकहरूले मनाइने चाडपर्वहरुमा प्रभाव पार्छ । यस्ले मनाइने चाडपर्वहरुमा क्षेत्रविशेषका कारणहरु समावेश गर्दछ ।"},{"question":"નાર્કોસ અમેરિકન સીરીઝ વિશે કહો.","answer":"નાર્કોસ એ અમેરિકન ક્રાઈમ ડ્રામા ટેલિવિઝન શ્રેણી છે જે ક્રિસ બ્રાન્કાટો, કાર્લો બર્નાર્ડ અને ડગ મીરો દ્વારા બનાવવામાં આવી છે. કોલંબિયામાં સેટ અને ફિલ્માંકન કરાયેલ, સીઝન 1 અને 2 કોલમ્બિયન નાર્કોટેરરિસ્ટ અને ડ્રગ કિંગપિન પાબ્લો એસ્કોબારની વાર્તા પર આધારિત છે, જે મેડેલિન કાર્ટેલના નેતા છે અને કોકેઈનના ઉત્પાદન અને વિતરણ દ્વારા અબજોપતિ બન્યા છે. આ શ્રેણી એસ્કોબારના ડ્રગ લોર્ડ્સ, ડ્રગ એન્ફોર્સમેન્ટ એડમિનિસ્ટ્રેશન (DEA) એજન્ટો અને વિવિધ વિરોધી સંસ્થાઓ સાથેની ક્રિયાપ્રતિક્રિયાઓ પર પણ ધ્યાન કેન્દ્રિત કરે છે. એસ્કોબારના પતન પછી સીઝન 3 શરૂ થાય છે અને તેઓ કુખ્યાત કાલી કાર્ટેલના ઉદયને બંધ કરવાનો પ્રયાસ કરતા DEAને અનુસરવાનું ચાલુ રાખે છે."},{"question":"نيوٽن جي حرڪت جا ٽي قانون ڪهڙا آهن؟","answer":"نيوٽن جا ٽي قانون حرڪت جا بنيادي اصول آهن ڪلاسيڪل ميڪانڪس ۾. پهريون قانون، جنهن کي اڪثر ڪري قانون جو inertia سڏيو ويندو آهي، اهو ٻڌائي ٿو ته ڪا شئي باقي رهي يا هڪ جهڙي حرڪت ۾ هڪ سڌي لڪير ۾ جيستائين ڪنهن بيروني قوت طرفان عمل نه ڪيو وڃي. هي قانون inertia جو تصور متعارف ڪرايو آهي، شين جو رجحان انهن جي حرڪت جي حالت ۾ تبديلين جي مزاحمت ڪرڻ لاء. ٻيو قانون ڪنهن شئي جي ماس، ان تي لاڳو ٿيندڙ قوت، ۽ ان جي رفتار جي وچ ۾ تعلق جي وضاحت ڪري ٿو. اهو اڪثر F = ma جي طور تي لکيو ويندو آهي، جتي F لاڳو ٿيل قوت آهي، m اعتراض جو ماس آهي، ۽ a آهي پيدا ٿيندڙ تيز رفتار. ٽيون قانون ٻڌائي ٿو ته هر عمل لاءِ هڪ برابر ۽ مخالف ردعمل هوندو آهي. مطلب ته جڏهن به ڪا شئي ٻي شئي تي زور لڳائي ٿي ته ٻي شئي پهرين تي برابر ۽ مخالف قوت استعمال ڪري ٿي. اهي قانون شيون جي حرڪت جي تجزيي لاءِ بنياد بڻجن ٿا ۽ ميڪانيات جي اصولن کي سمجهڻ لاءِ بنيادي آهن."},{"question":"පොළොන්නරුව වටදාගෙය කුමක් සඳහා ඉඳිකරන ලද ගොඩනැගිල්ලක් ද?","answer":"පෞරාණික නිර්මාණයක් වන පොළොන්නරුව වටදාගෙය, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පොළොන්නරුව යුගයේ ඉදිවූවකි. මෙය පළමුවන පරාක්‍රමබාහු රජ සමයේ, බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේගේ ශ්‍රී දන්ත ධාතුන් වහන්සේ තැන්පත් කිරීමට හෝ නිශ්ශංක මල්ල රජ සමයේ, බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේගේ පාත්‍ර ධාතුව තැන්පත් කිරීමට ඉදිකරවූවක් බවට විශ්වාසයන් පවතී. එකල මෙම පූජනීය ධාතූන් රාජ්‍යත්වයේ සංකේතයන් විය. පොළොන්නරුව ඓතිහාසික නගරය තුල පිහිටා ඇති මෙය රට තුල සංරක්ෂණය වී ඇති විශිෂ්ටතම වටදාගෙය මෙන්ම මෙම මාදිලියේ වාස්තුවිද්‍යාවේ අත්‍යන්ත සමෘද්ධිය විද්‍යාමාන කර‍යි. ශතවර්ෂ ගණනාවක් ජරාවාස වී තිබීමෙන් අනතුරුව 1903දී පොළොන්නරුව වටදාගෙයෙහි කැණීම් ආරම්භ විය."},{"question":"Khoảng bao nhiêu năm thì lịch âm có năm nhuận (năm có thêm một tháng nhuận)?","answer":"Một năm Âm lịch dài khoảng 354 ngày, như vậy sau mỗi năm, Âm lịch dư ra số ngày: 365 - 354 = 11 ngày. Do đó, khoảng gần ba năm sẽ dư một tháng Âm lịch (tháng nhuận)."},{"question":"Билимдүүнүн сөзү арыбайт,Булактын суусу карыбайт.","answer":"Билимдүү адам маанилүү сөздөрдү, пайдалуу сөздөрдү айтканы үчүн, анын айткан сөздөрү арыбайт, ошондой эле булактын суусу таза болуп, дайым агып тургандыктан ал карыбайт."},{"question":"வினா :தமிழ்நாட்டின் சமூக அமைப்பு குறித்து விரிவாக கூற முடியுமா?","answer":"விடை :தமிழ்நாட்டின் சமூக அமைப்பு பல்வேறு இனக்குழுக்களையும் சமூக வகுப்புகளையும் உள்ளடக்கியது. தமிழ்நாட்டில் பல சமூக அமைப்புக்கள் சமூகத்தில் சமத்துவம் மற்றும் சகோதரத்துவத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு பணியாற்றி வருகின்றன. தமிழ்நாட்டின் சமூக அமைப்பு மாநிலத்தின் பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் அரசியல் வளர்ச்சிக்கு பெரும் பங்களிப்பு செய்கிறது."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagaimana pohon tiada akan tumbang dipanah halilintar sebab baluh kulit ada di batangnya\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang bersubahat dengan orang jahat akhirnya akan binasa walaupun keturunan orang baik-baik."},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Ragal-leen bis boo xam ne bakkan du fa jariñ dara beneen bakkan; te duñu ko nangul rammu; duñu ko nangul njote. Te deesuleen dimbali.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Ragalléen bis boo xàm ne bakkan du fa jàriñ dara beneen bakkan; te du ñu ko nangul rammu; du ñu ko nangul njote. Te deesu léen dimble."},{"question":"Apakah cara-cara untuk mengatasi tekanan sendiri?","answer":"Tekanan atau stres boleh diatasi dengan berkongsi masalah atau bercerita tentang perkara yang dilalui kepada individu yang dipercayai. Alternatif lain yang dapat dilakukan oleh individu bagi mengelakkan tekanan atau stres adalah dengan melakukan aktiviti riadah seperti bersenam atau bersukan. Jika dilihat pada sudut pandang yang berlainan, tekanan dapat dielakkan dengan mendekatkan diri kepada Tuhan. Hal ini demikian kerana, ketenangan hati dan segala urusan duniawi adalah kurniaan dan ujian yang diberikan oleh Tuhan. Maka, kita seharusnya sentiasa bermuhasabah diri sama ada perkara atau kehidupan yang kita jalani seiring dengan ajaran dan kehendak Beliau."},{"question":"Quel a été le premier mammifère cloné ?","answer":"Le premier mammifère cloné été une brebis qui s'appelle Dolly. Elle est née le 5 juillet 1996 à Institut Roslin, et morte le 14 février 2003 au même endroit. Elle est une brebis célèbre pour être le premier clone de mammifère de l'histoire, obtenu à partir d'un noyau de cellule somatique adulte par l'équipe de Keith Campbell et Ian Wilmut chez PPL Therapeutics, en association avec l'Institut Roslin à Édimbourg en Écosse."},{"question":"Tìm ý và lập dàn ý cho Trao đổi về vấn đề “Chơi game chỉ có tác hại. Đúng hay sai?”","answer":"- Tìm ý:+ Game là một loại phần mềm được tạo ra bởi các nhà lập trình và được cài đặt vào các thiết bị điện tử với mục đích chính là cung cấp cho con người một công cụ giải trí. Ví dụ như DOTA 2, FIFA, Candy Crush Saga,…+ Lợi ích của việc chơi game:  Một công cụ giải trí. Vận động đầu óc một cách thoải mái Được công nhận là một môn thể thao điện tử viết tắt là E-Sports.+ Tác hại của việc chơi game: Dễ khiến việc học hành chậm tiến, hình thành các thói quen xấu như trộm cắp, nói dối cha mẹ,... Chơi game quá nhiều còn đem đến những ảnh hưởng vô cùng nghiêm trọng đến sức khỏe.+ Nên chơi game điều độ, dành một chút thời gian mỗi ngày để chơi.- Lập dàn ý:+ Mở đầu: Chơi game mang đến tác hại hay lợi ích?+ Nội dung chính:  Game là một loại phần mềm được tạo ra bởi các nhà lập trình và được cài đặt vào các thiết bị điện tử với mục đích chính là cung cấp cho con người một công cụ giải trí. Ví dụ như DOTA 2, FIFA, Candy Crush Saga,… Mặt tiêu cực:○ Dễ khiến việc học hành chậm tiến, hình thành các thói quen xấu như trộm cắp, nói dối cha mẹ,...○ Chơi game quá nhiều còn đem đến những ảnh hưởng vô cùng nghiêm trọng đến sức khỏe. Mặt tích cực:○ Một công cụ giải trí.○ Vận động đầu óc một cách thoải mái○ Được công nhận là một môn thể thao điện tử viết tắt là E-Sports. Nguyên nhân khiến các bạn trẻ nghiện game:○ Sự thiếu hiểu biết và không biết kiểm soát.○ Các bậc phụ huynh đó thiếu quan tâm, giáo dục đối với con cái.○ Nhà trường là sự thiếu tuyên truyền, giáo dục cho học sinh về tác hại của việc chơi game quá mức.+ Kết thúc:  Phương thức giải trí như chơi game không hề xấu nhưng lạm dụng quá mức thì sẽ thành nghiện.  Phải tự ý thức được mức độ giải trí, không nên quá đắm chìm vào việc chơi game mà bỏ bê việc học hành, sức khỏe."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి పర్యాయ పదాలని ఇవ్వండి: వెన్నెల","answer":"వెన్నెల పదానికి పర్యాయ పదాలు: కౌముది, జ్యోత్స్న, చంద్రిక"},{"question":"iza no tena mpampiasa ny lakana?","answer":"ny mpanjono an-dranomasina no tena mampiasa ny lakana"},{"question":"Un ejemplo de trivia en la siguiente categoría: politica","answer":"¿Fue Donald Trump vicepresidente antes de convertirse en presidente de los Estados Unidos? No"},{"question":"ما هو عدد الاسنان لدى القط؟","answer":"الجواب: أربعون سن."},{"question":"What is the historical significance of Sri Lanka's \\"Aligala\\" cave complex, and how do the intricate rock carvings, ancient inscriptions, and spiritual contexts distinguish this exceptionally rare archaeological site?","answer":"The \\"Aligala\\" cave complex in Sri Lanka holds immense historical significance, dating back to the prehistoric period. Carved into the rock surface are intricate depictions of flora, fauna, and early human activities, providing a unique glimpse into ancient Sri Lankan life. The positive impact lies in the preservation of rare rock art, showcasing the artistic capabilities and cultural practices of early inhabitants. Embracing \\"Aligala\\" ensures the conservation of this archaeological treasure, contributing to our understanding of the island's prehistoric heritage."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Na jakim terytorium Kanady znajduje się wyspa Vancouver?","answer":"Odpowiedź to: Kolumbia Brytyjska."},{"question":"આદિવાસી સંસ્કૃતિની ભાષા તથા વ્યાકરણ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"આદિવાસીઓની બોલી અને વ્યાકરણ ઘણાં અનોખા છે. જોકે અન્ય ભાષાઓની જેમં તેનું કોઇ લિખીત સ્વરૂપ નથી તેથી તે બોલી પુરતી જ સિમીત રહી શકી છે. આદિવાસી બોલીના ઘણાખરા શબ્દો આપણને થોડા સંસ્કૃત થોડા મરાઠી તથા થોડા ગુજરાતી જેવા લાગે છે.આદિવાસીઓની મુખ્ય બોલીઓમાં પંચમહાલ અને દાહોદ જિલ્લામાં બોલાતી ભીલી, ગામીત બોલી, વસાવા બોલી, કુકણા બોલી,ધોડીયા બોલી, ચૌધરી બોલી,રાઠવી,તડવી બોલી વગેરે આવે છે. આ તમામ બોલીઓમાં બહુવચન હોતુ નથી, તેમાં ઉમરમાં નાની વ્યકિત ને પણ તું અને ઉમરમાં મોટી વ્યકિત નેપણ તું કહીને બોલાવવામાં આવે છે. તે ઉપરાંત અન્ય ભાષાઓની જેમ તેમાં ૧૨ કાળ, પુલ્લિંગ અને સ્ત્રીલીંગ, તથા ક્રિયાપદો હોય છે."},{"question":"Tính một cách hợp lí:a) (– 6) . (– 3) . (– 5);b) 41 . 81 – 41. (– 19).","answer":"Lời giải:a) (– 6) . (– 3) . (– 5) = [(–6) . (– 5)] . (– 3)                 (tính chất giao hoán và kết hợp)= 30 . (– 3) = – 90. b) 41 . 81 – 41 . (– 19) = 41 . [81 – (– 19)]          (tính chất phân phối của phép nhân đối với phép trừ)= 41 . (81 + 19) = 41 . 100= 4 100. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mata duitan'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Makud simpulan bahasa tersebut ialah orang yang tamakkan wang. Contoh ayat: Zainon mata duitan sebab itulah suaminya terpaksa bekerja bertungkus-lumus untuk mencari wang yang lebih."},{"question":"Hingga kini, tuberkulosis (TBC) masih menjadi momok kesehatan di Indonesia. TBC di Indonesia memiliki sejarah panjang. TBC di Indonesia diduga sudah ada sejak abad ke-8. Dugaan tersebut merujuk pada penemuan relief yang menggambarkan seorang bertubuh kurus sedang sakit di panel Lalitawistara, salah satu relief Candi Borobudur.Apakah nama penyakit yang disebutkan pada paragraf di atas?Jawaban:","answer":"Penyakit yang masih menjadi momok kesehatan di Indonesia yang disebutkan pada paragraf di atas adalah penyakit tuberkulosis (TBC)."},{"question":"எந்த நோய் பாக்டீரியாக்களால் உருவாக்கப்படாதது?","answer":"டெங்கு.முடக்குக்காய்ச்சல் அல்லது முடக்கம்மை அல்லது டெங்குக் காய்ச்சல் (Dengue fever) என்ற டெங்கி காய்ச்சல் அல்லது எலும்பு முறிவுக் காய்ச்சல் மனிதர்களிடையே டெங்கு வைரசால் ஏற்படும் ஒரு அயனமண்டலத் தொற்றுநோய் ஆகும், இது கொசுக்களால் பரவுகிறது. இந்நோய் வந்தால் கடும்காய்ச்சலுடன் கடுமையான மூட்டு வலி, தசை வலி, தலைவலி, தோல் நமைச்சல் போன்ற உணர்குறிகள் ஏற்படும். தொற்றுநோய் தீவிரமடைந்த நிலையில் உயிருக்குத் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் டெங்கு குருதிப்போக்குக் காய்ச்சல் (கடுமையான குருதிப்போக்கை ஏற்படுத்தும்) மற்றும் டெங்கு அதிர்ச்சிக் கூட்டறிகுறி என்பன உண்டாகும். இது உயிர் ஆபத்துகளை விளைவிக்கக் கூடிய ஒரு கொடிய நோயாகும். இது உடலை மிகவும் வருத்தும் நோய் ஆகையால் எலும்பை முறிக்கும் காய்ச்சல் எனவும் அழைக்கப்படும்.வடக்கு ஆர்ஜெண்டீனா, வடக்கு அவுஸ்திரேலியா, பங்களாதேஷ், பார்படோஸ், பொலிவியா, பெலிஸ், பிரேசில், கம்போடியா, கொலம்பியா, கோஸ்ட்டா ரிக்கா, கியூபா, பிரான்ஸ், கெளதமாலா, குயான, ஹெயிட்டி, இந்தியா, இந்தோனேசியா, இலங்கை போன்ற வறண்ட, உலர் வெப்ப வலய நாடுகளில் இந்த நோய் பெரும்பாலும் பரவுகின்றது.ஏடிஸ் எஜிப்தி என்ற கொசு கடிப்பதன் மூலமாக மனிதர்களுக்கு டெங்கு காய்ச்சல் பரவுகிறது. காலை மற்றும் மாலை நேரங்களில் மட்டுமே இந்த கொசுக்களை பார்க்க முடியும். டெங்கு காய்ச்சல் உள்ள ஒருவருக்கு மிதமான முதல் தீவிர காய்ச்சல், கடுமையான தலைவலி, கை கால் மூட்டுகளில் வலி, கண்களின் பின்புறம் வலி, ரத்தக்கசிவு போன்றவை ஏற்படும். சில சமயங்களில் தொற்றுகள் தீவிரமாகி மருத்துவமணையில் தங்கி சிகிச்சை எடுக்கும் நிலைக்கு கூட தள்ளப்படுவிர்கள்."},{"question":" Marka lagu miisaamayo gabeyga aragtida gaarriye sideeloo miisaamayaa","answer":" waxa loo kala miisaamayaa hoojis iyo hooris"},{"question":"இந்த உரை என்ன முக்கியமான நிகழ்வைப் பற்றியது:தியோபந்தி என்பது இசுலாமின் சுன்னி பிரிவினரிடையே தோற்றுவிக்கப்பட்ட ஒரு மறுமலர்ச்சி இயக்கமாகும். இவ்வியக்கம் இந்தியா, பாக்கித்தான், ஆப்கானித்தான், வங்காளதேசம் ஆகிய நாடுகளில் இயங்குகிறது. தற்போது ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம், தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா வரை பரவியுள்ளது. இவ்வியக்கத்தின் பெயர் இந்தியாவின் உத்தரப்பிரதேச மாநிலத்தில் உள்ள தேவபந்து நகரின் பெயரில் இருந்து பிறந்தது. இந்நகரில் தாருல் உலூம் தேவ்பந்து பள்ளி அமைந்துள்ளது. இவ்வியக்கம் ஒரு தசாப்தத்திற்கு முன்னர் தோல்வியுற்ற சிப்பாய்க் கிளர்ச்சியின் பின்னணியில் 1867 இல் நிறுவப்பட்டது.","answer":"தியோபந்தி இயக்கம்."},{"question":"Skriv om detta till formellt språk: \\"Tjabba! Hur e leeeget?!\\"","answer":"Hej! Hur mår ni?"},{"question":"Menene launukan tutar ƙasar ta Jamus?","answer":"Baki, ja, da kalar zinariya"},{"question":"Viết và tính các lũy thừa sau:a) Năm mũ hai;b) Hai lũy thừa bảy;c) Lũy thừa bậc ba của sáu.","answer":"a) \\"Năm mũ hai\\" được viết là 5^2 Ta có: 5^2 = 5 . 5 = 25.b) \\"Hai lũy thừa bảy\\" được viết là 2^7 Ta có: 2^7 = 2 . 2 . 2 . 2 . 2 . 2 . 2                = 4 . 2 . 2 . 2 . 2 . 2                = 8 . 2 . 2 . 2. 2               = 16 . 2 . 2 . 2                = 32 . 2 . 2                = 64 . 2 = 128Vậy 2^7 = 128. c) \\"Lũy thừa bậc ba của sáu\\" được viết là 6^3 Ta có: 6^3 = 6 . 6 . 6 = 36 . 6 = 216. "},{"question":"క్రింది వానిలో సరియగు జత ………..A) BeCl2 – బంధకోణం 120°B) BF3 – బంధకోణం 180°C) NH3 – బంధకోణం 104°27′D) CH4 – బంధకోణం 109°28′","answer":"D) CH4 – బంధకోణం 109°28′"},{"question":"नेपालमा मिथक, किंवदन्ती, र सांस्कृतिक सम्पदालाई पारित गर्न \\"परम्परागत कथा कथन\\" को भूमिका बारे छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"परम्परागत कथा कथनले नेपालको मिथक, किंवदन्ती र सांस्कृतिक सम्पदालाई पुस्तासम्म संरक्षण गर्न र हस्तान्तरण गर्न महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका खेल्छ।"},{"question":"በኢትዮጵያ ከባህር ጠለል 2500 ሜትር ከፍታ የምትገኝ እንዲሁም በሀገሪቱ ትልቋ ከተማ ማን ትባላለች?","answer":"አዲስ አበባ ትባላለች"},{"question":"வேட்டை+ ஆட இச்சொல்லைச் சேர்த்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது ________வேட்டையடவேட்டையாடவேட்டைஆடுவெட்டையாட","answer":"விடை : வேட்டையாட"},{"question":"Кандай жаңылмач билесиң ?","answer":"Ала улагымдын туягында ал асы,Ала улагымдын кулагынын тазасы ай.Ала улагымдын туягынын ал асы ай.Ала улагымдын туяктарын, кулактарын карачы, ай."},{"question":"waxaad Sheegtaa  Kumuu Ahaa Asxaabigii Bilaabay Taariikhda Hijriyada?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Cumar Bin Khadaab RC."},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:- Moo ndax, dangeen xeemeem [,Yéen jullit ñi,] Yahuud yi wóolu leen? Te am na ci ñoom kurél boo xam ne déggoon nañu waxi Yàlla, ba noppi soppi ko ginnaw ba ñu ca xalaatee ba xam ko.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:- Moo ndax, da ngéen xemem [,Yéen jullit ñi,] Yahuud yi wóolu leen? Te àm na ci ñoom kurel boo xàm ne déggoon na ñu wàx i Yàlla, ba noppi soppi ko ginnaw ba ñu ca xalaatee ba xàm ko."},{"question":"Berikan saya resipi untuk sup tulang merah, tunjukkan langkah-langkahnya.","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 1 kilogram tulang bahagian kaki kambing atau tulang lembu., 1/4 senduk tomato sos, 1/2 senduk cili sos, 1/4 senduk minyak untuk menumis., 5 ulas bawang merah, 5 ulas bawang putih, 1 inci halia, 1 sudu besar jintan manis, 1 sudu besar jintan putih, 1 sudu besar serbuk ketumbar, sedikit rempah kasar 4 beradik (bunga lawang, buah pelaga, cengkih dan kayu manis), garam secukup rasa.Langkah penyediaan:1. Rebus daging sehingga empuk.2. Tumis bawang merah, bawang putih, halia dan empat beradik sehingga naik bau.3. Kemudian masukkan jintan manis, jintan putih dan serbuk ketumbar.4. Setelah pecah minyak, masukkan air anggaran satu liter.5. Apabila air sudah mendidih masukkan sos cili, sos tomato dan garam secukup rasa.6. Boleh masukkan daging dan masak sehingga sedikit pekat.7. Sedia untuk dihidangkan."},{"question":"Атам аттарына кыскача түшүндүрмө.АБАЗ атынын мааниси кандай?","answer":"Бул ысымдын негизи эки түрдүү чечмеленет: 1) арабча “тилек, үмүт”; 2) тажикче “добуш, үн”, мындайча айтканда: а) бала келечекте атаэнесинин улантуучусу болсун; б) ата-эненин бактылуу турмушунун шаңы, добушу, бийик чыккан үнү болсун деген тилекте кыз балдарга да, эркек балдарга да коюла берет. Эки (сейрек үч) компоненттүү аттардын биринчи бөлүгүн түзөт: Абазбек, Абазкан, Абазбүбү, Абазгүл ж.б. Апаз, Апас; Аппаз, Аппас; Апыс деген антропонимдер дагы ушул ысым менен байланыштуу."},{"question":"नेपालमा सामान्य जनसङ्ख्यामा उपलब्ध स्वास्थ्य सेवा पूर्वाधार र चिकित्सा सेवाहरूमा ब्रेन ड्रेनको प्रभावबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"ब्रेन ड्रेनले नेपालको स्वास्थ्य सेवा पूर्वाधारमा महत्त्वपूर्ण असर पार्छ, जसले गर्दा दक्ष चिकित्सा पेशेवरहरूको अभाव हुन्छ। यो अभावले सर्वसाधारण जनताको पहुँचमा उपलब्ध चिकित्सा सेवाको गुणस्तरलाई असर गर्छ।"},{"question":"Dárúkọ ọ̀kan nínú ohun tí a fi ń ṣe ìtọjú aláìsàn.","answer":"Àgbo ni."},{"question":"大相撲で支度部屋から土俵に向かう通路のことを何という？","answer":"花道です。"},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 政府は22日、将来のエネルギーの計画について会議を開きました。この会議で、地球の気温を上げるガスを出さないようにしながら、必要な電気をつくるための考え方を決めました。新しい考え方では、政府の原子力発電所についての考え方が大きく変わります。2011年に福島県の原発で事故が起こったあと、政府は新しい原発を作らないと言っていました。しかし、古い原発の代わりに、新しい技術を使った安全な原発を作ると決めました。1つの原発を動かすのは法律で60年までと決まっています。しかし、検査などで止まっている間は計算に入れないと決めて、60年より長く動かすことができるようにします。政府は来年の国会で、この考え方について話し合いたいと考えています。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"நைட்ரஜன் பற்றி குறிப்பு வரைக.விளக்குக?","answer":"உறுப்பு பெயர்: நைட்ரஜன்உறுப்பு சின்னம்: என்அணு எண்: 7அணு எடை: 14.006தோற்றம்: நைட்ரஜன் சாதாரண வெப்பநிலை மற்றும் அழுத்தத்தின் கீழ் மணமற்ற, சுவையற்ற, வெளிப்படையான வாயு ஆகும்.வகைப்பாடு: உலோகம் அல்லாத ( Pnictogen )எலக்ட்ரான் கட்டமைப்பு: [அவர்] 2s2 2p3நைட்ரஜன் அணு எண் 7, அதாவது ஒவ்வொரு நைட்ரஜன் அணுவிலும் 7 புரோட்டான்கள் உள்ளன. அதன் தனிம சின்னம் N. நைட்ரஜன் அறை வெப்பநிலை மற்றும் அழுத்தத்தில் மணமற்ற, சுவையற்ற மற்றும் நிறமற்ற வாயு ஆகும். இதன் அணு எடை 14.0067.நைட்ரஜன் வாயு (N 2 ) பூமியின் காற்றின் அளவு 78.1% ஆகும். இது பூமியில் மிகவும் பொதுவான இணைக்கப்படாத (தூய) உறுப்பு ஆகும். சூரிய குடும்பம் மற்றும் பால்வீதியில் (ஹைட்ரஜன், ஹீலியம் மற்றும் ஆக்சிஜனை விட மிகக் குறைந்த அளவுகளில் உள்ளது, எனவே கடினமான உருவத்தைப் பெறுவது கடினம்) 5வது அல்லது 7வது மிக அதிகமாக உள்ள தனிமமாக மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது . பூமியில் வாயு பொதுவானது என்றாலும், மற்ற கிரகங்களில் அது அவ்வளவு அதிகமாக இல்லை. உதாரணமாக, செவ்வாய் கிரகத்தின் வளிமண்டலத்தில் நைட்ரஜன் வாயு சுமார் 2.6 சதவீத அளவில் காணப்படுகிறது.நைட்ரஜன் ஒரு உலோகம் அல்லாதது . இந்த குழுவில் உள்ள மற்ற கூறுகளைப் போலவே, இது வெப்பம் மற்றும் மின்சாரத்தின் மோசமான கடத்தி மற்றும் திட வடிவத்தில் உலோக காந்தி இல்லை.நைட்ரஜன் வாயு ஒப்பீட்டளவில் மந்தமானது , ஆனால் மண்ணின் பாக்டீரியாக்கள் நைட்ரஜனை ஒரு வடிவத்தில் 'சரிசெய்ய' முடியும், இது தாவரங்கள் மற்றும் விலங்குகள் அமினோ அமிலங்கள் மற்றும் புரதங்களை உருவாக்க பயன்படுத்தலாம் .பிரெஞ்சு வேதியியலாளர் Antoine Laurent Lavoisier நைட்ரஜன் அசோட் என்று பெயரிட்டார் , அதாவது \\"உயிர் இல்லாமல்\\". பெயர் நைட்ரஜன் ஆனது, இது கிரேக்க வார்த்தையான நைட்ரான் என்பதிலிருந்து உருவானது , அதாவது \\"சொந்த சோடா\\" மற்றும் மரபணுக்கள் , அதாவது \\"உருவாக்கும்\\". தனிமத்தின் கண்டுபிடிப்புக்கான கடன் பொதுவாக டேனியல் ரூதர்ஃபோர்டுக்கு வழங்கப்படுகிறது, அவர் 1772 இல் காற்றிலிருந்து பிரிக்கப்படலாம் என்று கண்டறிந்தார்.நைட்ரஜன் சில சமயங்களில் \\"எரிந்த\\" அல்லது \\" டிஃப்லாஜிஸ்டிக்டேட்டட் \\" காற்று என்று குறிப்பிடப்படுகிறது , ஏனெனில் ஆக்ஸிஜனைக் கொண்டிருக்காத காற்று கிட்டத்தட்ட அனைத்து நைட்ரஜனும் ஆகும். காற்றில் உள்ள மற்ற வாயுக்கள் மிகக் குறைந்த செறிவுகளில் உள்ளன.நைட்ரஜன் கலவைகள் உணவுகள், உரங்கள், விஷங்கள் மற்றும் வெடிப்பொருட்களில் காணப்படுகின்றன. உங்கள் உடல் எடையில் 3% நைட்ரஜன் உள்ளது. அனைத்து உயிரினங்களிலும் இந்த உறுப்பு உள்ளது.அரோராவின் ஆரஞ்சு-சிவப்பு, நீலம்-பச்சை, நீலம்-வயலட் மற்றும் ஆழமான ஊதா நிறங்களுக்கு நைட்ரஜன் பொறுப்பு.நைட்ரஜன் வாயுவை தயாரிப்பதற்கான ஒரு வழி வளிமண்டலத்திலிருந்து திரவமாக்கல் மற்றும் பகுதியளவு வடிகட்டுதல் ஆகும். திரவ நைட்ரஜன் 77 K (−196 °C, −321 °F) இல் கொதிக்கிறது. நைட்ரஜன் 63 K (-210.01 °C) இல் உறைகிறது.திரவ நைட்ரஜன் என்பது ஒரு கிரையோஜெனிக் திரவம் , இது தொடர்பில் இருக்கும் போது தோலை உறைய வைக்கும் திறன் கொண்டது. லைடன்ஃப்ராஸ்ட் விளைவு சருமத்தை மிக சுருக்கமான வெளிப்பாட்டிலிருந்து (ஒரு வினாடிக்கும் குறைவாக) பாதுகாக்கும் அதே வேளையில், திரவ நைட்ரஜனை உட்கொள்வது கடுமையான காயத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும். ஐஸ்கிரீம் தயாரிக்க திரவ நைட்ரஜனைப் பயன்படுத்தும்போது, ​​நைட்ரஜன் ஆவியாகிறது. இருப்பினும், காக்டெய்ல்களில் மூடுபனியை உருவாக்க திரவ நைட்ரஜன் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது, திரவத்தை உட்கொள்வதில் உண்மையான ஆபத்து உள்ளது . வாயு விரிவடைவதால் ஏற்படும் அழுத்தம் மற்றும் குளிர் வெப்பநிலையில் இருந்து சேதம் ஏற்படுகிறது.நைட்ரஜனின் வேலன்ஸ் 3 அல்லது 5 ஆகும். இது எதிர்மறையாக சார்ஜ் செய்யப்பட்ட அயனிகளை (அயனிகள்) உருவாக்குகிறது, அவை மற்ற உலோகங்கள் அல்லாதவற்றுடன் உடனடியாக வினைபுரிந்து கோவலன்ட் பிணைப்புகளை உருவாக்குகின்றன.சனிக்கோளின் மிகப்பெரிய நிலவான டைட்டன், சூரிய குடும்பத்தில் அடர்த்தியான வளிமண்டலத்தைக் கொண்ட ஒரே நிலவு ஆகும். அதன் வளிமண்டலம் 98% நைட்ரஜனைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.நைட்ரஜன் வாயு தீப்பிடிக்காத பாதுகாப்பு வளிமண்டலமாக பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. தனிமத்தின் திரவ வடிவம் மருக்களை அகற்றவும், கணினி குளிரூட்டியாகவும், கிரையோஜெனிக்ஸ் செய்யவும் பயன்படுகிறது. நைட்ரஜன் நைட்ரஸ் ஆக்சைடு, நைட்ரோகிளிசரின், நைட்ரிக் அமிலம் மற்றும் அம்மோனியா போன்ற பல முக்கியமான சேர்மங்களின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும். மற்ற நைட்ரஜன் அணுக்களுடன் உருவாகும் மூன்று பிணைப்பு நைட்ரஜன் மிகவும் வலிமையானது மற்றும் உடைக்கப்படும்போது கணிசமான ஆற்றலை வெளியிடுகிறது, அதனால்தான் இது வெடிமருந்துகளில் மிகவும் மதிப்புமிக்கது மற்றும் கெவ்லர் மற்றும் சைனோஅக்ரிலேட் பசை (\\"சூப்பர் க்ளூ\\") போன்ற \\"வலுவான\\" பொருட்களில் உள்ளது.பொதுவாக \\"தி வளைவுகள்\\" என்று அழைக்கப்படும் டிகம்ப்ரஷன் நோய், இரத்த ஓட்டம் மற்றும் உறுப்புகளில் நைட்ரஜன் வாயு குமிழ்கள் உருவாக காரணமாக அழுத்தம் குறையும் போது ஏற்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Tác phẩm Việt Bắc với những câu thơ sau là sáng tác của ai?Mình về mình có nhớ ta?Mười lăm năm ấy thiết tha mặn nồng.Mình về mình có nhớ khôngNhìn cây nhớ núi, nhìn sông nhớ nguồn?","answer":"đây là tác phẩm của nhà thơ Tố HữuTố Hữu (1920-2002) được đánh giá là nhà thơ tiêu biểu nhất của dòng thơ cách mạng với khối lượng tác phẩm đồ sộ, trong đó nhiều bài thơ được đưa vào giảng dạy trong chương trình Văn học ở phổ thông như: Từ ấy, Lượm, Tiếng chổi tre, Việt Bắc... Các tập thơ của Tố Hữu đã xuất bản gồm: Từ ấy (1946), Việt Bắc (1954), Gió lộng (1961), Ra trận (1972), Máu và hoa (1977), Một tiếng đờn (1992).Tháng 7/1954, Hiệp định Genève được ký kết, hòa bình trở lại. Tháng 10/1954, những người kháng chiến từ miền núi trở về miền xuôi, Trung ương Đảng và Chính phủ rời chiến khu Việt Bắc trở về Hà Nội. Nhân sự kiện có tính chất lịch sử này, Tố Hữu sáng tác bài thơ Việt Bắc.Việt Bắc là vùng phía bắc Hà Nội, ngày nay thường được hiểu gồm sáu tỉnh Cao Bằng, Bắc Kạn, Lạng Sơn, Hà Giang, Tuyên Quang, Thái Nguyên hay còn được gọi tắt là Cao - Bắc - Lạng - Hà - Tuyên - Thái.Bài thơ gồm 150 câu viết theo thể lục bát, thể hiện tinh thần quân dân thắm thiết, bền chặt như người thân trong một gia đình sau 15 năm gắn bó. Việt Bắc được chọn lọc và xuất bản lần đầu năm 1954 trong tập thơ cùng tên.Mình về mình có nhớ ta?Mười lăm năm ấy thiết tha mặn nồng.Mình về mình có nhớ khôngNhìn cây nhớ núi, nhìn sông nhớ nguồn?Tiếng ai tha thiết bên cồnBâng khuâng trong dạ, bồn chồn bước điÁo chàm đưa buổi phân lyCầm tay nhau biết nói gì hôm nay..."},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 野球の世界一を決めるWBCで、日本が準決勝に出るための試合がありました。日本はイタリアと試合をして、9-3で勝ちました。WBCで5回続けて準決勝に出ることが決まりました。この試合で大谷翔平選手は、日本の最初のピッチャーと、バッターで出ました。最初の回から速いボールや変化球などで試合を進めました。ダルビッシュ有選手などほかのピッチャーもすばらしい活躍をしました。試合の後で、栗山監督は「このチームは若い選手が多いので、野球が生まれたアメリカで大リーグの選手たちと試合をさせたいと思っていました。必ず勝つという気持ちで次の試合も頑張ります」と話しました。準決勝は、日本の時間の今月21日にアメリカのフロリダ州で行います。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- 野球: 1）九人ずつの二チームが、たがいにバットでボールを打って攻め合い、点を争う競技。ベースボール。- 準決勝: 1）勝ちぬきの試合で、決勝の一つ前の試合。- 選手: 1）競技に出るために選ばれた人。- ピッチャー: 1）野球・ソフトボールで、バッターにボールを投げる人。投手。- バッター: 1）野球・ソフトボールで、ボールを打つ人。打者。- ボール: 1）ゴムや皮で作ったまり。球。2）野球・ソフトボールで、ストライクにならない投球。- 変化球: 1）投手が投げる球のうち、打者の近くで曲がったり落ちたりするもの。シュートやカーブなど。2）目先を変えたやり方。- 進め: 1）前のほうへ出す。2）程度を上げる。3）ものごとを、はかどらせる。4）時計の針を早める。- 活躍: 1）めざましく働くこと。- 監督: 1）指図や取りしまりなどをすること。また、その人。- チーム: 1）競技や仕事をするときの、組や団体。"},{"question":"बिद्यादेवी भण्डारीको श्रीमानको नाम के हो?  ","answer":"बिद्यादेवी भण्डारीको श्रीमानको नाम मदन भण्डारी हो। "},{"question":"Write an epic fantasy saga with multiple interconnected storylines and a richly developed fictional world.","answer":" एक ऐसा महाकाव्य फैंटेसी सागा लिखें जिसमें कई आपसी कथाएं और एक समृद्धि से विकसित किए गए काल्पनिक दुनिया हो।"},{"question":"شكون اللي الشهاده ديالو كاتساوي الشهاده ديال جوج ديال الرجال؟","answer":"خزيمة بن ثابت رضي الله عنه."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:ऐसा जो परम समर्थ । पूर्ण करी मनोरथ ।सप्रचीत भजनस्वार्थ । कल्लौ चंडीविनायेकौ ॥ २९॥अर्थ:","answer":"असे गणेशाचे अपार सामर्थ्य आहे. त्याची कृपा झाली असता भक्तांचे सर्व मनोरथ पूर्ण होऊन त्यांना अनुभवयुक्त परमार्थाची प्राप्ती होते. कलियुगात देवी (चंडी) व गणेशाची उपासना करावी, असे शास्त्र सांगते. (२९)"},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Ikan apa yang paling rajin?","answer":"Jawapan : Ikan bandaraya sebab suka cuci cermin akuarium."},{"question":"Bada Tatsuniyar Maraya da Matar Ubansa","answer":"Gata nan gata nan ku. Ta zo mu ji ta.Akwai wani yaro sunansa Janiya Jannati. Shi Janiya maraya ne, babarsa ta mutu, yana zaune tare da matar ubansa. Ita kuma wannan mata bata son wannan yaro. To dama babarsu tana da dukiya, kuma an raba musu gado. Daga cikin abubuwan da ya gada akwai wata saniya mai magana.Wannan mata kullum tana ta haƙon yadda za ta kashe yaron nan. Ashe duk abubuwan da take ƙullawa, saniyar nan ta sane da ita. Wata rana sai matar nan ta shirya cewa za ta zuba magani a cikin abinci ta baiwa yaron nan ya ci ya mutu. Sai saniyar nan ta ce da shi:Janiya, Janiya, Janiya Jannati.Za a baka tuwo da magani, Janiya Jannati.Tuwon nan idan an baka, Janiya Jannati.Kar ka ci, ka zo turkena, Janiya Jannati.Ka tona rami ka zuba, Janiya Jannati.Ka bar ɗan saura, Janiya Jannati.ka mayar ka ce ka ƙoshi, Janiya Jannati.Shike nan, sai aka baiwa yaron nan tuwo da magani a ciki. Sai ya tafi turken saniyar nan, ya haƙa rami, ya binne. Ya bar ragowa, ya mayar da akushin ya ce ya ƙoshi. Matar nan ta kashe kunne tana sauraron mutuwar yaro, amma shiru ka ke ji kamar an shuka dusa.Ana nan, ana nan, sai wata rana ta sake dabara, ta ce za ta zuba magani a kunu, ta bashi. Da yaron nan ya je gurin saniyar nan sai ta ce da shi:Janiya, Janiya, Janiya Jannati.Za a baka kunu da magani, Janiya Jannati.Amma idan an baka, Janiya Jannati.Kar ka sha kunun ka zo turkena, Janiya Jannati.Ka haƙa rami ka zuba, Janiya Jannati.Amma ka bar ɗan saura, Janiya, Jannati.Ka mayar da akushin ka ce ka ƙoshi, Janiya, Jannati.Da aka baiwa yaron nan kunu, sai ya tafi turken saniyar nan ya haƙa rami, ya juye a ciki, ya bar ragowa ya mayar ya ce ya ƙoshi. Matar nan ta karɓi akushin nan tana ta murna. Ta saurara cikin dare ko za ta ji cikin yaro ya murɗe ya mutu. Shiru, bata ji komai ba. Sai abin ya ɗaure mata kai.Ana nan, sai ta sake dabara ta ce, bari ta kai shi ɗakinta ta ƙona shi cikin dare. Da yaron nan ya je baiwa saniyar nan abinci, sai ta ce da shi:Janiya, Janiya, Janiya Jannati.Yau za a ƙona ka a ɗaki, Janiya Jannati.Amma idan aka kai ka ɗaki, Janiya Jannati.Kar ka yi barci, Janiya Jannati.Idan matar ubanka ta fita, Janiya Jannati.Ka cire rigar ɗanta ka saka, Janiya Jannati.Ka saka masa taka, Janiya Jannati.Ka tura shi makwancinka, Janiya Jannati.Kai kuma ka koma nasa ka kwanta, Janiya Jannati.Da dare ya yi, sai matar uban nasa ta ce da shi, Janiyana, na ga ɗakinka sauro yana damunka, yau ka zo ku kwana a ɗakina tare da ɗan’uwanka. Sai Janiya ya ce da ita to, zan zo.Da dare ya yi, sai Janiya ya tafi ɗakinta, ya kwanta a kan shimfiɗar da ta yi masa. Sai ya yi likimo, kamar yana barci, can tsakar dare, sai ya gan ta, ta taso saɗaf, saɗaf, ta fice waje. Kafin ta dawo sai ya ta shi a hankali ya cire kayan jikinsa ya saka wa ɗanta, shi kuma ya saka na ɗan nata. Sannan ya ɗauke shi a hankali ya kai shi makwancinsa, shi kuma ya koma makwancin ɗan nata ya kwanta. Yana gamawa sai ga matar nan ta shigo da wuta. Tana zuwa, ba ta yi wata-wata ba kawai sai ta zuba wa ɗan nan nata ba ta san shi ne ba. Da ɗan ya ji zafi, sai ya riƙa sowa yana cewa, iya ni ne fa, ita kuma tana cewa, mutu dan ubanka, yau jaraba ta ƙare. Yaron nan ya ƙone ƙurmus. Da gari ya waye, sai ta ga ashe ɗanta ta ƙona. Sai ta haɗiyi zuciya ta mutu.Tunƙurunƙus, badan Gizo ba da na yi ƙarya."},{"question":"Apakah asal-usul capati?","answer":"Capati berasal daripada perkataan bahasa India, 'Chapati' yang bermakna \\"leper bulat\\". Chapati dicatatkan di dalam Ain-i-Akbari, dokumen abad ke-16, oleh Maharaja Mughal, wazir Akbar, Abul-Fazl ibn Mubarak. Chapati adalah salah satu bentuk, di mana gandum yang ruji di utara Asia Selatan, paling banyak dimakan. Chapati adalah satu bentuk roti atau rotta (roti). Perkataan-perkataan tersebut sering digunakan silih berganti. Walaupun roti atau rotta merujuk kepada mana-mana roti yang tidak beragi rata, chapati adalah roti yang dibuat daripada tepung gandum dan dimasak pada tava (kuali rata)."},{"question":"Tunde Bello ti wọn lo fipa ba obinrin sun lẹyin to ji i gbe ti wa l’Eleweeran","answer":"L’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ni olu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to wa ni Eleweran niluu Abẹokuta, ipinlẹ Ogun, ṣafihan ọkunrin ẹni afurasi kan, Tunde Bello, ti wọn fẹsun kan pe o ji eeyan gbe, to tun fipa ba obinrin to ji gbe yii lo pọ.Ọjọ kẹtadinlogun, ọsu kẹsan-an, ọdun to kọja, ni wọn sọ pe iṣẹlẹ ọhun waye ni Mowe, nijọba ibilẹ Ọbafẹmi Owode, nipinlẹ Ogun, ni nnkan bii aago marun-un idaji.Arabinrin kan ti ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa fi orukọ bo laṣiiri lo wọ mọto Tunde Bello ni Mowe, lakooko to n ji lọ sibi iṣẹ ẹ l’Ekoo.Mọto Hyundai lo wọ lagbegbe Ogunrun, nigba to si de ojupopo nla ni Mowe lati kọri si ọna Eko ni Tunde yi ori mọto pada si ọna Ibadan, to si gbe obinrin yii lọ sinu igbo kan nibẹ.Nibẹ naa ni wọn sọ pe o ti lu arabinrin ọhun ni ilukulu, to si tun fipa ba a lopọ.Wọn ni lẹyin to ṣe bẹẹ tan lo tun fipa mu un ko maa pe awọn mọlẹbi ẹ lati fowo ranṣẹ sinu akaunti ẹ nibẹ, ti ko ba fẹẹ fiku ṣefa jẹ.Owo to to ẹgbẹrun lọna ogoje naira (#140,000) ni Tunde to n fi mọto ayọkẹlẹ gbero laarin Mowe si Eko yii gba lọwọ obinrin ọhun lẹyin to ti fipa ba a lopọ gẹge bi awọn ọlọpaa ṣe sọ.Ni kete ti obinrin yii bọ lo ti fọrọ ọhun to ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to wa ni Mọwe leti, nibẹ lawọn yẹn ti bẹrẹ iwadii tiwọn.Ọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun yii, lọwọ tẹ ẹ, bẹẹ ni wọn lo ti jẹwọ, ti ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa si ti sọ pe yoo foju bale-ẹjọ laipẹ yii.ALAROYE lanfaani lati fọrọ wa Tunde Bello lẹnu wọ, alaye to ṣe ni pe loootọ loun gbe obinrin naa ni mọto, ti oun ṣe bii ẹni to n gbero lọ si igboro Eko.Tunde ni, “Sadeede ni ẹmi buruku yii ba le mi, mi o ni in lọkan lati ja a lole rara, niṣe ni mo gbe mọto yẹn dori kọ ọna Ibadan, dipo Eko, ti mo ni mo n lọ. Nibi to ti fẹẹ fariwo bọnu ni mo ti da igbaju nla bo o, bi mo ṣe fi bẹliiti to yẹ ko fi kọrun so o mọ ara siiti ọkọ niyẹn, ti mo si gbe e wọnu igbo kan lọ. Loju-ẹsẹ nibẹ ni mo ti sọ pe owo ọwọ ẹ ni mo fẹẹ gba, nigba ti mo si wo baagi ẹ, ẹgbẹrun mejidinlogun naira pere lo wa nibẹ. Nibi ti mo ti ni ko maa pe awọn eeyan ẹ niyẹn. Eeyan meji lo fi ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọta naira (N50,000) ranṣẹ, owo bii ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun un ni mo ri gba, ki n too tu u silẹ.”Tunde fi kun un pe oun ko fipa ba obinrin naa sun gẹge bi awọn ọlọpaa ṣẹ sọ, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ọlọpaa kan sọ nibe pe oun nilo fọnran ti oun ka ọrọ ẹ si nibi to ti n ka boroboro pe loootọ loun ba obinrin naa lajọṣepọ lẹyin toun gba owo ọwọ ẹ tan.Ọkunrin yii sọ pe foonu ọmọbinrin naa ti oun gba lọwọ ẹ lo jẹ ki awọn ọlọpaa ri oun mu nigba ti wọn pe oun pe awọn fẹẹ gbe iṣẹ fun oun.O fi kun un pe iṣe awọn to n kun mọtọ loun n ṣe, o ni oun maa n ri iṣẹ gba daadaa, ati pe tẹtẹ ti oun fi gbogbo owo oun ta lo ko ironu ba oun, ti oun fi kọ lu obinrin naa, ko too di wahala si oun lọrun bayii."},{"question":"MS Word තුළදී Keyboard එකෙහි බහුලව භාවිතා කරන Keys වර්ග මොනවාද?","answer":"MS Word තුළදී Keyboard එකෙහි බහුලව භාවිතා කරන Keys වර්ග පහත දැක්වේ.·         Caps Lock Key – Caps Lock on අවස්ථාවේදී Type කරන සියලුම අකුරු කැපිටල් අකුරු වේ·         Shift Left/Right Key – Type කරන Text පමණක් කැපිටල් කර ගැනීම හෝ Button එකක ඇති Signals ඇතුළත් කර ගැනීම·         Space Bar – අකුරු අතර හිස්තැන් තැබීම·         Enter Key – Page එක තුළ පේලියෙන් පේලිය පහලට ඒම·         Back Space Key – Type කරන අතරතුර වැරදීමක් සිදුවුවහොත් Text එකින් එක ආපස්සට Delete කිරීම·         Delete Key – Cursor එකට දකුණු පසින් ඇති Text කොටස් ඉවත් කළ හැකිය"},{"question":"Inona no boky lava indrindra ao amin’ny Baiboly?","answer":"Ny boky lava indrindra ao amin’ny Baiboly dia ny Salamo, izay misy toko 150."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la capital de Tlaxcala?","answer":"La capital es Tlaxcala de Xicohténcatl y tiene 1 169 936 de habitantes."},{"question":"في أي غزوة استشهد جعفر بن أبي طالب ؟","answer":"غزوة مؤتة"},{"question":"Дай відповідь на питання: Який вид енергії використовує вітряна турбіна? Варіанти відповіді: (I) ядерну (II) теплову (III) хімічну (IV) механічну","answer":"(IV) механічну. Вітряна турбіна перетворює механічну енергію вітру на електричну. "},{"question":"Complete o seguinte trecho: Napoleão passou algum tempo como inspetor de fortificações costeiras na costa do Mediterrâneo, perto de Marselha, enquanto aguardava a confirmação do posto do Exército da Itália. Ele elaborou planos para atacar o Reino da Sardenha como parte da campanha da França","answer":"contra a Primeira Coalizão. Augustin Robespierre e Saliceti estavam prontos para ouvir o recém-promovido general de artilharia."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này:Hai mẹ con du khách Việt đuối nước khi tắm biển Phuket","answer":"Ông Suporn Muangkhai – một điều tra viên của cơ quan cảnh sát cho biết ông nhận được tin báo về vụ việc vào lúc 7h15' sáng từ lực lượng cứu hộ bờ biển. Trước đó, cờ đỏ đã được cắm dọc bãi biển để cảnh báo du khách không nên xuống tắm do gió mạnh, sóng lớn. Cảnh sát đã có mặt tại hiện trường để điều tra vụ việc, và được báo lại rằng 3 du khách Việt Nam – lưu trú tại khách sạn Pullman Phuket Arcadia Naithon – đã xuống biển bơi dù trên bờ cắm cờ đỏ. Hai mẹ con du khách Hoang H.V. (52 tuổi) và Nguyen C.A. (16 tuổi) đã bị sóng lớn cuốn trôi ra cách bờ khoảng 20m. Lực lượng cứu hộ đã nhanh chóng tiếp cận và đưa 2 người này lên bờ, đồng thời tiến hành hồi sức tim phổi. Sau đó các nạn nhân được đưa đến bệnh viện Thalang và được xác định đã tử vong. "},{"question":"Bana Türkçe bir şiir ver.","answer":"İşte Türkçe bir şiir:Kim o, deme boşuna...Benim, ben.Öyle bir ben ki gelen kapına;Başdan başa sen.Özdemir Asaf"},{"question":" Como se chamam os dois melhores amigos do personagem Harry Potter?","answer":"Hermione e Rony."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa magaca saxaabigii arkay Masiixu Dajjaal ?","answer":"Wuxuu ahaa Tamiim Binu Aws (RC)."},{"question":"السؤال: اليوم الذي خلق فيه سيدنا آدم عليه السلام، هو؟","answer":"الجواب: يوم الجمعة."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"ஜாதியை ஒழிக்காமல் பொதுவுடைமை பேசுவது - அரிச்சுவடி படிக்காமல் பி.ஏ., வகுப்பைப்பற்றி பேசுவதாகும்."},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut. Apakah kesan kepada pemandu yang menelefon semasa memandu tanpa menggunakan bantuan alat bebas tangan(hands free kit)?A. Memandu dengan selamatB. Kurang tumpuan kepada pemanduanC. Lebih tumpuan semasa memandu","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah B. Kurang tumpuan kepada pemanduan"},{"question":"உழவுத் தொழிலை வள்ளுவர் எவ்வாறு போற்றுகிறார்?","answer":"• உலகம் பல தொழில்களைச் செய்து இயங்கினாலும் (சுழன்று வந்தாலும்), உலகமானது ஏர்த்தொழிலாகிய உழவுத்தொழிலை நம்பியே அதன் பின் நிற்கிறது. அதனால் எவ்வளவு துன்பத்திற்கு உள்ளானாலும் உழவுத்தொழிலே முதன்மையான சிறந்த தொழிலாகும்.• பிற தொழில்கள் செய்யும் அனைவரையும் உழுபவரே தாங்கி நிற்பவர் ஆவார். எனவே உழவர்களே உலகத்துக்கு அச்சாணி போன்றவர் ஆவார்."},{"question":"Ayıp çeşitleri nelerdir?","answer":"Ayıp TürleriAçık Ayıp. Açık ayıp, satın alınan malın gözle görülebilecek şekilde ayıbının bulunması haline açık ayıp denir.Gizli Ayıp. Gizli ayıp, satın alınan malın gözle görülmeyen ve malın kullanılmasıyla ortaya çıkan ayıbı varsa gizli ayıp söz konusudur.Ekonomik Ayıp. ...Hukuki Ayıp."},{"question":"शक या राजाने आपली स्वतंत्र कालगणना केव्हापासून सुरू केली ?","answer":"शक या राजाने आपली स्वतंत्र कालगणना इ.स. 78 पासून सुरू केली "},{"question":"Theo em, những dòng thơ sau tả cảnh hay tả tình? Vì sao?- Giấy đỏ buồn không thắm;Mực đọng trong nghiên sầu...- Lá vàng rơi trên giấy,Ngoài giời mưa bụi bay.","answer":"Giấy đỏ buồn không thắmMực đọng trong nghiên sầuGiấy đỏ là thứ giấy dùng để ông đồ viết chữ lên, đó là một thứ giấy rất mỏng manh chỉ cần một chút ẩm ướt cũng có thể phai màu. Vậy mà “Giấy đỏ buồn không thắm”, không thắm là bởi không được sử dụng nên úa tàn theo năm tháng. Mực là thứ để ông đồ họa chữ, trước khi dùng ông phải mài rồi dùng bút long để “múa” lên các con chữ, vậy mà nay “Mực đọng trong nghiên sầu” nghĩa là mực đã được mài từ lâu, đã sẵn sàng cho bàn tay tài hoa của ông đồ để trổ tài nhưng đã đợi chờ trong vô vọng. Các từ buồn, sầu như thổi hồn vào sự vật cùng với phép nhân hóa đã khiến cho giấy đỏ, mực tàu vốn vô tri bỗng trở nên có hồn có suy nghĩ như con người.Lá vàng rơi trên giấyNgoài giời mưa bụi bayĐầu khổ thơ là hình ảnh mùa xuân với hoa đào nở, nhưng tại sao lại có lá vàng rơi? Hình ảnh lá vàng rơi gợi đến sự tàn phai, tàn lụi về một thời kỳ, một lớp người trong xã hội. Lá vàng rơi trên giấy để chỉ thế hệ ông đồ tàn phai, đã bị quên lãng. Nỗi buồn ấy âm thầm, tê tái nó đã khiến cơn mưa xuân vốn sức sống bền bỉ cũng trở nên đìu hiu xót xa “ngoài giời mưa bụi bay”. Câu thơ gợi ra tâm trạng buồn thảm của ông đồ trước cơn mưa bụi nhạt nhòa. Dẫu chỉ là mưa bay, mưa bụi nhưng nó cũng đủ sức xóa sạch đi dấu vết của một lớp người.Đó là những câu thơ tả cảnh để ngụ tình bởi vì mượn cảnh giấy đỏ buồn, mực đọng để chỉ tình cảnh đáng thương của ông đồ, mượn cảnh lá vàng, mưa bụi bay để gợi đến sự tàn phai, tàn lụi về một thời kỳ, một lớp người trong xã hội."},{"question":"توجد العديد من اسماء القرآن الكريم فما هي؟","answer":"الإجابة: من اسماء القرآن الكريم هو الكتاب، والفرقان، والقرآن."},{"question":"ਮੁੰਬਈ, 5 ਮਾਰਚਸ਼ਿਵ ਸੈਨਾ ਨੇ ਅੱਜ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਿਚਲੇ ਜੈਸ਼-ਏ-ਮੁਹੰਮਦ ਦੇ ਕੈਂਪ ’ਤੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਹਵਾਈ ਹਮਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਾਰੇ ਗਏ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਜਾਣਨ ਦਾ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਾਸੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੱਕ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਦਾ ਖ਼ੁਲਾਸਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਨਾਲ ਫੌਜੀ ਬਲਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਨੋਬਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਡਿੱਗੇਗਾ। ਭਾਈਵਾਲ ਭਾਜਪਾ ’ਤੇ ਚੁਟਕੀ ਲੈਂਦਿਆਂ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੇ ਅਖਬਾਰ ‘ਸਾਮਨਾ’ ਵਿੱਚ ਛਪੇ ਸੰਪਾਦਕੀ ਲੇਖ ਵਿਚ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਤੱਕ ਹਵਾਈ ਹਮਲਿਆਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਚਰਚਾਵਾਂ ਚੱਲਦੀਆਂ ਰਹਿਣਗੀਆਂ ਤੇ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਹਮਲੇ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ ਉਠਾਏ ਗਏ ‘ਭਖਦੇ ਮੁੱਦਿਆਂ’ ਨੂੰ ਹੁਣ ਲਾਂਭੇ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਸੰਪਾਦਕੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ, ‘‘ਦੇਸ਼ ਵਾਸੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਜਾਣਨ ਦਾ ਹੱਕ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਾਡੇ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਬਲਾਂ ਨੇ ਦੁਸ਼ਮਣ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਤੇ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਸਾਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਕਿ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਮੰਗਣ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਡੇ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਬਲਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਨੋਬਲ ਡਿੱਗੇਗਾ।’’ਕਿਹੜੀ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਦੀ ਸਹਿਯੋਗੀ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਦਿੱਤੇ  ਪੈਰੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਸ਼ਿਵ ਸੈਨ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਦੇ ਸਹਿਯੋਗੀ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"मोनालिसा या जगप्रसिध्द कलाकृतीचे निर्माते कोण आहे ? ","answer":"लिओनार्डो – दा – व्हीन्सी"},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và trả lời câu hỏi bên dưới:Câu hỏi: Tại sao nhu cầu về peel da ngày càng tăng lên?Đoạn văn: do nhu cầu làm đẹp bằng peel da ngày càng lớn nên nhiều sản phẩm được bày bán tràn lan trên thị trường cũng như mạng xã hội. Tuy nhiên, việc tự mua và thực hiện phương pháp này tại nhà tiềm ẩn rất nhiều rủi ro.Đầu tiên, việc sử dụng các sản phẩm không rõ nguồn gốc, thành phần có thể khiến da bị kích ứng, mẩn đỏ, lâu ngày sẽ khiến da trở nên nhạy cảm. Thứ hai, việc không đánh giá chính xác tình trạng, loại, các vấn đề mắc phải mà lạm dụng peel da sẽ khiến da dễ bị nám sạm, giãn mạch. Cuối cùng, việc thực hiện không đúng kỹ thuật sẽ tiềm ẩn nhiều rủi ro, như khiến da bị tổn thương, bỏng, viêm nhiễm, thậm chí để lại sẹo.Sau khi peel, da nhạy cảm cần được chăm sóc đúng cách để tối ưu hiệu quả điều trị, đẩy nhanh hồi phục và hạn chế biến chứng như viêm, nhiễm trùng.Do đó, để hiệu quả và an toàn, giúp làn da được tái sinh tươi mới, mọi người nên đến các cơ sở khám chữa bệnh uy tín để được khám, đánh giá và thực hiện bởi các bác sĩ da liễu nhiều kinh nghiệm.","answer":"Nhu cầu về peel da ngày càng tăng lên do người tiêu dùng ngày càng quan tâm đến việc làm đẹp và cải thiện tình trạng da của họ. Peel da là một phương pháp được nhiều người lựa chọn để tái tạo làn da, loại bỏ tế bào da chết, và giúp da trở nên mịn màng hơn. Sự phổ biến của các sản phẩm và quảng cáo trên mạng xã hội cũng góp phần làm tăng nhu cầu này khi mọi người tìm kiếm các giải pháp làm đẹp mà có thể thực hiện tại nhà. Tuy nhiên, như đoạn văn đã nêu, việc thực hiện peel da không đúng cách hoặc sử dụng sản phẩm không rõ nguồn gốc có thể dẫn đến những hậu quả tiêu cực cho làn da."},{"question":"IMPI YABOMDABU ISETHUNJINI – JC ButheleziFundisisa lesi siqeshana senoveli bese uphendula imibuzo elandelayo.'Sawubona Poppie. Ngiyaphila mina, wena unjani?''Sawubona bani? Mina ngithe sawubona myeni wami. Wena uthi sawubona bani?''Ngithe sawubona Poppie.''Angiyena uPoppie mina. Ngingumkakho.''Angikwazi lokho mina.''Ungathini ukuthi awukwazi lokho Ngubane?''Phela thina nawe sihlale iminyaka edlule emashumini amabili singoPoppie noBafana.Kungeke kuthi namuhla sesihlukene, bese ngibangumyeni wakho nawe ubengumkami. Thina nawe singoPoppie noBafana kwaphela nje. Angiboni ukuthi uzelapha ukuzongibuza ukuthi mina ngithi wena ungubani. Kunganjani ukuba ungeneodabeni ngoba ngimatasatasa kabi Poppie. Izinto zingimele kabi lapha emsebenzini.'Wathi ukusondeza isitulo sakhe uPoppie wasethi, 'Manje Bafana ngize lapha ukuzothimasiyeke le nto yethu yokuziphathisa okwezingane sibadala kangaka. Angiboni ukuthikukhona into engalungiswa ngokuduba. Khona ngiyazi ukuthi nina kwaNgubane nihlalangokuduba. Izinto zoniwa ngumlomo, zilungiswa ngumlomo futhi. Kuhle thina nawesihlale phansi, sibonisane, silungise lokho okonakele. Awukwazi ukuvele udubeuphume ngomnyango ungishiye nendlu nezingane.''Akukho esingakuxoxa nawe Poppie.''Singahlulwa yini myeni wami?''Singahlulwa ukuthi mina nawe siyizingane. Asivuthiwe neze.''Yini esikwenze ukuba ubone ukuthi asivuthiwe ngemuva kweminyaka engamashumiamabili nanhlanu.''Kuningi kabi Poppie.''Akusho nje okumbalwa ngizwe ukuthi kuyini.''Ukube wawuvuthiwe ngabe awulishiyanga eMlazi iBhayibheli owaliphiwa ngumama.''Awu kahle myeni wami. Wasuvusa indaba endala kangaka. Mina angisalazi ukuthilasalaphi iBhayibheli likamama wakho.''Akungimangalisi ukuthi awazi lasalaphi leli Bhayibheli ngoba ngelikamama wami,hhayi umama wethu. Eqinisweni thina nawe asikaze sibe yinto eyodwa. Angazi njeukuthi uyaphi lapha ngoba phela lokwehlukana kwethu yinto owawukade uyibumbaPoppie.''Singaba yinto eyodwa kanjani wena ungikhunga kule milando yakininakumaBhayibheli akini? Singaba yinto eyodwa kanjani wena uhlala ngokuduba umakukhona ongakuboni kahle? Nakhu manje awusahlali ekhaya ngoba ngithengeleizingane imoto, uma ungayifuni imoto, buya ekhaya sizokhuluma siyithengiseimoto.''Sihambile isikhathi manje Poppie. Ngisho ungaze uyithengise imoto ngeke iwusule lomonakalo osewenzekile ezinganeni zethu laphaya ekhaya. Zingeke ziphinde zilungelezi zingane zethu.''Manje uthi masenzenjani manje myeni wami?''Ngithi masiyeke zilime ziye etsheni. Phela igeja libanjwe yisiphukuphuku.''Noma ngonile ngathengela izingane imoto, angisona isiphukuphuku Bafana.''Lixhoshwa libhekile Ngubane. Angiboni ukuthi uma mina ngenze iphutha, kufaneleungibize ngesiphukuphuku.''Angizange ngithi wena uyisiphukuphuku. Mina ngithe igeja libanjwe yisiphukuphuku.Uma likulingana leli kepisi, ligqoke Poppie. Uyabona …'1. Chaza kafushane ukuthi lesi siqeshana siyigqamisa kanjani indikimba yokubanobuntu/nokungabi nobuntu kule noveli. ","answer":"1. Indikimba yale noveli imayelana nobuntu nokungabi nobuntu. UPoppie ufikaukhombisa ubuntu emsebenzini kaBafana umbiza kahle ngomyeni wakhe.UBafana ukhombisa ukungabi nobuntu ukhumbuza uPoppie ukuthi akazeamkhombise ubuntu ngenkathi ehlala naye iminyaka engama-25 futhiwashiya iBhayibheli aliphiwa ngunina kaBafana eMlazi. "},{"question":"Ba chomhalta de Institiúid Ríoga an Cholmúin é, den Royal Statistical Society agus den Royal Geographic Society (RGS). Ba chomhalta de Institiúid Ríoga na gColún é, an Royal Geographic Society, agus an Royal Statistical Society (RGS). Ceist: An léiríonn abairt 1 agus abairt 2 an bhrí chéanna? ","answer":"Ní léiríonn abairt 1 agus abairt 2 an bhrí chéanna"},{"question":"Mwanza ni wapi tanzania? ","answer":"Mwanza ni mkoa uliyo pakana na mara, simiyu, shinyanga, geita, na bukoba, ni eneo ambalo ziwa victoria liko ndani yake, haswa kabila kuu ni wasukuma"},{"question":"Gẹ́gẹ́ bí ọmọdé, kò wù mí kí n máa gbé nínú ìbẹ̀ru ogun","answer":"Awọn ọmọde lagbegbe Gaza ti n sọrọ sita lori oun ti wọn n foju wina bi irọkẹkẹ ada oloro ṣe n wa lati orilẹede Israel lẹyin ti awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ Hamas kan ṣe ikọlu si Israel lọjọ Satide.Gẹgẹ bi ajọ agbaye UN ṣe sọ, o to ẹgbẹrun mejila eeyan to ti di alarinkiri ati alainilelori nitori wahala naa.Fọnran kan ti Ileeṣẹ BBC gbe jade ṣe afihan bi awọn araalu Gaza ṣe n gbe ninu ibẹru, ti ọpọlọpọ dukia si ti bajẹ.Ọkan lara awọn ọmọde to ba BBC sọrọ sọ pe o wu oun pupọ ko jẹ wi pe ko si ogun ni awujọ ti oun n gbe.“Ti ko ni si ado oloro lori ile wa, ki gbogbo wa le pada si ile wa ninu alaafia “Baba onisowo, ẹni ọdun marundinlọgọta, kan pẹlu salaye bi nnkan ṣe n lọ niluu Gaza lẹyin ikọlu Israel.“Ki ni wọn tun fẹ ṣe? Ẹ saanu wa, o to gẹ.“Ẹni ọdun marindinlọgọta ni mi bayi, mo ti lo gbogbo akoko aye mi kuro lati ogun kan si kan”, eyi ni ọrọ ti ọkunrin naa sọ lẹyin ti ado oloro ṣe ijamba si ile itaja rẹ niluu Rafah ni Gaza.“Wọn ba ile wa jẹ ni Albarazeel, ni Abu Halawa, igba meji ni wọn ba ile wa jẹ.“Bayii, ile itaja mi, ti mo fi n tọ ọmọ okunrin marun un lo ti dawo yii, Ọlọrun lo ko wọn yọ, meji ninu wọn fi ẹsẹ paa”Kò sí iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná , omi, epo bẹntiro àti oúnjẹ fún Gaza mọ́ - IsraelOrilẹede Israel ti kede pe awọn yo fopin si gbogbo awọn anfani ti Gaza n jẹ lati ọdọ awọn bi ina mọnamọna, Omi, Epo bẹntiro, ati ounjẹ.Gẹgẹ bi awọn olugbe Gaza ṣe salaye pe awọn ko ti ri ohun iranwọ lati ọjọ Satide ti ikọlu ọhun ti waye.Fọnran ti BBC gbe jade se afihan awọn ijamba to waye lẹyin ikọlu ado oloro lati orilẹede Israel.O to eeyan ẹẹdẹgbẹrin to ti jade laye nitori awọn ikọlu yii, ti ogunlọgọ si farapa yanayana."},{"question":"कोविड-19 विरुद्ध लढण्यासाठी कोणत्या देशाने ‘महामारी रोग कायदा 1897’ लागू केला आहे?","answer":"भारत"},{"question":"Apakah kontroversi yang wujud dalam musim kedua untuk Malaysian Idol? Siapakah yang terlibat dalam kontroversi ini? Apakah sebab kontroversi ini berlaku dalam Malaysian Idol?","answer":"Walaupun berjaya meningkatkan bilangan penonton berbanding musim pertama (mengikut kajian media), musim kedua Malaysian Idol menerima pelbagai kritikan mengenai mutu para pesertanya, terutamanya juaranya Daniel Lee Chee Hun yang dikutuk oleh sebilangan orang sebagai tidak berbakat dalam nyanyian dan bergantung kepada paras rupanya yang \\"comel\\" untuk meraih undian oleh gadis muda. Bagaimanapun, Daniel dan peminatnya menghadapi cabaran tersebut dengan jualan album yang laris.Kontroversi yang menyelubungi Malaysian Idol tidak bermula di situ. Antara pertikaian yang terawal ialah penyingkiran Lee Kar Wei, seorang peserta perempuan yang terpuji kerana \\"nyanyiannya yang sangat bagus\\", di pusingan saringan sebelum bermulanya pertandingan, menyebabkan sebilangan penonton mempersoal kredibiliti dan profesionalisme para juri.Di pertandingan meraih undian pula, timbulnya keresahan antara sebahagian penonton setia yang mendapati bukan sahaja para peserta mempersembahkan lagu-lagu secara tidak konsisten, malah penyertaan peserta seperti Faizull dan Daniel kuat tercabar oleh orang awan yang meninggalkan pesanan di laman Internet, tambahan pula terjadinya penyingkiran awal peserta yang dianggap mereka sebagai paling bermutu, seperti Atilia, Trish dan Xerra.Yang sebenarnya ramai yang tidak berpuas hati dengan kemenangan Daniel Lee boleh disebabkan undian perkauman. Tambahan pula Malaysian Idol disiarkan di saluran Cina, itu menjadi penyebab adalah mustahil peserta bukan berbangsa Cina yang menang pertandingan ini. Sesiapa yang aktif dengan forummer di krees.com tahu bahawa pada malam penyingkiran Faizul Rock Orang Kampung, undian untuk Faizul tersekat. Ini diberitahu oleh orang dalam belakang tabir Malaysian Idol sendiri yang keluar memberitahu kepada forummer yang lain. Ramai yang tidak puas hati dengan keadaan itu, dan itulah yang menyebabkan Malaysian Idol jatuh standardnya yang tersendiri. Malah admin krees.com juga seperti berat sebelah dengan mengatakan Faizul kononnya diberikan hak untuk tidak menyanyikan lagu English. Ini adalah perbuatan yang tidak profesional. Jika Faizul adalah pilihan rakyat Malaysia untuk jadi pemenang, seharusnya tidak perlu sebarang komplot untuk buat mana-mana peserta tersingkir."},{"question":"भौतिक रूपमा नफर्की नेपालको विकासमा योगदान पुर्‍याउने दक्ष पेशेवरहरूलाई अवसरहरू प्रदान गर्न टाढाको काम र डिजिटल प्लेटफर्महरूको सम्भावनाको अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"रिमोट वर्क र डिजिटल प्लेटफर्महरूले दक्ष पेशेवरहरूलाई शारीरिक रूपमा नफर्की नेपालको विकासमा योगदान पुर्‍याउने अवसरहरू प्रदान गर्ने सम्भावना छ। भर्चुअल सहकार्य, अनलाइन परामर्श, र टाढाका परियोजनाहरूले डायस्पोराको विशेषज्ञतालाई उपयोग गर्न सक्छन्।"},{"question":"قم بكتابة مقال يجيب على هذا السؤال من هي الدولة التي يمر من خلالها نفق فيهمارنبيلت ؟.","answer":"يعمل نفق فيهمارنبيلت وخطوط السكة المزدوجة على تقليل مدة السفر بالقطار من هامبورغ, ألمانيا إلى كوبنهاغن من أربع ساعات و45 دقيقة إلى ثلاث ساعات و15 دقيقة. ووفقًا للمخططات الحالية، سيتم توفير قطار ركاب وقطاري بضائع في كل اتجاه في الساعة. وهكذا، من المحتمل حدوث ازدحام وتأخيرات في الجانب الألماني من الجسر مع حركة المرور الكثيفة هذه، وذلك إذا تأخر توسيع خط السكة الحديد."},{"question":"Ką tiria nefologija?","answer":"Nefologija yra debesų ir debesų susidarymo tyrimas. Britų meteorologas Luke'as Howardas buvo pagrindinis šios srities tyrinėtojas, sukūręs debesų klasifikavimo sistemą. Nors ši meteorologijos šaka tebeegzistuoja ir šiandien, terminas nefologija arba nefologas vartojamas retai."},{"question":"Эмнеге менин көп нерсеге убакытым жетпейт?","answer":"Пайдасыз досторуңуз көп…Эптеп эле убакыттын өтүшүн көздөп, туш келди адамдар менен убакыт өткөрүү, пайдасыз жолугушуулар, пайдасынан зыяны көп достор сизге эч качан ийгилик алып келбейт. Мындай адамдар энергиялык кан соргучтар катары бааланат. Сиз эч качан жакшы жакка өзгөрбөйсүз, болгону алардын катарын гана толуктаган болосуз. Андыктан өзүңүзгө пикирлеш адамдар менен мамиле түзүүгө алар менен пайдалуу жолугушууларды өткөрүүгө аракет жасаңыз."},{"question":"Лакаптар деген эмне?","answer":"Белгилүү бир окуядан , же адамдын мүнөзүнөн, жүрүш- турушунан улам айтылып калган, келип чыгыш тарыхы бар, эстелуу сөздөрдү лакаптар дейбиз . "},{"question":"ගොඩබිමේ ජීවත් ව​න වේගවත්ම සත්වයා කුමක්ද?","answer":"චීටා ගොඩබිමේ ජීවත් ව​න වේගවත්ම සත්වයා වේ."},{"question":"Sidee ayuu tiirka koowaad ee arkaanil-islaamku u koobayaa lixda tiir ee arkaanul-iimaanka?","answer":"LAAHU oo ah tiirka koowaad ee arkaanul-islaamka qaybtiisa hore, waxaa uu buuxiyey tiirkii koowaad ee arkaanul-iimaanka oo ahaa; \\"in Ilaahay la rumeeyo\\". Sidoo kale marka la qiro: Muxammed-un Rasuulu-Laah oo ah tiirka koowaad ee arkaanul-islaamka qaybtiisa dambe, waxaa soo gelaya shanta tiir ee dambe ee arkaanul-iimaanka oo kala ah: 1) In Malaaígtiisa la rumeeyo2) In Kutubtiisa la rumeeyo3) In Rusuuladiisa la rumeeyo4) In Maalinta qiyaame la rumeeyo5) Qaddarka Alle shar iyo khayrba la rumeeyo."},{"question":"ඔබ දන්නා පැල් කවියක් සඳහා සම්පූර්ණ උදහරණයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"පැල් කවියක් සඳහා සම්පූර්ණ උදහරණයක් පහත දැක්වේ.සසඳ සසඳ දිය පල්ලේ තිබෙයි අලසසඳ සසඳ දිය මතුපිට තිබෙයි කොලවැස්සට පිනි බබා මෝරන කැකුළු මලමස්තකයින්ට මුතු කුඩයකි නෙළුම් මල"},{"question":"Waa immisa tirada carrurta Rasuulka (SCW)?","answer":"Tirada Carrurta Rasuulka (SCW) waa 7 Todabo."},{"question":"Quantas teclas tem um piano?","answer":"88 teclas."},{"question":"人気コンビ「キンキキッズ」の２人とは堂本剛と誰？","answer":"堂本光一です。"},{"question":"Tôi đang sinh sống tại TP HCM, thu nhập hàng tháng 30-35 triệu đồng, vốn tự có 1,4 tỷ đồng, chưa lập gia đình. Hàng tháng tôi có thể tiết kiệm được ít nhất 40% thu nhập. Tôi đang muốn mua căn hộ hoặc nhà để chuẩn bị lập gia đình sau này. Tuy nhiên, tôi băn khoăn nên mua căn hộ 2 phòng ngủ, 2 vệ sinh giá khoảng 2-2,4 tỷ đồng hay mua nhà đất diện tích nền 20-30 m2 ở khu vực quận 7, quận 8, huyện Nhà Bè, giá 2,5 tỷ đồng.Tôi vẫn thích sở hữu nhà đất hơn là căn hộ chung cư. Mong được các chuyên gia và độc giả tư vấn!","answer":"Với số vốn sẵn có 1,4 tỷ đồng cùng với thu nhập cố định và khoản tiết kiệm hàng tháng, bạn có thể vay thêm một khoản tương đương 800 triệu đồng đến 1 tỷ đồng, thời hạn 15 năm. Như vậy, ngân sách để mua nhà của bạn tối đa là 2,4 tỷ đồng.Tại khu Nam Sài Gòn bạn nhắm đến, ngân sách trên có thể mua căn hộ chuyển nhượng diện tích 55-70 m2 ở quận 7, quận 8 hoặc diện tích 60-80 m2 ở huyện Nhà Bè. Tuy nhiên, nếu mua nhà đất, với ngân sách này chỉ có thể tìm được những căn nhà trong hẻm nhỏ diện tích dưới 25 m2 ở quận 7, dưới 40 m2 ở quận 8 hoặc 60 m2 tại những khu dân lâu đời ở huyện Nhà Bè.Để lựa chọn phân khúc bất động sản phù hợp, bạn cần xem xét mục tiêu mua bất động sản để dành là ở thực hay tích sản, chống trượt giá."},{"question":"shin Kano hausawa  ko fulani?","answer":"Manyan mazauna garin su ne Hausawa. Karnuka kafin Turawan mulkin mallaka, Kano ta kasance kasa mai karfin gaske tare da mazauna Larabawa, Berber, Abzinawa, Kanuri da Fula kuma ya kasance haka tare da harshen Hausa wanda sama da miliyan 70 ke magana a yankin."},{"question":"Sự kiện mở đầu cách mạng Pháp là gì?Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi trên trong những câu sau:A. Hội nghị ba đẳng cấp được họpB. Thông qua Hiến pháp.C. Nhân dân tấn công pháo đài Ba-xti.D. Hội đồng dân tộc thành lập.","answer":"Câu trả lời là: C. Nhân dân tấn công pháo đài Ba-xti."},{"question":"Nội dung hai văn bản Tại sao nên có vật nuôi trong nhà? và Vì sao chúng ta phải đối xử thân thiện với động vật? có điểm gì giống nhau? Điểm giống nhau ấy có ý nghĩa gì đối với em?","answer":"Nội dung hai văn bản Tại sao nên có vật nuôi trong nhà? và Vì sao chúng ta phải đối xử thân thiện với động vật? giống nhau ở chỗ cách đối xử thân thiện, có trách nhiệm với động vật. Điểm giống nhau ấy mang lại bài học cho em về cách đối xử động vật và nhận ra được những lợi ích to lớn mà động vật đem lại cho cuộc sống con người."},{"question":"*ما أصل كلمة كوكب ؟","answer":"يوناني"},{"question":"Ci gan kembaar la réewum Barbade nekk","answer":"Réewum Barbade mu ngi nekk ci kembaar bi ñuy wax Amerique"},{"question":"கேள்வி: இந்தியா முதல் அணுகுண்டு சோதனை நடத்திய இடம் \\t1. ஸ்ரீஹரிகோட்டா2. டிராம்பே3. பொக்ரான்4. தாராப்பூர்","answer":"பதில்:3. பொக்ரான்குறிப்பு:       பொக்ரான் என்ற நகரம் ராஜஸ்தான் மாநிலத்தில் ஜெய்சல்மேர் மாவட்டத்தின் தலைமையிடமான ஜெய்சல்மேர் நகரத்திலிருந்து ஜோத்பூர் செல்லும் சாலையில் சுமார் 110 கிலோ மீட்டர் தொலைவில் நிலை கொண்டுள்ளது. பிகானீரிலிருந்தும் பொக்ரானை அடையலாம்.புவியியல்:பொக்ரான் அமைந்த இடம் சராசரி உயரம்:223 மீட்டர்கள்ஆகும். இவ்விடம் மலைப்பாறைகளாலும், மணலாலும் சூழ்ந்துள்ளது, மேலும் சுற்று வட்டாரத்தில் ஐந்து உப்புக்கற்கள் கொண்ட வீச்சுகள் உள்ளன.வரலாறு:          பொக்ரான் 1440 ஆம் ஆண்டில் ராவ் மால்தேவ் உருவாக்கிய சிவந்த கல்லால் பதித்த அழகான வேலைப்பாடுகளுடன் கூடிய 'பால்கர்' என்ற ஒரு கோட்டைக்குப் பெயர் போனதாகும். இங்கு பாபா ராம்தேவ் நடத்தும் பிரபலமான குருகுலப் பள்ளிக் கூடமும் செயல்பட்டு வருகிறது. போக்ரானுக்கு மிக அருகிலேயே அமைந்துள்ள ஆசாபூர்ணா ஆலையம், கீம்வஜ் மாதா ஆலயம், கைலாஸ் தெக்ரி ஆகிய இடங்களைப் பார்வையிட சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் வந்த வண்ணம் உள்ளனர். பொக்ரானில் இருந்து சுமார் 3 கிலோ மீட்டர் தொலைவில் சாதல்மேர் என்ற இடம் பழம் காலத்தில் இவ்விடத்தை ஆட்சி புரிந்த மன்னர்களின் தலைநகரமாக விளங்கியது பெருமைக்குரியதாகும். அஜ்மல் தொமரும் அவர் மகன் பாபா ராம்தேவ்ஜீயும் இங்கே ஆண்டு வந்த அரசர்களில் பிரபலமானவர்கள். மார்வார் ஜோத்பூரைச் சார்ந்த சம்பாவத் என்ற ராதோர் வம்சத்தைச் சார்ந்தவர்கள் ஆட்சி புரிந்தனர். ஜைனர்கள் வழிபடும் 23 ஆவது தீர்த்தங்கரரான பார்ச்வனாதரின் ஜைன ஆலயமும் இங்கு உள்ளதனால் ஜைனர்கள் வணங்கும் ஒரு புண்ணியத்தலமாகவும் இவ்விடம் உள்ளது. சீக்கியர்கள் வழிபடும் தம்தமா சாஹிப்பின் குருத்வாரமும் புகழ் பெற்றதாகும், இங்கு குரு நானக் வந்து வழிபட்டதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.அண்மைய வரலாறு:    பொக்ரான் அணுக்கரு வெடிப்பு பரிசோதனைத் தளம். பொக்ரான் தற்பொழுது இந்திய அரசின் அணுக்கரு வெடிப்புப் பரிசோதனைத் தளமாக இயங்கி வருகிறது. 18-5-1974 அன்று இங்கு முதல் அணுககரு வெடிப்புப் பரிசோதனை (சிரிக்கும் புத்தர்) நடந்தேறியது. பிறகு 1998 ஆம் ஆண்டு மே மாதம் 11, 13 தேதிகளில் மேலும் ஐந்து பரிசோதனைகளை நிகழ்த்தியது. இது வரை ஆக்கபூர்வமான செயல்பாடுகளுக்கே பரிசோதனைகளை நடத்தியதாக அரசு கூறுகிறது."},{"question":"અહીં ગુજરાતી નાટક ના કલાકારો વચ્ચેની વાતો નીચે મુજબ આપેલી છે:\\"શિવ૦ – સાંભળોછ કે ? મેકું સાંભળોછ કે ?ભોળા૦- (આગલી પડસાળમાંથી લ્હેંકો કરી) ના-આ-અં-શિવ૦ – રાંડની પેઠે ચાળા કરતાંજ આવડેછ.ભોળા૦- ત્યારે રાંડ તું. મ્હેં તો ત્હારા ચાળા પાડ્યા.શિવ૦ – બક્યા ! હું રાંડ કહારે કહેવાઊં વારૂ?ભોળા૦- ત્હારો બાપ મરે ત્યારે.શિવ૦ – (ચ્હીડવાઈને,) ખબડદાર ! બાપ લાગી ન જતા. જુઓ ! નોકરી ચાકરી કરવી નહિ ને –ભોળા૦- રાંડ, મ્હેં તો બહુએ સાહેબી કીધીછ.શિવ૦ – કીધી ! ત્રણ દહાડા તો કોઈ ઠેકાણે ટાંટીયો ટક્યો નહિ ! અંગ્રેજીનું ઉકાળ્યુંછ તોએ કોઈ હવે રૂપિયાની નોકરી ઠોકેછ ?ભોળા૦- છટ ! ભોળાભટ શું ગુલામગીરી કરશે ? કદી નહિ.શિવ૦ – પતરાજ ન કરો. આમ લોકોની થોડી ખુશામત કરવી પડેછ!ભોળા૦- આહા ! એ તો લોકોને હસાવી રમાડીને પૈસા કહાડી લઊંછ.શિવ૦ – એજ આવડેછ તો. જે મળ્યું તેની સાથે મજાક ઠઠ્ઠાની વાત ! નહિ જોવો મહેતો કે નહિ જોવો મહેતર, કે નહિ જોવી બહેન કે નહિ જોવી વહુ ! છોકરાંઓ સાથે પણ ધીંગામસ્તી !ભોળા૦- જન્મીને શું લઈ જવુંછ? આનંદમાં રહ્યા ને બીજાને બે ઘડી રાખ્યા તે ખરૂં.શિવ૦ – ને બૈરાં છોકરાં મુઆં તો ધુળ લાખી.ભોળા૦- છાનીરહે, ભજન સાંભળ. હું તો પ્રભાતિયાં ગાઉંછું.\\"આ કલાકારો ની આગળની વાતો શું હશે?","answer":"રંડા, - આ ગામમાં ત્હારા જેવું તો બીજા કોઈને ખાવા પીવાનું સુખ નહિ હોય. શિવ૦ – ને વખતે કડાકા કરવાનુંએ કોઈને નહિ હોય. મળ્યા તો મીર નહિ તો ફકીર, એજ સુખ તમારે ઘેર કની ?ભોળા૦- ગાંડી, સુખ દુઃખતો મનનું કારણ છે. મ્હારા જેવો કોઈ સવાદીઓ નથી, પણ વખત પડે ત્રણ દહાડાનો લુખો રોટલોએ ચાલે.શિવ૦ – ને તે એ ન મળે તો રઝળતા મુકી કીધું પરદેશમાં કાળું. વરસમાં છ મહીના તો બારણે રખડવુંભોળા૦- કુંભારજા, બહુ બેહેકી કે? પૂજા કરૂં ?શિવ૦ – વારૂં હવે તેલ આપવું છે કે નહિ ? હા કે ના કહો. સાંભળોછકે ?ભોળા૦- ના. એકવાર ના કહી કે હું નથી સાંભળતો.શિવ૦ – ત્યારે બોલે છે કોણ ? બાળ્યો એ વઘાર કરવો, ને મુઈ હું ! (કડછી અફાડે છે).ભોળા૦- બોલછ કોણ ? હું નહિ તો તારો બાપ બોલેછ ?શિવ૦ – મુઆં મ્હારાં માબાપ ! મ્હને આવા વરને દીધી તે કરતાં પીપળાને કાં ન દીધી ?ભોળા૦- તારી માએ તને જણતી વખતે ટુંપો કાં ન દીધો કે મ્હારે કર્મે આવી કુભારજા ચોંટી.શિવ૦ – તમારા ધનભાએગ કે મ્હારા જેવી કન્યા મળી; બાકી કાગડાની કોટે દહીંથરૂં ક્હાંથી? તમારે તો રોજ રાંડ વિધાત્રીને સ્હો સ્હો વખત દંડવત કરવા જોઈએ કે આ કાળા કપાળમાં મને લખી. વિધાત્રી અજુગતું કીધું, એની તો તમારાથી પણ ના નહિ કહેવાય.ભોળા૦- ના , હું પણ રાંડ વિધાત્રી અજુગતું કીધું તેમાં રોજ તેને ગાળો દઊંછું.શિવ૦ – હું તે કેવી છઊં? મ્હારા જેવી કોઈ બીજી બૈરી તો બાતાવ. સાંજ સવાર તું પગ ધોઈને પીએ તોપણ એવી બીજી કોણ ત્હારે ત્હાં રહે?"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki ini? Saya pembekal oksigen, siapa saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah tumbuhan. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jangan meludah ke langit'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud jangan mengeji atau mencela ibu bapa atau saudara mara sendiri"},{"question":"மெய்நிகர் உதவியாளர் பற்றி விவரி.","answer":"உதவு மென்பொருள் :திறன் பேசியில் இயங்கும் உதவு மென்பொருள் கண்ணுக்குப் புலப்படாத மனிதனைப் போல நம்முடன் உரையாடி சில உதவிகளைச் செய்கிறது.செயல்பாடுகள் :*) இம்மென்பொருள் நாம் சொல்லுகிறவர்களுக்குத் தொலைபேசி அழைப்பு விடுக்கும்.*) நாம் திறக்கக் கட்டளையிடுகிற செயலியைத் திறக்கும்.*) நாம் கேட்பதை உலாவியில் தேடும். நாம் விரும்பும் அழகான கவிதையை இணையத்தில் தேடித் தரும். எந்தக் கடையில் எது விற்கும் என்றும் சொல்லும்.*) படிப்பதற்கு உரிய நூல்களைப் பட்டியலிடும்.*) நாம் எடுத்த ஒளிப்படங்களைப் பற்றிக் கருத்துரைக்கும்.எதிர்காலத்தில் :எதிர்காலத்தில் நம் நண்பர்கள், குடும்பத்தினர் ஆகியோரை விடவும் இது போன்ற மெய்நிகர் உதவியாளர் நம்மை நன்கு அறிந்திருக்கும்."},{"question":"Qual é a capital do Distrito Federal no Brasil?","answer":"Brasília é a capital federal do Brasil e a sede de governo do Distrito Federal, não sendo tecnicamente sua capital. \\"Distrito Federal\\" é uma unidade administrativa que também existe em diversos outros países além do Brasil."},{"question":"Soalan: Bilakah pengembaraan Olaf's Frozen Adventure dikeluarkan di TV?","answer":"14 Disember 2017"},{"question":"Kodi ndingayambe bwanji bizinesi ya mtedza?","answer":"Chitani Kafukufuku wamsika : Musanayambe bizinesi iliyonse, ndikofunikira kuchita kafukufuku wamsika kuti muwone kuthekera ndi phindu la bizinesiyo. Izi zikuphatikizapo kusanthula kufunikira kwa mafuta a mtedza, kuzindikira makasitomala omwe angakhale nawo, ndi kufufuza mpikisano."},{"question":"Inona no iantsoana ny lehilahy manambady ny rahavavinao?","answer":"Ny iantsoana ny lehilahy manambady ny rahavaviko dia ny zaodahy."},{"question":"Tambaya: daga ina ne kogin Paraguay ya fara da ƙarewa Amsa:","answer":"Kogin Paraguay ya fara ne a Brazil kuma ya ƙare ta hanyar haɗuwa da kogin Parana a Argentina."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Malásia?","answer":"Cuala Lumpur."},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.අන්න බලන් අත්තක ඉද ලෝලූපපුව පලාගෙන අඟනක් මද කෑලූකකා ගිය ලෙල්ල රසකර උයාලූඅද බැරිනම් හෙට තෝරාපන් යාලූ      ","answer":"ගොරකා"},{"question":"Tunjukkan resipi untuk tepung bungkus dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan A: 1 biji kelapa - diambil santannya, 300gm tepung beras, 2 sudu makan tepung pulut, Daun pisang secukupnyaBahan B (Inti): 1/2 biji kelapa parut, 240gm gula pasir, 300gm gula merah, 2 sudu makan tepung pulutCara memasak:1. Untuk membuat inti, kelapa parut digaul dengan gula merah dan gula pasir di atas api yang sederhana. Pastikan ia dikacau sebati. Setelah itu, angkat dan sejukkan. Kemudian gentelkan adunan bulat-bulat sebesar biji guli.2. Kemudian bancuh tepung pulut dengan sedikit air tetapi jangan terlalu cair. Ambil sejemput kecil bancuhan tepung pulut tadi dan balutkan pada inti yang telah digentel.Lakukan hingga selesai semuanya. Ketepikan.3. Untuk membuat adunan tepung bungkus homemade pula, tepung beras dibancuh dengan santan, kemudian jerangkan di atas api hingga pekat. Setelah itu, angkat dan sejukkan sebentar.4. Ambil sesudu adunan tersebut dan letakkan di atas daun pisang.5. Kemudian letakkan inti di tengahnya. Bungkuskan seperti membuat kuih naga sari. Lakukan sehingga habis semua adunan.6. Kukus sehingga masak. Sedia untuk dihidangkan.Tips Memasak Kuih Tepung Bungkus:-Guna gula nipah dan dicampur sedikit gula merah untuk rasa dan warna inti lebih menarik.-Tambah sedikit tepung gandum sebagai gam supaya inti tidak berderai.-Gunakan api sederhana semasa mengukus supaya bungkusan tidak terbuka.-Biarkan kuih sejuk dahulu sebelum makan supaya isi putihnya lebih keras-Sebelum membungkus adunan, layurkan daun pisang di atas api terlebih dahulu.- Bolehlah disapu sedikit minyak atas daun pisang supaya kuih tidak melekat dan tidak comot."},{"question":"Ayẹyẹ kan ni olukọ KWASU yii n lọọ dari lati Ilọrin to fi ku sinu ijamba ọkọ lọna Eko ","answer":"Ọmowe Ayọtunde Alao lo ti kagbako iku ojiji lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, opin ọsẹ to lọ yii, nigba to n rin irin-ajo lati ilu Ilọrin lọ si ipinlẹ Eko, lati lọọ dari ayẹyẹ kan.Alao jẹ olukọ nileewe giga Fasiti KWASU, niluu Malete, nipinlẹ Kwara, o si tun maa n tukọ eto lawọn ayẹyẹ gbogbo. Awọn eeyan a maa sọ pe oun ni ẹni ti yoo gba oye imọ ijinlẹ Ph.D, ti yoo si tun maa tukọ eto lode ayẹyẹ gbogbo (MC).Ọkunrin naa pẹlu Bobby Jay, to jẹ adẹrin-in poṣonu ati awọn mẹta miiran ni wọn jọ n rin irin-ajo lọ siluu Eko ninu ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ wọn.Itosi Sagamu ni wọn ti ni ijamba mọto, ti ọkunrin naa si ku, ẹsẹ kan aye, ẹsẹ kan ọrun ni awọn mẹta to wa laaye paapaa ṣi wa bayii."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക:  അവസാനത്തെ റഷ്യൻ ചക്രവർത്തിയായിരുന്നു സാർ നിക്കോളാസ് രണ്ടാമൻ (18 മെയ് 1868 – 17 ജൂലായ് 1918). അലക്സാണ്ടർ മൂന്നാമനു ശേഷം രാജ്യഭരണമേറ്റ നിക്കോളാസ് രണ്ടാമൻ 1894 മുതൽ 15 മാർച്ച് 1917 റഷ്യയുടെ ഭരണം നിയന്ത്രിച്ചു. 1917-ലെ","answer":"ബോൾഷെവിക്ക് വിപ്ലവത്തെ തുടർന്ന് അധികാരഭ്രഷ്ടനായ അദ്ദേഹത്തെ പത്നി, മകൻ, നാലു പെണ്മക്കൾ, കുടുംബവൈദ്യൻ, പരിചാരകർ എന്നിവർക്കൊപ്പം 1918 ജൂലൈ 16-17 രാത്രിയിൽ വിപ്ലവകാരികൾ വെടിവച്ചു കൊന്നു."},{"question":"పూర్తిస్థాయి పోరుకు భారత్ సిద్ధంగా లేదు. అప్పుడే","answer":"గోవాను విలీనం చేసుకుంది. కాశ్మీరులో పాకిస్తానుతో సరిహద్దు వివాదాన్ని ఎదుర్కొంటోంది. భారత్ ఎదుర్కొంటున్న సమస్యలకు భారత జాతీయ కాంగ్రెసు అహింసాయుత పరిష్కారాన్ని ప్రతిపాదించింది. పూర్తి స్థాయి యుద్ధానికి సన్నద్ధం కావాలని ప్రతిపాదించిన సైనికాధికారులను పట్టించుకోలేదు. లేదా వారిని తొలగించారు."},{"question":"Bi nnkan ṣe n lọ yii: Naijiria le fọ si wẹwẹ ni 2023","answer":"Naijiria jagun abẹle. Ogun to buru gbaa ni o. Laarin ọdun 1967 si ọdun 1970. Ọdun mẹta gbako. Akọsilẹ fi han pe bii miliọnu meji eeyan lo ba ogun naa lọ. Laarin awọn ṣọja ni ija naa ti bẹrẹ, ṣugbọn ki i ṣe awọn gan-an ni wọn da ija naa silẹ. Awọn oloṣelu ni. Ija, irẹjẹ ati iwa ibajẹ nla lo gbilẹ laarin awọn oloṣelu, nigba ti wọn si bara wọn ja de aaye ibi kan, awọn ṣọja fibinu gbajọba lọwọ wọn. Ṣugbọn awọn ṣọja ti wọn gbajọba naa, irẹjẹ ati ikunsinu to ti wa laarin awọn naa ko ṣee bo mọlẹ, o ti gbilẹ gidi gan-an. Ko si si ohun to fa a ju pe awọn ti wọn n ṣe olori ijọba igba naa ti wọn jẹ awọn ẹya Hausa-Fulani lo gbogbo ọna ti wọn mọ lati gbe awọn ẹya wọn leri gbogbo eya to ku, ati lati maa fi wọn ṣe olori ijọba Naijiria, bo tilẹ jẹ pe nigba naa, iriri ati ọgbọn iwe wọn ko to bẹẹ rara. Nibi ti wahala ti bẹrẹ niyẹn.Awọn Hausa-Fulani yii ti Sardauna Ahmadu Bello jẹ olori wọn ko fi kinni kan silẹ fun awọn ẹya to ku, afi awọn ti wọn ba foribalẹ si abẹ wọn nikan. Nidii eyi, wọn da ija silẹ laarin awọn ẹgbẹ oṣelu to ku, ẹnikẹni to ba si ti fara mọ iwa ibajẹ ti wọn n hu yii ni wọn yoo ti lẹyin, nigba to si jẹ awọn ni wọn n ṣakoso awọn ṣọja ati ọlọpaa, gbogbo ohun ti wọn ba fẹ ni i ṣee ṣe fun wọn. Wọn sọ awọn aṣaaju ẹgbẹ oṣelu ti wọn jẹ alatako wọn bii Ọbafẹmi Awolọwọ sẹwọn, wọn si lu ẹgbẹ oṣelu tirẹ fọ patapta. Wọn fi oye ti ko lagbara kan tan Nnamdi Azikiwe, wọn si ri i pe wọn da ẹgbẹ oṣelu rẹ naa ru, debii pe awọn nikan lo ku, ẹgbẹ ilẹ Hausa, NPC, nikan lo ku to jẹ ẹgbẹ oṣelu to fẹsẹ mulẹ, oun naa si ni awọn to ku n ba ṣe. Bo si tilẹ jẹ pe ibinu awọn eeyan ru soke si wọn, ti wọn ko fẹ ohun ti wọn n ṣe yii, ko sohun ti wọn le ṣe.Nigba yii ni awọn ṣọja kan ati ọkunrin Ibo ti wọn n pe ni Kaduna Nzeogwu dide laarin awọn ẹlẹgbẹ rẹ, o si ko awọn mi-in jọ, ni wọn ba fibọn gbajọba, wọn si pa awọn Sardauna, Balewa, Akintọla ati awọn mi-in ti wọn jọ wa nidii ibajẹ to ti ba awọn oloṣelu lati ọjọ yii wa. Ṣugbọn ọrọ naa ko tẹ awọn ṣọja ilẹ Hausa to ku lọrun, nigba to jẹ awọn ọga ṣọja to wa lati ọdọ wọn wa ninu awọn to ku. Inu si tubọ bi wọn si i nigba ti wọn ri i pe ọmọ Ibo lo ṣaaju awọn ti wọn yinbọn pa wọn. Bẹẹ, ni tododo, inu n bi awọn ṣọja ọmọ Ibo yii ni kọrọ tẹlẹ, ati awọn Yoruba kọọkan. Ohun to si fa a naa ni pe ki Naijiria too gba ominira ni 1960, awọn Ibo lo ni ọga ninu ṣọja ju ẹya mi-in ni Naijria lọ. Laye oyinbo lọrọ naa ti ri bẹẹ, awọn Yoruba lo ku to tẹle wọn. Nibi ti awọn Ibo ti ni bii ọga marun-un, ti Yoruba ni ọga mẹta, meji pere ni tawọn Hausa.Eyi ni pe ko too di pe awọn oyinbo gbejọba yii silẹ, awọn Ibo lo n dari ọmọ ogun orilẹ-ede yii, nitori awọn ni wọn ni awọn ọga ṣọja to pọ ju lọ. Ṣugbọn ni gbara ti Naijiria gba ominira, ti ijọba si bọ sọwọ awọn Hausa-Fulnai, kia ni wọn yi ohun gbogbo pada, wọn si din iwe to yẹ ki ẹni to ba fẹẹ wọ ṣọja ka ku, bẹẹ ni wọn ṣeto pe bi wọn ba ti pọ to ni agbegbe kan ni wọn yoo fi maa ko awọn eeyan siṣẹ ṣọja, ti wọn yoo si ma sọ wọn dọga, ati awọn eto mi-in bẹẹ, nigba ti yoo si fi di ọdun 1965, awọn ọga ṣọja lati ilẹ Hausa ti gbe awọn ti Ibo ati Yoruba min. Paripari rẹ si ni pe ọpọ ninu awọn ti awọn ọmọ Ibo wọnyi pada waa kọ niṣẹ tun di ọga wọn. Iru rẹ ni Muritala Muhammed ti Emeka Ojukwu kọ niṣẹ ologun, atawọn mi-in bẹẹ. Eyi jẹ ki ibinu ati ija orogun wa laarin awọn ọga ṣọja lati ilẹ Ibo ati awọn to gba ipo wọn lati ilẹ Hausa.Nidii eyi, nigba ti wọn fibọn gbajọba, to si jẹ awọn Ibo lo pọ ninu awọn ti wọn ṣe kinni naa, ibinu awọn ọga ṣọja lati ilẹ Hausa ru soke, wọn si n wa gbogbo ọna lati gbẹsan. Wahala naa tilẹ waa pọ nigba ti awọn Nzeogwu to ditẹ gbajọba naa ko le ṣe e, ti wọn ni ọga agba ju lọ ninu iṣẹ ologun lo gbọdọ ṣe olori ijọba. Ibo ni iyẹn naa, Aguiyi Ironsi. Oun ni ko lo ju oṣu mẹfa lọ ti wọn fi yinbọn pa a, awọn Hausa lo ṣe iyẹn. Nigba ti wọn pa a tan ni wahala bẹrẹ, Ojukwu to ti di gomina ilẹ Ibo ni nigba ti wọn ti le pa ẹni to jẹ olori ijọba, ọga ṣọja to ba tun pọwọ le e ni ko gbajọba. Bo ba jẹ wọn fẹẹ mu eyi ṣẹ, ọmọ Yoruba kan to jẹ igbakeji Ironsi, Babafẹmi Ogundipẹ, ni iba ṣe olori ijọba Naijiria. Ṣugbọn awọn ṣọja Hausa yii lawọn ko ni i gba ki Ogundipẹ, tabi ki ẹya mi-in ti ki baa ṣe Hausa ṣe olori awọn. Eyi ni wọn fi mu Yakubu Gowon, ti oun si di olori ijọba.Eyi naa lo bi Ojukwu ninu pe ẹni to kere ninu iṣẹ ologun ko le waa ṣe olori awọn ti awọn jẹ ọga rẹ, pe ko gbejọba fẹni to ga ju u lọ. Awọn Gowon ko gba. Ati pe nigba naa, awọn Hausa ti bẹrẹ si i wa awọn ẹya Ibo to wa niluu wọn kaakiri, lati Kaduna de Sokoto, lati Kano de Zaria, ati de Katsina, wọn kan pa wọn lọọ ṣaa ni. Nibi yii ni ogun abẹle ti bẹrẹ, nitori wọn o pari ija naa, ko ṣee pari, ọrọ naa lo si di ogun nla to gbẹmin awọn eeyan to sun mọ ẹgbaagbeje (2.8m). Ni ibẹrẹ, gbogbo aye lo n da awọn Ibo lẹbi, wọn si n da Ojukwu to ṣaaju awọn ọmọ ogun Biafra yii lẹbi, wọn ni oun lo da ogun silẹ. Ṣugbọn nigba ti ogun pari, ti iwadii ijinlẹ si bẹrẹ lori ohun to fa ogun yii loootọ, o han pe awọn oloṣelu lati ilẹ Hausa lo da eyi to pọ ju ninu ọrọ naa silẹ, ati pe awọn ṣọja lati ọdọ tiwọn ti wọn fi tipa tipa gbe le awọn ọga wọn lori pẹlu irẹjẹ lo jẹ kọrọ naa di tawọn ologun. Ohun to wa n ba awọn eeyan lẹru naa niyi o.Ohun to fa idi ibẹru yii ni pe iru awọn irẹjẹ to ṣẹlẹ lọdun naa lọhun-un, awọn irẹjẹ naa ti pada de bayii, awọn irẹjẹ yii si ju ti asiko awọn oloṣelu ilẹ Hausa ọjọsi lọ. Awọn Kristẹni ti n pariwo gidi bayii, nitori o fẹrẹ jẹ gbogbo ibi ti wọn wa ni Kaduna, ati ni agbegbe awọn Tiv, ni Benue, Plateau, gbogbo ibẹ lawọn Fulani onimaalu ti n pa wọn kaakiri. Bakan naa ni wọn si ti wọ ilẹ Yoruba, ti wọn n pa awọn eeyan. Ohun to waa buru, to si n mu ibẹru wa ni pe ijọba to wa lode yii ko ṣi wọn lọwọ ohun ti wọn n se yii, bi aburu yii si ti n pọ to, bẹẹ nijọba n yi oju si ẹgbẹ kan si i. Eyi ti waa jẹ ki awọn eeyan ti wọn ki i ṣe Fulani bẹrẹ si i runra ni Naijiria, ti wọn si n fọhun jade pe o da bii pe ijọba yii fẹẹ gba ilẹ to jẹ ti awọn ẹya mi-in fun awọn Fulani alarinkiri yii ni, ki wọn le ribi maa gbe, ki wọn si sọ ilẹ onilẹ di tiwọn.Yato si eyi, ọpọlọpọ ohun-ini, awọn ohun alumọọni ati ajogunba to jẹ ti awọn ẹya mi-in, paapaa ni awọn ipinlẹ wọn ni ijọba yii n fi ofin ati agidi gba sọdọ tiwọn, nigba ti wọn si mọ pe nigbẹyin, awọn Fulani ni wọn yoo fun lanfaani lati lo kinni naa. Ọna oju omi gbogbo ni orilẹ-ede yii, ijọba apapọ ni awọn yoo gba a ki wọn le gbe e si abẹ awọn eeyan wọn lati maa dari, ile ifowopamọ ilẹ wa, ileeṣẹ elepo ilẹ wa, ileeṣẹ ologun gbogbo nilẹ wa, gbogbo awọn nnkan wọnyi ni ijọba yii ti fi ọgbọn gba, ti wọn si gbe wọn si abẹ awọn eeyan lati ilẹ Hausa tabi awọn ẹya Fulani wọnyi. Ni ojoojumọ ni wọn n kowo buruku ti ko ṣee fẹnu royin jẹ. Ṣugbọn bo ba ti jẹ awọn ẹya tiwọn ni wọn ko owo yii min, koda ki ariwo ọrọ naa jade, wọn yoo mọ bi wọn yoo ti pa ina rẹ mọlẹ ni. Ni ojoojumọ ni irẹjẹ naa n pọ si i loju awọn eeyan, ti wọn ko si rohun ti wọn le ṣe.Ohun kan lawọn araalu fẹẹ ṣe, iyẹn naa ni pe wọn ti mọ pe nigba ti yoo ba fi di ọdun mẹta si asiko yii, iyẹn lọdun 2023, ijọba yoo kuro lọwọ awọn eeyan ilẹ Hausa, yoo si bọ si ọwọ Ibo tabi Yoruba, awọn yoo si le fi asiko naa tun awọn nnkan ti awọn eeyan yii n bajẹ ṣe. Gbogbo ohun to dorikodo, ati irẹjẹ to fẹẹ da Naijiria ru bayii, gbogbo rẹ lawọn ti wọn n woye ọrọ ni yoo yipada bi ijọba ba ti kuro lọwọ awọn eeyan yii. Ṣe gẹgẹ bii eto to wa nilẹ, bi awọn ara Guusu (Ilẹ Yoruba ati Ibo tabi Delta) ba ṣejọba tan, awọn ara Ariwa (Ilẹ Hausa) naa yoo ṣe. Gẹgẹ bi eto ti lọ yii, awọn ara ilẹ Yoruba ti ṣe, laye ijọba Ọbasanjọ, Yar’Adua naa si ti ṣe gẹgẹ bii eeyan lati Ariwa nilẹ Hausa. Jonathan naa ṣe lati ilẹ Delta, ni Guusu, Buhari naa si n ṣe ijọba rẹ lọ bayii lati apa Ariwa. Bi Buhari ba kuro ni 2023, ẹtọ ni ki eeyan kan lati Guusu tun bọ sibẹ gẹgẹ bii olori ijọba. Eleyii lawọn aṣaaju Hausa wọnyi ko fẹ ko ṣẹlẹ mọ, ibi ti biliisi yoo si ti de niyẹn.Nigba tọrọ naa kọkọ bẹrẹ, ti awọn eeyan lati ilẹ Hausa bẹrẹ si gbegi dina, ti wọn si n tu awọn aṣiri kan jade nipa Aṣiwaju Bọla Ahmed Tinubu, ohun tawọn eeyan kọkọ n ro ni pe Tinubu ni wọn ko fẹ, wọn yoo mu eeyan mi-in ti wọn ba fẹ lati ilẹ Yoruba, bo si jẹ apa ilẹ Ibo ni. Ṣugbọn ni bayii, ko jọ pe ohun to ṣẹlẹ ree, o jọ pe gbogbo ọna lawọn eeyan naa n wa lati fi ma gbe ijọba silẹ, ko jẹ ọdọ Hausa mi-in ni wọn yoo tun gbe kalẹ pe ko maa ṣejọba Naijria lọ ni. Iroyin ko yee pariwo orukọ Nasir El-Rufai to n ṣe gomina ipinlẹ Kaduna bayii, awọn eeyan si n fẹsun kan an pe nitori o fẹẹ di Aarẹ, ti ko si fẹ ki awọn Fulani kọyin si oun lati asiko yii lo ṣe yiju si ẹgbẹ kan bi awọn Fulani onimaaluu ṣe n fi ojoojumọ paayan ni ipinlẹ rẹ, ti ko si ri ohun kan bayii ṣe si i ju ko tun maa bu wọn lọ, pe awọn Kristẹni ni wọn kọkọ n waja wọn lọ.Aipẹ yii ni olori ile-igbimọ aṣofin kekere tẹlẹ jade kuro ninu PDP, to ti sa lọ tẹlẹ, to ni oun pada wa sinu APC. Ohun ti awọn eeyan kọkọ gbe jade ni pe wọn fẹ ko waa ṣe igbakeji fun Tinubu lasiko ibo to n bọ ni 2023 yii ni, ṣugbọn ALAROYE ti fi ẹsẹ rẹ mulẹ pe ko si ohun to jọ bẹẹ, oun ba tirẹ wa ni, awọn kan si ti n ṣeto bi wọn yoo ti ṣe fi i ṣaaju pẹlu atilẹyin Buhari ati awọn eeyan rẹ, ti wọn yoo ni ko du ipo Aarẹ. Ko si ẹni to ti kọkọ ro pe eleyii yoo ṣee ṣe ju igba ti ẹnikan to sun mọ Buhari pẹkipẹki, ẹni ti ẹnu ti kun titi pe oun gan-an lo n dari aburo rẹ yii, nitori ẹgbọn Buhari lo n ṣe, to jade, to ni ki ijọba pa eto ki olori maa wa lati awọn ẹya ni jẹ-ki-n-jẹ rẹ, pe ẹni yoowu to ba kun oju oṣuwọn, to si ti ni iriri to to ni ki wọn maa fi ṣe Aarẹ. Ọkunrin naa mọ pe awọn ara Guusu lo gbọdọ fa Aarẹ kalẹ lasiko yii, idi to si fi n sọ bẹẹ ni pe bi eleyii ba fi le wọle, wọn yoo ni awọn ọmọ ilẹ Hausa le jade niyẹn igba to ba wu wọn lati du aarẹ.Bi awọn Hausa ba waa debẹ, ọrọ naa yoo le diẹ, nitori oju kan ni wọn yoo dibo wọn si, wọn yoo si lo ariwo pe awọn lawọn pọ ju la ti fi ṣe ojooro ibo naa si ọdọ wọn. Bi wọn ba ti fi ojoro ṣeto ibo naa si ọdọ wọn ti wọn ni ọmọ Hausa mi-in lo wọle, wọn yoo bẹrẹ si i fi ọlọpaa ati ṣọja halẹ mọ gbogbo ẹni to ba fẹẹ di wọn lọwọ, wọn yoo si ti ọpọlọpọ mọle ki ijọba wọn tuntun naa le ṣee ṣe. Awọn kan ti wa n leri silẹ de wọn bayii pe ni ọọkan ibi ti Naijiria yoo ti fọ si wẹwẹ ree, bi iru rẹ ba fi le ṣẹlẹ lẹẹkan si i. Ohun ti yoo mu ifọsiwẹwẹ yii ṣẹlẹ ni pe ọrọ ijọba awọn Hausa-Fulani, ati ọpọlọpọ iwa irẹjẹ ati aburu wọn, nibi ti awọn mi-in ti n sọ ọ kan awọn ẹya to ku loju pe awọn lawọn ni Naijiria, awọn to ku n ba awọn ṣe e lasan ni, ti de gongo fawọn eeyan, ajaga ti wọn di ru ilu lori yii si ti di ohun ti kaluku fẹẹ yọ kuro lọrun.Ni ọsẹ to kọja yii, ẹgbẹ apapọ awọn ọmọ Yoruba ti wọn n pe ni Yoruba World Congress ti mu orukọ Yoruba wọ inu ẹgbẹ agbaye kan ti wọn n pe ni UNPO, ẹgbẹ awọn ẹya ti wọn ko ni alafẹyinti, tabi awọn ẹya ti wọn n rẹ jẹ laarin orilẹ-ede wọn. Olori ẹgbẹ Yoruba World Congress yii, Ọjọgbọn Banji Akintoye, sọ pe ohun to mu Yoruba lọ sinu ẹgbẹ yii ko ju irẹjẹ ati iwa ika ti awọn Hausa-Fulani n hu si wọn lọ. Ọjọgbọn naa ni lati bii ogoji ọdun bayii lawọn ẹya yii ti fa Yoruba sẹyin, ti wọn si di wọn lọwọ, ti wọn ko jẹ ki wọn dagba soke mọ, ti wọn ko gbogbo ohun-ini Yoruba sabẹ wọn, ti wọn si n lo o bi wọn ti fẹ, to si jẹ bi wọn ba lo o titi naa, wọn yoo pada ba a jẹ ni. Ọjọgbọn naa ni awọn Hausa-Fulani wọnyi ko ni eto fun Yoruba, ohun ti wọn n tori ẹ ṣe Naijiria ni tiwọn ko ju ki wọn fawọn mi-in ṣe ẹru lọ, nigba ti Yoruba ko si ni i ṣe ẹru ẹni kan, o di dandan ki wọn jade wọọrọ kuro ni Naijiria, lai ni i mu ija dani rara.Lọjọ ti awọn lọ yii naa ni awọn Biafra lọ sibi ipade UNPO yii, ọjọ yii kan naa ni wọn si gba awọn naa wọle sinu ẹgbẹ yii, ẹjọ kan naa ti awọn paa ro fun wọn nibẹ ni pe Naijiria n rẹ awọn jẹ, awọn ko ṣe mọ, ifiyajẹni naa pọ, bi wọn ko ba si jẹ ki awọn jade kuro ni Naijiria wọọrọ, ọrọ naa le dogun lawọn ṣe wa sinu ẹgbẹ agbaye yii. Ṣe ko too di asiko yii ni ẹgbẹ awọn ọdọ ilẹ Ibo naa ti wa, ti wọn ti n sọ pe awọn ki i ṣe ọmọ Naijiria, Biafra lawọn, iyẹn ẹgbẹ MASSOB ti Nnamdi Kanu jẹ olori wọn. Awọn yii ti ja, ti wọn si ti fi gba kan koju ijọba Buhari yii, wọn ti da aṣọ ṣọja wọn pada si aṣọ ọlọpaa tiwọn, wọn si ṣe owo Biafra ti wọn ni awọn yoo maa na. Ọpọlọpọ awọn ẹgbẹ ọmọ Yoruba naa ni wọn wa lẹyin odi, ti wọn ni afi ki Yoruba kuro ni Naijiria, bẹẹ ni awọn ọmọ Naija-Dẹlta ati awọn aṣaaju wọn pọ ti wọn ni awọn ko ṣe Naijiria yii mọ.Ohun tawọn agba, ati awọn ọjọgbọn aye waa n tẹ wọn lẹsẹ si, ohun ti wọn n tori rẹ da wọn duro naa ni ibo ọdun 2023, pe ki wọn ni suuru, ẹya mi-in yoo gbajọba Naijiria nigba naa, ohun gbogbo yoo si yipada. Ṣugbọn kinni naa ni ko fẹẹ ṣee ṣe yii, bi ko ba si ti ṣee ṣe, Naijiria yii le fọ si wẹwẹ ko too digba naa, tabi nigba naa gan-an. Ki eku ile gbọ, ko sọ fun toko o."},{"question":"Tuliskan sebuah karangan ceramah yang bertajuk ‘Masalah Pengangkutan Awam di Negara Malaysia’.","answer":"          Dalam sistem perhubungan, pengangkutan awam menjadi pilihan orang ramai untuk bergerak dari satu destinasi ke satu destinasi yang lain. Sistem pengangkutan ini turut menjadi pilihan golongan marhaen khususnya bagi mereka daripada golongan masyarakat pertengahan dan yang kurang berkemampuan. Rangkaian pengangkutan awam di negara kita adalah seperti pengangkutan bas awam, teksi, Sistem Transit Tren Ringan (LRT), monorel dan sebagainya. Memang sudah banyak usaha yang dilakukan untuk menyatukan semua perkhidmatan ini tetapi kejayaannya masih jauh lagi. Oleh itu, pelbagai kemelut yang melanda sistem pengangkutan awam negara kita harus difahami untuk menangani masalah yang sudah berlanjutan sekian lama.          Sudah pasti dilema utama yang dihadapi oleh masyarakat terhadap sistem pengangkutan awam kita ialah kos atau tambangnya yang agak mahal. Kadar tambang terutamanya bagi penumpang teksi dan LRT adalah dianggap mahal terutamanya bagi mereka yang berpendapatan rendah serta menghalang mereka daripada menggunakan sistem pengangkutan itu dengan lebih kerap. Kadaan ini menyebabkan jumlah pengguna pengangkutan awam terutama LRT agak kurang dan tidak menyeluruh. Kebanyakan daripada mereka hanya menggunakan pengangkutan awam hanya apabila terdesak atau hanya untuk ke pejabat sahaja. Jadi, kemelut utama ini harus diselesaikan oleh kerajaan jika mereka mahu melihat rakyat negara ini berduyun-duyun menggunakan pengangkutan awam tersebut.        Selain itu, kemelut pengangkutan awam ini turut dikaitkan dengan amalan pengurusannya yang tidak cekap. Masyarakat menganggap sistem pengangkutan awam terutamanya bas awam tidak boleh diharap dari segi ketepatan waktu operasinya. Kelewatan bas kerap berlaku dan tidak mengikut jadual perjalanan yang ditetapkan. Hal ini menyebabkan masyarakat sukar untuk merancang dan menjangka tempoh perjalanan yang bakal mereka hadapi. Masalah kelewatan sampai ke tempat kerja menjadi isu utama akibat kegagalan pihak pengurusan mengatasi masalah tersebut. Masalah penjagaan bas awam, LRT dan teksi turut dikatakan termasuk dalam kategori yang mengecewakan kerana penyelenggaraannya yang tidak menyeluruh. Oleh itu, masyarakat bukan sahaja kecewa melihat kegagalan pengangkutan awam mematuhi jadual perjalanan malah pada masa yang sama kegagalan untuk menjaga kualiti perkhidmatan pengangkutan awam turut dirasai.          Kita juga sering terdengar rungutan orang awam yang mengatakan bahawa tumpuan perkhidmatan awam di negara kita tidak menyeluruh. Kemudahan stesen LRT umpamanya hanya terletak di kawasan tertentu yang kadang-kala menyukarkan orang ramai tiba ke pejabat. Hal ini bertambah rumit kerana masalah kekurangan pengangkutan tambahan atau “fider bus” di kawasan itu. Kalau anda sering menggunakan pengangkutan awam sudah pasti anda akan menghadapi masalah untuk menukar sistem pengangkutan, contohnya di antara stesen monorel dengan stesen LRT atau di antara stesen bas dengan tesen monorel. Hal ini menyebabkan penjalanan penumpang terganggu kerana terpaksa beratur untuk membeli tiket sebelum menaiki pengangkutan awam yang lain pula. Dalam era globalisasi yang mengutamakan kepantasan, sudah pasti keadaan ini dianggap merumitkan kehidupan masyarakat. Maka, satu sistem tiket yang bersepadu harus diadakan oleh kerajaan sebelum kemelut ini menjadi semakin rumit untuk diselesaikan.          Malah, pengangkutan awam turut turut terjejas akibat tindakan segelintir pekerja mereka seperti pemandu teksi dan pemandu bas yang tidak sopan ketika memandu. Sering kali masyarakat mengadu kerakusan pemandu pengangkutan awam di jalan raya yang dibuktikan oleh meningkatkan kemalangan yang melibatkan pengangkutan awam ini. Sikap tidak prihatin mereka ini telah memberi satu imej negatif kepada semua pekerja yang bekerja dalam sistem pengangkutan awam negara kerana seekor kerbau membawa lumpur, semuanya terpalit. Ada di antara mereka yang masih mengamalkan sikap ingin menjadi sang juara di jalan raya. Hal ini bukan sahaja membahayakan penumpang kenderaan tersebut malah pada masa yang sama turut membahayakan keselamatan pengguna jalan raya yang lain. Justeru, semua pekerja pengangkutan awam harus diberi satu kursus untuk memastikan mereka lebih mesra pelanggan dan bukannya dibenci oleh pelanggan serta masyarakat awam yang lain.          Banyak juga aduan yang sering kita baca di dada-dada akhbar mengenai rungutan orang awam tentang kekurangan tempat letak kereta di stesen LRT dan komuter. Hal ini berlaku kerana kurangnya perancangan yang teliti sebelum projek tersebut dilaksanakan. Kelemahan ini bukan sahaja menyukarkan orang ramai meletakkan kenderaan mereka malah menghalang orang ramai untuk menaiki kemudahan awam tersebut. Di beberapa buah stesen komuter dan LRT di ibu kota Kuala Lumpur umpamanya, kekurangan tempat untuk meletakkan kenderaan menyebabkan orang ramai meletakkan kenderaan mereka sesuka hati atau di tepi-tepi jalan. Hal ini bukan sahaja menyebabkan berlakunya kesesakan malah kadang-kala boleh menyebabkan berlakunya kemalangan. Lebih malang pula, ada sebahagian kenderaan tersebut turut di saman oleh pihak polis biarpun masalah ini timbul akibat kelemahan pengurusan terbabit. Jelasnya, rungutan pengguna pengangkutan awam tersebut perlu ditangani dengan baik agar pengangkutan awam di negara kita tidak menjadi “indah khabar dari rupa”.          Kesimpulannya, masalah pengangkutan awam di negara kita amat perlu diambil berat oleh pihak yang terbabit. Sekiranya perkara tersebut masih terus didiamkan tanpa sebarang tindakan, kita bimbang hasrat kerajaan untuk menjadikan pengangkutan awam sebagai salah satu pengangkutan utama di negara kita akan terkubur. Kesungguhan pihak kerajaan untuk mengambil langkah awal dalam menangani masalah ini amat ditagih dan pihak berwajib tidak harus bertindak hanya apabila isu itu menjadi tatapan masyarakat dalam media massa negara. Mungkin sudah sampai masanya kerajaan bertindak tegas dalam kemelut ini dan bukan bersikap “sudah terhantuk baru terngadah”."},{"question":"Quem foi a primeira mulher negra a ganhar o Oscar de Melhor Atriz?","answer":"Halle Berry. Ela ganhou o Oscar de Melhor Atriz por sua atuação no filme A Última Ceia, de 2001."},{"question":"Quantos jogadores existem em uma equipe de pólo aquático?","answer":"Sete"},{"question":"Inona no planeta farany hotsidihin'ny fitsidihan'ny NASA amin'ny 2021?","answer":"Nitsidika an'i Mars tamin'ny 2021 ny NASA Space Probe Perseverance."},{"question":"Apakah maksud peribahasa \\"ada sampan hendak berenang\\" ?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah sengaja menyusahkan diri."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai ayam yang terkecundang\\"?","answer":"Sangat takut"},{"question":"Oṣiṣẹ ileewosan alabọọde ko Korona ni Meiran, nijọba ba ti ibẹ pa","answer":"Titi gbọin ni ileewosan alabọọde to jẹ ti ijọba ni Meiran (Meiran Primary Health Care Centre), wa bayii. Ijọba ipinlẹ Eko lo ti i nitori ọkan ninu awọn oṣiṣẹ ibẹ to ko arun Korona.Ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, ni igbesẹ yii waye, nigba ti Alaga agbegbe Idagbasoke Agbado/Oke-Odo, Ọgbẹni David Famuyiwa, paṣẹ pe ki wọn ti ọsibitu naa latari oṣiṣẹ to ti ni Korona nibẹ, ko ma baa di pe kinni naa yoo tun maa ran mọ awọn eeyan mi-in ti wọn n ṣiṣẹ nibẹ ati awọn ti wọn ba wa fun itọju.Bakan naa ni alaga yii pe fun wiwa awọn mi-in ti wọn ti ni nnkan an ṣe pẹlu ẹni to ni Korona yii, awọn oṣiṣẹ yooku atawọn alaarẹ to n gbatọju, bẹẹ ni wọn ti ya ẹni to ni aisan naa sọtọ gẹgẹ bii aṣẹ NCDC.Amọran ti waa lọ sọdọ awọn olugbe Meiran ati agbegbe ẹ, pe ki wọn ṣọra fun arun yii, ki wọn tẹle ofin gbogbo to de Korona lati dẹkun itankalẹ rẹ lawujọ."},{"question":"請完成以下段落 - 由此，辛克上校在開戰後一直統率著第506傘兵團在各地作戰，成為整場第二次世界大戰裡面506傘兵團唯一的指揮官。除了分別參與D-day和市場花園行動","answer":"的跳傘降落之外，亦隨團在極度嚴寒的巴斯通指揮整場突出部之役。為了繼續留在506傘兵團，辛克上校在戰事期間更不惜兩度拒絕晉升，因此該團有時被稱之為「Five-Oh-Sink」而並非「Five-Oh-Six」，辛克上校在軍隊中受擁戴的程度可見一斑。"},{"question":"කරුණාකර කැනඩාව විස්තර කරන කෙටි සාරාංශයක් සපයන්න.","answer":"කැනඩාව උතුරු ඇමරිකාවේ පිහිටි රටකි. එහි පළාත් දහය සහ භූමි ප්‍රදේශ තුන අත්ලාන්තික් සාගරයේ සිට පැසිෆික් සාගරය දක්වාත් උතුරු දෙසට ආක්ටික් සාගරය දක්වාත් විහිදෙන අතර, එය ලොව දිගම වෙරළ තීරය සහිත මුළු භූමි ප්‍රමාණය අනුව ලොව දෙවන විශාලතම රට බවට පත් කරයි. එය කාලගුණ විද්‍යාත්මක සහ භූ විද්‍යාත්මක කලාප දෙකෙහිම පුළුල් පරාසයකින් සංලක්ෂිත වේ. රටෙහි ජනාවාස විරල වන අතර, අති බහුතරය නාගරික ප්‍රදේශවල 55 වන සමාන්තරයෙන් දකුණින් වාසය කරයි. කැනඩාවේ අගනුවර ඔටාවා වන අතර එහි විශාලතම නාගරික ප්‍රදේශ තුන වන්නේ ටොරොන්ටෝ, මොන්ට්‍රියල් සහ වැන්කුවර් ය. ආදිවාසීන් වසර දහස් ගණනක් තිස්සේ වර්තමාන කැනඩාවෙහි අඛණ්ඩව වාසය කර ඇත. 16 වැනි සියවසේ පටන් බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය සහ ප්‍රංශ ගවේෂණ ගවේෂණය කර පසුව අත්ලාන්තික් වෙරළ තීරයේ පදිංචි විය. විවිධ සන්නද්ධ ගැටුම්වල ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස, ප්‍රංශය 1763 දී උතුරු ඇමරිකාවේ සිය යටත් විජිත සියල්ලම පාහේ පවරා දෙන ලදී. 1867 දී, කොන්ෆෙඩරේෂන් හරහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය උතුරු ඇමරිකානු ජනපද තුනක් එක් කිරීමත් සමඟ කැනඩාව පළාත් හතරක ෆෙඩරල් ආධිපත්‍යයක් ලෙස පිහිටුවන ලදී. මෙය 1931 වෙස්ට්මිනිස්ටර් ප්‍රඥප්තිය මගින් උද්දීපනය කරන ලද එක්සත් රාජධානියේ සිට ස්වාධීනත්වය වැඩි කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියක් ආරම්භ වූ අතර, එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව මත නීත්‍යානුකූලව යැපීමේ ශේෂයන් ඉවත් කරන ලද කැනඩා පනත 1982 මගින් අවසන් විය. . කැනඩාව පාර්ලිමේන්තු ලිබරල් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයක් සහ වෙස්ට්මිනිස්ටර් සම්ප්‍රදායේ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත රාජාණ්ඩුවකි. රටේ රජයේ ප්‍රධානියා අගමැති වන අතර, තේරී පත් වූ පොදු මන්ත්‍රී මණ්ඩලයේ විශ්වාසය දිනා ගැනීමේ හැකියාවෙන් නිලතල දරන අතර, රාජ්‍ය නායකයා වන කැනඩාවේ රජතුමා නියෝජනය කරන ආණ්ඩුකාර ජනරාල්වරයා විසින් \\"අමතනු ලැබේ\\". රට පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය රාජ්‍යයක් වන අතර ෆෙඩරල් අධිකරණ බලය තුළ නිල වශයෙන් ද්විභාෂා (ඉංග්‍රීසි සහ ප්‍රංශ) වේ. එය රජයේ විනිවිදභාවය, ජීවන තත්ත්වය, ආර්ථික තරඟකාරිත්වය, නවෝත්පාදනය සහ අධ්‍යාපනය පිළිබඳ ජාත්‍යන්තර මිනුම්වල ඉතා ඉහළ ශ්‍රේණිගත කර ඇත. එය මහා පරිමාණ සංක්‍රමණවල ප්‍රතිඵලයක් වන ලෝකයේ වඩාත්ම වාර්ගික වශයෙන් විවිධ වූ සහ බහු සංස්කෘතික ජාතීන්ගෙන් එකකි. එක්සත් ජනපදය සමඟ කැනඩාවේ දිගු හා සංකීර්ණ සබඳතාව එහි ඉතිහාසය, ආර්ථිකය සහ සංස්කෘතිය කෙරෙහි සැලකිය යුතු බලපෑමක් ඇති කර ඇත. ඉතා සංවර්ධිත රටක් වන කැනඩාව ගෝලීය වශයෙන් ඉහළම නාමික ඒක පුද්ගල ආදායමක් ඇති රටක් වන අතර එහි දියුණු ආර්ථිකය එහි බහුල ස්වභාවික සම්පත් සහ හොඳින් සංවර්ධිත ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙළඳ ජාලයන් මත ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් විශ්වාසය තබමින් ලෝකයේ විශාලතම රටවල් අතරට පැමිණේ. කැනඩාව එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය, නේටෝ, G7, දහයේ කණ්ඩායම, G20, ආර්ථික සහයෝගිතාව සහ සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ සංවිධානය (OECD), ලෝක වෙළඳ සංවිධානය (WTO), පොදු රාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලය ඇතුළු ප්‍රධාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහ අන්තර් රාජ්‍ය ආයතන කිහිපයක හෝ කණ්ඩායම් කිහිපයක කොටසකි. ආක්ටික් කවුන්සිලය, ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධානය, ආසියා පැසිෆික් ආර්ථික සහයෝගිතා සංසදය සහ ඇමරිකානු රාජ්‍ය සංවිධානය."},{"question":"Inona ny orinasa namokatra ny sarimihetsika mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Malok'ila\\"?","answer":"Ny \\"Scoop Digital\\" no orinasa namokatra ny sarimihestika mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Malok'ila\\"."},{"question":"Туура аналогияны таңда.Шырдак : оймолуу(А) төшөк : калың (Б) килем : гүлдүү (В) кийиз : күрөң (Г) көшөгө : чачтуу","answer":"1)Эталондук(үлгү) жуп: шырдак : оймолуу;2)Үлгү жуптагы байланыштын түрү : Зат жана анын сыпаты байланышы; 3)Зат жана анын сыпаты байланышындагы аналогиянын түрү: Зат жанаанын сын атоочтук сыпаты;Бул аналогиянын байланышы - Зат жана анын сын атоочтук сыпаты. Шырдак кооз болуу үчүн оймолор оюлат. Төшөк кооз болуу үчүн калың болбойт. Килем кооз болуу үчүн гүлдүү болот. Кийиз кооз болуу үчүн күрөң болбойт, бул жөн гана анын түсү болуп эсептелинет. Көшөгө кооз болуу үчүн чачтуу болот. Дагы эске алуучу жагдай, биз шырдакты жерге салышыбыз мүмкүн же дубалга илишибиз мүмкүн. Варианттарды карасак, килем шырдак сыяктуу жерге дагы салынат же дубалга илинет. Бирок, көшөгө жерге салынбайт, бул вариант туура эмес жооп."},{"question":"Berikan penerangan ringkas untuk Bukit Bendera.","answer":"Bukit Bendera merupakan sebuah kawasan Parlimen di negeri Pulau Pinang, negara Malaysia. Berada pada ketinggian lapan ratus tiga puluh meter di atas George Town, puncak Bukit Bendera (Bahasa Inggeris: Penang Hill) mempunyai suhu yang dingin dan panorama yang mengasyikkan."},{"question":"س280- قارة تعرف بالقارة السمراء ؟","answer":"ج280- أفريقيا"},{"question":"Türkiye'nin en uzun tüneli ne?","answer":"Cumhurbaşkanımız, “Zigana Tüneli Dünyanın 3., Avrupa'nın ve ülkemizin en uzun çift tüplü karayolu tüneli olarak inşa edildi. Trabzon'la Gümüşhane arasındaki bu tünelle Karadeniz'i Doğu ve Güney Doğu Anadolu'ya oradan İran ve Ortadoğu'ya yani Tarihi İpek Yolu'na bağlıyoruz."},{"question":"1/2 बाट 3/5 घटाउनुहोस् र नतिजालाई यसको सरल अंशात्मक रूपमा सरल बनाउनुहोस्।","answer":"भिन्नहरू घटाउनको लागि, तपाईंलाई एक सामान्य भाजक चाहिन्छ। यस अवस्थामा, सामान्य भाजक 10 हो। त्यसैले, 1/2 5/10 बन्छ, र 3/5 यथावत रहन्छ। अब, घटाउदै: (5/10) - (3/5) = (5/10) - (6/10) = (-1/10)।"},{"question":"Ар бир адам психикалык жана психологиялык жактан дени сак болсо, дүйнө генийлерден куру калмакпы?","answer":"Эгерде мурунку адамдарда антидепрессанттар, психологдор болгондо, бизде поэзия, сүрөт, искусство чыгармалары эч качан болмок эмес. Бул эң кеңири таралган туура эмес түшүнүктөрдүн бири. Анын үстүнө көптөр буга ишенет жана бул тантырактарды интернетке таратып, башкаларды адаштырышат. Бул логикага ылайык, невроз клиникалары толугу менен генийлер менен толтурулган. Ал эми таланттуу адамдардын арасында психологиялык жактан соо адамдар жок.Ой жүгүртүүнүн бузулушу жаңыны жаратпайт, бирок адамдын потенциалынын ачылышын чектейт. Талант – бул “Чыныгы Мен”, менин өзүмдүн көрүнүшүм. Эгерде Ван Гог маниакалдык-депрессиялык психоздон, алкоголизмден жана инсандын чек ара бузулушунан дарыланган болсо, дүйнө мындан да таланттуу сүрөтчүгө ээ болмок. Дени сак адамдар үчүн шедеврлерди жаратууга түрткү депрессиянын же психоздун чабуулдары эмес, тескерисинче шыктануу, аткаруудан ырахаттануу чыгармачылыкка умтулуу болмок."},{"question":"Magbigay ng magalang na pagbati sa Filipino.","answer":"Ito ang ilan sa mga magalang na pagbati sa Filipino:1. \\"Magandang araw po.\\":  Ito ang pangkaraniwang pormal na pagbati na maaaring gamitin sa anumang oras ng araw. Maaari ring palitan ang oras na ginamit depende sa kasalukuyang oras, katulad ng \\"Magandang umaga po\\" o \\"Magandang gabi po\\".2. \\"Mabuhay!\\": Ginagamit ito bilang pagbati sa nakakatanda o sa taong may mataas na atas sa buhay. Kadalasan din itong ginagamit sa pagbati ng mga turista o dayuhan sa bansa.3. \\"Kamusta kayo?\\": Isa itong magalang na pagtanong tungkol sa kalagayan ng kausap. Madalas na sinasagot sa tanong na ito ang \\"Mabuti naman\\" o iba pang tugon na may kagandahang-loob."},{"question":"මලාලා  යූසුෆ්සායි නොබෙල් සාම ත්‍යාගය දිනාගත්තේ කවදාද, ඒ වන විට ඇයගේ වයස කීයද?","answer":"මලාලා යූසුෆ්සායි 2014 වසරේ නොබෙල් සාම ත්‍යාගයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබුවේ ඇයට වයස අවුරුදු 17 දීය. ඇය මෙම ත්‍යාගය දිනා ගත්තේ ළමයින් සහ තරුණයින් මර්දනයට එරෙහිව සහ සියලුම දරුවන්ගේ අධ්‍යාපන අයිතිය වෙනුවෙන් කළ අරගලය වෙනුවෙන්. එකල මලාලා නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගලාභී ලාබාලතමයා විය."},{"question":"भारतात पहिला राष्ट्रीय उठाव कोणत्या वर्षी झाला ?","answer":"भारतात पहिला राष्ट्रीय उठाव इ.स 1857 मध्ये वर्षी झाला ."},{"question":"नैसर्गिक शेतीला चालना देण्यासाठी कोणत्या दोन केंद्रीय मंत्रलयानी संयुक्तपणे कृषी सखी अभियानाची/प्रशिक्षनाची सुरुवात केली आहे?(A)  केंद्रीय ग्रामविकास आणि कृषी मंत्रालय(B) केंद्रीय ग्रामविकास आणि जल मंत्रालय(C) केंद्रीय वस्त्रोद्योग आणि कृषी मंत्रालय(D) केंद्रीय गृह आणि वित्त मंत्रालय","answer":"(A) केंद्रीय ग्रामविकास आणि कृषी मंत्रालय"},{"question":"Vişne ekşiyken neden kiraz tatlı?","answer":"Vişne yani Latince adıyla Prunus cerasus ve kiraz yani Latince adıyla Prunus avium gülgiller ailesinde yer alan meyve türleridir. Vişnenin ekşi, kirazın tatlı bir meyve olması ise içerdikleri şeker ve asit miktarının birbirinden farklı olmasından kaynaklanıyor. Glikoz ve fruktoz, vişneye ve kiraza tatlılık veren iki basit şeker türü. Ekşilik ise meyvelerin içindeki organik asitlerden özellikle de malik asit isimli maddeden kaynaklanıyor. Vişnenin içerdiği şeker oranı yaklaşık %8 iken, kirazınki %13 civarında. Asit oranı ise vişnede yaklaşık %1,7, kirazda yaklaşık %0,8’dir. Yani vişne kiraza göre yaklaşık iki kat daha fazla organik asit içerir."},{"question":"வினா:arrow key-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"விடை:திசை குறி"},{"question":"Ngano gina kaon ang Pancit ilabina pag adlawang natawhan?","answer":"Kay ang mga pilipino nagtuo nga ang pagkaon sa pancit nagsimbolo sa taas nga kinabuhi"},{"question":"René Lalique - mugadziri weArt Nouveau - akashanda nezvinhu zvipi?   ","answer":"Mugadziri weArt Nouveau René Lalique aive nemukurumbira nekuda kwekusikwa kwake kwakagadzirwa kubva kumagirazi. Magadzirirwo ake akaoma kunzwisisa akachinja magirazi kuita zvidimbu zveunyanzvi zvinokwezva."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air besar, batu bersebak\\"?","answer":"Hubungan saudara-mara atau sahabat akan berpecah-belah apabila menimbul perselisihan yang besar."},{"question":"Dalam banyak-banyak api la kan, ada sejenis api yang tak panas. Api apa tu?","answer":"Bil Api."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Gần đây, vòng hai càng to hơn, mỡ tích tụ nhiều dù chế độ ăn của tôi rất lành mạnh. Tôi phải làm sao để cải thiện tình trạng này? Trả lời: Khi bước vào tuổi trung niên, tốc độ trao đổi chất của người phụ nữ chậm lại, đốt cháy ít calo hơn. Do đó chị em dễ tăng cân nếu vẫn giữ chế độ ăn như cũ mà không cắt giảm lượng calo tiêu thụ đi. Chưa kể, mỡ thường tập trung tích tụ vào những vị trí không mong muốn trên cơ thể, đặc biệt là vùng eo bụng. Các thay đổi về hormone ở cơ thể phụ nữ thời kỳ tiền mãn kinh đều dẫn đến tình trạng tích mỡ bụng, mông và đùi. Ngoài mỡ dưới da, các loại mỡ nội tạng bao quanh những cơ quan có thể làm gia tăng nguy cơ mắc bệnh tim mạch, tiểu đường và ung thư. Ở cả nam và nữ giới béo bụng, nguy cơ ung thư túi mật cao hơn 83%, ung thư thận tăng 39%, ung thư gan tăng 25%. Tỷ lệ ung thư ruột và ung thư vú tăng lần lượt 14% và 11%. Nguy cơ gia tăng tổng thể của tất cả 24 bệnh ung thư được đánh giá là 5% nếu một người có lượng mỡ nội tạng cao. Một số nguyên nhân khác cũng có thể khiến phụ nữ trung niên dễ tăng cân, béo bụng như ít tập luyện và vận động, thường xuyên căng thẳng. Ăn uống không khoa học, rối loạn giấc ngủ hoặc tác dụng phụ của thuốc khiến quá trình giảm cân trở nên khó khăn hơn. Phụ nữ sau mãn kinh tiêu thụ tinh bột không còn hiệu quả như trước. Do đó, chế độ ăn nhiều cơm, tinh bột như bún, miến, cháo, phở sẽ ngày càng làm vấn đề béo bụng trầm trọng hơn. Chị em cần luyện tập thể dục thường xuyên để rèn luyện sức khỏe và hỗ trợ kiểm soát cân nặng. Ăn nhiều hoa quả, các loại hạt. Ngủ đủ giấc mỗi ngày. Kiểm soát căng thẳng, sống lạc quan, giữ tinh thần thoải mái. Khi có dấu hiệu tăng cân quá mức, chị em nên gặp bác sĩ tham vấn chế độ dinh dưỡng và thể dục hợp lý để kiểm soát cân nặng, giảm bệnh tật. Bác sĩ Phan Chí Thành Khoa Khám bệnh, Bệnh viện Phụ sản Trung ương","answer":"Vì sao phụ nữ tuổi trung niên dễ béo bụng?"},{"question":"ഈ ഖണ്ഡിക ആരെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്: \\"രാജാ രവിവർമ്മ (ചിത്രമെഴുത്തു കോയി തമ്പുരാൻ ഏപ്രിൽ 29, 1848 - ഒക്ടോബർ 2, 1906): രാജാക്കന്മാർക്കിടയിലെ ചിത്രകാരനും ചിത്രകാരന്മാർക്കിടയിലെ രാജാവുമായിരുന്നു. ചിത്രമെഴുത്ത്‌ യൂറോപ്യന്മാരുടെ കലയാണെന്ന് സാമാന്യജനം വിചാരിച്ചിരുന്ന കാലത്ത്‌, സ്വന്തം ചിത്രങ്ങളിലൂടെ ചിത്രകലയുടെ ഉന്നമനത്തിനും വരകളിലെ വേഷവിധാനത്തിലൂടെ സാംസ്കാരികോന്നമനത്തിനും അദ്ദേഹം വഴിതെളിച്ചു.എഴുമാവിൽ നീലകണ്ഠൻ ഭട്ടതിരിപ്പാടിന്റെയും ഉമാ അംബാഭായി തമ്പുരാട്ടിയുടേയും പുത്രനായി 1848 ഏപ്രിൽ 29ന്‌ കിളിമാനൂർ കൊട്ടാരത്തിൽ ജനിച്ചു. പൂരൂരുട്ടാതി നാളിൽ ജനിച്ച കുട്ടിക്ക്‌ പുരാണകഥകളോടായിരുന്നു കുട്ടിക്കാലത്തേ താൽപര്യം. കുട്ടിക്ക്‌ രണ്ടു മൂന്ന് വയസ്സായപ്പോൾ തന്നെ കിളിമാനൂർ കൊട്ടാരത്തിന്റെ ചുവരുകൾ ചിത്രങ്ങൾ കൊണ്ട്‌ നിറഞ്ഞു തുടങ്ങി.അദേഹത്തിന്റെ സഹോദരി മംഗളാ ഭായി തമ്പുരാട്ടിയും ചിത്രകാരി ആയിരുന്നു. ആ കരിക്കട്ടച്ചിത്രങ്ങളുടെ തനിമ കണ്ടറിഞ്ഞ മാതുലനും സ്വാതിതിരുനാൾ മഹാരാജാവിന്റെ ആസ്ഥാന ചിത്രകാരനും ആയിരുന്ന രാജരാജവർമ്മ കുട്ടിയിലെ പ്രതിഭ കണ്ടെത്തുകയും ഉടൻ തന്നെ ചിത്രകല പഠിപ്പിക്കുവാൻ ആരംഭിക്കുകയും ചെയ്തു. ഒരിക്കൽ ഗുരുവും മാതുലനുമായിരുന്ന രാജരാജവർമ്മ പകുതി വരച്ചിട്ടു പോയ ഒരു ചിത്രം, ഗുരു, മനസ്സിൽ കണ്ടതുപോലെ തന്നെ രവിവർമ്മ പൂർത്തിയാക്കി വച്ചു. പ്രകൃതി പ്രതിഭാസങ്ങളെയും ഈ ലോകത്തിലെ എല്ലാ ചരാചരങ്ങളെയും മനസ്സിൽ ഒപ്പിയെടുക്കുകയും അവയെ ചിത്രത്തിൽ പകർത്തുകയും ചെയ്യുക കൊച്ചുരവിവർമ്മയ്ക്ക്‌ സന്തോഷം പകരുന്ന കാര്യമായിരുന്നു. കഥകളി സംഗീതത്തിലും കച്ചകെട്ടിയാടുന്നതിലും താളം പിടിക്കുന്നതിലുമെല്ലാം കഴിവു തെളിയിച്ച ആ വ്യക്തിത്വം അങ്ങനെ ബഹുമുഖപ്രതിഭയായി വളരാൻ തുടങ്ങി.\\"","answer":"ഇന്ത്യൻ ചിത്രകാരനും കലാകാരനുമായ രാജാ രവിവർമ്മയെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് ഈ ഭാഗം സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്. ഇന്ത്യൻ കലയുടെ ചരിത്രത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും മികച്ച ചിത്രകാരന്മാരിൽ ഒരാളായി അദ്ദേഹം കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്നു. തികച്ചും ഇന്ത്യൻ സംവേദനക്ഷമതയും ഐക്കണോഗ്രഫിയും ഉള്ള യൂറോപ്യൻ അക്കാദമിക് കലയുടെ സംയോജനത്തിന്റെ മികച്ച ഉദാഹരണങ്ങളിലൊന്നാണ് അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ കൃതികൾ.  "},{"question":"ప్రశ్న: మైదాన ప్రాంతాలు ఎందువలన ఎక్కువ జనసాంద్రతను కలిగి ఉంటాయి?","answer":"మైదాన ప్రాంతాలలో జనసాంద్రత అధికంగా ఉండటానికి గల కారణాలు :1. మైదాన ప్రాంతాల్లోని నేలలు సారవంతంగా ఉండి మంచి పంటల దిగుబడినిస్తాయి.2. భారతదేశంలో ఎక్కువ మంది వ్యవసాయంపైనే ఆధారపడుతున్నారు. ఈ ప్రాంతాల్లో అనేక రకాల పంటలు పండించడానికి అనుకూలమైన నేలలున్నాయి.3. మైదాన ప్రాంతాలు బాగా అభివృద్ధి చెందిన నగరాలకు ఆలవాలంగా ఉన్నాయి.4. ఇక్కడ మెరుగైన రవాణా సౌకర్యాలు అభివృద్ధి చెందినాయి, చెందుతున్నాయి.5. వ్యవసాయదారులు మిగులు సొమ్మును పెట్టుబడిగా మార్చి పరిశ్రమల స్థాపనకు దోహదం చేయటం వలన వృత్తి ఉద్యోగావకాశాలు ఎక్కువగా లభిస్తాయి.6. మైదాన ప్రాంతాలు బాగా అభివృద్ధి చెందిన “సాగు నీరు, త్రాగునీరు” వసతులు కల్గి ఉండి ఇండ్ల నిర్మాణానికి అనుకూలంగా ఉండి జననివాస యోగ్యంగా ఉన్నాయి.7. మైదాన ప్రాంతాలు ప్రాచీన కాలం నుండి మానవ ఆవాసాలకు నిలయం.ఉదా : సింధూ నాగరికత."},{"question":"Bagaimanakah menyediakan roti canai? ","answer":"Penyediaan: Gaulkan 3 bahan pertama, masukkan telur, susu dan air sedikit demi sedikit hingga adunan menjadi doh. Uli selama 10 min hingga licin dan lembut. Jika terlalu keras, basahkan tangan dengan air kemudian uli lagi. Bahagikan 7 atau 8 bebola. Letak dalam mangkuk. Lumur dengan minyak dan minyak sapi. Tutup dengan tuala lembab, biar 6-8 jam (semalaman). Ambil sebiji, leperkan seberapa nipis yang boleh (stail tersendiri). Angkat hujungnya dan biar memanjang seperti tali kemudian buatkan bulatan. Leperkan agar lapisannya bercantum semua. Jika cara ini sukar, memadai dengan melipat 4 kemudian goreng dalam sedikit campuran minyak/minyak sapi."},{"question":"Isikan tempat-tempat kosong dengan penjodoh bilangan yang sesuai. \\"Pemenang yang bertuah itu mendapat hadiah se _______ basikal dan dua _______ kasut sukan.\\"","answer":"Jawapannya ialah 'buah' dan 'pasang'."},{"question":"By Richard Spillett, Kieran Corcoran, and Wills Robinson A passenger killed when a light aircraft crashed in a flaming wreck yesterday afternoon only went up in the plane after a chance offer while visiting an airfield, according to local reports. They say the 'family man' had not been intending to fly. But after accepting an offer, he died along with the plane's pilot when their Yak 52 aircraft came down near the village of North Weald in Essex. The passenger was named as father-of-one and flying enthusiast Simon Chamberlain. Fuselage: The wreckage of the crashed Yak 52 was being removed from the airfield near Writtle, Essex.@highlightTwo men died after a Yak 52 plane crashed near Chelmsford, Essex.@highlightLocal reports named one of the victims as Simon Chamberlain from Harlow.@highlightOnlookers claim the plane was attempting somersault and then 'nose-dived'@highlightFire crews say the wreckage was 'completely alight' when they arrived.@highlight'Family man' passenger was only at the airfield by chance, it is claimed.@highlightWitness describes running to the crash, where flames were '10 feet high'@highlightHe said he was joined by two teenage Army cadets, but they couldn't help.@highlightThe model of aircraft involved has suffered a number of fatal accidents.'Two men, a pilot and his passenger, both from @placeholder, were on board.I am trying to decide what \\"placeholder\\" means in the previous text.Help by choosing an option between:- Army- Chelmsford- Essex- HarlowKieran CorcoranNorth WealdRichard SpillettSimon ChamberlainWills Robinson- WrittleYak 52","answer":"Essex"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi an Íoslainn. ","answer":"Is tír oileánach í an Íoslainn, nó Inis Tuile, atá suite san Aigéan Atlantach. Is í Réicivíc an phríomhchathair agus an chathair is mó.Is í an Alþingi parlaimint náisiúnta na hÍoslainne."},{"question":"ബ്രിട്ടനിലെ അടുത്ത ടോപ്പ് മോഡൽ 2016 ആര് നേടി? ","answer":"2016ൽ ക്ലോയി കീനനാണ് പുരസ്കാരം നേടിയത്."},{"question":"Inona no fihetseham-pon'ity fanambarana manaraka ity?\\"Nampiasa vola be tamin'ny tahiriko aho tao amin'ny orinasa iray izay nahitana fatiantoka betsaka. Ny famoizana ny volako nokasaiko dia loza lehibe. Mahatsiaro ho rava tanteraka aho.\\"","answer":"Miiba ny fihetseham-po, noho ny fahaketrahana taorian'ny fahaverezan'ny vola tamin'ny fatiantoky ny orinasa."},{"question":"9 sınıfta açığa nasıl geçilir?","answer":"Açık liseye geçmek isteyen öğrencilerin öğrenim süresi içinde iki defa sınıf tekrarı olması gerekiyor. Bu durum gerçekleşirse öğrencilerin okulla ilişi kesilerek veli ve öğrenci talebine göre açık liseye geçişi sağlanabilecek."},{"question":"ما اسم العضلة الأكثر قوة في جسم الإنسان؟ ","answer":"عضلة الفك."},{"question":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti le Sajẹnti Adamu to yinbọn pa Ọmọọba l’Oṣogbo lẹnu iṣẹ","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti le Sajẹnti Adamu to yinbọn pa Ọmọọba pa Ọmọọba l@fun igbẹjọ ati ijiya to tọ.A oo ranti pe lọjọ kẹtadinlogun, oṣu keje, ọdun yii, niṣẹlẹ buburu naa ṣẹlẹ ni nnkan bii aago marun-un irọlẹ loju-ọna Ọ̀bà, lagbegbe Islahudeen to jade si Ring Road, niluu Oṣogbo.Lasiko ti awọn ọlọpaa kogberegbe naa n kọja ninu sun-kẹrẹ-fa-kẹrẹ ọkọ lagbegbe ọhun ni ọkan lara wọn yinbọn soke, to si ba Saheed loju.Latigba naa lo ti wa nileewosan UNIOSUN pẹlu ẹnjinni ti wọn fi n mi lẹnu rẹ, ṣugbọn to jade laye lọgbọnjọ, oṣu keje.Ọmọ ẹgbọn Aragbiji ti ilu Iragbiji, Ọba Abdulrasheed Ayọtunde Ọlabomi, ni Saheed, ṣugbọn ilu Oṣogbo lo n gbe.O ni iyawo kan, o si bimọ meji. Ileewe Poli ipinlẹ Kwara lo ti kẹkọọ pari, ko to bẹrẹ ka-ra-ka-ta niluu Oṣogbo. Ọmọ ọdun mejidinlọgbọn ni ko too pade iku ojiji nirọlẹ ọjọ naa."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਜਿਸ ਕਾ ਦੀਆ ਪੈਨੈ ਖਾਇ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਸਿਉ ਆਲਸੁ ਕਿਉ ਬਨੈ ਮਾਇ ॥੧॥ਖਸਮੁ ਬਿਸਾਰਿ ਆਨ ਕੰਮਿ ਲਾਗਹਿ ॥ਕਉਡੀ ਬਦਲੇ ਰਤਨੁ ਤਿਆਗਹਿ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤਿਆਗਿ ਲਾਗਤ ਅਨ ਲੋਭਾ ॥ਦਾਸਿ ਸਲਾਮੁ ਕਰਤ ਕਤ ਸੋਭਾ ॥੨॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਰਸੁ ਖਾਵਹਿ ਖਾਨ ਪਾਨ ॥ਜਿਨਿ ਦੀਏ ਤਿਸਹਿ ਨ ਜਾਨਹਿ ਸੁਆਨ ॥੩॥ਕਹੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਹਮ ਲੂਣ ਹਰਾਮੀ ॥ਬਖਸਿ ਲੇਹੁ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਅੰਤਰਜਾਮੀ ॥੪॥੭੬॥੧੪੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 195 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮਾਂ ! ਜਿਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ (ਅੰਨ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਖਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਕੱਪੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਪਹਿਨਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਯਾਦ ਵਲੋਂ ਆਲਸ ਕਰਨਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਭੀ ਫਬਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਮਾਲਕ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਦੀ ਯਾਦ) ਭੁਲਾ ਕੇ ਹੋਰ ਹੋਰ ਕੰਮ ਵਿਚ ਰੁੱਝੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਨਕਾਰੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਵੱਟੇ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣਾ ਕੀਮਤੀ ਮਨੱੁਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਗਵਾ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ । (ਉਹ ਰਤਨ ਤਾਂ ਸੁੱਟ ਦੇਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪਰ ਕਉਡੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਂਭਦੇ ਹਨ) ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਹੋਰ (ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਦੇ) ਲੋਭ ਵਿਚ ਲੱਗਿਆਂਤੇ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ) ਦਾਸੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਨੂੰ ਸਲਾਮ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਕਿਤੇ ਭੀ ਸੋਭਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਦੀ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਕੁੱਤੇ (ਦੇ ਸੁਭਾਅ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਸੁਆਦਲੇ ਭੋਜਨ ਖਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਚੰਗੇ ਚੰਗੇ ਖਾਣੇ ਖਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪੀਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਪੀਂਦੇ ਹਨ,ਪਰ ਜਿਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ (ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਦਾਰਥ) ਦਿੱਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦੇ-ਪਛਾਣਦੇ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ।੩।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਆਖ—ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਅਸੀ ਜੀਵ ਨਾ-ਸ਼ੁਕਰੇ ਹਾਂ । ਹੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਦਿਲ ਜਾਣਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਸਾਨੂੰ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ ਲੈ ।੪।੭੬।੧੪੫।\\""},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഒരു പേപ്പർ വിമാനം എങ്ങനെ നിർമ്മിക്കാം?","answer":"ഉത്തരം:1. ചതുരാകൃതിയിലുള്ള കടലാസ് ഉപയോഗിച്ച് ആരംഭിക്കുക.2. പേപ്പർ പകുതി നീളത്തിൽ മടക്കിക്കളയുക, ചെറിയ അറ്റങ്ങൾ ഒരുമിച്ച് കൊണ്ടുവരിക.3. പേപ്പർ മടക്കി മുകളിലെ മൂലകൾ താഴേക്ക് മടക്കി മധ്യഭാഗത്തെ മടക്കിക്കളയുക, മുകളിൽ ഒരു ത്രികോണാകൃതി ഉണ്ടാക്കുക.4. പുതുതായി രൂപപ്പെട്ട മുകളിലെ ത്രികോണം പേപ്പറിന്റെ താഴത്തെ അറ്റത്തേക്ക് മടക്കുക.5. നീളമുള്ളതും ഇടുങ്ങിയതുമായ ദീർഘചതുരം സൃഷ്‌ടിച്ച് മുകളിലെ അറ്റം കാണുന്നതിന് താഴെയുള്ള അറ്റം മുകളിലേക്ക് മടക്കുക.6. ദീർഘചതുരത്തിന്റെ മുകളിലെ അറ്റങ്ങൾ താഴേക്ക് മടക്കി മധ്യഭാഗത്തെ മടക്കിക്കളയുക, മുകളിൽ വീണ്ടും ഒരു ത്രികോണാകൃതി ഉണ്ടാക്കുക.7. മുഴുവൻ പേപ്പറും മധ്യഭാഗത്തെ മടക്കിനൊപ്പം പകുതിയായി മടക്കിക്കളയുക, പുറത്ത് ത്രികോണാകൃതി.8. ഓരോ വശത്തിന്റെയും മുകളിലെ പാളി എടുത്ത് ഒരു ചെറിയ കോണിൽ പുറത്തേക്ക് മടക്കിക്കൊണ്ട് ചിറകുകൾ താഴേക്ക് മടക്കുക.9. ഒപ്റ്റിമൽ ഫ്ലൈയിംഗിനായി നിങ്ങൾക്ക് ആവശ്യമുള്ള ആകൃതിയിലും കോണിലും ചിറകുകൾ ക്രമീകരിക്കുക.10. കടലാസ് വിമാനം അടിയിൽ പിടിച്ച് സൌമ്യമായി എറിയുക, അത് വായുവിലൂടെ സഞ്ചരിക്കാൻ അനുവദിക്കുക."},{"question":"\\"иштиктүү мамилелер - операцияны (бүтүмдү) жүзөгө ашыруу боюнча кызматтарды \\" ушул текстти улантып берчи.","answer":"Сиз берген текстти мындайча улантсак болот: \\"көрсөтүү тууралуу келишимдин (оозеки же жазуу) негизинде келип чыгуучу кардар менен финансылык мекеменин же кардар менен финансылык эмес категориядагы жактардын ортосундагы мамилелер;\\""},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa bishii ayfurteen muslimiinta maka?","answer":"Waa bisha Ramadaan."},{"question":"Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi sau: Chòm sao nào chiếm diện tích nhỏ nhất trên bầu trời?A. Andrimeda - Tiên NữB. Crux - Nam Thập TựC. Gemini - Song Tử","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng: B. Crux - Nam Thập TựGiải thích Crux - Nam Thập Tự (viết tắt: Cru) là chòm sao chiếm diện tích nhỏ nhất trên bầu trời, gồm bốn sao chính Acrux, Mimosa, Gacrux, Crucis.Crux thuộc bán thiên cầu Nam. Cái tên Nam Thập Tự có nghĩa là chữ thập phương Nam, gồm bốn sao xếp thành hình một chữ thập. Trước đây, chòm sao này là một phần của chòm Centaurus, đến thế kỷ 16, bốn ngôi sao được chia thành chòm Crux độc lập. Bốn ngôi sao của Crux đều có độ sáng yếu, chỉ có thể quan sát trong điều kiện thời tiết và khí quyển tốt.Việt Nam nằm ở Bắc bán cầu nên người quan sát chỉ có thể thấy Crux vào chập tối trong khoảng tháng 5-7 hàng năm. Chòm sao Crux xuất hiện trên quốc kỳ của nhiều quốc gia, chẳng hạn Australia, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea."},{"question":"Dhamani ya marafiki hasa no ipi katika maisha ya binadamu hapa duniani?","answer":"Marafiki wanaweza kuwa sehemu muhimu ya maisha yetu. Marafiki wanaweza kutusaidia kuwa na furaha zaidi, afya bora, na kuridhika zaidi na maisha yetu.Hapa kuna baadhi ya njia mahususi ambazo marafiki wanaweza kutusaidia:Marafiki wanaweza kutusaidia kukabiliana na hisia zetu: Wakati tukiwa na huzuni, furaha, hasira, au hofu, marafiki wanaweza kutusaidia kuzichakata hisia zetu na kupata njia za kukabiliana nazo kwa afya.Marafiki wanaweza kutusaidia kujifunza kuhusu ulimwengu: Marafiki wanaweza kutuambia kuhusu uzoefu wao, kutushirikisha katika shughuli mpya, na kutusaidia kupata mitazamo mipya.Marafiki wanaweza kutusaidia kufikia malengo yetu:  Marafiki wanaweza kutupa usaidizi na motisha tunapohitaji, na wanaweza kutusaidia kushinda vikwazo.Ikiwa una bahati ya kuwa na marafiki, thamini urafiki huo. marafiki ni zawadi ya thamani."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පරිපාලනය සඳහා බෙදා ඇති පළාත් ගණන කීය ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පරිපාලනය සඳහා පළාත් 9 බෙදා ඇත."},{"question":"வினா: சித்தன்ன வாசல் ஓவியங்கள் யாருடைய புகழை பறைசாற்றுகின்றது?1. குப்தர்கள்2. பல்லவர்கள்3. சாளுக்கியர்கள்4. குஷாணர்கள்","answer":" விடை:2. பல்லவர்கள்"},{"question":"Di manakah kedudukan geographi Pulau Pinang?","answer":"Pulau Pinang merupakan salah satu daripada 13 negeri di Malaysia. Terletak di persisiran barat laut Semenanjung Malaysia, bersempadan dengan negeri Kedah di sebelah utara dan timur, negeri Perak di sebelah selatan dan perairan Selat Melaka di sebelah barat. Pulau Pinang terdiri daripada bahagian pulau dan juga tanah besar yang dikenali sebagai Seberang Perai. Keluasan kawasan pulau adalah 285 kilometer persegi yang terpisah sepenuhnya daripada Seberang Perai. Kedua-dua bahagian dihubungkan dengan perkhidmatan feri dan Jambatan Pulau Pinang yang panjangnya 13.5 kilometer."},{"question":"Ajụjụ: Ebee ka a ga-eme Rugby World Cup n'afọ ọzọ","answer":"Atumatu iko mba Rugby nke ụmụ nwoke 2027 ka ọ bụrụ mbipụta nke iri na otu nke iko mba ụwa Rugby, asọmpi ụwa nke anọ maka otu egwuregwu rugby ụmụ nwoke. A na-eme atụmatụ ime na Australia site na 1 October ruo 13 Nọvemba 2027."},{"question":"மல்லிகை சூடினாள் – ஆகுபெயர் கூறுக?","answer":"ஆகு பெயர் எனப்படுவது, ஒரு சொல் அதன் பொருளைக் குறிக்காமல் அச்சொல்லோடு தொடர்புடைய வேறு ஒரு பொருளைக் குறிப்பது. ஒன்றினது இயற்பெயர் அதனோடு தொடர்புடைய வேறொன்றுக்கு ஆகி வருவது. பெயர்ச்சொல்லின் ஒரு இயல்பாக வருவது. ஆகுபெயர் எல்லாமே பெயர்ச்சொல். ஆனால், பெயர்ச்சொல் எல்லாம் ஆகுபெயராகாது.ஆகுபெயர்கள் பத்தொன்பது வகைப்படும்.அவையாவன:பொருளாகு பெயர்சினையாகு பெயர்காலவாகு பெயர்இடவாகு பெயர்பண்பாகு பெயர்தொழிலாகு பெயர்எண்ணலளவையாகு பெயர்எடுத்தலளவையாகு பெயர்முகத்தலளவையாகு பெயர்நீட்டலளவையாகு பெயர்சொல்லாகு பெயர்காரியவாகு பெயர்கருத்தாவாகு பெயர்உவமையாகு பெயர்அடை அடுத்த ஆகுபெயர்தானியாகுபெயர்இருபடியாகு பெயர்மும்மடியாகு பெயர்கருவியாகு பெயர்பொருளாகுபெயர்மல்லிகை சூடினாள்.மல்லிகை என்னும் ஒரு முழுப்பொருளின் பெயர் அதன் ஓர் உறுப்பாகிய மலரைக் குறிக்கிறது. இவ்வாறு பொருளின் பெயர் அதன் சினையாகிய உறுப்புக்கு ஆகிவருவது பொருளாகுபெயர் எனப்படும். இதனை முதலாகு பெயர் எனவும் கூறுவர்."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Samy niezaka nanaja sy nakato ireo fady samy afa ny tsirairay mba isian'ny filaminana.\\"","answer":"Ity ny fanambarana miaraka amin'ny hadisoana voahitsy :\\"Samy niezaka nanaja sy nankato ireo fady samihafa ny tsirairay mba hisian'ny filaminana.\\""},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Các nhà khoa học đã tiến hành khảo sát 2.000 người trưởng thành ở Mỹ để xem họ rèn luyện thể dục thể thao như thế nào sau đại dịch. Theo đó, nhiều người đang áp dụng một số cách đặc biệt để có thể duy trì vận động trong ngày. Tổng cộng 54% số người được hỏi cho biết họ đi bộ quanh nhà khi nghe điện thoại và 42% thực hiện các bài tập như gập bụng và squat khi xem TV. Những người được hỏi khác cũng có nhiều ý tưởng sáng tạo về cách giữ dáng như tập squat khi gọi điện, cõng cháu trên lưng, tập nhảy. Theo The Sun, các cách vận động còn bao gồm thực hiện bài tập với ghế đẩu trong khi hâm nóng đồ uống hoặc những thứ khác trong lò vi sóng. \\"Sau khi ăn một món gì đó, tôi chạy bộ quanh đảo bếp 5 phút\\", \\"Tôi vừa đi vừa đánh răng\\", \\"Tôi chơi với 5 con chó nhiều lần hằng ngày\\" là tâm sự của một số người tham gia. Cuộc khảo sát ghi nhận, hơn bao giờ hết, người Mỹ đang có kế hoạch nỗ lực để có vóc dáng đẹp hơn. 38% tập thể dục tại nhà, 31% đi bộ để chăm sóc sức khỏe tâm thần. Tuy nhiên, 39% chật vật trong việc","answer":"tập luyện do thiếu động lực và 42% nản lòng do bị đau khớp. Điều đó cho thấy, cơn đau là rào cản phổ biến ảnh hưởng đến những người đang cố gắng tăng cường vận động. Những người bị viêm xương khớp đặc biệt gặp khó khăn, vì viêm khớp ảnh hưởng đến họ trung bình 4 ngày một tuần. Từ năm 2017 tới 2022, IBISWorld ước tính, tỷ lệ béo phì ở người lớn từ 18 tuổi trở lên ở Mỹ đã tăng 1,8% mỗi năm, lên 33%. Có nhiều yếu tố ảnh hưởng đến sự gia tăng này trong giai đoạn trên. Môi trường làm việc hiện đại tạo điều kiện cho tình trạng không hoạt động. Covid-19 dẫn tới lối sống ít vận động khi mọi người thường ở nhà, đặt hàng giao tận cửa. Ngoài ra, còn có áp lực từ việc đối phó với virus SARS-CoV-2, không tiếp cận được với các hoạt động giải trí và thực phẩm không lành mạnh."},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Dañuy jéem a nax Yàlla ak way-gëm ñi; waaye naxuñu lu dul seen bopp, te yëguñu ko.","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Da ñu'y jéem a nàx Yàlla ak waygëm ñi; waaye nàxu ñu lu dul séen bopp, te yëgu ñu ko."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన మొదటి పేరా మరియు చివరి పేరా అనుసరించు మధ్య పేరా రాయండి:మొదటి పేరా:ఇద్దాసు తత్వాలు ఆత్మపరంగ, తత్వపరంగ తెలంగాణ నుండి పుట్టిన మాణిక్యాలు. వేదాంత శాస్త్రజ్ఞాన సారాంశాన్ని సామాన్య ప్రజలకు ఈయన అందించాడు. వేదాంత తత్వాక అంశాలను పరిచయం చేయటం ఈ తత్వాల ఉద్దేశ్యం.చివరి పేరా:ఓ నామః అని అక్షరాలు రాస్తున్నాం నేర్చుకుంటున్నాం కాని, మన జీవిత ఆనవాళ్ళను తెలుసుకోలేకపోతున్నాం. దాని అంతు తెలియక అల్లరిపాలు అవతున్నాం. మంచి చెడులను తెలుసుకొని మసలు కోవాలని ఇద్దాసు పలుకుతున్నారు.","answer":"ఈ దేహం శాశ్వతం కాదు. కనుక ఈ దేహంపై మోహం విడచిపెట్టాలి. మంచి గురువును ఆశ్రయించి జీవన రాహిత్యాన్ని పొందటానికి ప్రయత్నించాలి. అపుడే మోక్షాన్ని పొందగలుగుతాము. భార్యాబిడ్డలు, ధనధాన్యాల పట్ల మోహాన్ని వదలిపెట్టాలి. ఏదో ఒకనాటికి కీలు వదలిన బొమ్మలా ఈ దేహం రాలిపోక తప్పదు."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Kto otrzymał Nagrodę Nobla z Literatury w 2022 roku?","answer":"Oto odpowiedź na to pytanie. W 2022. roku Nagrodę Nobla z dziedziny literatury otrzymała Annie Ernaux ( Francja) „za odwagę i kliniczną przenikliwość, z jaką odkrywa korzenie, alienacje i zbiorowe ograniczenia osobistej pamięci”."},{"question":"“ਪੰਜਾਬ” ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ ?","answer":"“ਪੰਜਾਬ” ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ-ਪੰਜ ਪਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਧਰਤੀ ।"},{"question":"Inona no antsoina hoe fokonolona vahoaka?","answer":"Ny antsoina hoe fokonolona vahoaka dia ny olona rehetra na antitra na tanora, na lehibe na kely, na salama na marofy, ka voamarina fa tena mitoetra ao amin'ny faritra iray."},{"question":"Qual é o tipo de madeira mais pesado?","answer":"Lignum vitae é uma madeira, também chamada guayacan ou guaiacum, e em partes da Europa conhecida como pockholz ou pokhout, de árvores do gênero Guaiacum. As árvores são nativas do Caribe e da costa norte da América do Sul (por exemplo: Colômbia e Venezuela) e têm sido uma importante cultura de exportação para a Europa desde o início do século XVI. A madeira já foi muito importante para aplicações que exigiam um material com sua extraordinária combinação de resistência e densidade. "},{"question":"请给以下的文言文它的译文：（李）存审出于寒微,常戒诸子曰：“尔父少提一剑去乡里，四十年间，位极将相，其间出万死获一生者非一，破骨出镞者凡百馀。”因授以所出镞，命藏之，曰：“尔曹生于膏梁,当知尔父起家如此也。”","answer":"李存审出身贫穷没有地位，他常常训诫他的孩子们说：“你们的父亲年轻时只带一柄剑离开家乡，四十年了，地位到达将相之高，在这中间经过万死才获得一次生存的险事绝不止一件，剖开骨肉从中取出的箭头共有一百多个。”于是，把所取出的箭头拿出给孩子们看，吩咐他们贮藏起来，说：“你们这些人都出生在富贵之家，应当记得你们的父亲当年起家时就是这样艰难啊。”"},{"question":"ලොව වැඩිම ජන ඝනත්වයක් ඇති රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"මොනාකෝ රාජ්‍යය"},{"question":"Qual a resposta correta para a pergunta a seguir: Qual o nome do companheiro do Lone Ranger?","answer":"A resposta correta é Tonto"},{"question":"कोणार्कच्या सूर्य मंदिराचे निर्माण कोणी करून घेतले ?","answer":"कोणार्कच्या सूर्य मंदिराचे निर्माण नरसिंह प्रथमने करून घेतले ."},{"question":"Sürekli ağlayan bebek nasıl susturulur?","answer":"Ağlayan bir bebekle başa çıkmak için bazı ipuçları:Kucağınıza alın.Kundak yapın.Besleyin.Altını değiştirin.Araba ile dolaştırın.Sling veya kanguru ile yürüyüşe çıkın.Beyaz gürültü yapın.Müzik dinletin."},{"question":"Content: అయితే, ప్రస్తుత అధ్యక్షుడు డోనల్డ్ ట్రంప్ తాజా ఎన్నికల్లో జో బైడెన్ చేతిలో తనకు ఎదురైన ఓటమిని అంగీకరించడం లేదు. అందుకే, ఒకవేళ ట్రంప్ వైట్ హౌజ్‌ను వదిలివెళ్లేందుకు నిరాకరిస్తే ఏం జరుగుతుందా అన్నది ఇప్పుడు చర్చనీయంగా మారింది.ఎన్నికల్లో బైడెన్ చేతుల్లో ట్రంప్ ఓడినట్లు ప్రకటనలు రాగానే ట్రంప్ ఎన్నికల ప్రచార బృందం ఓ ప్రకటన విడుదల చేసింది.''జో బైడన్ తనను తాను విజేతగా తప్పుగా చూపించుకుంటున్నారు. కొన్ని మీడియా సంస్థలు ఆయనకు సాయం చేసేందుకు హద్దులు దాటి ప్రయత్నిస్తున్నాయి. నిజం బయటకు రాకూడదనివాళ్లు కోరుకుంటున్నారు'' అని ట్రంప్ ప్రచార బృందం వ్యాఖ్యానించింది.ఎన్నికల ప్రక్రియలో అక్రమాలు జరిగాయంటూ ట్రంప్ ఆరోపణలు చేస్తున్న సంగతి తెలిసిందే. ఓట్ల కౌంటింగ్, ఫలితాల వెల్లడి ప్రక్రియలపై ఆయన కోర్టుల్లో దావాలు ఇంకా వేస్తారన్న సంకేతాలు కనిపిస్తున్నాయి.ప్రస్తుత అధ్యక్షడి పదవి కాలం జనవరి 20 మధ్యాహ్నంతో ముగిసిపోతుందని అమెరికా రాజ్యాంగం స్పష్టంగా చెబుతోంది.ఎన్నికల్లో ఎలక్టోరల్ కాలేజీలో అవసరమైన మెజార్టీ జో బైడెన్ సాధించారు. రాబోయే నాలుగేళ్లు అధ్యక్షుడిగా ఉండేందుకు ఆయనకు హక్కు ఉంది.అయితే, ఎన్నికల ఫలితాలను సవాలు చేసేందుకు న్యాయపరమైన, చట్టపరమైన అవకాశాలు కొన్ని ట్రంప్ ముందు ఉన్నాయి. కానీ, ఎన్నికల్లో అక్రమాలు జరిగాయని ఆయన చేస్తున్న ఆరోపణలకు ఎలాంటి ఆధారాలూ లేవు.సైన్యం పంపించేస్తుందా?ఎన్నికల ప్రచారంలో పాల్గొన్నన్ని రోజులూ ట్రంప్ తాను ఓటమిని అంగీకరించబోనని చెబుతూ వస్తున్నారు. ఎన్నికల్లో అక్రమాలు జరిగితే తప్ప తాను ఓడిపోనన్నది ఆయన ఉద్దేశం.ఈ నేపథ్యంలో ఒకవేళ ట్రంప్ అధికారాన్ని బైడెన్‌కు అప్పగించేందుకు నిరాకరిస్తే, ఏం జరుగుతుందా అన్నది చాలా మంది ముందున్న సందేహం. ఈ అంశం గురించి జో బైడెన్ ఇదివరకే ఓ టీవీ ఇంటర్యూలో మాట్లాడారు. ఎన్నికల్లో ఓడిన తర్వాత ‘ట్రంప్ వైట్ హౌజ్‌ను ఖాళీ చేసి వెళ్లేందుకు నిరాకరిస్తే పరిస్థితి ఏంటన్నది ఆలోచించారా?’ అని బైడెన్‌ను కమెడిన్ ట్రెవర్ నోవా ప్రశ్న అడిగారు.అందుకు... ''అవును. ఆలోచించాను. అలాంటి పరిస్థితి వస్తే, సైన్యం ఆయన్ను వైట్ హౌజ్ నుంచి పంపించేస్తుందని భావిస్తున్నా'' అని బైడెన్ బదులు ఇచ్చారు.అమెరికా సీక్రెట్ సర్వీస్ కూడా ఇలా ట్రంప్‌ను వైట్ హౌజ్‌ నుంచి బయటకు తీసుకువెళ్లవచ్చని భావిస్తున్నారు.అధ్యక్షుడి భద్రత బాధ్యత సీక్రెట్ సర్వీస్‌దే. మాజీ అధ్యక్షులకు కూడా ఈ విభాగం భద్రత అందిస్తుంది.","answer":"244 ఏళ్ల అమెరికా చరిత్రలో ఎన్నికల్లో ఓడిన తర్వాత వైట్ హౌజ్‌ను వదిలి వెళ్లేందుకు అధ్యక్షులు నిరాకరించిన సందర్భం ఎప్పుడూ లేదు."},{"question":"Forniscimi informazioni generali e alcune curiosità sul regista Sergio Leone.","answer":"Sergio Leone (Roma, 3 gennaio 1929 – Roma, 30 aprile 1989) è stato un regista, sceneggiatore e produttore cinematografico italiano.È riconosciuto a livello mondiale come uno dei più grandi e influenti registi di tutti i tempi. Celebre per i suoi film del genere spaghetti-western, nonostante abbia diretto pochi film la sua regia ha fatto scuola, contribuendo alla rinascita del western negli anni sessanta grazie a titoli come \\"Per un pugno di dollari\\", \\"Per qualche dollaro in più\\", \\"Il buono, il brutto, il cattivo\\" (che formano la cosiddetta \\"trilogia del dollaro\\") e \\"C'era una volta il West\\", mentre con \\"C'era una volta in America\\" ha profondamente rinnovato il lessico dei gangster movie (queste ultime due pellicole, assieme a \\"Giù la testa\\", fanno parte invece della \\"trilogia della seconda frontiera americana\\", come definita dallo stesso Leone, altresì conosciuta in seguito come \\"trilogia del tempo\\" da una definizione datagli dal critico cinematografico Morandini o anche, infine, \\"trilogia della fiaba\\").Leone portò nel genere western (e non solo) grandi novità e il suo stile è influente ancora oggi. Nei western tradizionali statunitensi, tanto gli eroi, quanto i cattivi tendono ad avere dei tratti caratteriali idealizzati e stereotipati. Al contrario i personaggi di Leone presentano elementi di marcato realismo e verità: raramente sono sbarbati e appaiono sporchi e talvolta rozzi. Si presentano in genere come antieroi, personaggi dalle personalità complesse, astuti e spesso senza alcuno scrupolo. Questi elementi di crudo realismo continuano a vivere in alcuni western odierni.Ecco alcune curiosità su Sergio Leone:* Quentin Tarantino ha definito Sergio Leone il primo regista post-moderno, che ha influenzato numerosissimi registi. Grande amante del cinema italiano e di Leone, Tarantino, secondo un aneddoto raccontato da lui stesso sul set de \\"Le iene\\" del 1992, agli inizi della propria carriera, non conoscendo ancora tutti i termini tecnici cinematografici era solito chiedere ai propri cameraman \\"give me a Leone\\", ovvero \\"datemi un Leone\\", per avere uno di quei suggestivi primissimi piani sui dettagli, marchio di fabbrica del regista romano.* Stanley Kubrick dichiarò che non avrebbe potuto realizzare \\"Arancia meccanica\\", se non avesse visto \\"Il buono, il brutto, il cattivo\\".* Per la sua importanza nello sviluppo del cinema, non solo per quel che riguarda il western, nel 1992 Clint Eastwood, regista e interprete de \\"Gli spietati\\", inserì nei titoli di coda la dedica \\"A Sergio\\". Lo stesso ha fatto undici anni dopo, nel 2003, Quentin Tarantino, nei titoli di \\"Kill Bill: Volume 2\\". * Nel 1986, scrisse con Carlo Verdone il soggetto e la sceneggiatura del film \\"Troppo forte\\"."},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Inggris yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.I see an orange duck wishing me good luck.Terjemahan:","answer":"Aku melihat seekor bebek jingga mendoakan keberuntunganku."},{"question":"ఈ ఆర్టికల్ ను సంగ్రహించండి:  అవి మంచు యుగం యొక్క అతిపెద్ద దిగ్గజాలు, ఉత్తర అర్ధగోళం యొక్క మంచు మైదానాలలో తిరుగుతూ ఉన్నాయి. కానీ అది ఉన్ని మముత్ యొక్క చివరి రోజులు మనుగడ కోసం ఒక విచారకరమైన పోరాటం అని తెలుస్తోంది. రెండు ఉన్ని మముత్ అవశేషాల జన్యు విశ్లేషణ వారి జనాభా చాలా తక్కువగా ఉందని చూపిస్తుంది, అవి దీర్ఘకాలికంగా అంతర్జాతిగా మారాయి. వీడియో కోసం క్రిందికి స్క్రోల్ చేయండి. చివరి ఉన్ని మముత్ లు (పైన ఉన్న పునర్నిర్మాణంలో చూపబడింది) సుమారు 5,000 సంవత్సరాలుగా ఆర్కిటిక్ ద్వీపంలో ఒంటరిగా ఉన్నాయి, వారి జనాభా తగ్గుతున్న కొద్దీ 4,500 సంవత్సరాల క్రితం అదృశ్యమయ్యే వరకు వాటిని పెంపకం చేయమని బలవంతం చేసింది. ఆర్కిటిక్ లోని ఒక చిన్న ప్రాంతంలో, ప్రధాన భూభాగం నుండి వేరుచేయబడినట్లు కనిపించే ఒక ద్వీపంలో ఈ జీవులు కట్టుబడి ఉన్నాయని పరిశోధకులు నిర్ధారించారు. ఆధునిక ఏనుగులను క్లోన్ చేసే పద్ధతులను ఉపయోగించి ఈ మహా క్షీరదాలను తిరిగి బ్రతికించగలమనే ఆశ కూడా ఈ అధ్యయనంలో పెరిగింది. ఒక ఏనుగు యొక్క జీవన డిన్ఏ లోకి ఒక డజనుకు పైగా జీవుల జన్యువులను చొప్పించడం ద్వారా శాస్త్రవేత్తలు ఉన్ని మముత్ ను పునర్నిర్మించడానికి ఒక పెద్ద అడుగు వేసినట్లు పేర్కొన్నారు. అంతరించిపోయిన 14 జంతువుల జన్యువుల యొక్క ఖచ్చితమైన కాపీలను పునరుత్పత్తి చేయడానికి పరిశోధకులు ఆర్కిటిక్లో సంరక్షించబడిన మముత్ల నుండి డిన్ఏ యొక్క నిర్మాణాన్ని అధ్యయనం చేశారు. ఆ తరువాత మసాచుసెట్స్ లోని హార్వర్డ్ విశ్వవిద్యాలయ నిపుణులు వీటిని ఏనుగు జన్యువులో చేర్చారు - అవి సాధారణ డిన్ఏ  లాగా పనిచేశాయి. 'క్రిస్ప్ర్' అని పిలువబడే ఒక నూతన పద్ధతి శాస్త్రవేత్తలకు డిన్ఏ లో ఖచ్చితమైన మార్పులు చేయడంలో సహాయపడింది - దీనిని జన్యుశాస్త్ర ప్రొఫెసర్ జార్జ్ చర్చి ఉపయోగించారు, అతను ఏనుగు డిన్ఏ యొక్క భాగాలను మాముత్ జన్యువులతో భర్తీ చేశాడు. ఇతర పరిశోధకులు డాలీ గొర్రెల క్లోన్ చేయడానికి ఉపయోగించిన పద్ధతికి సమానమైన పద్ధతిని ఉపయోగించి ఒక ఏనుగు యొక్క డిన్ఏ ను భర్తీ చేయడానికి మముత్ డిన్ఏ ను ఉపయోగించాలని ప్రతిపాదించారు. అయితే, ఈ జంతువులు తమ ప్రాచీన ఆవాసాలు లేకుండా ఆధునిక ప్రపంచంలో మనుగడ సాగించలేవు అని చాలా మంది శాస్త్రవేత్తలు భయపడుతున్నారు. ఇటువంటి పద్ధతులు కూడా జంతువులలో వైకల్యాలు మరియు ఆరోగ్య సమస్యలకు దారి తీయవచ్చు. అయితే, జన్యు విశ్లేషణ వెనుక ఉన్న పరిశోధకులు జంతువులకు దీనివల్ల కలిగే బాధలకు భయపడి ఇతర శాస్త్రవేత్తలు దీనిని ప్రయత్నించవద్దని కోరారు. బదులుగా, వారు వారి ఆవిష్కరణలు కొత్త అంతర్దృష్టులు వెల్లడించింది చెప్పటానికి.","answer":"చివరి మముత్ లు 4,500 సంవత్సరాల క్రితం ఆర్కిటిక్ ద్వీపంలో మరణించాయి. సుమారు 5,000 సంవత్సరాలుగా వ్రేంగెల్ ద్వీపంలో ఒంటరిగా ఉన్న వారు అంతర్జాతిగా మారారు. పరిశోధకులు గతంలో మాముత్ జనాభా క్షీణించినట్లు కనుగొన్నారు. మముత్ లను తిరిగి బ్రతికించే అవకాశం కూడా డిన్ఏ సీక్వెన్సింగ్ ను పెంచుతుంది."},{"question":"Chii chinofanira kuputswa usati wachishandisa?","answer":"Mazai anofanira kuputswa asati ashandiswa."},{"question":"‘நீர்நிலைகளிலிருந்து உதடுகள் குவித்துஉறிஞ்சுகிறது ஒளிக்கதிர்கள்” – இக்கவிதையின் அடி,‘தூங்கும் பனிநீரை வாங்கும் கதிரோனே’ என்னும் நாட்டுப்புறப் பாடலின் தொடர்ச்சியாய் அமைவதைப் பற்றி எழுதுக.","answer":"* ஏற்றம் இறைப்பவர்கள் அலுப்புத் தெரியாமல் இருக்க பாடும் பாடல்களில் இதுவும் ஒன்று.* விடியும் போது மூங்கில் இலை நுனியில் ஒரு சொட்டு பனிநீர் வைரம் வைத்தது போல இருக்கும். சூரியனின் ஒளிக்கதிர்கள் அந்த * ஒருதுளி நீரையும் விட்டு வைக்காமல் தானே எடுத்துக் கொள்வான்.* அதிகாலையில் மூங்கில் இலையில் இருக்கும் பனிநீரை மீண்டும் சூரியன் வாங்கிக் கொள்கிறான். இஃது ஓர் நீர்வட்டம்.“நீர்நிலைகளிலிருந்து உதடுகள் குறித்துஉறிஞ்சுகிறது ஒளிக்கதிர்கள்”நீர் நிலைகளை வந்தடையும் மழை நீரைச் சூரியன் தன் ஒளிக்கதிர் என்ற உதடுகளால் உறிஞ்சுகிறான்.வானில் இருந்து விழும் மழை நீரை மீண்டும் வானுக்கே எடுத்துக் கொள்கின்றான் சூரியன். இது ஒரு நீர் வட்டம்.நயம் :* நாட்டுப்புறப்பாடலில் ஒரு துளி பனி நீரைக்கூட சூரியன் விடுவதில்லை தன் ஒளிக்கதிர்களால் எடுத்துக் கொள்கிறான் எனக் குறிப்பிடப்படுகிறது.* பிறகொரு நாள் கோடை’ கவிதையில் கவிஞர் மழையாக வந்து நீர்நிலைகளை நிரப்பும் நீரைத் தன் கதிர்களால் இதழ் குவித்து உறிஞ்சுகிறது சூரியன் என்கிறார்.* பனித்துளியை வாங்கிக் கொண்டான் கதிரவன் – நாட்டுப்புறப்பாடல்.* நீர்நிலை மழைத்துளிகளை உறிஞ்சுக் கொண்டான் கதிரவன் – பிறகு ஒரு நாள் கோடை."},{"question":"बर्षाको मात्रा नाप्ने यन्त्रलाइ के भनिन्छ ?","answer":"रेन गज"},{"question":"ලෝක ගුවන්විදුලි දිනය සමරනු ලබන්නේ කවදාද ?","answer":"සෑම වසරකම පෙබරවාරි 13 වන දින ලෝක ගුවන්විදුලි දිනය සමරනු ලබයි. මෙම දිනය 2011 දී යුනෙස්කෝ (එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ අධ්‍යාපනික, විද්‍යාත්මක සහ සංස්කෘතික සංවිධානය) සාමාජිකයින් විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද අතර පසුව 2012 දී එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා මණ්ඩලය විසින් ජාත්‍යන්තර දිනයක් ලෙස සම්මත කරන ලදී. ලෝක ගුවන්විදුලි දිනය ගුවන්විදුලිය හරහා තොරතුරු වෙත ප්‍රවේශය, ප්‍රකාශනයේ නිදහස සහ ස්ත්‍රී පුරුෂ සමානාත්මතාවය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමේ මාධ්‍යයක් ලෙස ගුවන්විදුලියේ චිරස්ථායී වැදගත්කම පිළිගනී. පුළුල් ප්‍රේක්ෂක පිරිසක් වෙත ළඟා වීමට සහ ධනාත්මක සමාජ වෙනසක් ඇති කිරීමට ගුවන්විදුලියට ඇති සුවිශේෂී හැකියාව පිළිබඳ මතක් කිරීමක් ලෙස මෙම දිනය ක්‍රියා කරයි."},{"question":"إقرأ التغريدة التالية :#انهانت_كرامتي وقت اي حدا لفكر يهين لبنان بتنهان كرامتي لان كرامة لبنان كرامتنا انهانت كرامتي لما دول بتقدر تتحكم فينا وبقرارتنا. ثم حلل مشاعرها.","answer":"المشاعر في التغريدة السابقة سلبية."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Richards första internationella mästerskap var","answer":"VM 1987 i Rom där hon sprang 400 meter men blev utslagen i semifinalen. Hon deltog vidare vid Olympiska sommarspelen 1992 i Barcelona där hon gick vidare till final, men tiden 50,19 räckte bara till en sjunde plats."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'cakap mulut'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud bahasa yang digunakan dalam percakapan harian. Contoh ayat: Terdapat perbezaan antara bahasa tulisan dengan cakap mulut."},{"question":"Sheeg beertii loo yaqaanay xadiiqatul-mowt,saxaabigii yiraahdey hala iiga tuuro aniga ayaa idin furaaye?","answer":"waxa uu ahaa Baraa Binu maalik (Rc)"},{"question":"휴대전화를 오래 쓰면 암이나 백혈병에 걸릴까?","answer":"휴대전화의 전자파는 인체 조직의 온도를 상승시키는 영향을 줄 수 있어, 주로 SAR(전자파흡수율)로 평가합니다. 국내 기준은 조직 1g당 평균 1.6 W/kg의 SAR 기준을 넘지 않는 제품만 판매하도록 규정하고 있습니다. 이는 인체의 온도 1°C가 상승할 수 있는 산술적으로 계산된 전자파 강도 값의 1/50 수준입니다.다만, 2011년 5월 31일 WHO 산하 국제암연구소(IARC)에서는 RF 전자파의 발암 등급을 2B(possibly to carcinogenic)로 발표하였습니다. 이는 휴대전화와 암 발생 가능성에 대해 역학조사 결과를 토대로 매우 제한적이고 약한 상관관계가 있다는 내용입니다. 역학 조사 결과의 내용은 핸드폰을 10년 동안 매일 30분씩 한쪽 귀로 통화를 하게 되면, 악성 뇌종양의 일종인 신경교종의 발병률이 높아진다는 것입니다. WHO의 이러한 발표는 휴대전화 전자파가 사전주의 차원에서 예방조치 요구 및 필요성이 제기되는 상황이며, 과학적인 근거 마련을 위한 추가적인 심층 연구가 필요함을 밝힌 것입니다."},{"question":"\\" કોણ વધુ બળવાન? \\" બાળવાર્તા લખો.","answer":"એક વખત પવન અને સૂરજ ચડસાચડસીમાં ઊતરી પડ્યા. પવન કહે, ‘સૂરજ, તારા કરતાં હું બળવાન’.‘તું બળવાન? હં!’ સૂરજે કહ્યું: ‘મારી આગળ તારી કશી વિસાત નહિ, સમજ્યો?’પવને કહ્યું: ‘ના ના, તારા કરતાં હું ખૂબ બળવાન, બોલ!’આ જ વખતે તેમણે પૃથ્વી પર રસ્તે ચાલ્યા જતા એક મુસાફરને જોયો. તેણે પોતાના શરીરે શાલ લપેટેલી રાખી હતી.સૂરજે પવનને કહ્યું: ‘પેલા મુસાફરની શાલ આપણા બેમાંથી જે ઉતરાવે તે વધુ બળવાન. બોલ છે કબૂલ?’પવને કહ્યું: ‘મંજૂર!’‘જા, પહેલી તક તને આપું છું’, સૂરજે પવનને કહ્યું.‘અરે, હમણાં જ તેની શાલ ઉડાડી દઉં છું. જોજેને!’ પવન બોલ્યો.પવન મુસાફરના શરીર ઉપરથી શાલ ઉડાડવા જોરજોરથી ફૂંકાવા લાગ્યો. પરંતુ પવન જેટલો જોરથી ફૂંકાવા લાગ્યો, મુસાફર એટલા જ જોરથી શાલ કસીને પોતાના શરીર સાથે લપેટીને રાખવા લાગ્યો. આ સંઘર્ષ ત્યાં સુધી ચાલ્યો જ્યાં સુધી પવનનો વારો પૂરો ન થયો.હવે સૂરજનો વારો આવ્યો. સૂરજે હળવેથી પૃથ્વી પર માત્ર હૂંફાળું સ્મિત વેર્યું. મુસાફરને જરાક ગરમી લાગી. એણે તરત જ શાલની પકડ ઢીલી કરી નાંખી. જેમ જેમ સૂરજનું સ્મિત વધતું ગયું તેમ તેમ પૃથ્વી પર ગરમી વધતી ગઈ. હવે મુસાફરને શાલ ઓઢી રાખવાની જરૂર ન લાગી. તેણે શાલ ઉતારીને પોતાના હાથમાં લઈ લીધી. પવનને માનવું પડ્યું કે પોતાનાથી સૂરજ બળવાન છે.ઘણી વખત જે કામ બળથી ન થાય તે કામ કેવળ એક નાનકડું, મીઠડું સ્મિત કરી જાય છે!"},{"question":"چیستان: کدام حیوان را اگر برعکس کنید قرمز می شود؟","answer":"پاسخ خرس است."},{"question":": Waxaad Sheegtaan waxa ku waajibay qofkii ugu yeera qof kaali aan ciyaarne qamaar?","answer":": Qofkii qof ugu jeera iney qamaaraan ama qamaar ciyaaraan wuxuu bixinayaa saddaqo sida ka sugnaatay Nabiga (scw).    "},{"question":"மாணவர்களுக்கு இரண்டு கைகளாலும் எழுதப்பயிற்சி அளிக்கும் நாடு எது ?","answer":"ஜப்பான்."},{"question":"Sino ang nag-imbento ng calculus?","answer":"Noong ika-18 na siglo, nagkaroon ng pagtatalo sa kung sino kay Isaac Newton at Gottfriend Leibniz ang unang nag-imbento ng calculus. Si Newton ang unang nagsulat tungkol sa calculus noong 1669, ngunit si Leibniz ang unang naglathala ng kayang gawa tungkol noong 1684.  Ngayon, karaniwan nang pinaniniwalaan na hiwalay na inimbento nina Newton at Leibniz ang calculus, lalo na't magkaiba ang paraan na ginamit ng bawat isa upang ilarawan ito."},{"question":"めぐみとしあき、いしづかひでひこ、といえば２人のコンビ名は何？","answer":"ホンジャマカです。"},{"question":"తుమున్నాద్యర్థకము గురించి రాసి ఉదాహరణలు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"తుమున్నాద్యర్థకము – కారణమును తెలియజేసేది. ధాతువునకు “అన్” చేరును.ఉదా : చేయన్, తినన్."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jadi abu arang'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud barang yang telah rosak. Contoh ayat: Basikal saya yang dipinjamnya telah menjadi abu arang."},{"question":"Xagee ka helnaa oksajiinta?","answer":"Oksajiinta waxaan ka helnaa dhirta."},{"question":"Orilẹ-ede Yoruba: Awọn eeyan wọde l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Arọni o wale Onikoyi o sinmi ogun lawọn to n beere fun Orilẹ-ede Yoruba n wi, iyẹn naa lo si gbe wọn jade layajọ ‘June 12’, l’Abẹokuta.Orin kan naa ti wọn n kọ bi wọn ṣe n kiri igboro ilu naa ko ju pe awọn fẹẹ kuro ni Naijiria, Orilẹ-ede Yoruba lawọn fẹ.Mọto rẹpẹtẹ ati ọkada pupọ lawọn oluwọde naa fi n polongo kiri awọn agbegbe bii Ibara ati Ṣapọn. Koda, wọn gba iwaju ọgba ẹwọn ati ileefowopamọ ilẹ wa kọja n’Ibara, wọn ko sọ nnkan meji ju pe awọn n fẹ ilẹ Olominira Yoruba lọ.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe iwọde naa ko mu ija wa, nigba ti wọn de iwaju ọgba ẹwọn Ibara, awọn agbofinro to wa nibẹ ni ki wọn maa lọ, ki wọn ma jo de iwaju awọn rara.Ọrọ naa dija nibudokọ Lagos Garage, n’Ijẹbu-Ode, nigba ti awọn ọmọọta gba iwọde naa mọ awọn ti wọn n ṣe e lọwọ, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i yinbọn."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ॥ਜੋ ਜਨ ਲੇਹਿ ਖਸਮ ਕਾ ਨਾਉ ॥ ਤਿਨ ਕੈ ਸਦ ਬਲਿਹਾਰੈ ਜਾਉ ॥੧॥ਸੋ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਨ ਗਾਵੈ ॥ਸੋ ਭਾਈ ਮੇਰੈ ਮਨਿ ਭਾਵੈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਜਿਹ ਘਟ ਰਾਮੁ ਰਹਿਆ ਭਰਪੂਰਿ ॥ ਤਿਨ ਕੀ ਪਗ ਪੰਕਜ ਹਮ ਧੂਰਿ ॥੨॥ਜਾਤਿ ਜੁਲਾਹਾ ਮਤਿ ਕਾ ਧੀਰੁ ॥ਸਹਜਿ ਸਹਜਿ ਗੁਣ ਰਮੈ ਕਬੀਰੁ ॥੩॥੨੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 328 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਭਗਤ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਾਲਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦੇ ਹਨ, ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।੧।ਜੋ ਵੀਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸੁਹਣੇ (ਨਿਰਮਲ) ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਹੈਤੇ ਉਹ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਰਗਟ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੌਲ ਫੁੱਲ ਵਰਗੇ (ਸੁਹਣੇ) ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਅਸੀ ਧੂੜ ਹਾਂ (ਭਾਵ, ਚਰਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ) ।੨।ਕਬੀਰ ਭਾਵੇਂ ਜਾਤ ਦਾ ਜੁਲਾਹ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਮੱਤ ਦਾ ਧੀਰਜ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ) ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।੨੬।\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'gigi dengan lidah ada kalanya tergigit juga'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kerap kali juga timbul perselisihan antara suami isteri, sanak saudara dan sahabat handai."},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum France","answer":"Péeyum réwum France mu ngi tudu Paris"},{"question":"انشئ قصيدة رثاء من بحر الكامل.","answer":"لَولا يَذُمُّ الرَكبُ عِندَكَ مَوقِفيحَيَّيتُ قَبرَكَ يا أَبا إِسحَقِكَيفَ اِشتِياقُكَ مُذ نَأَيتَ إِلى أَخٍقَلِقِ الضَميرِ إِلَيكَ بِالأَشواقِهَل تَذكُرُ الزَمَنَ الأَنيقَ وَعَيشُنايَحلو عَلى مُتَأَمَّلٍ وَمُذاقِوَلَيالِيَ الصَبَواتِ وَهيَ قَصائِرٌخَطفَ الوَميضِ بِعارِضٍ مِبراقِلا بُدَّ لِلقُرَباءِ أَن يَتَزايَلوايَوماً بِعُذرِ قِلىً وَعُذرِ فِراقِأَمضي وَتَعطِفُني إِلَيكَ نَوازِعٌبِتَنَفُّسٍ كَتَنَفُّسِ العُشّاقِوَأَذودُ عَن عَيني الدُموعَ وَلَو خَلَتلَجَرَت عَلَيكَ بِوابِلٍ غَيداقِوَلَوَ اِنَّ في طَرفي قَذاةً مِن ثَرىًوَأَراكَ ما قَذَّيتُها مِن ماقيإِن تَمضِ فَالمَجدُ المُرَجَّبُ خالِدٌأَو تَفنَ فَالكَلِمُ العِظامُ بَواقيمَشحوذَةٌ تَدمى بِغَيرِ مَضارِبٍكَالسَيفِ أُطلِقَ في طُلى الأَعناقِيُقبِلنَ كَالجَيشِ المُغيرِ يَؤُمُّهُكَمِشُ الإِزارِ مُقَلِّصٌ عَن ساقِقِرَطاتُ آذانِ المُلوكِ خَليقَةٌبِمَواضِعِ التيجانِ وَالأَطواقِعَقَدوا بِها المَجدَ الشَرودَ وَأَثَّلوادَرَجاً إِلى شَرَفِ العُلى وَمَراقيأَوتَرتَها أَيّامَ باعُكَ صُلَّبٌوَكَدَدتَها بِالنَزعِ وَالإِغراقِحَتّى إِذا مَرِحَت قُواكَ شَدَدتَهابِاِسمٍ عَلى عَقِبِ اللَيالي باقيكَنَجائِبٍ قَعَدَت بِها أَرماقُهامَحسورَةً فَمَشَينَ بِالأَعراقِ"},{"question":"బాయిలరు గ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ","answer":"బాయిలరు గ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరు అను ఉపకరణం బాయిలరులో వున్న నీటి మట్టాన్ని తెలుపుతుంది.గ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరు బాయిలరు లోని నీటిమట్టాన్ని నేరుగా కచ్చితంగా చూపును.గ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరు బాయిలరు మీద అమర్చబడి వుండు ముఖ్యమైన ఉపకరణం. గ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరును  బాయిలరు వాటరు గేజ్ అనికూడా అంటారు[1].బాయిలరు గ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరు ఆవశ్యకతబాయిలరు పనిచేయునప్పుడు, బాయిలరులోని నీరు ఆవిరిగా మారడం వలన నీటిమట్టం క్రమంగా తగ్గుతుంది.బాయిలరులోని నీటిమట్టం బాయిలరు లోపలి బాయిలరు గొట్టాల కన్నతక్కువ మట్టానికి పడిపోయిన, ఫ్లూగ్యాసేస్ ఉష్ణోగ్రతకు బాయిలరు ట్యూబులు అమితంగా వేడెక్కి పేలి పోవును.అందువలన ఆవిరిగా మారుతున్న నీటి ప్రమాణానికి సరి పడా నీ టిని బాయిలరులోనికి ఎప్పడికప్పుడు పంపు ద్వారా పంపించ వలసి వున్నది.బాయిలరు డ్రమ్ములో నీటి మట్టం బాయిలరు లోణి హీటింగు ట్యూబుల బండిల్ మట్టాన్నిదాటి,షెల్ లో దాదాపు గరిష్టంగా మూడు వంతులు ఉండును.పంపు ద్వారా నీటిని ఎప్పటి కప్పుడు లోనికి మూడు వంతులు ఉండేలా నింపుటకు లోపల ఎంతవరకు నీరు వున్నది తెలియాలంటే  బాయిలరు  గ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరు ఉపకరిస్తుంది.ఈ వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరులో వున్న గ్యాసు గొట్టం వలన బాయిలరు లోని నీటి మట్టం క చ్చితంగా తెలుస్తుంది.గ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరులోని భాగాలుగ్లాసు ట్యూబు:ఇది సాధారణంగా 1/2\\" లేదా 3/4\\"సైజులో వుండును.10.5నుండి 24.7 కేజిల పిడనాన్ని,మరియు 220°Cనుండి400°C ఉష్ణోగ్రత తట్టుకో గల్లును.పొడవు బాయిలరును బట్టీ 400-500 మిల్లి.మీటర్లు వుండును.గ్లాసు బోరోసిలికెట్ తో చెయ్యబడి దృఢంగా వుండును.కాక్ లు(Cocks)+ఇవి సాధారణంగా ఇత్తడి లేదా కంచుతో చేసినవి.గ్లాసు ట్యూబు రక్షక గాజు పలకల స్టీలు ఫ్రేముగ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరు అమరికగ్లాసు ట్యూబు వాటరు లెవల్ ఇండికేటరులో మందమైన గాజు గొట్టం మరియు మూడు కాక్ /వాల్వులు వుండును.అందులోఒకటి స్టీము కాక్, రెండవది వాటరు కాక్, మూడవది డ్రైన్ కాక్.గాజు గొట్టం అధిక వేడిని మరియు స్టీము పీడనాన్ని తట్టుకునే దృడత్వము కల్గి వుండును.స్టీము కాక్ బాయిలరు లోని స్టీము బాగంకు అతికించబడి వున్న పైపు ఫ్లాంజికి బిగించబడి వుండును. ఈ స్టీము కాక్ తో  ఇండికేటరుపరికరానికి స్టీమును వచ్చేలా, ఆగేలా చెయ్య వచ్చును. స్టీము కాక్ గ్లాసు ట్యూబుకు పైభాగాన అమర్చబడి వుండును. అలాగే వాటరు కాక్..."},{"question":"Quelle est une astuce pour mieux dormir la nuit ?","answer":"Éviter d’utiliser des écrans comme les tablettes tactiles, les téléphones intelligents ou encore les ordinateurs, au moins 30 minutes avant d’aller au lit. La luminosité des appareils stimule votre cerveau."},{"question":"Качество языковых моделей в задачах классификации текста измеряется такими метриками, как: ","answer":"полнота, точность и доля правильных ответов. Также часто используется F1-мера для оценки качества."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga:\\"Ny teny toy ny fonosana, ka _.\\"","answer":"\\"Ny teny toy ny fonosana, ka izay mamono no mamaha.\\""},{"question":"Nếu được đi thăm Đồng Tháp Mười, em sẽ đến nơi nào nêu trong bài du kí Đồng Tháp Mười mùa nước nổi ? Vì sao?","answer":"Nếu được đi thăm Đồng Tháp Mười, em sẽ đến đầm lầy sen mọc giữa rừng tràm ở trong bài du kí. Bởi vì em muốn xem thực sự sen nơi đây nhiều đến mức nào mà khiến tác giả cảm thấy ngợp. Và em cũng muốn được trải nghiệm cảm giác rợn ngợp và cô độc giữa cái mênh mông của sen tinh khiết, sen ngạo nghễ.Xem thêm các bài Soạn văn lớp 6 Cánh diều hay nhất, ngắn gọn khác:"},{"question":"\\"Ny fanohanana matihanina, amin'ny endrika fitsaboana na torohevitra, dia mety hahasoa amin'ny fandresena ireo fanamby ara-pihetseham-po amin'ny fisarahana.\\". Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia ny fisarahana."},{"question":"Tahun ini merupakan tahun kemerdekaan negara Malaysia ke?A) Ke 58B) Ke 55C) Ke 65D) Ke 61","answer":"C) Ke 65"},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, ọmọ Baba Adeboye lọkunrin ku lojiji","answer":"Agbọ-sọgba-nu ni iroyin iku Pasitọ Dare Adeboye, ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ Pasitọ ijọ Ridiimu, Enock Adeboye, jẹ fun gbogbo awọn eeyan, paapaa awọn ọmọ ijọ naa.Idi ni pe ọkunrin naa ko saisan ti tẹlẹ, wọn ni niṣe ni pasitọ ẹni ọdun mejilelogoji naa to jẹ oluṣọagutan ijọ Ridiimu to wa niluu Eket, nipinlẹ Akwa Ibom, sun ti ko si ji mọ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe ko si nnkan kan to ṣe pasitọ naa, wọn ni o pa foonu rẹ, o ni oun ko fẹ ki ẹnikẹni yọ oun lẹnu, oun fẹẹ sun, bẹẹ lo si lọọ sun.Ṣugbọn nigba ti iyawo rẹ, Temiloluwa Adeboye, ṣakiyesi pe ọkọ oun ti sun tipẹ, ti ki i si i sun bẹẹ tẹlẹ lo pe foonu rẹ, nigba to pe foonu yii ti ko gbọ ijẹ kankan latọdọ rẹ, to si gba ilẹkun yara naa ti ko sẹni to daa loun lo mu ariwo bọnu.O ṣe ni laaanu pe nigba ti wọn pada ṣilẹkun yara naa, oku Pasitọ Dare Adeboye ni wọn ba, ọkunrin naa ti ku. Awọn ojiṣẹ Olọrun ijọ naa kora wọn jọ lati gbadura boya ọkunrin yii le ji saye, ṣugbọn ọrọ ko ri bẹẹ mọ.Adari eto iroyin fun ijọ Ridiimu, Pasitọ Ọlaitan Olubiyi, fidi iroyin iku ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ olori ijọ Ridiimu naa mulẹ, o ni loootọ ni Pasitọ Dare ti ku ni Eket, nipinlẹ Akwa Ibom, to n gbe, ṣugbọn ohun ko ti i le ṣalaye ohunkohun nipa iku rẹ.Ti ki i baa ṣe iku to pa oju rẹ de yii, inu oṣu to n bọ, iyẹn oṣu kẹfa, ọdun yii, ni Pasitọ Dare to jọ Baba Adeboye bii imumu iba pe ẹni ọdun mẹtalelogun laye.Ọkunrin yii ni akọbi Pasitọ Adeboye lọkunrin, ọmọ iyanu ni baba naa si maa n pe e.Ni ọdun to kọja ti Pasitọ Adeboye ki ọmọ rẹ yii ku oriire lo sọ pe Ọlọrun dojuti satani nigba ti awọn bi ọmọkunrin awọn yii.O kọ ọ pe ‘Ọmọ iyanu wa akọkọ, a gbadura pe Ọlọrun yoo tẹsiwaju ninu iṣẹ iyanu rẹ ninu aye rẹ ati ninu aye gbogbo awọn ti wọn nilo iyanu lonii. A lo ọ gẹgẹ bii ohun eelo afọwọkan fun aye tiwọn naa lorukọ Jesu. Ọrọ ifẹ yii wa lati ọdọ baba, mama ati gbogbo mọlẹbi Adeboye lapapọ.’Bi baba yii ṣe kọ ọrọ ikinni si ọmọ rẹ ti wọn ni o jẹ ọkan ninu awọn pasitọ to maa n waasu fun awọn ọdọ ti awọn eeyan si fẹran daadaa ọhun ree lasiko ọjọ ibi rẹ lọdun to kọja. Ṣugbọn o ṣe ni laaanu pe iku ko jẹ ki o ṣe ọjọ ibi mi-in loke eepẹ.Ọpọ awọn to ti gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ buruku naa ni wọn n ba mọlẹbi Adeboye kẹdun, ti wọn si n gbadura pe ki Ọlọrun tu wọn ninu."},{"question":"أريد أن أتعلم الشعر. أنشيء قصيدة عتاب من بحر مجزوء الكامل.","answer":"حسناً بالتأكيد: لا تَعذُلَنّي في السُكوتِ فَرُبَّ قَولٍ لا يُقالُكَم صامِتٍ مُتَوَقِّعٍأَنّى يَعِنُّ لَهُ المَقالُإِنَّ التَحَمُّلَ نُطفَةٌأَبَداً يُرَنِّقُها السُؤالُما كُنتُ أَرغَبُ في الحَياةِ وَلَيسَ لي عِزٌّ وَمالُلي لَو عَلِمتُ إِلى ذُرى العَلياءِ آمالٌ طِوالُ."},{"question":"Write a Python function to implement a custom sorting order. Sort a list of tuples based on the second item in descending order.","answer":"def custom_sort(lst):    return sorted(lst, key=lambda x: x[1], reverse=True)tuples_list = [(1, 3), (3, 2), (2, 5)]print(custom_sort(tuples_list))  # Output: [(2, 5), (1, 3), (3, 2)]"},{"question":"Pada pandangan anda, apakah faktor yang membolehkan Malaysia berjaya menangani pelbagai isu global? ","answer":"Skema jawapan:F1 Kepimpinan yang berkaliber.H1a Kebijaksanaan menyusun strategi berasaskan isu.C1 Isu kempen Antiminyak sawit.H1b Berusaha mendapatkan pengiktirafan badan dunia.Н1c Melaksanakan amalan baik dalam pengeluaran sawit.H1d Menggunakan pendekatan diplomatik.H1e Memberikan penerangan melalui hubungan / lawatan dua hala.I Mengelakkan sebarang konflik dalam penyelesaian isu.F2 Pembangunan prasarana / kemudahan asas.H2a Menyediakan tenaga kepakaran bidang kesihatanC2 Isu penyakit berjangkit.H2b Mendapatkan khidmat nasihat badan antarabangsaH2c Melakukan pemeriksaan kesihatan secara berterusanH2d Mengurangkan masalah penularan wabak.H2e Mendapatkan perakuan daripada WHO.I Menyediakan khidmat kesihatan bertaraf dunia. "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਭੁਗਤਿ ਗਿਆਨੁ ਦਇਆ ਭੰਡਾਰਣਿ ਘਟਿ ਘਟਿ ਵਾਜਹਿ ਨਾਦ ॥ਆਪਿ ਨਾਥੁ ਨਾਥੀ ਸਭ ਜਾ ਕੀ ਰਿਧਿ ਸਿਧਿ ਅਵਰਾ ਸਾਦ ॥ਸੰਜੋਗੁ ਵਿਜੋਗੁ ਦੁਇ ਕਾਰ ਚਲਾਵਹਿ ਲੇਖੇ ਆਵਹਿ ਭਾਗ ॥ਆਦੇਸੁ ਤਿਸੈ ਆਦੇਸੁ ॥ਆਦਿ ਅਨੀਲੁ ਅਨਾਦਿ ਅਨਾਹਤਿ ਜੁਗੁ ਜੁਗੁ ਏਕੋ ਵੇਸੁ ॥੨੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 6 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੀ ਸਰਬ-ਵਿਆਪਕਤਾ ਦਾ ਗਿਆਨ ਤੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਭੰਡਾਰਾ (ਚੂਰਮਾ) ਹੋਵੇ, ਦਇਆ ਇਸ (ਗਿਆਨ-ਰੂਪ) ਭੰਡਾਰੇ ਦੀ ਵਰਤਾਈ ਹੋਵੇ, ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਜਿਹੜੀ (ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ ਰੌ ਚੱਲ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ, (ਭੰਡਾਰਾ ਛਕਣ ਵੇਲੇ ਜੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਇਹ ਨਾਦੀ ਵੱਜ ਰਹੀ ਹੋਵੇ,  ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਥ ਆਪ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਹੋਵੇ, ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਵੱਸ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਰੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਹੈ,ਇਹ) ਰਿੱਧੀਆਂ ਤੇ ਸਿੱਧੀਆਂ (ਤਾਂ) ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਪਾਸੇ ਖੜਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਸੁਆਦ ਹਨ। ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੀ “ਸੰਜੋਗ” ਸੱਤਾ ਤੇ “ਵਿਜੋਗ” ਸੱਤਾ ਦੋਵੇਂ (ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਇਸ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਦੀ) ਕਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਚਲਾ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਲੇਖ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ (ਦਰਜਾ-ਬ-ਦਰਜਾ ਸੁਖ ਦੁਖ ਦੇ) ਛਾਂਦੇ ਮਿਲ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਕੇਵਲ ਉਸ (ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ) ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਮ ਕਰੋ, ਜੋ (ਸਭ ਦਾ) ਮੁੱਢ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਸੁੱਧ ਸਰੂਪ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਮੁੱਢ ਨਹੀਂ (ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦਾ), ਜੋ ਨਾਸ ਰਹਿਤ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਜੋ ਸਦਾ ਇਕੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨੯।\\""},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:રણમાં આવેલો લીલોતરીવાળો પ્રદેશ","answer":"રણદ્વીપ "},{"question":"Адмирал (калдыркан) бул...","answer":"Адмирал (калдыркан) (Pyrameis atalanta) - калдыркандардын бир түрү."},{"question":"Como o átomo atende o celular?","answer":"Próton!"},{"question":"O que são números primos na matemática?","answer":"Números primos são números naturais maiores que 1 que são apenas divisíveis por 1 e por eles mesmos, sem qualquer outro divisor."},{"question":"ਬਾਰਸੀਲੋਨਾ:  ਸਪੈਨਿਸ਼ ਕਲੱਬ ਬਾਰਸੀਲੋਨਾ ਨੇ ਚੈਂਪੀਅਨਜ਼ ਲੀਗ ਫੁਟਬਾਲ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਟਾਰ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਲਿਓਨਲ ਮੈਸੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਗੈਰ ਖੇਡਦਿਆਂ ਇੰਟਰ ਮਿਲਾਨ ਨੂੰ 2-0 ਨਾਲ ਹਰਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਹੱਥ ’ਤੇ ਫਰੈਕਚਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮੈਸੀ ਤਿੰਨ ਹਫ਼ਤਿਆਂ ਲਈ ਟੀਮ ’ਚੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਬਾਰਸੀਲੋਨਾ ਐਤਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਅਗਲਾ ਮੈਚ ਰਿਆਲ ਮੈਡਰਿਡ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਖੇਡੇਗੀ। ਉਂਜ ਇਸ ਜਿੱਤ ਨਾਲ ਬਾਰਸੀਲੋਨਾ ਨੇ ਆਖਰੀ 16 ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਲਈ ਥਾਂ ਲਗਪਗ ਪੱਕੀ ਕਰ ਲਈ ਹੈ।ਐਤਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਬਾਰਸੀਲੋਨਾ ਖਿਲਾਫ ਕੌਣ ਖੇਡੇਗਾ?","answer":"ਰੀਅਲ ਮੈਡਰਿਡ ਐਤਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਬਾਰਸੀਲੋਨਾ ਖਿਲਾਫ ਖੇਡੇਗਾ।"},{"question":"संविधान सभा नेपालले कति वर्षमा संविधान बनायो?","answer":"२०७२ सालमा"},{"question":"नेपालको पवित्र पोखरीमा कसरी पुग्ने ?","answer":"काठमाडौंदेखि जनकपुरसम्म सिधा उडान गर्ने धेरै एयरलाइन्स छन् । लामो दूरीका बसहरू रात र दिन दुवै सेवाहरू देशका प्रमुख केन्द्रहरूबाट शहरमा सञ्चालन हुन्छन्।"},{"question":"வினா : தமிழ்நாட்டின் ஈரோட்டில் பிறந்த புகழ்பெற்ற இந்தியக் கணிதவியலாளர் யார்?","answer":"விடை : ஸ்ரீனிவாச ராமானுஜன்."},{"question":"අත්‍යන්තයෙන් මෙම වචනයේ තේරුම කියනවද?","answer":"අති + අන්ත ( ගාත්‍රාදේශය)ඉතාමත්ම / අතිශයින්ම /තදබල ලෙසින් ම / අධික භාවයේ උපරිමයෙන් ම"},{"question":"Moa ve ny \\"Grande muraille de Chine\\" no rindrina lava indrindra eran-tany?","answer":"Eny, ny \\"grande muraille de Chine\\" no rindrina lava indrindra eran-tany, mirefy 21 000 kilaometatra mahery."},{"question":"Verfassen Sie mir eine passende Trivia-Frage zur folgenden Kategorie: Video-Spiele.","answer":"Was ist Marios ursprünglicher Name? Ossan"},{"question":"Những câu thơ sau (bản dịch) của tác giả nào?Đừng tưởng xuân tàn hoa rụng hết,Đêm qua, sân trước, một cành maia. Mãn Giácc. Nguyễn Trãic. Nguyễn Bỉnh Khiêm","answer":"đây là thơ của thiền sư Mãn GiácCáo tật thị chúng (Có bệnh, bảo mọi người) của thiền sư Mãn Giác (1052-1096), được đánh giá là một trong những tác phẩm hay nhất thời Lý.Theo Từ điển Văn học Việt Nam (Nhà xuất bản Văn học, 2018), thiền sư Mãn Giác tên thật là Lý Trường, là một nhà sư, nhà văn đời Lý. Sinh trưởng trong một gia đình quan lại, ông am tường cả Nho giáo và Phật giáo từ rất sớm. Lý Trường được vua Lý Nhân Tông vời vào cung, đặt tên là Hoài Tín. Sau đó, Hoài Tín dâng biểu xin xuất gia, học với Thiền sư Quảng Trí và vân du khắp nơi.Thiền sư Mãn Giác là bậc lĩnh tụ pháp môn trong một thời, được vua cùng hoàng hậu kính nể và dựng chùa Giáo Nguyên thỉnh sư làm trụ trì. Cáo tật thị chúng là bài một bài kệ ngắn gồm sáu câu, vừa ngầm diễn tả quan niệm luân hồi của Phật giáo, vừa muốn nói đến tính tương đối của chính quan niệm ấy.Xuân khứ bách hoa lạcXuân đáo bách hoa khaiSự trục nhãn tiền quáLão tòng đầu thượng laiMạc vị xuân tàn hoa lạc tậnĐình tiền tạc dạ nhất chi mai.Bản dịch thơ của Ngô Tất Tố:Xuân qua, trăm hoa rụng,Xuân tới, trăm hoa cười.Trước mắt, việc đi mãi,Trên đầu, già đến rồi.Đừng tưởng xuân tàn hoa rụng hết;Đêm qua, sân trước, một cành maiTheo Từ điển tác giả, tác phẩm văn học Việt Nam dùng cho nhà trường (Nhà xuất bản Đại học Sư phạm, 2009), bài thơ trên là tác phẩm duy nhất còn lại của thiền sư Mãn Giác. Bài thơ đã thể hiện một quan niệm triết lý của Phật giáo thiền tông, đồng thời đạt đến chỗ mỹ lệ và tinh tế nhất của tình yêu thiên nhiên, những cảm giác chân thật.Tác phẩm cũng thể hiện sự nhạy bén của tác giả với sức sống tự nhiên cứ tuôn chảy dào dạt, xem đó mới chính là bản chất bất biến trong quy luật sinh thành mà Phật giáo gọi là chân như - tức là thể tính chân thực, không biến đổi, có trong hết thảy muôn vật."},{"question":"Германиянын борбору?","answer":"Германиянын борбору Берлин. "},{"question":"સીએનઇટી એટલે શું?","answer":"સીએનઇટી (કમ્પ્યુટર નેટવર્ક માટે ટૂંકા) એ એક અમેરિકન મીડિયા વેબસાઇટ છે જે વૈશ્વિક સ્તરે સમીક્ષાઓ, સમાચાર, લેખ, બ્લોગ્સ, પોડકાસ્ટ અને ટેકનોલોજી અને ગ્રાહક ઇલેક્ટ્રોનિક્સ પરના વિડિઓઝ પ્રકાશિત કરે છે.સીએનઇટે મૂળ રૂપે તેના ઇન્ટરનેટ ટેલિવિઝન નેટવર્ક, સીએનઇટી વિડિઓ અને તેના પોડકાસ્ટ અને બ્લોગ નેટવર્ક દ્વારા નવી મીડિયા વિતરણ પદ્ધતિઓ લાગુ કરતા પહેલા તેની વેબસાઇટ ઉપરાંત રેડિયો અને ટેલિવિઝન માટે સામગ્રીનું નિર્માણ કર્યું.1992 માં હેલ્સી માઇનોર અને શેલ્બી બોની દ્વારા સ્થપાયેલ, તે સીએનઇટી નેટવર્ક્સની ફ્લેગશિપ બ્રાન્ડ હતી અને 2008 માં સીએનઇટી નેટવર્ક્સના એકમના સંપાદન દ્વારા સીબીએસ ઇન્ટરેક્ટિવની બ્રાન્ડ બની હતી. 30 ઓક્ટોબર, 2020 થી તેની માલિકીની છે.અંગ્રેજી સિવાય, સીએનઇટીના ક્ષેત્ર- અને ભાષા-વિશિષ્ટ આવૃત્તિઓમાં ચાઇનીઝ, ફ્રેન્ચ, જર્મન, જાપાની, કોરિયન અને સ્પેનિશ શામેલ છે.\\""},{"question":"ਅਨਿਲ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਅਨਿਲ ਰਾਧਾਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ (ਜਨਮ 17 ਅਕਤੂਬਰ 1970) ਇੱਕ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਟੀਮ ਦਾ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਕਪਤਾਨ ਵੀ ਹੈ। ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਬਤੌਰ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਟੀਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੇਡਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਅਨਿਲ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਜਿਮ ਲੇਕਰ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਟੈਸਟ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਪਾਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ 10 ਵਿਕਟਾਂ ਲਈਆਂ ਹਨ। ਉਹ ਕਰਨਾਟਕ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਬੰਗਲੋਰ ਨਗਰ ਦਾ ਨਿਵਾਸੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਨਮਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਸ ਨਗਰ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਮੁੱਖ ਚੌਕ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ 'ਅਨਿਲ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਚੌਕ' ਰੱਖਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਇਕ ਮੈਚ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਾਂ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੇ ਟੁੱਟੇ ਜਬਾੜੇ ਨਾਲ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ 2 ਵਿਕਟਾਂ ਲੲੀਆਂ ਸਨ। == ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜੀਵਨ ==ਅਨਿਲ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 17 ਅਕਤੂਬਰ 1970 ਨੂੰ ਬੰਗਲੋਰ(ਕਰਨਾਟਕ) ਵਿੱਚ ਪਿਤਾ ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਸਵਾਮੀ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਸਰੋਜਾ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਹੋੲਿਆ।ਅਨਿਲ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਦੇ ਭਰਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਂਮ ਦਿਨੇਸ਼ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਹੈ। ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਦੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਦਾ ਨਾਂਮ ਚੇਤਨਾ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਦੋ ਬੱਚੇ ਹਨ- ਪੁੱਤਰ ਮਾੲਿਆਸ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਅਤੇ ਪੁੱਤਰੀ ਸਵਾਸਤੀ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ।ਉਸਦੀ ੲਿੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਲਡ਼ਕੀ ਹੈ, ਅਰੁਣੀ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ (ਜੋ ਕਿ ਚੇਤਨਾ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਜਨਮੀ ਸੀ)।ਛੋਟੇ ਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ 'ਹੋਲੀ ਸੰਤ ੲਿੰਗਲਿਸ਼ ਸਕੂਲ' ਵਿੱਚ ਪਡ਼੍ਹਦਾ ਸੀ। ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਬੰਗਲੋਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਗਲੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੇਡਣ ਲੱਗਾ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ 13 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ 'ਜਵਾਨ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟਰਸ' ਕਲੱਬ ਨਾਲ ਜੁਡ਼ ਗਿਆ। ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੇ ੲਿਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਕਾਲਜ ਬਾਸਾਵਾਂਗੁਵਡ਼ੀ ਤੋਂ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਗ੍ਰਹਿਣ ਕੀਤੀ। ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਗ੍ਰੈਜੂੲੇਸ਼ਨ ਮਕੈਨੀਕਲ ੲਿੰਜੀਨੀਅਰਿੰਗ ਵਿੱਚ 'ਰਸ਼ਤਰਿਆ ਵਿਦਿਆਲਾ ੲਿੰਜੀਨੀਅਰਿੰਗ ਕਾਲਜ' ਤੋਂ 1991-92 ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸਦਾ ਨਾਂਮ 'ਜੰਬੋ' ਨਾ ਸਿਰਫ ਉਸਦੇ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ ਕਰਕੇ ਪਿਆ ਸਗੋਂ ਉਸਦੇ ਪੈਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਕਾਰ ਵੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਵੱਡਾ ਸੀ, ੲਿਸ ਲੲੀ ਵੀ ਉਸਨੂੰ 'ਜੰਬੋ' ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਣ ਲੱਗਾ।ਅਨਿਲ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਦਾ ਆਖ਼ਰੀ ਨਾਮ ਭਾਵ 'ਕੁੰਬਲੇ', ੲਿੱਕ ਕੁੰਬਲਾ ਨਾਂਮ ਦੇ ਪਿੰਡ ਤੋਂ ਪਿਆ ਜੋ ਕਿ ਜਿਲ੍ਹਾ ਕਾਸਾਰਾਗੋਡ(ਕੇਰਲਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੈ। ਅਨਿਲ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਦੇ ਨਾਂਮ ਤੇ ਕੁਝ ਚੌਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਉਦਘਾਟਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।== ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ===== ਘਰੇਲੂ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ===ਕਰਨਾਟਕ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਘਰੇਲੂ ਮੈਚ 1989 ਵਿੱਚ ਹੈਦਰਾਬਾਦ ਖਿਲ਼ਾਫ ਖੇਡਿਆ। ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਚਾਰ ਵਿਕਟ ਲੲੇ। ਉਸਦੇ ੲਿਸ ਬਿਹਤਰੀਨ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਦੇ ਹੋੲੇ, ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਖਿਲ਼ਾਫ ਅੰਡਰ 19 ਟੀਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਚੁਣ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।=== ਅੰਤਰ-ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ===ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੇ ਅੰਤਰ-ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ੲਿੱਕ ਦਿਨਾ ਮੈਚ ਸ੍ਰੀਲੰਕਾ ਖਿਲ਼ਾਫ ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ 1990 ਨੂੰ ਖੇਡਿਆ। ੲਿਸ ਸਾਲ ਹੀ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਟੈਸਟ ਮੈਚ ੲਿੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਖਿਲ਼ਾਫ ਖੇਡਿਆ। ਅਨਿਲ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ 132 ਟੈਸਟ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ 236 ਪਾਰੀਆ ਵਿੱਚ 619 ਵਿਕਟ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਟੀਮ ਦੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ ਬਣੇ ਹੋੲੇ ਹਨ। 271 ੲਿੱਕ-ਦਿਨਾ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ 265 ਪਾਰੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ 337 ਵਿਕਟ ਲੈਣ ਦੀ ਗੌਰਵ ਵੀ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਦੇ ਨਾਂਮ ਹੈ। ਕੁੰਬਲੇ  ਨਵੰਬਰ 2007 ਤੋਂ 1 ਸਾਲ ਤੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਟੀਮ ਦੇ ਟੈਸਟ ਕਪਤਾਨ ਵੀ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।== ਰੌਚਕ ਤੱਥ ==ਭਾਰਤੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਟੀਮ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਟੈਸਟ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਵਿਕਟਾਂ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼। ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੇ 1990 ਤੋਂ 2008 ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਟੈਸਟ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੇਡੇ 132 ਟੈਸਟ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ 40850 ਗੇਂਦਾ ਸੁੱਟ ਕੇ 18355 ਰਨ ਦੇ ਕੇ 29.65 ਦੀ ਔਸਤ ਨਾਲ 619 ਵਿਕਟ ਲੲੇ।ਭਾਰਤ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਟੈਸਟ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ 500 ਅਤੇ 600 ਵਿਕਟਾਂ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲੇ ੲਿਕਲੌਤੇ ਅਤੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼।ਟੈਸਟ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ੲਿਤਿਹਾਸ ਦੀ ੲਿੱਕ ਟੈਸਟ ਪਾਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ 10 ਵਿਕਟਾਂ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲਾ ੲਿੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਦੇ ਜਿਮ ਲੇਕਰ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਦੂਸਰਾ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼। ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ 4 ਫ਼ਰਵਰੀ 1999 ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋੲੇ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਟੈਸਟ ਮੈਚ ਦੀ ਚੌਥੀ ਪਾਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ 26.3 ਓਵਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ 9 ਮੇਡਨ(ਬਿਨਾਂ ਕੋੲੀ ਰਨ ਦਿੱਤੇ) ਓਵਰ ਸੁੱਟ ਕੇ 74 ਰਨ ਦਿੰਦੇ ਹੋੲੇ, 10 ਵਿਕਟਾਂ ਲੈਣ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨਾਮਾ ਕੀਤਾ। ਓਨ੍ਹਾ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ੲਿੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਦੇ ਜਿਮ ਲੇਕਰ ਨੇ ਆਸਟ੍ਰੇਲੀਆ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ 26 ਜੁਲਾੲੀ 1956 ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋੲੇ ਟੈਸਟ ਮੈਚ ਦੀ ਤੀਜੀ ਪਾਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ 51.1 ਓਵਰ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ 23 ਮੇਡਨ ਓਵਰ ਸੁੱਟ ਕੇ 53 ਰਨ ਦੇ ਕੇ 10 ਵਿਕਟ ਲੲੇ ਸਨ, ਤੇ ਓਹ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ ਬਣੇ ਸਨ।ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਉਸਦੇ ਲੰਬੇ ਕੱਦ ਕਰਕੇ 'ਜੰਬੋ' ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ।ੲਿੰਡੀਅਨ ਪ੍ਰੀਮੀਅਰ ਲੀਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁੰਬਲੇ ਬੰਗਲੋਰ ਦੀ ਟੀਮ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਖੇਡਦੇ ਸਨ।== ਹੋਰ ਦੇਖੋ ==== ਹਵਾਲੇ =="},{"question":"imbwa hadzi inonzi chii?","answer":"imbwa hadzi"},{"question":"கேள்வி: \\"முயற்சி திருவினை ஆக்கும் முயற்றின்மை                  இன்மை புகுத்தி விடும்.\\"                                                                -இக்குறட்பாவில் அமைந்துள்ள  பொருள்கோளை விளக்குக. ","answer":"பதில்:பொருள்கோள் - அறிமுகம்: ஒரு செய்யுளிலுள்ள சீர்களையோ அடிகளையோ பொருள் உணர்ச்சிக்கு ஏற்றவகையில் அமைத்துக்கொள்ளும் முறை பொருள்கோள் என அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. செய்யுளில் சொற்களைப் பொருளுக்கு ஏற்றவாறு சேர்த்தோ மாற்றியோ பொருள் கொள்ளும் முறைக்குப் 'பொருள்கோள்' என்பர்.                                                                                                                                        பொருள்கோள் வகைகள்: பொருள்கோள் எட்டு வகைப்படும். அவையே, 1.ஆற்றுநீர்ப் பொருள்கோள், 2.மொழிமாற்றுப் பொருள்கோள், 3.நிரல்நிறைப் பொருள்கோள், 4.அற்பூட்டுப் பொருள்கோள், 5.தாப்பிசைப் பொருள்கோள்,6.அளையறியாப்புப் பொருள்கோள்,7.கொண்டுகூட்டுப் பொருள்கோள், 8.அடிமறிமாற்றுப் பொருள்கோள்.                                                                                                                                       ஆற்றுநீர்ப் பொருள்கோள் இலக்கணம்:பாடலின் தொடக்கம் முதல் முடிவு வரை ஆற்றுநீரின் போக்கைப் போல நேராகவே பொருள் கொள்ளுமாறு அமைதல் ஆற்றுநீர்ப் பொருள்கோள்.குறளின் பொருள்கோள் விளக்கம் :இப்பாடலில் முயற்சி செல்வத்தைத் தரும்; முயற்சி செய்யாமை வறுமையைத் தரும் என்று பாடலின் தொடக்கம் முதல் முடிவு வரை நேராகப் பொருள் கொள்ளும் முறையில் அமைந்திருப்பதால் இது ஆற்று நீர்ப்பொருள்கோள் ஆயிற்று."},{"question":"மக்கள் வாழும் நிலப்பகுதியைக் குறிக்கும் சொல் ………அ) வைப்புஆ) கடல்இ) பரவைஈ) ஆழி","answer":"அ) வைப்பு"},{"question":"O que é \\"goma-laca?\\"","answer":"\\"Goma-laca\\" é uma resina expelida pelo inseto \\"Kerria lacca,\\" que é encontrado nas florestas da Índia e da Tailândia. O material bruto é refinado em diversos graus, com diferentes propósitos. A \\"goma-laca,\\" tipicamente, seca rapidamente, formando uma película dura, forte e flexível, sendo útil para envernizar pisos e móveis. As duas melhores variedades, disponíveis no mercado, são a \\"goma-laca laranja,\\" que nos chega em forma de flocos finos na cor laranja-marrom e translúcidos e a \\"goma-laca\\" branca, ou alvejada. Tanto a \\"goma-laca\\" branca, quanto a laranja são solúveis no álcool."},{"question":"Berilah contoh ayat untuk peribahasa \\"bagai bulan dengan matahari\\".","answer":"Pasangan pengantin yang bersanding itu sama cantik sama padan seperti bulan dengan matahari."},{"question":"Про який літературний твір йдеться у тексті? Тарас Григорович Шевченко  — український поет, прозаїк, мислитель, живописець, гравер, етнограф, громадський діяч. Національний герой і символ України. Діяч українського національного руху, член Кирило-Мефодіївського братства. Академік Імператорської академії мистецтв (1860). Літературна спадщина Шевченка, центральну роль у якій відіграє поезія, зокрема збірка «Кобзар», вважається основою сучасної української літератури та багато в чому літературної української мови.","answer":"збірка «Кобзар»"},{"question":"shin batun me ake magana a wannan mai zuwa? \\"sai An hada kai za a Iya tabbatar da kawar da Polio\\":(a) Lafiya(b) Afirka(c) Najeriya(d) Siyasa(e) Duniya","answer":"Amsa : \\"sai An hada kai za a Iya tabbatar da kawar da Polio\\" na batu ne a kan (a) Lafiya."},{"question":"කුමන ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානය කුරුළු පාරාදීසයක් ලෙස සැලකෙන්නේ කුමක් නිසා ද? එහි දක්නට ලැබෙන පක්ෂි විශේෂ මොනවා ද?","answer":"කුමන ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානය කුරුළු පාරාදීසයක් ලෙස සැලකෙන්නේ එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පක්ෂි විශේෂවලින් 50%කට නිවහන වන බැවින් සහ සංක්‍රමණික මෙන් ම ජලජ පක්ෂීන්ගෙන් 35%කට සත්කාරකත්වය සපයන බැවිනි. විවිධ පක්ෂි විශේෂ සඳහා ආහාර, නවාතැන් සහ අභිජනන ස්ථාන සපයන කලපු, මෝය, කඩොලාන සහ ලුණු වගුරු බිම් ඇතුළු විවිධ ස්ථාන මෙහි ඇත. කුමන ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානයේ දක්නට ලැබෙන පක්ෂීන් අතරට යුරේසියානු spoonbill (Eurasian spoonbill), කළු බෙල්ලේ කොකා, Great thick-knee, ආසියානු open bill, ග්ලෝසි අයිබිස් (Glossy ibis) සහ තවත් බොහෝ වර්ග ඇතුළත් වේ."},{"question":"Awọn ọlọpaa Eko n wa Adeyẹmi o, wọn lo gun ọkọ ale ẹ lọbẹ pa","answer":"Awọn ọlọpaa Eko ni awọn n wa Adekunle Adeyẹmi bayii bayii o, ẹsun ti wọn si n tori ẹ wa a ni pe wọn lo gun ọkọ ale rẹ ti wọn n pe ni Chisom pa. Agbegbe Grammar School ni Ikorodu ni iṣẹlẹ naa ti ṣẹlẹ nipari oṣu keje, lati igba naa lawọn ọlọpaa yii si ti n wa afurasi naa ti wọn ko ri i.Ile kan naa ni Arinze Onuoha pẹlu iyawo rẹ ati Adeyẹmi jọ n gbe ni Red Block Street, nibẹ naa si ni  ẹnu ti bẹrẹ si i kun Adeyẹmi pe o n mu nnkan jẹ lara Chisom, iyawo Arinze. Ọrọ yii lo di ariyanjiyan rẹpẹtẹ, ni Adeyẹmi ba fa ọbẹ alaṣoro yọ, o si gun Arinze lapa osi ni igbaaya rẹ, nigba ti wọn yoo si fi gbe tọhun de ọsibitu, o ti ku pata.N lawọn ọlọpaa ba gbọ ọrọ yii ni wọn sare wa sile naa, ṣugbọn ki wọn too de, gbogbo awọn araale ti sa lọ, ko si sẹni to tilẹ gburoo Adeyẹmi to da kinni naa silẹ rara. Iyẹn lawọn ọlọpaa ṣe ni awọn n wa Adeyẹmi, awọn si ti bẹrẹ ifimufinlẹ lori bi awọn yoo ṣe ri i."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Theo Sohu, Trương Trí Lâm nhập viện cấp cứu khi đang làm việc trên phim trường. Nam diễn viên đột nhiên thấy không khỏe, cơn đau quặn thắt khiến anh ngã quỵ xuống. Ê-kíp của Trí Lâm cùng các nhân viên hiện trường đã nhanh chóng gọi xe cấp cứu đưa anh nhập viện. Trả lời truyền thông, quản lý của tài tử cho biết anh được bác sĩ chẩn đoán viêm túi mật. \\"Cảm ơn mọi người quan tâm. Anh ấy đã ổn hơn sau 1 ngày nằm viện. Vì muốn đảm bảo Trí Lâm được nghỉ ngơi nên mọi lịch trình công việc chúng tôi phải ngưng lại\\", người đại diện chia sẻ. Diễn viên Viên Vịnh Nghi - bà xã Trương Trí Lâm hiện kề cận chăm sóc chồng. Trương Trí Lâm hiện là sao nam trung niên đắt show bậc nhất hiện nay tại thị trường Hong Kong và Đại lục. Từ năm ngoái, anh được khán giả đặc biệt yêu thích nhờ góp mặt các show truyền hình thực tế như Anh trai vượt mọi chông gai, Night in the Greater Bay... Tài tử nổi tiếng với tính cách hài hước, thái độ chuyên nghiệp trong công việc. Trương Trí Lâm được săn đón ở tuổi trung niên. Lịch trình bận rộn khiến nam diễn viên gần như không có nhiều thời gian nghỉ ngơi. Trong một bài phỏng vấn, Trí Lâm tiết lộ giai đoạn đỉnh điểm anh chỉ ngủ 2-3 tiếng mỗi ngày, gần như không trò chuyện, vui chơi với vợ con. Trương Trí Lâm bên vợ - Hoa hậu Hong Kong/ diễn viên Viên Vịnh Nghi. Viên Vịnh Nghi - Trương Trí Lâm kết hôn năm 2001 và có với nhau một cậu con trai năm nay 15 tuổi. Đôi vợ chồng hiện là một trong những nghệ sĩ gốc Hong Kong được chào đón như sao hạng A tại thị trường Trung Quốc. Theo On, nhờ tài năng và hình ảnh gia đình kiểu mẫu, họ được các đài truyền hình, đơn vị sản xuất và nhãn hàng săn đón. Nhờ thế, cặp đôi có cuộc sống giàu có, sở hữu loạt bất động sản cùng sở thích sưu tầm siêu xe, túi hiệu... Trương Trí Lâm sinh năm 1971, anh gia nhập làng giải trí năm 20 tuổi. Tài tử sớm nổi tiếng qua vai Quách Tĩnh trong Anh hùng xạ điêu 1994 cùng các phim Đường về hạnh phúc, Bao la vùng trời, Đội chống tham nhũng... Trí Lâm là một trong những nam diễn viên giữ phong độ nghề tốt với tên tuổi, danh tiếng hàng đầu hiện nay. Thúy Ngọc","answer":"Diễn viên Trương Trí Lâm nhập viện cấp cứu"},{"question":"Курманжан Датка» (англ. Kurmanjan Datka) — «Алай ханышасы» аталган Курманжан Датка тууралуу көркөм, тарыхый, биографиялык драма режиссеру — Садык Шер-Нияз. Кыргызстандын тарыхындагы эң алгачкы тарыхый тасманы аткарган каармандар (актёр) кимдер?","answer":"Курманжан 3 — 4 жаштагы кезин — Лунара АяскановаКурманжан Датка 16 жана 40 жаштагы кезин — Элина Абай кызы[11]Курманжан Датка 50 — 60 жаштагы кезин — Назира Мамбетова[12]Курманжан Датка 90 жаштагы кезин — Жамал СейдакматоваАлымбек Датка — Азиз Мурадилаев[13]Акбалбан — Мирлан Абдулаев[14]Камчыбек — Адилет Усубалиев[15]Абдылдабек — Адыл Болорбек уулу[16]Эмир Музаффар — Ашыр Чокубаев[17]Кудаяр Хан — Жениш СмановЖантай Хан — Акылбек АбдыкалыковШабдан баатыр — Улан Өмүралиев[18]Элтойду — Нурбек Саматов[19]Генерал Скобелев — Александр Голубков[20]Генерал Швыйковский — Василий Ползунов[21]Чотон — Рыспек Жумабаев[22]Император — Дмитрий МатлинГенерал Ионов — Дмитрий МитрофановГенерал Кауфман — Виктор КостецкийГенерал Милютин — Леонид МозговойГраф Гейден — Александр Машанов[23]Генерал — Роман ЛазаревМаннергейм — Дмитрий Романченко[24]Кулсейит — Өмүрбек Насыпбек уулуМаматбай — Руслан КурманалиевСоно — Динара Абдыкадырова[25]Миңбашы — Султанбек Дикамбаев[26]Акбалбан 9 жаштагы — Айбек КокеевКамчыбек 6 жаштагы кезин — Нурдавлет БакировАбдылдабек 9 жаштагы кезин — Нурмухаммед БакировКулсеиттин досу — Камчы СарыбаевЭлтойду (карыган кезин) — Абдыкалык АкматовЖантай хандын аялы — Шайгуль АлсеитоваАсел (Камчыбектин аялы) — Гульнур АсановаАйтбүбү (Абдылдабектин аялы) — Чолпон ИдрисоваНиязаалы — Руслан ЖумабаевАлдаяр — Акылбек МураталиевКулсеиттин апасы — Айнура ТургунбаеваУлуу агасы — Нурислам БекболотовБазардагы карыя — Дилдорбек ажы Рахмонов."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Índia?","answer":"A capital da Índia é Nova Deli."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து வெங்காய பக்கோடா செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:½ கப் கடலை மாவு¼ கப் அரிசி மாவு3 பெரிய வெங்காயம்2 பச்சை மிளகாய்1தே க்கரண்டி சோம்பு1 சிட்டிகை பெருங்காய தூள்தேவையான அளவு மிளகாய் தூள்தேவையான அளவு உப்புதேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்சிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லிசிறிதளவு கறிவேப்பிலை","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் வெங்காயம், பச்சை மிளகாய், கறிவேப்பிலை, மற்றும் கொத்தமல்லியை நறுக்கி வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்த ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் நாம் நீளவாக்கில் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் வெங்காயத்தை போட்டு அதை கைகளின் மூலம் நன்கு பிரித்து விடவும்.3. பின்பு அதில் நம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் பச்சை மிளகாய், சோம்பு, பெருங்காய தூள், தேவையான அளவு உப்பு, ஒரு தேக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய், மற்றும் அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப மிளகாய் தூளை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.4. பிறகு அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் கொத்தமல்லி மற்றும் கருவேப்பிலையை போட்டு அதை நன்கு கிளறி விடவும்.5. பின்னர் அதில் கடலை மாவு மற்றும் அரிசி மாவை கொட்டி அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும். (இதில் நாம் தண்ணீர் எதுவும் சேர்த்து விட கூடாது.)6. இப்பொழுது ஒரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் பக்கோடாவை போட்டு பொரித்து எடுப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.7. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் நாம் கலந்து வைத்திருக்கும் கலவையில் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீரை தெளித்து அதை கடாயின் அளவிற்கேற்ப எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யில் உதிர்த்து விடவும். (மாவில் தண்ணீரை தெளித்து தான் விடவேண்டும் ஊற்றினால் அது பஜ்ஜி மாவு போல் ஆகி விடும்.)8. பக்கோடா கட்டியாக இருப்பதை விரும்புவார்கள் அதை சிறு சிறு கட்டிகளாக எண்ணெய்யில் போடவும்.9. பின்பு அது ஒரு புறம் வெந்ததும் அதை ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் மறு புறம் திருப்பி விட்டு அது நன்கு பொன்னிறமானதும் அதை கரண்டியில் எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யை நன்கு வடித்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.10. இவ்வாறே மீதமுள்ள மாவையும் எண்ணெய்யில் போட்டு பொரித்து எடுத்து அதை சுட சுட பரிமாறவும். (தேவைப்பட்டால் மாவை எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யில் போடுவதற்கு முன் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீரை தெளித்து கொள்ளவும்.)11. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் நன்கு மொறு மொறுப்பாக இருக்கும் வெங்காய பக்கோடா தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"Can you paraphrase the following text for me: 83-vuotias ehti odottaa teloitustaan kuolemansellissä liki 20 vuotta.","answer":"83-vuotias odotti teloitustaan vankilassa lähes 20 vuotta."},{"question":"\\"ප්‍රපංචය\\" වචනයේ තේරුම පහදන්න","answer":"\\"ප්‍රපංචය\\" වචනයේ තේරුම  ප්‍රමාදය ට හේතුවන කියන එකයි."},{"question":"جملي 1: رمن جي قدرتي نسليت کان علاوه ، مصنوعي نسليت ۽ جنين جي منتقلي ڪيترن سالن کان آسٽريليا ۽ نيوزي لينڊ ۾ رڍن جي نسلن جي پروگرامن ۾ استعمال ڪئي وئي آهي. جملو 2: رمن جي قدرتي نسيمت کان علاوه ، آسٽريليا ۽ نيوزيلينڊ ڪيترن سالن کان  رڍن جي نسلن جي پروگرامن ۾ مصنوعي نسيمت ۽ ايمبريو منتقلي استعمال ڪري رهيا آهن. سوال: ڇا جملي 1 ۽ جملي 2 هڪ ئي معنيٰ جو اظهار ڪن ٿا؟ ها يا نه؟","answer":"ھائو"},{"question":"Эң көп спутниги бар планета кайсы?","answer":"Юпитерде бардык изилденген планеталардын эң көп спутниги бар - 67."},{"question":"MAGTA LAGA BIXINAYO HADDII HAWEENEY LA DILO !XADIISYADA AAN SAXDA AHAYN (BUGTA AH) EE LOO XUJAYSTO IN DIYADA DUMARKA LAGA BIXINAYAA AY NUS KA TAHAY TAN RAGGA LAGA BIXINAYO?","answer":"MAGTA LAGA BIXINAYO HADDII HAWEENEY LA DILO !XADIISYADA AAN SAXDA AHAYN (BUGTA AH) EE LOO XUJAYSTO IN DIYADA DUMARKA LAGA BIXINAYAA AY NUS KA TAHAY TAN RAGGA LAGA BIXINAYO?Waxaa lama huraan ah in uu ruux walbaa maanka ku hayo in guud ahaanba Xadiisyada arintaan quseeya ee la soo weriyey lana ogaaday ilaa hadda, ay yihiin kuwa isla markiiba la xaqiijiyey in ay been abuur yihiin, ama ugu yaraan laga shakiyey saxnimadooda. Kuwaasi waxa ay gaarayaan tiro ahaan saddex. Waxaana qof kaste oo xukunka Islaamka u dhabba galay gran karaa in ay marka horeba shaki abuuri karto in saddex xadiis oo keli ah si aan toos ahayn u dejiyaan xukun sidaas u weyn ee ku taxalluqa naf aadane. Waayo waxaa la ogyahay in diintu ay leedahay ahmiyado sida jaran jarada u taxan, ayna mar walba muhimadda koowaad siiso nafta qofka. Sidaa darteed xukunkii ku saabsan naf go’day, waxa uu mar walba noqdaa mid banaan cad yaalla oo aan laba ku doodi karinin ama aysan daliishiisu baadi goob u baahnayn. Aan hadalka soo gaabinee, waxa ay saddexdaas xadiis kala yihiin sida soo socota;1- xadiiska laga soo weriyey Mucaad bin Jabal ee ah; “Diyatul mar’ati cala nisfi diya rajul” 2- Xadiiska laga soo weriyey Camra bin Xazam ee ay ku jirto; “ diyatul mar’at nisfu diyat rajul” 3- Xadiiska laga soo weriyey Camra bin Shuceyb, ee ah “caql al mar’ati..”  XADIISKA MUCAAD BIN JABAL. Beyhaqi ayaa kitaabkiisa (Sunan al Kubra”, Kitaab al-diyaat, Baabu Maa jaa’a fi diyat almar’at)  ku soo weriyey: “Waxa uu inoo sheegay Xafsa bin Cabdillahi, oo ka sheegay Ibraahim bin Dhahmaan, oo ka sheegay Bakar bin Khunays, oo ka sheegay Cubaadata bin Nusaya, oo ka sheegay Ibnu Gunma, oo ka sheegay Mucaad bin Jabal in uu yiri; Nebiga (NNKHA) ayaa yiri: “Magdhawga dumarku waxa uu badh ka yahay magdhawga ragga”. Xadiiskani waa daciif, taag daran, sababaha soo socda awgood: Guud ahaanba ragga Xadiiska soo wariyey, marka Mucaad bin Jabal laga reebo, waa rag aan sidaa loogu kalsoonayn warkooda. Waxaa ka mid ah rag ku caan ah allifidda xadiisyada beenta ah, oo inta ay hadallo isku toos toosiyaan ku naba rag asxaabihii ka mid ah oo beri hore dhintay si ay ugu fulsadaan dano iyaga u gaar ah. Haddaan iminka hal hal ugu qabano tooshka, bal aan ku horayno ninka la yiraahdo; Bakra bin Khunays.     A- Bakra bin Khunays, waxa uu ahaa nin reer Kuufi ah kana sii ahaa reer Baqdaad. Waxa uuna ahaa nin ay culimadii waa weyneyd ee xilligiisii noolaa isku raaceen in uu beenta kalax kalax ugu miisi jiray, oo aan warkiisa la qaadan karin. Waxaana ka mid ah hadaladii ay culimadu ka dheheen xaalkiisa: Mar wax laga weydiiyey Sheekha la odhan jidhay “Ibnu Mucayn” xaalka bin Khunays waxa uu ku jawaabay “Bakra bin Khunays waxba ma ahan ee warkiisa nagala hera - naga daaya\\"39. Maalin kale ayaa hadana is la su’aashaas la weydiiyey. Markaa ayuu ku jawaabay hadana “ ninkaasi waa waxbayahay. Xadiiskiisuna waa daciif ama been abuur”40. Waxaa kale oo arinta bin Khunays la weydiiyey Beyhaqi. Markaa ayuu ku jawaabay; “ Ninkaa hadallo badan baa laga sheegayey, warkiisana waa laga shakisnaa”41 Ibnu xabbaan isna waxa uu ka yiri; “ Nimankaa reer Kuufi iyo reer Basri xadiisyo badan oo been abuur ah, oo aad qaarkood dareemi karto in loogu tala galay been abuurkooda ayaa laga soo weriyey”42. Daara qudhni oo isna arinta Khunays ka hadlaya ayaa yiri; “War waa beenlow warkiisana lama qaato”. Markaas ayuu  Ibnu Cadiya ugu sii daray; “laakiin Xadiisyada uu sheego waa la iska qoraa iyada oo lagu darayo liiska kuwa la been abuuray – bugta ah”43 Ibnu Abii Xaatim oo ka mid ahaa jiilkii ka dambeeyey ayaa isna yiri; “ Waxa aan maqlay Aabahay  oo inta la weydiiyey – runlownimada ama beenlownimada Bakra bin Khunays ku jawaabay: Ninkaasi wax la sheego ma ahan xadiiskiisuna tabar lagu rumaysto malahan”44. AlXaafid isagu waxa uu yiri; “ War ninku sidaa beenlow uma ahan ee wuu qaladaad badanyahay oo hadalada ayaa isaga dhex darsama”45. Intaa haddaan uga harno arinka Bin Khunays, bal aan hadana eegno arinka saaxiibkiisa kale ee ka soo weriyey laftigiisa. Kaasi waa Ibraahim bin Dhahmaan. "},{"question":"imisa bilood ayey kadanbeysay faadumo nebiga(s.c.w)?","answer":"waa 6bilood"},{"question":"Dwala libushelelezi ngokushelela amadoda asekhaya. Ngwazi!(Akhuleke qede angene bese ephinda ekhuleka.) Hlobolophatha!(Akhothame.)(Emamatheka ngothotho lwamazinyo akhe amhlophe.)Sekwenzenjani mfo kaMgingqika, wangena usugingqika nje?Wena kaMshwilansimbi. Akukonakali lutho. Ngiphangisa njengizobika eNkosini ukuthi naba abafowabo beNkosi esangweni.OwakwaNtuthu, owasoDibini, owaseKupholeni, owaseKuphumuleninowaseNhlambamasoka.Ubamiseleni esangweni? Anginitshelanga yini ukuthi abafowethuabangalindiswa esangweni. Akothi uma befika bangeniswe?Batshele bangene!Yibona abangithume ukuba ngibabike kuqala. Ngwazi! (Akhothameaphume.)(Baphakamisa izandla ngambili kanyekanye.)Ngwazi! Hlobolophatha! Mathangakahlangani!Ahlangana ngoba esebona umyeni.(Kuhlehla izihlathi.) Ngenani nina bakaMashilansimbi ingemlenze.Ngenani bafowethu1. Beka ngokufingqiwe izenzo zikaMphiliphili ezibonisa ukuthi ungumlingiswaongathembekile enkosini uSalimani.","answer":"UMphiliphili uhlangana noZithulele yize eyinduna yenkosi elokhu emthengangemali nangezinkomo. Akalikhulumi iqiniso uma ebuzwa inkosi uSalimaniukuthi bebexoxa ngani noZithulele. Akakhethanga ubhontshisi omnyamakepha wakhetha omhlophe ohambisana noHulumeni."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai kucing kehilangan anak\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud seseorang yang berada dalam keadaaan binggung. Rohayu bagai kucing kehilangan anak apabila mendapat tahu tentang kemalangan yang menimpa ibunya."},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند؟:  او در دارالسلام، تانزانیا و نایروبی، کنیا تحت تعقیب بود. وی به عنوان باتجربه‌ترین برنامه‌ریز عملیاتی القاعده توصیف شده و به عنوان فرمانده دوم سازمان شناخته می‌شد.عبدالله احمد عبدالله (؛ ۶ ژوئن ۱۹۶۳۷ اوت ۲۰۲۰)، معروف به ابو محمد المصری، یک عضو بلندپایه القاعده مصر بود. او توسط ایالات متحده به اتهام نقش داشتن در بمب‌گذاری ۱۹۹۸ سفارت ایالات متحده ...","answer":"بمب‌گذاری ۱۹۹۸ سفارت ایالات متحده"},{"question":"Sheeg Imisa Ayey Ahaayeen Tirida Ciidamadda Muslimiinta Dagaalkii Beder?","answer":"Tirada Muslimiinta Dagaalkii Beder Waxay Ahaayeen 313 Nin, 70 Rati (GEEL) Iyo LabaFaras"},{"question":"የዊንዶውስ ሶፍትዌር አምራች ድርጅት ማነው?","answer":"ማይክሮሶፍት"},{"question":"Kết quả của phép tính (– 15) : 5 là:A. 3B. 5 C. – 3D. – 5 ","answer":"Lời giảiTa có: (– 15) : 5 = – (15 : 5) = – 3.Chọn đáp án C. "},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Nhiều khó khăn, vướng mắc trong thu hồi tài sản tham nhũng Trao đổi với Báo Điện tử Chính phủ, ông Nguyễn Văn Dụng, Vụ Nghiệp vụ 2 (Tổng cục Thi hành án dân sự) đánh giá, pháp luật Việt Nam đã có những quy định tương đối đầy đủ về các biện pháp, trình tự, thủ tục thu hồi tài sản có liên quan đến hành vi tham nhũng, kinh tế thông qua 2 cơ chế chủ yếu là thu hồi tài sản theo quyết định hành chính của người có thẩm quyền trong hoạt động thanh tra khi có đủ căn cứ kết luận tiền bị chiếm đoạt, sử dụng trái phép hoặc bị thất thoát do hành vi vi phạm pháp luật gây ra theo quy định của pháp luật thanh tra; thu hồi tài sản liên quan đến tội phạm tham nhũng, kinh tế theo bản án, quyết định có hiệu lực của Tòa án. Đây là cơ chế thu hồi tài sản tham nhũng chủ yếu ở Việt Nam hiện nay, được thực hiện thông qua cơ quan Thi hành án dân sự, phù hợp với quy định của pháp luật tố tụng hình sự về trách nhiệm chứng minh tội phạm và yêu cầu về đảm bảo quyền con người mà Hiến pháp năm 2013 quy định \\"người bị buộc tội được coi là không có tội cho đến khi được chứng minh theo trình tự luật định và có bản án kết tội của Toà án đã có hiệu lực pháp luật\\". Theo ông Nguyễn Văn Dụng, để đánh giá một cách tổng thể và toàn diện thì hệ thống pháp luật hiện hành của Việt Nam liên quan đến vấn đề thu hồi tài sản tham nhũng, kinh tế chưa xử lý được những trường hợp sau: Một là, trường hợp có căn cứ khẳng định tiền, tài sản liên quan đến hành vi tham nhũng nhưng chưa thể truy cứu trách nhiệm hình sự người phạm tội được do nhiều lý do khác nhau như đối tượng phạm tội đã chết, mất tích hoặc bỏ trốn... thì theo quy định của Bộ luật Tố tụng hình sự sẽ áp dụng biện pháp đình chỉ điều tra, tạm đình chỉ điều tra, truy nã... Như vậy, sẽ chưa thể hoặc không thể thu hồi ngay được số tiền, tài sản này. Hai là, liên quan đến vấn đề xác định nguồn gốc tài sản để thực hiện việc tịch thu, thu hồi tiền, tài sản cho Nhà nước, hệ thống pháp luật hiện hành quy định nghĩa vụ chứng minh nguồn gốc tiền, tài sản thuộc về cơ quan có thẩm quyền (cơ quan tiến hành tố tụng, cơ quan thanh tra). Quy định này của hệ thống pháp luật dẫn đến thực tế là hầu hết các vụ án hình sự về tham nhũng, kinh tế người phạm tội luôn tìm thủ đoạn chuyển các tài sản liên quan đến tội phạm thành tài sản khó hoặc không thể xác định được nguồn gốc do phạm tội mà có nên việc thu hồi tiền, tài sản rất khó thực hiện được. Ba là, trong trường hợp qua hoạt động kiểm soát tài sản, thu nhập mà phát hiện tài sản, thu nhập đó có dấu hiệu từ hành vi tham nhũng, Luật phòng, chống tham nhũng quy định cơ quan có thẩm quyền sẽ chuyển vụ việc cho cơ quan chức năng hoặc yêu cầu cơ quan chức năng, cá nhân có thẩm quyền áp dụng biện pháp cần thiết theo quy định của pháp luật nhằm ngăn chặn việc tẩu tán, huỷ hoại, chuyển dịch tài sản. Như vậy, Luật Phòng chống tham nhũng chưa quy định các biện pháp ngăn chặn khi phát hiện tài sản có dấu hiệu tham nhũng qua việc kiểm soát tiền, tài sản của người có chức vụ, quyền hạn trong cơ quan, tổ chức. Như vậy, cơ quan kiểm soát tài sản, thu nhập của cán bộ, công chức không có thẩm quyền áp dụng biện pháp ngăn chặn cần thiết để ngăn ngừa việc tẩu tán, chuyển dịch hoặc huỷ hoại tài sản. Tài sản tham nhũng do người có chức vụ chiếm đoạt bị \\"che chắn\\", \\"bảo vệ\\" Cũng đề cập đến vấn đề này, Luật sư Mạnh Xuân Sơn (Đoàn Luật sư Hà Nội) cho rằng, nền kinh tế và thói quen sử dụng tiền mặt dẫn đến việc khó kiểm soát tài sản, thu nhập cũng như các giao dịch tiền mặt, tạo điều kiện cho các tổ chức, cá nhân dễ dàng che giấu nguồn gốc bất minh của tài sản và gây khó khăn cho các cơ quan có thẩm quyền trong việc lần theo dòng tiền, chứng minh mối liên hệ giữa tài sản và hành vi vi phạm. Luật sư Mạnh Xuân Sơn phân tích, thực tiễn các tội phạm tham nhũng, kinh tế thường do người có chức vụ, quyền hạn, có trình độ học vấn và chuyên môn nhất định, am hiểu pháp luật, quản lý kinh tế, có khả năng nhận biết những kẽ hở pháp luật, thậm chí có thể can thiệp để cố tình tạo nên những kẽ hở đó; có điều kiện tạo dựng được nhiều mối quan hệ có khả năng \\"che chắn\\", \\"bảo vệ\\" cho hành vi sai phạm; có sự chuẩn bị chu đáo khi phạm tội, khi thực hiện xong chủ động xoá hết mọi dấu vết, tiêu huỷ giấy tờ, hoá đơn, sổ sách, tẩu tán tài sản do phạm tội mà có. Quá trình thực hiện tội phạm thường là quy trình khép kín, diễn ra lâu năm, có liên quan đến nhiều người và có sự liên kết, thống nhất về mặt lợi ích, có tổ chức chặt chẽ, dẫn đến việc tìm chứng cứ, chứng minh tội phạm và xác minh","answer":"các tài sản liên quan đến tội phạm gặp nhiều khó khăn. Tài sản xử lý để thu hồi trong các vụ án tham nhũng kinh tế là những tài sản phức tạp như tài sản đã bị tẩu tán ra nước ngoài, tài sản là các dự án bất động sản chưa hoàn thành về pháp lý, tài sản là cổ phần, cổ phiếu... gây khó khăn rất nhiều cho hoạt động thu hồi tài sản. Theo Luật sư Mạnh Xuân Sơn, thu hồi tài sản tham nhũng trong giai đoạn thi hành án dân sự phụ thuộc rất nhiều vào điều kiện thi hành án của người phải thi hành án, đặc biệt là việc áp dụng các biện pháp truy tìm, chứng minh nguồn gốc tài sản; áp dụng các biện pháp kê biên, phong toả để ngăn chặn việc tẩu tán tài sản trong các vụ án tham nhũng. Trong quá trình xử lý vụ án hình sự, cần kịp thời áp dụng các biện pháp ngăn chặn việc tẩu tán tài sản, toà án chưa quan tâm đúng mức đến phần trách nhiệm dân sự và xử lý vật chứng. Cần quy định cho phép theo dõi biến động mọi tài sản, thu nhập của người có chức vụ Đề xuất về giải pháp hoàn thiện pháp luật, ông Nguyễn Văn Dụng cho rằng, cần hoàn thiện cơ chế và tổ chức thực hiện nghiêm quy định về kiểm soát thu nhập của người có chức vụ, quyền hạn. Để phát hiện, ngăn chặn những hành vi trái quy định liên quan đến thu nhập của người có chức vụ, quyền hạn, cần thiết phải có các quy định cho phép theo dõi biến động của mọi tài sản, thu nhập của người có chức vụ, quyền hạn ở mọi thời điểm (kể cả việc tăng, giảm tài sản, thu nhập). Kiểm soát thu nhập của người có chức vụ, quyền hạn nhằm tạo cơ sở quan trọng cho việc minh bạch hóa thu nhập và tài sản của người có chức vụ, quyền hạn và là một giải pháp hết sức quan trọng nhằm phòng ngừa và phát hiện tham nhũng cũng như gó phần nâng cao hiệu quả thu hồi tài sản cho Nhà nước. Nghiên cứu, hình sự hóa hành vi làm giàu bất hợp pháp để tăng hiệu quả chế tài xử lý tham nhũng. Kinh nghiệm lập pháp một số nước cho thấy, họ đã hình sự hóa hành vi làm giàu bất hợp pháp như một giải pháp để đấu tranh hiệu quả đối với tội phạm tham nhũng. Thực chất, hình sự hóa hành vi này là đảo ngược trách nhiệm chứng minh; nghĩa là trách nhiệm chứng minh tài sản có bất minh hay không được chuyển từ các cơ quan tố tụng sang người nắm giữ tài sản. Nếu cán bộ, công chức có chức vụ quyền hạn không chứng minh được tài sản của mình là hợp pháp thì tài sản đó là tài sản tham nhũng. Xây dựng cơ chế tịch thu, thu hồi tài sản thông qua việc khởi kiện dân sự được nhiều nước sử dụng. Hiện nay, các quốc gia sử dụng bốn phương thức cơ bản để thu hồi tài sản tham nhũng là thu hồi tài sản dựa trên truy tố hình sự; thu hồi tài sản không dựa trên bản án hình sự; thu hồi tài sản thông qua quyết định hành chính; khởi kiện dân sự để thu hồi tài sản. Trong đó, phương thức thu hồi tài sản dựa trên quy trình khởi kiện dân sự được Công ước Liên Hợp Quốc về chống tham nhũng (UNCAC) khuyến nghị các quốc gia nghiên cứu để áp dụng: \\"Mỗi quốc gia thành viên, căn cứ vào pháp luật quốc gia sẽ tiến hành các biện pháp cần thiết cho phép quốc gia thành viên khác khởi kiện vụ án dân sự tại toà án để xác định quyền hay quyền sở hữu đối với tài sản có được qua việc thực hiện các tội được quy định trong Công ước này\\". Để thực hiện được nội dung này, cần hoàn thiện các quy định của Bộ luật Dân sự và Bộ luật Tố tụng dân sự theo hướng sửa đổi, bổ sung quy định về trách nhiệm của cơ quan, tổ chức được giao quản lý tài sản thuộc sở hữu nhà nước trong việc khởi kiện vụ án dân sự để đòi lại những tài sản thuộc quyền quản lý của cơ quan, tổ chức nhưng bị hành vi tham nhũng xâm phạm; trong trường hợp cơ quan, tổ chức sở hữu tài sản nhà nước bị tham nhũng không khởi kiện vụ án, cho phép bên thứ ba khởi kiện vụ án dân sự đòi lại tài sản hoặc bồi thường thiệt hại tài sản này. Cùng với việc hoàn thiện pháp luật trong nước, cần tăng cường việc ký kết, tham gia các điều ước quốc tế về thu hồi tài sản tham nhũng, nhất là cơ chế tương trợ tư pháp về hình sự giữa các quốc gia trong việc phong tỏa, thu hồi tài sản của người phạm tội đã tẩu tán ở nước ngoài. Lê Sơn"},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన దానిని సంగ్రహించండి తెలంగాణ నుంచి పవన్ కళ్యాణ్ రాజకీయ యాత్రnతెలంగాణ రాష్ట్రం కరీంనగర్ జిల్లాలోని కొంగడట్టు ఆంజనేయ స్వామి ఆలయం నుంచి ఈ యాత్ర ప్రారంభమవుతుందని ఆయన శనివారం ట్విటర్‌లో తెలిపారు.ప్రజారాజ్యం పార్టీ యువజన విభాగం అధ్యక్షుడి హోదాలో 2009 ఎన్నికల్లో ప్రచారం చేస్తుండగా కరీంనగర్ జిల్లాలో పవన్‌కు కరెంట్ షాక్ తగిలింది. ఆ విషయాన్ని ఆయన గుర్తు చేసుకుంటూ.. ‘‘2009 ఎన్నికలకు ప్రచారం చేస్తున్న తరుణంలో సంభవించిన పెను ప్రమాదం నుంచి నేను ఇక్కడే క్షేమంగా బయటపడ్డాను’’ అని పేర్కొన్నారు.‘‘సర్వమత ప్రార్థనల అనంతరం రెండు తెలుగు రాష్ట్రాల ప్రజల ఆశీస్సుల కోసం, సమస్యలను అధ్యయనం చేసి, అవగాహన చేసుకోవడానికి ఈ యాత్ర ద్వారా మీ ముందుకు వస్తున్నాను’’ అని పవన్ ఈ ట్వీట్‌ ద్వారా తెలిపారు. జనవరి 22వ తేదీ నుంచి ఈ యాత్ర ప్రారంభం కానుంది.యాత్రకు సంబంధించిన మరిన్ని వివరాలకు సంబంధించి కూడా పవన్ కళ్యాణ్ స్పష్టత ఇస్తూ.. ‘‘నా పర్యటన ప్రణాళికను కొండగట్టులో  ప్రకటిస్తాను’’ అని ట్వీట్‌లో పేర్కొన్నారు.గతేడాది డిసెంబర్ 31వ తేదీన జనసేన సభ్యత్వ నమోదు కార్యక్రమాన్ని పవన్ ప్రారంభించారు. తొలి సభ్యత్వం ఆయనే స్వీకరించారు.‘‘కులాలని కలిపే ఆలోచన విధానం, మతాల ప్రస్తావన లేని రాజకీయం, భాషల్ని గౌరవించే సంప్రదాయం, సంస్కృతులను కాపాడే సమాజం, ప్రాంతీయతని విస్మరించని జాతీయవాదం. ఇవి దేశ పటిష్టతకు మూలాలు. ఇవే జనసేన సిద్ధాంతాలు’’ అని గతంలో  పవన్ కళ్యాణ్ ట్వీట్ చేశారు.గత కొంత కాలంగా ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్, తెలంగాణ రాష్ట్రాల్లో జిల్లాల వారీగా పార్టీ నిర్మాణ కార్యక్రమాలను కూడా చేపడుతున్నారు.ఇవి కూడా చదవండి:(బీబీసీ తెలుగును ఫేస్‌బుక్, ఇన్‌స్టాగ్రామ్‌, ట్విటర్‌లో ఫాలో అవ్వండి.  యూట్యూబ్‌లో సబ్‌స్క్రైబ్ చేయండి.)","answer":"త్వరలో ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్, తెలంగాణ రాష్ట్రాల్లో రాజకీయ యాత్ర చేపట్టనున్నట్లు జనసేన అధ్యక్షుడు పవన్ కళ్యాణ్ ప్రకటించారు."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:ऐसी याची फळश्रुती । श्रवणें चुके अधोगती ।मनास होय विश्रांती । समाधान ॥ ३७॥","answer":"अर्थ:या ग्रंथाची फलप्राप्ती अशी आहे की, केवळ श्रवणाने अधोगती तर चुकतेच; शिवाय मनास सहज संतोषरूपी समाधान लाभून परम विश्रांतीही प्राप्त होते. (३७)"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو حكم زكاة الفطر؟","answer":"الإجابة: واجبة على كل مسلم وجد ما يفضل عن قوته وقوت عياله ليلة العيد ويومه"},{"question":"Misy zoro firy ny biriky?","answer":"NY biriky dia misy zoro valo."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Banyak kaki, ada gunting.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah ketam "},{"question":"Inona no fitaovam-piadiana noforonin'i Ernest Swinton nampiasaina tamin'ny 1916 ? ","answer":"Ny Tank no fitaovam-piadiana noforonin'i Ernest Swinton nampiasaina tamin'ny 1916."},{"question":"අද්‍යතන කෙටිකථාවේ ආදිකතෘ ලෙස පිදුම් ලබන ලෝක පූජිත ප්‍රංශ ලේඛකයා කවුද?","answer":"අද්‍යතන කෙටිකථාවේ ආදිකතෘ ලෙස පිදුම් ලබන ලෝක පූජිත ප්‍රංශ ලේඛකයා ගී ද මෝ පසාං ය."},{"question":"Cuál es la respuesta correcta para la siguiente pregunta: ¿En qué siglo se desarrolló el jazz?","answer":"El jazz​ es un género musical nacido a finales del siglo XIX en los Estados Unidos, y se expandió de forma global a lo largo del siglo XX."},{"question":"नेपाली सांकेतिक भाषाको इतिहास के हो ?","answer":"नेपाली सांकेतिक भाषाको उत्पत्ति नेपालकै पहिलो बहिरा विद्यालयबाट भएको हुनसक्छ, जुन सन् १९६६ मा काठमाडौंमा एक नाक कान घाँटीडाक्टरले स्थापना गरेका थिए। पछि विद्यालयलाई नक्सलको बाल गृहमा सारिएको थियो। विद्यालयको उद्देश्य बहिरा बालबालिकालाई बोल्न सिकाउनको लागि स्पीच थेरापी सिकाउनु थियो।"},{"question":"جاوب على السؤال ده: فيلم فلاي بويز كان من بطولة ممثل اترشح لجايزة الأوسكارعن دوره فى فيلم 127 ساعة، مين هو الممثل ده؟","answer":"يسعدنى أجاوبك على السؤال ده.جيمس فرانكو هو الممثل اللى شارك فى بطولة فيلم فلاي بويز و اترشح لجايزة الأوسكارعن دوره فى فيلم 127 ساعة.أتمنى أكون جاوبتك. عندك أسئلة تانية؟"},{"question":"السؤال: من كان يحالف الخزرج من قبائل اليهود قبل إسلامهم؟","answer":"الإجابة: بني النضير وبني قينقاع"},{"question":"पोलिओ रोगामुळे शरीराच्या कोणत्या भागास इजा होते ?उत्तर :","answer":"पोलिओ रोगामुळे शरीराच्या मज्जासंस्था भागास इजा होते."},{"question":"එක්දින ජාත්‍යන්තර තරඟ වලදී ශ්‍රීලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් වේගවත්ම ලකුණු 10,000 ලබාගත් ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුද?","answer":"එක්දින ජාත්‍යන්තර තරඟ වලදී ශ්‍රීලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් වේගවත්ම ලකුණු 10,000 ලබාගත් ක්‍රීඩකයා තිලකරත්න මුදියන්සේලාගේ ඩිල්ෂාන් ය"},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 子どもの寝る時間が短い　細かく調べる研究が始まった","answer":"国は、小学校5年生と中学校2年生の全部で約200万人が1日にどのくらい寝ているか調べました。去年は「9時間より短い」と答えた小学生は60％以上で、「8時間より短い」と答えた中学生は70％以上でした。東京大学などのグループは、子どもの寝る時間について細かく調べる研究を始めました。グループによると、日本の子どもの寝る時間は、必要だと言われている時間より1時間ぐらい短いです。スマートフォンなどを使う子どもが増えて、夜遅くまで起きていることが多くなっています。このため、勉強や心の健康に問題が出ないか心配だと言っています。研究では、子どもに腕時計のような機械をつけて1週間生活してもらいます。寝ているときの脳の状態も調べます。5万人ぐらいを調べて、子どもたちがよく眠ることができるようにしていきたいと言っています。"},{"question":"ಸ್ವತಂತ್ರ ಭಾರತದ ಮೊದಲ ಪ್ರಧಾನಿ ಯಾರು?","answer":"ಸ್ವತಂತ್ರ ಭಾರತದ ಮೊದಲ ಪ್ರಧಾನಿ ಜವಾಹರಲಾಲ್ ನೆಹರು. ಅವರು ಆಗಸ್ಟ್ 15, 1947 ರಿಂದ ಮೇ 27, 1964 ರಂದು ಅವರ ಮರಣದ ತನಕ ಪ್ರಧಾನಿಯಾಗಿ ಸೇವೆ ಸಲ್ಲಿಸಿದರು."},{"question":": ज्वारीय ऊर्जाको पछाडिको सिद्धान्त व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"ज्वारभाटाको उदय र पतनलाई प्रयोग गरेर बिजुली उत्पादन गर्न ज्वार उर्जा उत्पन्न गरिन्छ। यो नवीकरणीय स्रोतमा पूर्वानुमान योग्यता र न्यूनतम वातावरणीय प्रभावको फाइदा छ।"},{"question":"මුහුද සහ සාගරය අතර ඇති වෙනස්කම කුමක්ද?","answer":"'මුහුද' යනු සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ගොඩබිම් සහ සාගරය හමුවන ස්ථාන (වෙරළ) ආසන්නයේ පවතින නොගැඹුරු සාගරය වන අතර ඒවා බොහෝවිට මහාද්වීපික තටක මත පිහිටයි. 'සාගරය' යනු ලොව විශාල භූමි ප්‍රමාණයක් ආවරණය කරගත් ජලස්කන්ධයක් වන අතර  ලෝකයේ ජලය පවතින විශාලතම ආකාරය වේ.උදාහරණය: 'අත්ලාන්තික් සාගරයේ' පවතින මුහුදක් ලෙස 'මධ්‍යධරණී මුහුද' හැඳින්විය හැකියි. මෙහි දී අත්ලන්තික් යනු 'සාගරයක්' ලෙසත් මධ්‍යධරණී යනු 'මුහුදක්' ලෙසත් හඳුනාගත හැකියි.\\"මුහුද\\" සහ \\"සාගර\\" යන පද සමහර විට එකිනෙකට සමාන ලෙස භාවිතා වේ, නමුත් ඒවා  අතර වෙනස්කම් බොහොමයක් තිබේ :1. ප්‍රමාණය සහ ගැඹුර: සාගර මුහුදට වඩා විශාල හා  ගැඹුරුය. ඒවා විශාල ප්‍රදේශ ආවරණය වන අතර ලෝකයේ ජලයේ ප්‍රධාන බෙදීම් වේ. මුහුද කුඩා වන අතර සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ගොඩබිම සහ සාගරය හමුවන තැන පිහිටා ඇත. සාමාන්‍යයෙන් මුහුදක් අර්ධ වශයෙන් ගොඩබිමෙන් වටවී ඇත.2. ස්ථානය සහ සංයුතිය: මුහුද සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සාගර මායිම්වල දක්නට ලැබෙන අතර අර්ධ වශයෙන් ගොඩබිමෙන් වට වී ඇත. අනෙක් අතට සාගර යනු විශාල විවෘත ජලයයි. නිදසුනක් වශයෙන්, මධ්‍යධරණී මුහුද යුරෝපය, ආසියාව සහ අප්‍රිකාවෙන් වටවී ඇති අතර පැසිෆික් සාගරය ගොඩබිමෙන් වට නොවූ විශාල ජල කඳකි.3. ලවණතාව සහ පරිසර පද්ධතිය: මුහුදු සහ සාගර අතර ලවණතාව සහ පරිසර පද්ධති වෙනස් විය හැක. මුහුද ගොඩබිමට සමීප බැවින් ගංගා සහ අනෙකුත් මිරිදිය මූලාශ්‍රවල බලපෑම හේතුවෙන් විවිධ ලවණතා මට්ටම් සහ විවිධ පරිසර පද්ධති තිබිය හැක.4. සංඛ්‍යාව සහ නම්: සාගර පහක් (පැසිෆික්, අත්ලාන්තික්, ඉන්දියානු, ආක්ටික් සහ දකුණු) ඇතත් බොහෝ මුහුදු (කැරිබියන් මුහුද, දකුණු චීන මුහුද වැනි) ඇත.සාරාංශයක් ලෙස, සාගර විශාල, ගැඹුරු සහ ගොඩබිමෙන් වට වී නැති අතර මුහුද කුඩා, නොගැඹුරු සහ බොහෝ විට ගොඩබිමෙන් වට වී ඇත."},{"question":"Apakah maksud dengan peribahasa 'orang kaya suka dimakan, orang muda selendang dunia'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang hartawan yang selalu dermawan, orang muda adalah perhiasan dunia (untuk puji-pujian)"},{"question":"Ci man kembaar la réewum Andorre nekk ?","answer":"Réewum Andorre moo ngi nekk ci kembaar bi ñuy wax Europe"},{"question":"கேள்வி : இரட்டைக்  காப்பியங்கள் குறித்து கட்டுரை வரைக.","answer":"பதில் :இரட்டை காப்பியங்கள் கட்டுரைகுறிப்பு சட்டகம்முன்னுரைசிலப்பதிகாரம்மணிமேகலைஇரட்டைக் காப்பியங்களின் பிறபெயர்கள்இரட்டைக் காப்பியங்களின் சிறப்புக்கள்முடிவுரைமுன்னுரைகற்பனை வளம், சிந்தனைத் திறன், சுவை உணர்வு, இலக்கிய நயம் ஆகியவை மிக்க ஓர் உன்னதப் படைப்புத்தான் காப்பியமாகும்.முற்காலத்தில் தமிழில் எழுதப்பட்ட ஐம்பெரும் காப்பியங்களாக சிலப்பதிகாரம், மணிமேகலை, குண்டலகேசி, வளையாபதி, சீவக சிந்தாமணி என்பன அறியப்படுகின்றன.இதில் சிலப்பதிகாரமும், மணிமேகலையும் இரட்டை காப்பியங்கள் எனப்படும். இவ்விரு காப்பியங்களும் தமிழ்நாட்டைக் கதைக் களமாக கொண்டவையாகும். இந்த இரட்டை காப்பியங்கள் பற்றி இக்கட்டுரையில் நோக்கலாம்.சிலப்பதிகாரம்சிலம்பு – அதிகாரம் என்ற இரு சொற்களால் ஆனது சிலப்பதிகாரம். சிலம்பு காரணமாக விளைந்த கதையானதால் சிலப்பதிகாரம் ஆயிற்று.கி. பி. இரண்டாம் நூற்றாண்டில் இந்நூல் “இளங்கோ அடிகள்” என்பவரால் எழுதப்பட்டது. காப்பியங்களுக்கான இலக்கண அமைப்பு அனைத்தும் பொருந்தி வரும்படி இயற்றப்பட்ட காப்பியமாகும்.சிலப்பதிகாரத்தின் கதை மாந்தர்களாக கண்ணகி, கோவலன், மாதவி போன்றோர் முக்கியம் பெறுகின்றனர்.அக்காலத் தமிழ் மக்களின் வாழ்க்கை பற்றிய செய்திகள் இதில் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளன. தமிழறிஞர்களால் மிகுதியாக ஆய்வுக்கு உட்பட்ட நூல் இதுவேயாகும்.மணிமேகலைசிலப்பதிகாரத்திற்கு அடுத்ததாக இலக்கிய அழகில் பெருமைவாய்ந்த மணிமேகலை ஐம்பெரும் தமிழ் காப்பியங்களுள் ஒன்றாகும்.மணிமேகலைக் காப்பித்தை இயற்றியவர் சீத்தலைச் சாத்தனார் ஆவார். மணிமேகலை காப்பியத்தின் காலம் தொடர்பாக முரண்பட்ட கருத்துகள் உள்ளன.எனினும் மணிமேகலை நியாயப் பிரவேசம் எனும் நூலைப் பின்பற்றித் தோன்றியது என்று கருதப்படுகிறது. இக்காப்பியத்தின் தலைவியான மணிமேகலை சிலப்பதிகாரத்தின் கோவலன் மற்றும் மாதவி என்பவர்களின் மகளாவாள்.இரட்டைக் காப்பியங்களின் பிறபெயர்கள்சிலப்பதிகாரம் வேறு பெயர்கள்தமிழின் முதல் காப்பியம்உரையிடையிட்ட பாட்டுடைச் செய்யுள்முத்தமிழ்க்காப்பியம்முதன்மைக் காப்பியம்பத்தினிக் காப்பியம்நாடகப் காப்பியம்குடிமக்கள் காப்பியம்புதுமைக் காப்பியம்பொதுமைக் காப்பியம்ஒற்றுமைக் காப்பியம்ஒருமைப்பாட்டுக் காப்பியம்தமிழ்த் தேசியக் காப்பியம்மூவேந்தர் காப்பியம்வரலாற்றுக் காப்பியம்போராட்ட காப்பியம்புரட்சிக்காப்பியம்சிறப்பதிகாரம்பைந்தமிழ் காப்பியம்மணிமேகலை வேறு பெயர்கள்மணிமேகலைத் துறவுமுதல் சமயக் காப்பியம்அறக்காப்பியம்சீர்திருத்தக்காப்பியம்குறிக்கோள் காப்பியம்புரட்சிக்காப்பியம்சமயக் கலைச் சொல்லாக்க காப்பியம்கதை களஞ்சியக் காப்பியம்பசிப்பிணி மருத்துவக் காப்பியம்பசு போற்றும் காப்பியம்இரட்டைக் காப்பியங்களின் சிறப்புக்கள்தமிழில் தோன்றிய முதல் காப்பியம் என்ற சிறப்பை சிலப்பதிகாரம் பெறுகின்றது. பாவின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு வித்திட்ட நூல் சிலப்பதிகாரம் “நெஞ்சை அள்ளும் சிலப்பதிகாரம்” என பாரதியார் கூறுகிறார்.இரட்டை காப்பியத்துள் கிளைக்கதைகள் மிகுந்த நூல் மணிமேகலை ஆகும். மனித வாழ்வு செம்மை அடைவதற்காக அறநெறிகளை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டு பாடப்பட்டதே மணிமேகலைக் காப்பியமாகும்.இக்காப்பியமானது உணவிடும் உன்னதப் பணியினை கூறுகின்றது. திருவள்ளுவரை “பொய்யில் புலவன்” எனவும் திருக்குறளைப் “பொருளுறை” என்றும் முதலில் கூறிய காப்பியம்.முடிவுரைஇலக்கியங்கள், காலம் காட்டும் கண்ணாடியாகும். இரட்டைக் காப்பியங்களான சிலப்பதிகாரம், மணிமேகலை, ஆகிய இரண்டும் காப்பியத் தன்மை மிகுந்து தமிழின்பம் நல்கும் நூல்களாக அமைந்துள்ளன.இக்காப்பியங்கள் அறக் கருத்துக்களைப் போதித்து மக்களை நல்வழிப்படுத்த வழியாக திகழ்கின்றன. இவ் அறக்கருத்துக்களைப் பின்பற்றி வாழ்வில் சிறப்போமாக."},{"question":"Berikan saya lirik lagu negeri Negeri Sembilan.","answer":"Lirik lagu negeri Negeri Sembilan iaitu \\"Berkatlah Yang Dipertuan Besar Negeri Sembilan\\" adalah seperti berikut:Berkatlah Yang Dipertuan Besar Negeri SembilanKurniai sihat dan makmurKasihi rakyat lanjutkan umurAkan berkati sekalian yang sediaMusuhnya habis binasaBerkatlah Yang Dipertuan Besar Negeri Sembilan"},{"question":"Sử dụng tiêu đề sau để viết một bài báo khoảng 500 chữ: \\"Mỹ hỗ trợ 12 tỷ USD cho xe điện.\\"","answer":"Chính phủ Mỹ hôm 31/8 thông báo sẽ trợ cấp và cho vay các hãng xe để tăng tốc chuyển dịch sang xe điện.Bộ trưởng Năng lượng Mỹ Jennifer Granholm hôm 31/8 cho biết chính quyền Tổng thống Mỹ Joe Biden sẽ hỗ trợ 12 tỷ USD dưới dạng trợ cấp và cho vay với các hãng xe và nhà cung cấp cho họ. Mục đích là trang bị thêm cho các nhà máy để sản xuất xe điện và các loại xe tiên tiến khác.2 tỷ USD trợ cấp sẽ đến từ Đạo luật Giảm Lạm phát đã được thông qua năm ngoái. 10 tỷ USD khoản vay đến từ Văn phòng Cho vay thuộc Bộ Năng lượng Mỹ. Chính phủ Mỹ cũng sẽ hỗ trợ 3,5 tỷ USD cho các hãng sản xuất pin trong nước, Granholm cho biết.\\"Trong quá trình chuyển dịch sang xe điện, chúng tôi muốn đảm bảo các lao động có thể chuyển dịch tại chỗ. Sẽ không có người nào, không cộng đồng nào bị bỏ lại phía sau\\", Granholm cho biết trước báo giới.Đầu năm nay, chính quyền Biden đưa ra đề xuất chính sách đầy tham vọng, rằng xe điện sẽ chiếm hai phần ba xe mới bán ra tại Mỹ từ nay đến năm 2032.Việc tăng tốc hỗ trợ để chuyển đổi các nhà máy ôtô hiện tại sang sản xuất xe điện cũng có thể giúp Nhà Trắng xoa dịu chỉ trích từ các hãng xe và Công đoàn Công nhân Xe hơi Mỹ (UAW). Trước đó, giới chức Mỹ đề xuất nhiều quy định về bảo vệ môi trường nhằm mở ra kỷ nguyên xe điện.UAW từng cảnh báo việc thay đổi quá nhanh có thể khiến hàng nghìn việc làm bị đe dọa, tại các bang như Michigan, Ohio, Illinois và Indiana. Sau thông báo của chính phủ Mỹ, Chủ tịch UAW Shawn Fain cho biết chính sách này \\"đã giúp các hãng xe hiểu rõ rằng việc chuyển dịch sang xe điện cần đi kèm với tăng lương và các tiêu chuẩn an toàn mà UAW đang yêu cầu\\".Tổng thống Mỹ Joe Biden cũng khẳng định \\"xây dựng một nền kinh tế năng lượng sạch có lợi cho cả đôi bên - cả các hãng xe và người lao động - những thành phần đã hỗ trợ kinh tế Mỹ hàng thập kỷ nay\\".Fain trước đó cam kết bảo vệ một nhà máy sản xuất xe Jeep tại Illinois mà công ty Stellantis muốn đóng cửa. Dù vậy, hãng xe này để ngỏ khả năng mở cửa nếu nhà máy này ra được sản phẩm mới với hỗ trợ từ chính phủ.Khi được hỏi về khả năng khoản hỗ trợ 12 tỷ USD giúp các nhà máy mở cửa, Granholmcho biết các nhà máy \\"sẽ hưởng lợi từ các cơ hội mở ra nhờ khoản tiền này\\".Một quan chức Bộ Năng lượng Mỹ cho biết hiện chưa có quy định cụ thể về lao động để các công ty được hỗ trợ. Tuy nhiên, các dự án có điều kiện lao động tốt sẽ có cơ hội nhận vốn cao hơn."},{"question":"Waxad Sheegtaa magaca abwaankii curiyey riwaayaddii “Xiddigtii is Xujaysay”?","answer":" Waxaa curiyey Axmed Naaji Sacad."},{"question":"පහත තුන් තෙරවිල්ල තෝරන්න.කෙලවර හපහපා","answer":"කෙලවර නම් කොණ , හපහපා නම් කකා = කොණ කකා  , කණ කොකා"},{"question":"Heesta: Nin Haween JeclaadayFanaan: Cumar Dhuule Cali","answer":"Nin haweeyn jeclaaday Hawl iyo dhibaatiyo Waayi maayo hadimee Anoo kuu hanweynweyn baadHalbowlaha i go’ysooWarba iima haysideeHadal tiro ma fiicneeAdoon iga haraadinMaxaa kulaa hagaagsan?Inaan kaa hadhaanIminka taladeed hayaaHadaynaan heshiinaynWa inaynu kala hadhnaaKala hawl yaraysanaaHadiway baxaysaaIlayn haybsan maayeAan kaa horeeyeeHaddii kale aan hoydooHalkii loo badnaa iyoAakhiro u hayaameeHadal tiro ma fiicneAdoon iga haraadinMaxaa kulaa hagaagsanInaan kaa hadhaanImika taladeed hayaaHadaynaan heshiinaynWaa inaynu kala hadhnaaKala hawl yaraysanaa."},{"question":"মুক্তিযুদ্ধে নারীদের ভূমিকা ছিল গৌরবোজ্জ্বল— ব্যাখ্যা কর।","answer":"বাংলাদেশের মুক্তিযুদ্ধে নারীদের ভূমিকা ছিল গৌরবোজ্জ্বল।১৯৭১ সালের মার্চ মাসের শুরু থেকে দেশের বিভিন্ন অঞ্চলে যেসব সংগ্রাম পরিষদ গঠিত হয়, নারীরা তাতে স্বতঃস্ফূর্তভাবে অংশগ্রহণ করেন। কিছুসংখ্যক নারী অস্ত্রচালনা এবং গেরিলা প্রশিক্ষণ গ্রহণ করে সরাসরি মুক্তিযুদ্ধে অংশ নেন। এ ছাড়া মুক্তিযোদ্ধাদের আশ্রয়দান, যুদ্ধ সংক্রান্ত তথ্য সরবরাহ এবং আহতদের সেবা-শুশ্রষা করে নারীরা মুক্তিযুদ্ধে গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ভূমিকা রাখেন।"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Ryynänen deltog vid OS 2006 i Turin där han slutade 37:a i sprinttävlingen. Ryynänens","answer":"främsta merit är guldet i stafett från VM 2007 i Sapporo."},{"question":"السؤال: من أول من استلم الحجر الأسود من الأئمة ؟","answer":"الإجابة : عبد الله بن الزبير ."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kuku kambing'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud alat yang digunakan untuk menanam padi. Contoh ayat: Suatu masa dahulu kuku kambing digunakan untuk menanam padi."},{"question":"\\"අව්වට වැස්සට හුරු මිනිසුන්නේ\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"අව්වට වැස්සට හුරු මිනිසුන්නේදෑතේ විරියෙනි රටවල් නැගුනේඒ මිනිසුන්ගේ මළගම වෙනුවෙන්මොන රජ මැදුරෙද සුදු කොඩි නැගුනේදා ගැබ් මහ වැව් කලා නිකේතනනුඹලා දෑතිනි මිහි මත මැවුනේඒ නුඹලාටයි දූ දරුවන්ටයිමොන රජ මැදුරෙද දොරටුව හැරුනේරජ සැප විඳිනට රජ දරුවන් හටනුඹලා දෑතිනි මන්දිර මැවුනේඒ නුඹලාගේ දුක දැක ගන්නටමොන රජ දරුවද පැලකට වැඩියේ"},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.කන්න දෙනකොට ජීවත් වෙනවා වතුර දෙනකොට මැරෙනවා","answer":"ගින්දර"},{"question":"Me dê um exemplo de trivia nessa categoria: videogames","answer":"Qual jogo de Mario está no NES e não possui Bowser como vilão? Super Mario Bros. 2"},{"question":"An dtéann an ghrian suas níos déanaí sa gheimhreadh? ","answer":"i gcoitinne is féidir leat smaoineamh ar ghrian suas mar ag éirí níos déanaí de réir mar a théann na míonna ar aghaidh tríd an mbliain féilire. Feicfidh na háiteanna is faide ó thuaidh / ó dheas an ghrian amach is luaithe ar an solstice samhraidh, agus feicfidh na suíomhanna is faide ó dheis an grian amach is déanaí ar an solestice geimhreadh."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన వ్యాక్యంలో తప్పు ఉంటె సరిచేసి రాయండి:  ఒకవేళ మూత్రపిండాలు విఫలం అయితే, శరీరం నీరు మరియు వ్యర్థ ఉత్పత్తులతో నిండి ఉంటుంది. ఈ స్థితిని ఎడిమ అంటారు.","answer":"ఒకవేళ మూత్రపిండాలు విఫలం అయితే, శరీరం నీరు మరియు వ్యర్థ ఉత్పత్తులతో నిండి ఉంటుంది. ఈ స్థితిని యూరేమియా అంటారు."},{"question":"Complete o seguinte trecho: Nos tempos modernos, o Japão e a Santa Sé mantêm relações cordiais e estão empenhados na cooperação cultural. Apesar do pequeno número de cristãos no Japão, muitos japoneses têm simpatia pela fé e, de acordo com o embaixador Hidekazu Yamaguchi, o governo japonês reconhece \\"a contribuição que a Igreja Católica deu à educação e à saúde do povo japonês por meio de suas escolas e hospitais\\", bem como a ajuda humanitária que a Santa Sé prestou logo após o","answer":"terremoto e tsunami de Tohoku em 2011. Ele acrescentou que o Japão e o Vaticano compartilham opiniões sobre muitas questões."},{"question":"Inona avy ny karazana fitiavana?","answer":"Ny karazana fitiavana dia ahitana ny fitiavana romantika, ny fitiavana ny fianakaviana, ny fitiava-namana ary ny fitiavana tsy misy fitiavan-tena. "},{"question":"Кыргызстандын Ысык-Көл облусу тууралуу маалымат бер.","answer":"Ысык-Көл облусу — Кыргыз Республикасынын чыгыш бөлүгүндө жайгашкан облус. Борбору — Каракол шаары. Курамында 5 район (Ак Суу, Жети Өгүз, Тоң, Түп, Ысык Көл), 3 шаар (Балыкчы, Каракол, Чолпон-Ата) , 5 шаарча (Ак-Булак, Жыргалаң, Кажы-Сай, Прежевальск пристаны, Орто-Токой) , 57 айыл округу жана 171 айыл бар(2012). Түндүгүнөн жана түндүк-чыгышынан Казакстан, чыгышынан жана түштүк-чыгышынан Кытай, батышынан жана түштүк-батышынан Нарын, түндүк-батышынан Чүй облустары менен чектешет.Аянты 43,1 миң км² (республиканын айантынын 21,6%). Калкы 496,4 миң (2020 ж.; республиканын калкынын 7,6%)."},{"question":"பெரி பெரி நோயைக் கண்டுபிடித்தவர்?","answer":"விடை: மாக்மிலன்."},{"question":"س258- من النبي الذي عرف منذ صغره بالجمال ؟","answer":"ج258- سيدنا يوسف عليه السلام"},{"question":"துப்பாக்கியை கண்டுபிடித்தவர்?","answer":"வரலாறு அமெரிக்க கண்டுபிடிப்பாளர், ஹைரம் பெர்சி மாக்சிம் வணிகரீதியாக வெற்றிபெற்ற ஒலியடக்கி மாதிரியை, சுமார் 1902-ல் கண்டுபிடித்தவர் ஆவார் (காப்புரிமம் பெற்றது மார்ச் 30, 1909)."},{"question":"Rose water සඳහා රෝස වතුර හැර වෙනත් ලස්සන වචනයක් නැද්ද","answer":"ඒවට කියන නියම නම පිනිදිය. රෝස් වෝටර් කියන්නෙ ඉංග්‍රිසියෙන්."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Có thể nói Kang Tae Oh là cái tên hot nhất màn ảnh Hàn hiện nay. Sau 9 năm chật vật đóng phim, nam diễn viên đã một bước đổi đời và thành sao hạng A nhờ bộ phim hiện tượng đang \\"làm mưa làm gió\\" toàn cầu. Kang Tae Oh còn được biết đến như một nam thần \\"số hưởng\\" vì toàn đóng cặp với những người tình màn ảnh toàn là minh tinh, idol xinh đẹp, tài năng hàng đầu từ showbiz Hàn Quốc đến Việt Nam. Điểm chung của dàn nữ diễn viên đóng cặp với Kang Tae Oh đó là họ đều sở hữu nụ cười toả nắng. Nữ diễn viên sinh năm 1992 Park Eun Bin vốn là sao nhí một thời của Giày Thuỷ Tinh. Từ hồi nhỏ, cô nàng đã gây ấn tượng với gương mặt xinh xắn sắc nét. Lớn lên, Park Eun Bin dậy thì cũng rất thành công, cô nổi tiếng với nhan sắc ngọt ngào, trong trẻo thuần khiết, đặc biệt gây ấn tượng với nụ cười rạng rỡ như ánh nắng. Nét đẹp của cô được đánh giá là hợp gu người Hàn, gương mặt không quá mĩ miều nhưng lại cực kỳ gây thiện cảm với khán giả. Trước Park Eun Bin, Nhã Phương mới chính là bạn diễn được các fan Việt \\"đẩy thuyền\\" rầm rộ nhất nhờ cơn sốt Tuổi Thanh Xuân. Thời điểm đó, Kang Tae Oh mới chỉ là diễn viên tân binh, nhưng anh đã thể hiện rất tốt vai diễn và chiếm trọn trái tim của khán giả Việt. Từ thời Tuổi Thanh Xuân, Nhã Phương đã nổi danh là một trong những mỹ nhân nổi trội về nhan sắc của Vbiz. Nữ diễn viên sở hữu ngoại hình gây thiện cảm với khán giả, thần thái nhẹ nhàng và nụ cười rạng ngời. Nổi bật nhất có lẽ chính là đôi mắt to tròn, lúc nào cũng như ngấn lệ và có chút buồn đầy chất thơ. Đó là lý do Nhã Phương luôn khiến khán giả xúc động với những cảnh khóc hết nước mắt. Dù hiện tại đã là mẹ bỉm sữa và vượt ngưỡng tuổi 30 nhưng Nhã Phương vẫn giữ được vẻ ngoài trẻ trung đáng ngưỡng mộ cùng thân hình thon gọn, nuột nà. Kim So Hyun thời còn làm diễn viên nhí tuy được khen ngợi về tài năng diễn xuất song lại nhận phải nhiều ý kiến trái chiều về nhan sắc. Tuy nhiên theo thời gian, Kim So Hyun đã có màn \\"dậy thì\\" ngoạn mục, càng trưởng thành lại càng xinh đẹp và rạng rỡ hơn, ra dáng nữ thần mới của màn ảnh Hàn Quốc. Ngay từ khi mới ra mắt, Sooyoung đã nổi tiếng là chân dài của SNSD. Nữ idol kiêm diễn viên sở hữu chiều cao 1m70 cùng đôi chân siêu dài, thân hình chuẩn mẫu. Mỹ nhân SNSD khiến khán giả mê mệt vì combo ngoại hình hoàn hảo từ gương mặt tới thân hình. Không ít đàn em ghen tỵ với Sooyoung vì khuôn mặt dịu hiền, xinh xắn đối lập với thân hình gợi cảm. Nguồn: Twitter","answer":"Kang Tae Oh \\"số hưởng\\" đóng cặp với toàn mỹ nhân từ Hàn tới Việt, Park Eun Bin - Nhã Phương không thua gì nữ thần SNSD"},{"question":"भारत में प्रधानमंत्री के औहदे  को क्या  माना जाता है?","answer":"उत्तर: कार्यकारी प्रमुख"},{"question":"کوم اسم دی چې فزیکي مواد بیانوي، کوم چې ځای هم نیسي او وزن لري؟ د پخوانۍ پوښتنې په پام کې نیولو سره ، یو داسې شرایط ولیکئ چې ځواب پکې شامل وي. دا د 1 - 20 جملو څخه کیدی شي. په دې اړه:","answer":"هرڅومره چې ښوونکی موضوع ته وده ورکوي هغومره به زده کونکي له موضوع څخه ګټه پورته کوي. د ښوونکي د لیوالتیا درې مهم اړخونه د تدریس په اړه لیوالتیا، د زده کونکو لیوالتیا او د موضوع په اړه لیوالتیا دي. ښوونکی باید له تدریس څخه خوند واخلي. که دوی د هغه څه څخه خوند نه اخلي چې دوی یې کوي، زده کونکي به وکوالی شي ووایی. دوی باید د خپلو زده کونکو سره خوند واخلي. یو ښوونکی چې د خپلو شاګردانو پاملرنه کوي د هغه فرد سره مرسته کوي چې په خپل راتلونکي ژوند کې بریالي شي. ښوونکي باید د هغه مضمون په اړه جذب وي چې دوی یې تدریس کوي. د مثال په توګه، یو ښوونکی چې د کیمیا په اړه خبرې کوي باید د کیمیا له هنر څخه خوند واخلي او خپلو زده کونکو ته یې وښيي. په ښوونکي کې یو څراغ هم کولی شي په زده کونکي کې د لیوالتیا څرنګوالی راولي. یو په زړه پوری ښوونکی د دې وړتیا لري چې د ځوانو زده کونکو په ژوند کې خورا اغیزناک وي."},{"question":"Đặt tiêu đề cho đoạn văn sau:  Đài CNN dẫn một số báo cáo gần đây chỉ ra rằng các nhà tuyển dụng ở Trung Quốc dường như chỉ đang tập trung thuê công nhân chưa đến 35 tuổi, độ tuổi thậm chí chưa được gọi là trung niên.Cụm từ \\"lời nguyền tuổi 35\\" ban đầu được dùng để mô tả việc các công ty sa thải các lao động từ 35 tuổi trở lên. Tuy nhiên, hiện nó cũng được \\"áp dụng\\" để gọi việc các nhà tuyển dụng chỉ tìm kiếm những sinh viên mới ra trường.Văn hóa làm việc 996Việc ưa thích những người lao động trẻ tuổi một phần là do văn hóa làm việc đòi hỏi mọi người phải làm việc nhiều giờ ở Trung Quốc.\\"Lời nguyền tuổi 35\\" là một nhánh của \\"văn hóa làm việc 996\\" đầy áp lực của quốc gia tỉ dân.  Đối với \\"996\\", những công nhân Trung Quốc muốn thăng tiến phải tuân theo một lịch trình khắt khe, làm việc từ 9 giờ sáng đến 9 giờ tối, liên tục 6 ngày trong tuần.Do yêu cầu khắc nghiệt, các nhà tuyển dụng ưu ái những người trẻ, khỏe mạnh và sẵn sàng làm việc nhiều giờ. Tờ Business Insider dẫn lời chuyên gia Tianlei Huang của Viện Kinh tế Quốc tế Peterson (Mỹ) cho biết: \\"Những người lao động trẻ có điều kiện sức khỏe tốt hơn những người lớn tuổi và họ có ít nghĩa vụ gia đình hơn những người trên 35 tuổi, vì vậy họ có thể làm việc nhiều giờ hơn\\".Nhiều học giả và quan chức hàng đầu của Trung Quốc cũng đã thừa nhận vấn đề này. Tờ China Youth Daily dẫn phát biểu của nhà lâp pháp Tưởng Thắng Nam, trong đó nói rằng \\"sự phân biệt đối xử vô hình về độ tuổi đối với những người 35 tuổi luôn tồn tại ở nơi làm việc\\" và việc từ chối những ứng viên ở độ tuổi 35 là một sự lãng phí rất lớn về tài năng\\".Giải pháp pháp lýCác chuyên gia cho rằng cách tốt nhất để chống lại chủ nghĩa phân biệt tuổi tác và bất bình đẳng giới là thông qua cải cách pháp lý. Hãng thông tấn nhà nước Tân Hoa xã trong năm nay đã đề xuất một số chính sách đặc biệt ưu tiên người lao động trên 35 tuổi, cùng với hỗ trợ tài chính và các quy định chống phân biệt tuổi tác.Tuy nhiên, nhiều người không thể đợi đến khi các giải pháp trên được thực hiện. Trong bối cảnh Trung Quốc vẫn đang nỗ lực phục hồi sau thiệt hại kinh tế do đại dịch Covid-19 gây ra và có dấu hiệu tăng trưởng chậm lại, tình trạng thất nghiệp đã trở thành mối lo ngại cấp bách đối với nhiều lao động.Trên toàn quốc, tỷ lệ thất nghiệp chính thức đã tăng lên mức cao gần kỷ lục 6,1% vào năm ngoái và mặc dù việc dỡ bỏ lệnh phong tỏa đã giúp giảm nhẹ nhưng tỷ lệ này vẫn ở mức 5,2%.Đối với nhiều phụ nữ Trung Quốc, \\"lời nguyền\\" càng làm trầm trọng thêm tình trạng phân biệt giới tính vốn đã ăn sâu bám rễ ở nơi làm việc.Phụ nữ ở độ tuổi 35 thường cho biết họ phải đối mặt với áp lực từ phía người sử dụng lao động bởi các doanh nghiệp không muốn trả lương cho thời gian nghỉ thai sản. Nhiều người cho biết họ đã mất cơ hội thăng tiến vì người chủ sợ họ sẽ nghỉ việc lâu dài.Nam giới cũng có thể bị ảnh hưởng. Nhiều lao động nam thậm chí bị giao những nhiệm vụ được cho là không phù hợp, ví dụ như đi công tác vào lúc vợ vừa mới sinh. Nhà nghiên cứu Yiran Zhang, trợ lý giáo sư tại Trường Luật Cornell (Mỹ), cho biết mặc dù luật lao động của Trung Quốc cấm phân biệt đối xử vì lý do sắc tộc, giới tính và tín ngưỡng tôn giáo nhưng lại không cấm phân biệt việc đối xử không công bằng vì lý do tuổi tác, theo CNN.Và ngay cả ở những đối tượng được cung cấp một số biện pháp bảo vệ, chẳng hạn như đối với các bà mẹ đang nghỉ thai sản, việc thực thi luật còn yếu và tình trạng phân biệt đối xử về giới vẫn còn phổ biến.Những nhân viên thành công khởi kiện chủ lao động có thể chỉ nhận được mức bồi thường thiệt hại thấp, khiến một số người không mặn mà với việc theo đuổi hành động pháp lý.","answer":"'Lời nguyền tuổi 35' đối với người lao động Trung Quốc"},{"question":"Sheeg Magaalada Kaliya Ee Soomaaliya Bariiska Ka Baxo?","answer":"Waa Magaalada Jowhar Ee Gobolka Shabellada Dhexe."},{"question":"فيينا","answer":"فِييَنَّا هي عاصمة النمسا وأكبر مدنها من حيث عدد السكان. وسميت بهذا تطويرا عن اسمها اللاتيني القديم (فيندوبونا) ومعناه الهواء الجميل أو النسيم العليل. يبلغ عدد سكان فيينا حوالي 1.7 مليون نسمة، وهي عاشر أكبر مدينة من ناحية عدد السكان في الاتحاد الأوروبي.   كانت فيينا عاصمة الإمبراطورية النمساوية المجرية وازدهرت في القرن التاسع عشر مركزاً للتعليم والأدب والموسيقى والعلوم، إلى أن تراجعت مكانتها بعد انهيار إمبراطورية هابسبورغ بعد نهاية الحرب العالمية الأولى في عام 1918. أصبحت فيينا بعد الحرب العالمية الثانية مركزاً عالمياً للمؤتمرات ومركز وكالات عالمية متعددة. وتستضيف فيينا العديد من المنظمات الدولية الكبرى مثل منظمة الأمم المتحدة ومنظمة أوبك."},{"question":"Chifukwa chiyani kalulu ndi wapadera?","answer":"Akalulu ndi nyama zaukhondo kwambiri ndipo nzosavuta kuswa ndi kuphunzitsa. Mofanana ndi galu, kalulu amatha kuphunzitsidwa kubwera ku dzina lake, kukhala pamiyendo panu, ndi kuchita zinthu zosavuta. Akalulu okondwa amakhala ndi khalidwe lokongola, amalumpha m'mwamba ndikuzungulira zungulira!"},{"question":"Por favor, indique seu gênero.","answer":"Eu sou um software de computador de inteligência artificial e, consequentemente, não tenho um gênero, identidade ou características humanas. Posso ajudar com informações de forma imparcial e neutra, sem características pessoais. Não tenho propriedades físicas como seres humanos."},{"question":"የናዋትል ቋንቋ አሁን የሚጸፈው በምን ፊደላት ነው?","answer":"በላቲን"},{"question":"Ai không nên uống nước chanh?A. Người mắc bệnh dạ dày, viêm loétB. Người mắc bệnh đường tiêu hóa, hay ợ hơi, ợ chua, trào ngượcC. Cả hai đáp án trên","answer":"Đáp án chính xác là C.Người bị viêm loét dạ dày, các bệnh về thận, túi mật, bệnh tiêu hóa nên hạn chế uống nước chanh. Vị chua của chanh sẽ làm tăng tiết axit trong dạ dày. Người có chứng ợ nóng cũng không nên uống nhiều vì có thể gây kích thích, lâu dần gây bệnh đường tiêu hóa.Bạn có thể thêm gừng, mật ong, muối, sữa... để tăng hương vị, giảm độ chua, tránh cảm giác khó chịu, cồn cào."},{"question":"काठमाडौं–पोखरा सडकको नाम के हो ?","answer":"काठमाडौं–पोखरा सडकको नाम पृथ्वी राजमार्ग हो। पृथ्वी राजमार्ग नेपालको राजधानी काठमाडौंबाट २६ किलोमिटर टाढा रहेको त्रिभुवन राजमार्गको नौबिसे र नेपालको पश्चिमी भागको पर्यटकीय सहर पोखराको पृथ्वीचोक जोड्ने १७४ किलोमिटर लामो राजमार्ग हो।"},{"question":"Iza no mpanimba ny tontolo iainana?","answer":"Ny mpanimba ny tontolo iainana dia isika olombelona ihany amin'ny alalan'ny fandotoana sy ny tsy fanajana azy."},{"question":"Ọpọ eeyan ko jade dibo ijọba ibilẹ nipinlẹ Ogun","answer":"Ko sija, ko si jagidijagan, ṣugbọn ko si awọn oludibo to bẹẹ ju bẹẹ lọ pẹlu, iyẹn nibi eto idibo sawọn ijọba ibilẹ to waye nipinlẹ Ogun lọjọ Satide, ọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu keje, ọdun 2021.Ni Aarin-Gbungbun Ogun, Iwọ-Oorun ati Ila-Oorun, awọn oludibo to jade ko to nnkan rara, bẹẹ, awọn eeyan forukọ silẹ, ṣugbọn lọjọ idibo yii, awọn to jade dibo kere gidi.Lori idi ti eyi fi ri bẹẹ, Dokita Abdullahi Mohammed Jabi, to sọrọ lorukọ ẹgbẹ ‘Civil Society Organisation’, ṣalaye pe akọkọ ni pe ẹru n ba awọn eeyan, nitori ko si aabo laarin ilu.O ni ikeji ni pe inu awọn eeyan ko dun, ara ko si ya wọn sijọba yii nitori ọrọ aje to n bajẹ, ti gbogbo ọja n gbowo leri lojoojumọ, ti ko si tun sowo ti wọn yoo fi ra a, titi kan ohun jijẹ ti ko ṣee ma ni.Dokita Jabi sọ pe loootọ nijọba ipinlẹ Ogun pese aabo to peye ṣaaju idibo yii, to jẹ gbogbo awọn ẹṣọ alaabo lo duro wamu, o ni inu didun lo n mori ya, ẹni ti inu rẹ ko dun, ti ko rowo na ko le ronu ibo didi, nitori yoo maa ro o pe eyi toun ti n di latẹyin wa, ki lo ba de.Ṣa, Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun ṣapejuwe ibo naa bii eyi to lọ nirọwọ-rọsẹ, ti ko mu wahala dani, ti awọn eeyan si jade ṣe ojuṣe wọn.O gboriyin fun ajọ OGSIEC to ṣeto ibo naa, o ni wọn ṣiṣẹ wọn bii iṣẹ lohun gbogbo ṣe lọ bo ṣe yẹ.Aago mejla ọsan ku iṣẹju mẹtadinlogun ni Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun de si Wọọdu kẹta, n’Ipẹru, Uniiti keji lo ti dibo, n’Ita  Ọsanyin, Ipẹru Rẹmọ.Nipa awọn ẹka PDP ti wọn lawọn ko ni i kopa ninu idibo naa, Gomina Abiọdun sọ fawon akọroyin pe oun ko mọ nnkan kan nipa ẹ.O ni o ṣee ṣe ko jẹ abala ti kootu ko da mọ lo ṣe ipinnu iru rẹ, o ni ṣugbọn nigba ti oun ki i ṣe lọọya, toun ko si ki i ṣe OGSIEC, ko si boun yoo ṣe le sọ ohunkohun nipa awọn ti wọn lawọn ko ni i kopa."},{"question":"كم تبلغ درجه حراره الشمس؟","answer":"15 مليون درجه مئوية."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو معنى كلمة “عسعس”؟","answer":"الإجابة: أدبر"},{"question":"Cindy, seorang perempuan yang setiap hari melintas di Jalan Enggano, Tanjung Priok, Jakarta Utara, mengatakan, menyeberang di jalan itu adalah sebuah keterpaksaan.\\"Terpaksa. Setiap hari lewat jalan itu. Sulit menyeberang karena kendaraannya ramai dan ngebut\\", ujarnya.Opini Cindi di atas termasuk sentimen apa? Berikan jawaban beserta alasannya.Jawaban:","answer":"Opini di atas termasuk sentimen negatif. Ada kata-kata ulasan bermakna negatif, seperti: terpaksa; sulit menyeberang; kendaraannya ramai dan ngebut."},{"question":"What is the capital of Bahrain?","answer":"The capital of Bahrain is Manama."},{"question":"पूर्वी तट का डेल्टा क्षेत्र अक्सर चक्रवातों से प्रभावित होता है। इसका क्या कारण हैं?","answer":"उत्तर-पश्चिमी भारत में निम्न दबाव की स्थिति नवंबर की शुरुआत में बंगाल की खाड़ी में स्थानांतरित हो जाती है। यह बदलाव चक्रवाती अवसादों की घटना से जुड़ा है, जो अंडमान सागर के ऊपर उत्पन्न होते हैं। ये चक्रवात आम तौर पर भारत के पूर्वी तटों को पार करते हैं और भारी और व्यापक बारिश का कारण बनते हैं। ये उष्णकटिबंधीय चक्रवात अक्सर बहुत विनाशकारी होते हैं। गोदावरी, कृष्णा और कावेरी के घनी आबादी वाले डेल्टा अक्सर चक्रवातों से प्रभावित होते हैं, जो जीवन और संपत्ति को भारी नुकसान पहुंचाते हैं। कभी-कभी ये चक्रवात उड़ीसा, पश्चिम बंगाल और बांग्लादेश के तटों पर पहुँच जाते हैं।"},{"question":"Continua il testo. Alla quinta gara chiuse secondo davanti al pubblico di casa, mentre durante il GP d'Europa 2003, accusato da David Coulthard e dall'amministratore delegato della McLaren di aver rallentato improvvisamente durante la gara mentre era dietro proprio il pilota britannico, causando così un incidente tra i due, venne scagionato dai commissari FIA dopo un colloquio con i piloti e dopo un controllo accurato della telemetria. Divenne in seguito alla vittoria all'","answer":"Hungaroring il più giovane pilota in Formula 1 ad aver vinto una corsa. Chiuse l'anno al sesto posto in classifica generale, con 55 punti e quattro podi."},{"question":"வினா: தாஜ்மஹால் எந்த கற்களால் கட்டப்பட்டது?","answer":"ராஜஸ்தானில் இருந்து கொண்டுவரப்பட்ட மிகவும் விலையுயர்ந்த பளிங்குக் கற்களால் தாஜ்மஹாலை கட்டமைத்தார் முகலாய பேரரசர் ஷாஜகான்."},{"question":" sheeg asxaabigii sunta cabay hadana eysan waxba ka dhibin","answer":" jawab. wuxu ahaa khaalid bin waliid rc."},{"question":"Pendant un entretien d'embauche, comment devrais-je répondre à la question: 'Que savez-vous sur notre entreprise ?'","answer":"Cette question est une sorte de test pour vérifier si le candidat s’est, ou non, intéressé à la société. Évoquez quelques données significatives et chiffrées qui témoignent de votre intérêt pour l’entreprise.Pour bien préparer un entretien d’embauche, n’oubliez pas de bien vous renseigner sur le poste mais également sur l’entreprise, sur ses principes, sur ses produits, sur son fonctionnement, etc. Ainsi, le recruteur verra que vous avez un réel intérêt pour l’entreprise et que vous avez des connaissances précises.Par exemple:“Hermès, marque née en France et à l’origine dédiée aux accessoires d’équitation, est une marque leader dans le marché de la maroquinerie de luxe. La maison soutien aujourd’hui les jeunes designers grâce au prix Émile Hermès, créé en 2010. Je serais très fier de rejoindre une entreprise qui porte des valeurs fortes d’artisanat et d’innovation. ”"},{"question":"السؤال: ماذا كانت لعبة حفلات الأطفال الشهيرة التي لا تتضمن الكرات في الأولمبياد من 1900 إلى 1920؟","answer":"الإجابة: شد الحبل"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: 7 xu thế trong chuyển đổi số ngành tài chính ngân hàng.","answer":"Nhiều doanh nghiệp tài chính ngân hàng đang trên chặng đường biến đổi các sản phẩm, dịch vụ theo hướng đáp ứng tốt hơn các nhu cầu, cá nhân hóa chuyên sâu hơn và tăng sự gắn kết của khách hàng.Trong đó, có thể kể đến một số xu thế như: các giải pháp thanh toán số Fintech; giải pháp vay ngang hàng (peer-to-peer lending); ứng dụng Blockchain trong thanh toán chuyển khoản ngân hàng; ứng dụng AI để mang đến dịch vụ phù hợp cho khách hàng; ứng dụng công nghệ sinh trắc học và internet vạn vật (IoT) để cung cấp các dịch vụ số mà không cần khách hàng giao tiếp trực tiếp; ứng dụng dữ liệu lớn Big data và đặc biệt là các công nghệ bảo mật."},{"question":"ಕನ್ನಡದಲ್ಲಿ ಒಂದು ತಮಾಷೆಯ ಜೋಕ್ ಬರೆಯಿರಿ","answer":"ಅಧ್ಯಾಪಕ: ಕುದುರೆ ಹಾಗೂ ಆನೆಗಳ ವ್ಯತ್ಯಾಸವೇನು?ಪುಟ್ಟು- ಕುದುರೆಗಳಿಗೆ ಹಿಂದುಗಡೆ ಮಾತ್ರ ಬಾಲವಿರುತ್ತೆ, ಆದರೆ ಆನೆಗಳಿಗೆ ಎರಡು ಕಡೆ ಬಾಲವಿರುತ್ತೆ"},{"question":"‘रघुवंशम’ हे महाकाव्य कोणी लिहिले ?","answer":"महाकवी कालिदास"},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο:  Αφού έγινε ο νεότερος άνθρωπος ποτέ που ολοκλήρωσε το διδακτορικό του στο Πανεπιστήμιο της Βαρσοβίας, ο Ταρσκί δίδαξε λογική στο Πολωνικό Παιδαγωγικό Ινστιτούτο, μαθηματικά και λογική στο Πανεπιστήμιο, και υπηρέτησε ως βοηθός του Λουκέιτζεβιτζ. Επειδή αυτές οι θέσεις ήταν κακοπληρωμένες, ο Ταρσκί επίσης δίδαξε μαθηματικά σε σχολείο δευτεροβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης της Βαρσοβίας. Πριν τον Β' Παγκόσμιο Πόλεμο, δεν ήταν ασυνήθιστο για τους Ευρωπαίους διανοούμενους της έρευνας διαμετρήματος να διδάσκουν στο γυμνάσιο. Ως εκ τούτου, από το 1923 μέχρι και την αναχώρησή του για τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες το 1939, ο Τάρσκι όχι μόνο έγραψε πολλά βιβλία και πολλά χαρτιά, ορισμένα από τα οποία ήταν ριζοσπαστικά, αλλά επίσης το έκανε ενώ συντηρούσε τον εαυτό του κυρίως με τη διδασκαλία μαθηματικών γυμνασίου. Το 1929 ο Τάρσκι παντρεύτηκε τη συνάδελφο Μαρία Βιτκόφσκα (Witkowska), η οποία ήταν Πολωνή με Καθολικό φόντο. Είχε εργαστεί ως μεταφορέας για το στρατό στον","answer":"Πολωνικό-Σοβιετικό Πόλεμο. Απέκτησαν δύο παιδιά, ένα γιο Γιαν (Jan) που έγινε φυσικός, και μια κόρη Ίνα (Ina) που παντρεύτηκε τον μαθηματικό Έρενφεουχτ ()."},{"question":"సొంతవాడకాలను నిర్వచించండి.","answer":"తన సొంత అవసరాల కోసము యజమాని సంస్థ నుంచి వాడుకున్న నగదు, వస్తువులను సొంతవాడకాలు అంటారు. ఆస్తి అప్పుల పట్టీలో ఈ సొంతవాడకాలను అప్పులవైపు మూలధనము నుంచి తీసివేయబడతాయి."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. ගෙල වට බැන්දා වූ මුතු පොටේ දිස්නෙට මුහුණේහි ඔප වැටේඔසරි නෙරියට නළල් තිලකෙටබැන්ද සිටු පෙම් ආනන්ද වේ","answer":"ගෙල වට බැන්දා වූ මුතු පොටේ දිස්නෙට මුහුණේහි ඔප වැටේඔසරි නෙරියට නළල් තිලකෙටබැන්ද සිටු පෙම් ආනන්ද වේකෝකිල සංදේශ කවි පොතේඔය වැනි උපමා ද තව ඇතේරුවැති ළඳකට තනිව මග තොටයන්න නිදහස දැන් නෑ වගේකාගේ කවුරුද ඉන්නේ කොතැනදනෑ අපි අඳුනන්නේආගන්තුක අපි ආවම කඳුරටනැතුවද පිළිගන්නේකෝකිල සංදේශ කවි පොතේ…..ගෙලවට බැන්දා වූ මුතු පොටේ…..සෙංකඩගලපුර පෝදා සඳ මෙනිමේ මුතු මැණිකේලාදළදා සමිඳුන් වැඩ හිඳිනා බිමනෑ හොඳ නෑ ඕවාගෙලවට බැන්දා වූ මුතු පොටේ…..කෝකිල සංදේශ කවි පොතේ…..ප්‍රියා සූරියසේන, නිරංජලා සරෝජිනීඅජන්තා රණසිංහප්‍රියා සූරියසේන"},{"question":"स्वास्थ्य सेवाको विकासमा प्रविधिको भूमिकाबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"टेक्नोलोजीले टेलीमेडिसिन र इलेक्ट्रोनिक हेल्थ रेकर्डबाट मेडिकल नवाचारहरू, बिरामी हेरचाह सुधार गर्न, र चिकित्सा जानकारीमा पहुँच बढाउँदै स्वास्थ्य सेवाको प्रगतिलाई प्रेरित गरेको छ।"},{"question":"Soruyu cevapla: Miami Dolphins en son ne zaman playoff'a katıldı?","answer":"Miami Dolphins en son playoff'a 2016 yılında katıldı."},{"question":"ธาตุ Au มีชื่อเรียกธาตุในภาษาไทยว่าอะไร","answer":"ธาตุทองคำ"},{"question":"வினா:இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள்:- நேபாளிகள் 1814-இல் பகுதிகளைக் கார்வால் கோட்டம் குமாவுன் கோட்டம், சிக்கிம் மற்றும் டார்ஜீலிங் பகுதிகளைக் கைப்பற்றினர். ஆங்கிலேயர் இதனைச் சவாலாக எற்றுக்கொண்டு கூர்க்கர் இனத்தலைவர் அமர்சிங்கைத் 1814-1816 ஆங்கிலேய-நேபாளப் போரில்","answer":"விடை:வென்றனர். மார்ச் 1816-ஆம் ஆன்டில் கூர்க்கர்கள், ஆங்கிலேயர்களோடு சுகௌலி உடன்படிக்கையின் படி இந்த , நேபாளிகள் வென்ற பகுதிகள் அனைத்தும் மீண்டும் இந்தியாவிற்கு திருப்பி கொடுத்தனர்."},{"question":"چند نمونه از ورزش‌های رزمی را نام ببر.","answer":" از معروفترین رشته های رزمی می‌توان به کیک بوکسینگ، تکواندو، جودو، کاراته، بوکس، سامبو، ووشو، جوجیتسو، موای تای اشاره کرد"},{"question":"सटीक कृषिमा रोबोटिक्सको भूमिकाबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"रोबोटिक्सले रोपण, फसल काट्ने र बाली अनुगमन जस्ता कार्यहरू स्वचालित गरेर सटीक कृषिमा महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका खेल्छ। इन्जिनियरहरूले सेन्सरहरू र एआईले सुसज्जित रोबोटिक प्रणालीहरू विकास गर्छन् जसले दक्षता र उत्पादन वृद्धिको लागि खेती गर्ने अभ्यासहरूलाई अनुकूलन गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Napisz pytanie dotyczące fragmentu tekstu: Interstate 70 (I-70) jest autostradą międzystanową w Stanach Zjednoczonych, która biegnie od Interstate 15 w pobliżu Cove Fort w stanie Utah do Park and Ride w pobliżu Baltimore w stanie Maryland.","answer":"\\"Którymi stanami przejeżdża autostrada 70?\\""},{"question":"四国地方は全部で４つの県です。では九州地方は沖縄を含めて全部で何県でしょう？","answer":"８県です。"},{"question":"グエル公園、カサ・ミラ、サグラダ・ファミリア教会などの設計で知られるスペインの建築家は誰でしょう？","answer":"アントニオ・ガウディです。"},{"question":"Dublin moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Dublin moy péeyu réwum Irlande"},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Éy yéen ñi gëm! Teetléen (moytu) njort yu bàri ndàx yenn njort yi bàkkaar la.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Éy yéen ñi gëm! Teetléen (moytu) njort yu bàri ndàx yenn njort yi bàkkaar la.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Éy: INTJyéen: PRONñi: PRONgëm: VERB!: PUNCTTeetléen: VERB(: PUNCTmoytu: VERB): PUNCTnjort: NOUNyu: PRONbàri: ADJndàx: SCONJyenn: DETnjort: NOUNyi: DETbàkkaar: NOUNla: AUX.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa Ilaha cuntada laga helo Iodine.?","answer":"Cunnooyinka ugu muhiimsan ee iodine-ta laga helo waa kalluunka badda, caano, cawsbadeed,khudaarta cagaaran ee laga beero badda agteeda(khaasatan isbinaajka), cusbada lagu dara iodineiyo biyaha fareeshka (saafiga) ah (waxay kuxiran tahay degaanka)."},{"question":"Иреттик сан атооч деген эмне ?","answer":"Заттын иретин көрсөтүп, канчанчы? неченчи? деген суроолоргожооп берген сан атоочтор иреттик сан атооч деп аталат.М и с а л ы: төртүнчү класс, экинчи катар, бешинчи көчө ж. б."},{"question":"(Uzwakala engaphandle, ehleka engahleki) Hho! Mhlawumbe wenaucabanga ukuthi kwenqakwa amagenda lapha, yingakho njeungichithela isikhathi ngoba sewuze wakhohlwa nawukuthingiyasebenza lapha mina. Uyazi ukuthini? Angenqeni phela minaukuvele ngisebenzise amagunya ami njengephoyisa wokubangivele ngisibhodloze mina lesi sicabha. Awuthi futhi kengi …(asho esikhahlela ngamawala)(Uzwakala ngaphakathi) Kahle ngamawala bo muntu womthetho.Ngilinde ngikuvulele. (Asho abe egudluza umshudu ngaphakathimaqedane kuvuleke.)Ehhe! Sase sithelekile ngaphakathi. Sangena maqedane lagcwalaumoya ibhulukwe endodeni. E … ake usisize kanjena-kemnumzane wami: njengamanje phuma uyongena evenini.Uyangizwa ukuthi ngithini lapha kuwe?(usehlahle amehlo, umangele) ngoba kwenzekenjani? Ngizozengingene evenini nje ngoba konakaleni?(ngezwi eliphakeme) Habe! Kanti usabuza wena ekubeni uvele njeunayo impendulo? (athinte kancane isikhwehlela) lalela-kesikutshele thina esizazi kangcono: usuboshiwe!(Useqwebule amehlo) ngize ngiboshwe nje mina bomthethongimangelelwe ngubani?(Ngesankahlu) ungaze ubuze lowo mbuzo ocimeze kanjalo nje,usho ngoba ungaboni njalo wena ukuthi sewenze monakalo muniwena? Lo mame esimfica enhlinhliza lapha futhi ephophozaizinyembezi ebusweni, ngabe uqonde ukusitshela ukuthi kadeeniselwa yinkasa yezivande namasimu?1. Uyavumelana nokuthi kulo mdlalo kukhona umyalezo otholakalaesakhiwaneni othi; Akukho qili lazikhotha emhlane? Sekela impendulouyibhekise kumlingiswa onguHeshane.","answer":"Ngiyavumelana. UHeshane owayesebenza emNyangweni wezaSekhayawayeshadisa abantu ngomgunyathi njengoba enza ubuqili bokushadisauHlengiwe noChivenga, wagcina etholakele wamiswa emsebenzini."},{"question":"How do you implement a list comprehension to produce a list of all possible permutations of a given list of numbers?","answer":"from itertools import permutationsdef list_permutations(lst):    return [list(p) for p in permutations(lst)]numbers = [1, 2, 3]print(list_permutations(numbers))  # Output includes all permutations of [1, 2, 3]"},{"question":"Ọdun to n bọ niṣẹ yoo pari patapata lori atunṣe biriji afara ẹlẹẹkẹta","answer":"Ni bayii ti ijọba apapọ ti pari atunṣe apa kan biriiji afara kẹta, iyẹn Third Mainland Bridge, l’Ekoo, wọn ti ni ko ni i si irinna rara lori biriiji ọhun fun wakati mejidinlogun, bẹrẹ lati aṣaalẹ  Abamẹta, Satide.Oludari fun ileeṣẹ to n ṣatunṣe oju popo nipinlẹ Eko, Ọgbẹni Olukayọde Popoọla, lo kede yii lasiko to ṣabẹwo lori ibi ti wọn ba iṣẹ de.O ni gbogbo eto lo ti pari nipa atunṣe ori afara ọhun si Oworonṣoki. Bẹẹ lo dupẹ lọwọ awọn awakọ gbogbo ti wọn n lo oju popo naa fun suuru wọn.Ni bayii ti wọn ti pari abala akọkọ, o ti sọ pe gbogbo irinṣẹ atawọn panti to le maa dina fun lilọ bibọ ọkọ ni wọn maa ko kuro bayii, ti eto atunṣe yoo si bẹrẹ ni apa keji oju popo afara Third Mainland Bridge naa. O ni wakati mejidinlogun lawọn yoo fi gbe biriiji ọhun ti pa, ti ko ni i si lilọ-bibọ ọkọ rara.Lati Satide, ọjọ Abamẹta, ni wọn ti ti ojuna naa, titi wọ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu kọkanla yii. Ohun ti wọn si n ṣe ni kiko awọn irinṣẹ atawọn panti kuro lojuna, bẹẹ gẹgẹ lo sọ pe awọn yoo ri i pe iṣẹ ọhun pari ki ilẹ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, too mọ, nigba ti awọn awakọ yoo lanfaani lati maa lo apa kan ọna ọhun pada fun lilọ-bibọ wọn.Popoọla sọ pe gbogbo awọn akiyesi lati ya soju popo mi-in naa ni yoo wa bo ti ṣe wa tẹlẹ, ati pe iṣẹ ti a fẹẹ ṣe bayii lati biriji Adekunle si Adeniji Adele Phase B, nigboro Eko.Ọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu kọkanla yii, ni iṣẹ ọhun yoo bẹrẹ, ti yoo si pari lọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu keji, ọdun 2021.Ohun ti eyi tumọ si ni pe, oṣu mẹta gbako ni wọn yoo fi gbe apa kan biriji ọhun ti pa, lati Adekunle si Adeniji-Adele, ti atunṣe iṣẹ yoo maa lọ nibẹ."},{"question":"Maxay ka koobanyihiin tilmaamaha iimaanku?","answer":"Tilmaamaha iimaanku waxay ka kooban yihiin saddex walxood (wax ama shay) oo kala ah:1) Rumayn qalbiga ah. 2) Qiritaan afka ah.3) Iyo ku dhaqmid."},{"question":"他的儿子阿洛卡·莱亚纳奇与演员萨姆亚·莱亚纳奇和英德拉卡帕·莱亚纳奇的女儿结婚, 他的儿子阿洛卡·莱亚纳奇与演员杰克逊·安东尼的女儿结婚, 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":" Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa qofkii ugu horeeyey ee qora Bismillaahi Raxmaanil Raxiim.","answer":" Wuxu ahaa Nabi Suleymaan Cs."},{"question":"Які існують спадкові хвороби нуклеїнових кислот?","answer":"До групи хвороб нуклеїнових кислот входить декілька добре вивчених хвороб. Особливості цих дефектів можна спостерігати на прикладі синдрому Леша-Наяна. Синдром зустрічається рідко (1:300,000 новонароджених) і успадковується зазчепленим рецесивним типом. Хвороба розвивається у грудному віці, проявляється м'язовим гіпертонусом, підвищеною рефлекторною збудливістю, олігофренією, імпульсивною схильністю дитини до самопошкоджень. Виділяють також атипову форму дорослих, що проявляється симптомами подагри.Первинний дефект: це нестача ензиму гіпоксантин-фосфорибозилтрансферази (ГФРТ), необхідного для синтезу ДНК. Він каталізує перетворення вільних пуринових основ - гуаніну і гіпоксантину - до нуклеотидів. При нестачі цього ферменту кінцевим продуктом розпаду основ є сечова кислота. Високий вміст її солей призводить до формування уратів і розвитку нирковокам'яної хвороби.Фермент ГФРТ знаходиться в усіх соматичних клітинах. Тому можлива точна діагностика шляхом визначення його активності в клітинах. На практиці для цього використовують культивовані фіброблас- ти шкіри, а при пренатальній діагностиці - амнїстичні клітини. Виявлення активності ферменту в культивованих клітинах дозволяє, шляхом сумісного культивування клітин від різних хворих, диференціювати генетично різні форми у випадку метаболічного кооперування (часткового поновлення активності ГФРТ у клітинах хворих)."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Miaina tsy misy fitiavana toy ny _ tsy misy fofona\\"","answer":" Miaina tsy misy fitiavana toy ny vonikazo tsy misy fofona"},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Nhưng vế còn lại khó tốt cho hoàn cảnh của Bùi Tiến Dũng ở CLB TPHCM. Có câu nhập gia tuỳ tục. Nếu bạn muốn khác biệt so với phần còn lại thì cần phải giỏi và chứng tỏ được tài năng trên sân bóng. Cả hai thứ đó thì Bùi Tiến Dũng đều chưa có ở CLB TPHCM. Anh bắt chính 3 trận liên tiếp, mắc hai sai lầm dẫn đến bàn thua và TPHCM nhận 3 thất bại. Lấy một ví dụ cụ thể, Lee Nguyễn - ngôi sao lớn nhất từng thi đấu cho TPHCM vào năm ngoái. Lee Nguyễn rất nổi tiếng, giàu có với mức phí lên đến 1 triệu USD/năm. Nhưng anh về Việt Nam thi đấu thì chọn cách đi xe máy đến sân bóng. Câu chuyện của Lee Nguyễn đáng để suy ngẫm nếu so với chính anh trong quá khứ. Lee Nguyễn là ai? Anh là ông hoàng ăn chơi ở V.League, là cầu thủ từng dính tin đồn hẹn hò với những chân dài đình đám nhất thời đó như Pha Lê, Trúc Diễm… Hơn 10 năm trước, Lee Nguyễn đúng","answer":"nghĩa \\"một vị vua\\" bao gồm về tiền bạc, tài năng và sự nổi tiếng. Mức phí để Lee Nguyễn về HAGL lớn đến mức anh không thể từ chối, tiền lương cao ngất ngưởng. Từ một ông hoàng ăn chơi, Lee Nguyễn bình dị với hình ảnh đi xe máy đến sân tập. Nó phản ánh rằng, sau nhiều năm qua thì Lee Nguyễn đã đúc kết được những thăng trầm trong sự nghiệp cầu thủ, biết cách trân trọng sự nỗ lực của bản thân trên sân cỏ. Anh hiểu được sự hà khắc của môn thể thao vua. Vì tạo ra khoảng cách với tập thể thì Lee Nguyễn sẽ khó thành công. Với Bùi Tiến Dũng, anh thành công sớm và gặt hái được tiền bạc. Sự đãi ngộ ở CLB TPHCM cho anh cũng cao nhất nhì đội, khi mức kinh phí ba năm vào khoảng 10 tỷ, bao gồm tiền lót tay, tiền lương và thưởng. Sự ngộ đãi cao ngất ngưởng thì Bùi Tiến Dũng lúc nào cũng phải thi đấu với tư cách của một kẻ dẫn đầu toàn đội. Nhưng nghịch lý là anh chỉ dự bị và mỗi lần vào sân lại mắc sai lầm dẫn đến bàn thua. Ba năm ở TPHCM, Bùi Tiến Dũng không để lại giá trị về chuyên môn, chỉ có sự khác biệt về hình ảnh một ngôi sao thường đi siêu xe đến sân tập, hay nổi bật với những câu chuyện ngoài sân cỏ. Trong bóng đá, ngôi sao phải thể hiện thái độ tích cực và giá trị chuyên môn, không phải ngồi ngoài sân theo kiểu đình công hay khoác lên vẻ hào nhoáng so với phần còn lại. Nếu chưa tốt về chuyên môn thì hình ảnh bên lề chỉ là \\"chiếc áo quá khổ\\" để tạo thêm áp lực cho cầu thủ. Theo Team Thể Thao (Saostar.vn) https://saostar.vn/sao-sport/nghich-ly-thu-mon-bui-tien-dung-roi-san-bang-sieu-xe-lieu-co-dep-202207311215475438.html Trang Thông tin điện tử Docbao.vn Công ty Cổ phần Quang Minh Việt Nam Giấy phép thiết lập Trang thông tin điện tử tổng hợp trên Internet số 2372/GP-STTTT cấp ngày 29/8/2014. SĐT: 024. 666.40816 Địa chỉ: P604, Tầng 6, Tòa nhà Golden Field, Khu đô thị mới Mỹ Đình 1, phường Cầu Diễn, quận Nam Từ Liêm, Hà Nội Chịu trách nhiệm nội dung: Điều Thị Bích; ĐT: 0903.263.198; Email: docbao@kib.vn Đọc báo trực tuyến hiện tại chỉ sử dụng tên miền duy nhất là docbao.vn; độc giả lưu ý tránh nhầm lẫn. Chính sách bảo mật RSS"},{"question":"Inona no loko ampiasaina matetika mba hanehoana ny maoderina sy ny teknolojia?a) volondaveninab) lokom-bolamenad) lokom-bolafotsye) volomparasy","answer":"d) lokom-bolafotsy no loko ampiasaina matetika mba hanehoana ny maoderina sy ny teknolojia"},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Czy Johannesburg jest stolicą RPA?","answer":"Oto odpowiedź. Nie, Johannesburg nie jest stolicą RPA, lecz jego najludniejszym miastem. Aglomeracja Johannesburga liczy 8 000 000 mieszkańców, co czyni ją jedną z najbardziej zaludnionych na świecie."},{"question":"ለሚከተለው ጽሁፍ ርዕስ ይፍጠሩ: nቤዛዊት በዕድሜ የገፉ እናቷ የደም መርጋት በሽታ ያሰቃያቸዋል፡፡ በጤና እንዲቆዩ ሪቫሮክሳባን የሚባል መድኃኒት ሳያቋርጡ መውሰድ ነበረባቸው፡፡ ይህ መድኃኒት እየተገባደደ ሲመጣ ቤዛዊት እንደተለመደው ለመግዛት ወጣች፡፡ ወትሮ በቀላሉ ታገኘው የነበረው ሪቫሮክሳባን ከየት ይምጣ፡፡ ዮሐንስ-አራት መንታ-ሰባራ ባቡር አካባቢ ይገኛል አሏት፡፡ አልሆነም፡፡ ቀይ መስቀል ሞክሪ ተባለች፡፡ አልሆነም፡፡ ከነማ ተሰለፈች፡፡ አልሆነም፡፡ ወጣች ወረደች፡፡ ጠዋት ወጥታ፣ ማታ ገባች፡፡ አልሆነም፡፡ የመድኃኒት ደላሎችን ሳይቀር ተማጸነች፡፡ ከየትም ሊገኝ አልቻለም፡፡ መድኃኒቱ ግን የት ገባ? ምንም አማራጭ አልነበራት፤ አውስትራሊያ የሚገኝ የሩቅ ዘመድ ማስቸገር የግድ ሆነ፡፡ ለካንስ መድኃኒት ከውጭም ቢሆን ለማስገባት ቀላል አልነበረም፡፡ ዲኤችኤል፣ ፌዴክስ እና ሌሎች የጥቅል ዕቃ ተላላኪ ኩባንያዎች፣ በነርሱ በኩል መድኃኒት ለማስላክ ከመድኃኒት ቁጥጥር ባለሥልጣን ደብዳቤ ይፈልጋሉ፡፡ ሌላ መከራ፡፡ ሌላ ስቃይ፡፡ ቀን እየገፋ ሲመጣ ቤዛዊት ተጨነቀች፡፡ ምክንያቱም መድኃኒቱ ከተገባደደ እናቷ ችግር ውስጥ ይወድቃሉ፡፡ መፍጠን አለባት፡፡ በመጨረሻ በሰው በሰው፣ ከብዙ የስልክ ልውውጦች በኋላ፣ ከብዙ ተማጽኖ በኋላ፣ ከኬንያ ወደ ኢትዮጵያ እየበረረች በነበረች አንዲት በጎ ፈቃደኛ በኩል መድኃኒቱ ደረሰላት፡፡ የእናቷን ሕይወትም ታደገች፡፡ ይህ የመድኃኒት ፍለጋ እሽክርክሪት የቤዛዊት ብቻ አይደለም፡፡ በርካቶች በየቀኑ ይኖሩታል፡፡ የሚሰወሩት መድኃኒቶች በተለይ ከቅርብ ጊዜ ወዲህ ከውጭ ምንዛሬ መመናመን ጋር ተያይዞ መድኃኒቶች ድንገት ይሰውሩ ይዘዋል፡፡ መንግሥት ለምግብና መድኃኒት የውጭ ምንዛሬን አይሰስትም፡፡ ኾኖም ግን ይህ መድኃኒቶች እንደልብ እንዲገኙ አላስቻለም፡፡ ደላሎች ደብቀው አስወድደው ይሸጧቸዋል ይባላል፡፡ የጨነቀው ቤተሰብ የትኛውንም ዋጋ ከፍሎ እንደሚገዛቸው ያውቃሉ፡፡ በሰው ችግር ያተርፋሉ፡፡ አሁን አሁን የጠፉ መድኃኒቶች ብቻ አይደሉም፣ የሚገኙትም የት እንደሚገኙ ማወቅ ጊዜና ጉልበትን ይጠይቃል፡፡ በአዲስ አበባ ሺህ ፋርማሲዎች አሉ፡፡ የሚፈልጉት መድኃኒት ወይ ቦሌ ወይም ጉለሌ አንድ ፋርማሲ መደርደሪያ ላይ ቁጭ ብሎ ሊሆን ይችላል፡፡ ነገር ግን ሁሉን ፋርማሲ አዳርሶ ይሆናል እንዴ? በዚህ ሕዝብ ጤፍ በሆነበት ከተማ ከጦር ኃይሎች-ሲኤምሲ፣ ከቦሌ-ሸጎሌ ለመድረስ ግማሽ ቀን አይበቃም፡፡ ይህን ችግር መነሻ አድርጎ ታዲያ አንድ የጤና ድርጅት መፍትሄ ፍለጋ ተነሳ፡፡ መድኃኒቶችን የሚያፈላልግ ድረ ገጽ ፀነሰ፡፡ ድረ ገጹ የስልክ መተግበሪያን ወለደ፡፡ የስልክ መተግበሪያው የጥሪ ማዕከልን ፈጠረ፡፡ ለምን ሁሉንም መድኃኒቶች ወደ አንድ ቋት አስገብተን የሕዝብን እንግልት አንታደግም ያለው ይህ ድርጅት ማን ነው? የመድኃኒት ዝርዝሮችን በስልክ ‹‹ጤናዎ›› የሞባይል መተግበሪያ የጤና ጥበቃ ከፍተኛ ተጠሪ በተገኙበት በሸራተን አዲስ የተመረቀው ከወራት በፊት ነበር፡፡ ኬ.ኤም.ኤስ ሄልዝ ትሬዲንግ ይባላል ድርጅቱ፡፡ ባለአክሲዮኖቹ በኢትዮጵያ፣ ካናዳ፣ እንግሊዝና አሜሪካ የሚገኙ ትውልደ ኢትዮያዊያን ናቸው፡፡ ገሚሶቹ የድርጅቱ መሥራቾች ታዲያ አገር ቤት በዚሁ የጤና ዘርፍ የተሠማሩ ባለሙያዎች መሆናቸው ለዚህ ትርምስምሱ ለወጣ የጤና ሥርዓት መፍትሄ እንዲሹ ሳይገፋፋቸው አልቀረም፡፡ ይህም ካለፉበትና በየቀኑ ከሚያስተውሉት ችግር ተነስተው ለማኅበረሰብ መፍትሄ ለመስጠት አግዟቸዋል፡፡ የዚህ ሐሳብ አፍላቂና የድርጅቱ መሥራች ዶ/ር ሲሳይ አበበ፣ በሠሩባቸው ሐኪም ቤቶች ሁሉ በተደጋጋሚ አንድ ነገር አስተዋሉ፡፡ ‹‹ታማሚዎች ተመልሰው መጥተው ያዘዝኩላቸውን መድኃኒት ማግኘት እንዳልቻሉ  ይነግሩኝ ነበር›› ይላሉ፡፡ ይህ ሁኔታ መደጋገሙ ታዲያ ዶ/ር ሲሳይ የመተግበሪያውን ሐሳብ እንዲያብሰለስሉ ምክንያት ሆናቸው፡፡ ለመሆኑ የጤናዎ መተግበሪያ ተግባር ምንድነው? በአጭሩ ለማስቀመጥ ደንበኛው የሚፈልገው መድኃኒት የት እንዳለ ይጠቁመዋል፡፡ ይህን የሚያደርገው በስልክ መተግበሪያ በመጠቀም ነው፡፡ መተግበሪያው አሠራሩ ከነ ኡበር፣ ራይድ ወዘተ የታክሲ ማሰሻ መተግበሪያዎች ጋር ተመሳሳይ ይመስላል፡፡ መጀመርያ ለደንበኛው፣ ካለበት በ500 ሜትር ራዲየስ ያሉ መድኃኒት ቤቶችን ያሳየዋል፡፡ ወይም ደግሞ መድኃኒት ፈላጊዋ ካለችበት ሆና በከተማው ያሉ መድኃኒት ቤቶቹን እያማረጠች በመተግበሪያው በምናብ ፋርማሲዎች ውስጥ ትዘልቃለች፡፡ የመድኃኒት ዝርዝራቸውን መመልከት ትችላለች፡፡ የምትፈልገው መድኃኒት መኖሩን ስታረጋግጥ ደግሞ ዋጋቸውን ማመሳከር ይቻላታል፡፡ ይህ ነው ‹‹የጤናዎ የስልክ መተግበሪያ›› ተግባር፡፡ ይህ መተግበሪያ በከፊል ሥራ ጀምሯል፡፡ የመረጃ ቋቱን ብዛትና ጥራት ከጊዜ ወደ ጊዜ እያሳደገ ነው፡፡ ‹‹የተገልጋዩን ጊዜ፣ ጉልበትና ገንዘብ ከብክነት መታደግ ነው ቀዳሚው ፍላጎታችን›› ይላሉ ዶ/ር ሲሳይ አበበ፡፡ ዶ/ር ሲሳይ የኬ.ኤም.ሲ ሄልዝ ዋና ሥራ አስፈጻሚ ናቸው፡፡ ጤናዎ መተግበሪያ ታዲያ በስልክ ብቻ የሚገኝ አገልግሎት አይደለም፡፡ ዘመናዊ ስልክ ላልታደሉና ከቴክኖሎጂ ላልተዋወቁ የማኅበረሰብ ክፍሎች ሌላ አማራጭ አለው፡፡ 24 ሰዓት አገልግሎት የሚሰጥ 9456 የጥሪ ማዕከል፡፡ ሐኪምና ታካሚን ማገናኘት የጤናዎ መተግበሪያ ዋናው ተግባሩ የትኞቹ መድኃኒቶች በየትኛው ፋርማሲ ውስጥ ይገኛሉ የሚለውን መጠቆም ይሁን እንጂ ሌሎች ተጓዳኝ አገልግሎቶችም አሉት፡፡ ለምሳሌ በግል ጤና ጣቢያ ለመታከም የሚፈልግ ተገልጋይ የት ሆስፒታል ማን የሚባል ስፔሻሊስት መቼ እንደሚገኝ ማወቅ ቢፈልግ ይህን መረጃ ከዚሁ ማግኘት ይችላል፡፡ በዚህ መተግበሪያ ውስጥ 80  የሚሆኑ ሐኪሞች፣ በተለያየ ስፔሻላይዜሽን ያሉ፣ ማንነታቸውና የሥራ ልምዳቸው ተካቷል፡፡ በቀጣይ ዓመታትም በርካታ ሐኪሞች የዚሁ መተግበሪያ አባል ይሆናሉ ተብሎ ይጠበቃል፡፡ ይህ ማለት አንድ ታካሚ ሐኪሙን ከተገቢ ምክር ጋር የመምረጥ፣ ካለበት ሆኖ ቀጠሮ የማስያዝ ዕድልን ይሰጠዋል፡፡ ዶ/ር ሲሳይ እንደሚሉት በአሁኑ ጊዜ ድርጅታቸው በየትኛውም የግል ሆስፒታል የታካሚና የሐኪም ቀጠሮን የማስያዝ ተጨማሪ ሥራን ይሠራል፡፡ ‹‹ታካሚዎች የትኛውን ሐኪም፣ መቼ፣ የት ክሊኒክ ማግኘት እንደሚችሉ ማማከር ብቻ ሳይሆን ቀጠሮም እንይዝላቸዋለን፡፡ በሆስፒታል እየሄዱ ወረፋ መያዝ፣ መንገላታትን ለማስቀረት ነው እየሞከርን ያለነው›› ይላሉ፡፡ አገር ውስጥ የሌሉ መድኃኒቶችን ፍለጋ በቀድሞ ጊዜ የምሽት ተረኛ መድኃኒት ቤቶች በየቀኑ በብሔራዊ ራዲዮ ይነገሩ ነበር፡፡ ልክ ዛሬ የአየር ትንበያና ስፖርት ዘገባዎች ከዜና በኋላ እንደሚታወጁት ሁሉ፡፡ ዛሬ ይህ ነገር መኖሩን እንጃ፡፡ ዜጎች አጣዳፊ የመድኃኒት ጥያቄ ቢገጥማቸው እንግልታቸውን ለማስቀረት ያለመ ነበር ነገሩ፡፡ ያን ጊዜ ጥቂት ፋርማሲዎች ነበር በከተማው የነበሩት፡፡ አሁን መድኃኒት ቤቶች እንደ አሸን በፈሉበት ዘመን፣ ኮንዶሚንየም ግቢ ድረስ ዘልቀው የነዋሪዎች ጎረቤት መሆን በቻሉበት ዘመን ነገሩ ያን ያህልም አልተቃለለም፡፡ ለምን? መድኃኒት ቤቶችን እንጂ መድኃኒቶችን ማግኘት አልተቻለም፡፡ ይህ ሀቅ የጤናዎ መተግበሪያ ፈጣሪዎችም የሚክዱት አይደለም፡፡ በቂ መድኃኒቶች በሌሉበት ፋርማሲ መጠቆም ምን ይፈይዳል? በገበያ የሚገኙት መድኃኒት ቤቶችማ ወትሮም የትም የሚገኙ ናቸው፡፡ የማይገኙት ደግሞ የትም አይገኙም፡፡ ዶ/ር ሲሳይ ይህን ሁኔታ ድርጅታቸው እንደሚረዳ ለቢቢሲ አስረድተው ለዚህም ሲባል መድኃኒት ከውጭ የማስመጣት ፍቃድ መውሰዳቸውን አብራርተዋል፡፡ ለጊዜው ሰዎች ከገበያ ያጧቸውን መድኃኒቶች በተናጥል ጥያቄ ሲያቀርቡልን ከውጭ ለማስመጣት ዝግጅት ጨርሰናል ይላሉ፡፡ ዶ/ር ሲሳይ እንደሚሉት ታዲያ የጤና ድርጅቱ ሥራ በመድኃኒት አድራሻና ዋጋ ጥቆማ የሚቆም አይደለም፡፡ ለምሳሌ ኤምአርአይ ወይም ሌላ የኢሜጂንግ ወይም የላቦራቶሪ አገልግሎት የሚፈልግ ደንበኛ በአቅራቢያው ይህን አገልግሎት የሚሰጥ ተቋም ስለመኖር አለመኖሩ፣ የዋጋ ዝርዝሩን እና ለአገልግሎቱ የሚጠየቀውን ተያያዥ መረጃ ሁሉ አቀናጅቶ አስቀድሞ መረጃ የማቀበል ተግባርም በመስጠት ላይ ናቸው፡፡ በጤና ሚኒስቴር የኢንፎርሜሽን ቴክኖሎጂ ዳይሬክቶሬት ዳይሬክተር አቶ ገመቺስ መልካሙ ይህ አዲስ የጤና መተግበሪያ የተገልጋይ እንግልትን፣ ጊዜና ጉልበትን በመቆጠብ ሁነኛ ሚና እንደሚጫወት መተግበሪያው በተመረቀበት ሥነ ሥርዓት ላይ ተገኝተው አድናቆታቸውን ገልጠው ነበር፡፡ ይህ መተግበሪያ፣ የጥሪ ማዕከልና የጤና ድረ ገጽ ኅብረተሰብን በማገዝ ረገድ ሁነኛ ሚና ስላለው መሥሪያ ቤታቸው አስፈላጊውን ትብብር ሁሉ እንደሚያደርግም ቃል ገብተዋል፡፡ ከዚህ ቀደም ብቅ ጥልቅ እያሉም ቢሆን የጤና ዘርፉን ለማዘመን የተሞከሩ ሙከራዎች እንደነበሩ የጠቀሱት ዶ/ር ሲሳይ በበኩላቸው ጤናዎ መተግበሪያ አስተማማኝና ዘላቂ አገልግሎት ለመስጠት ከሐኪሞችና ከጤና ተቋማት ጋር መጠነ ሰፊ ግንኙነት መፍጠሩንና፣ በእስካሁኑ አጭር ተሞክሮም ተስፋ ሰጪ ሁኔታዎች እንዳዩም ለቢቢሲ ተናግረዋል፡፡ የዚህ አገልግሎት ልዩ ባህሪም የግል ዘርፉን የጤና አገልግሎት በአንድ ጥላ ጠቅልሎ መያዙ እንደሆነ ያስረዳሉ፡፡ ይህም ማለት ሐኪም ቀጠሮ ከማስያዝ ጀምሮ እስከ መድኃኒት ዋጋ ድረስ ዲጂታል በሆነ አሠራር ቀላል ማድረግን፣ በዚህም የጤና ሥርዓቱን ማዘመንን ያካተተ ነው፡፡ የዲጂታል ነገር፣ እስኪዘልቅና ዘላቂነቱ ከቅርብ ጊዜ ወዲህ አዳዲስ ይበል የሚያሰኙ ሐሳቦች ይመነጫሉ፡፡ ወዲያው ይከስማሉ፡፡ አንዱ ምክንያት የኅብረተሰቡ ለውጡን ለመቀበል ዳተኛ መሆን ነው፡፡ ወደ ሕዝብ አይዘልቁም፡፡ ቢዘልቁም ዘላቂነት አይኖራቸውም፡፡ በዚህ ረገድ ጤናዎ መተግበሪያ የት ርቀት ይሄድ ይሆን? ዶ/ር ሲሳይ አንዱ ፈተና ይኸው መሆኑን አውስተዋል፡፡ ወደ ዲጂታል ሄልዝ ለመሸጋገር ለብዙ ሰዎች ቀላል እንዳልሆነ በዚህ አጭር ቆይታ ራሱ የተረዱት ዶ/ር ሲሳይ፣ ድርጅታቸው ታዲያ ሕዝቡን ከአግልግሎቱ ጋር በቀላሉ ለማስተዋወቅ በማሰብ ለጊዜው ማንኛውንም ክፍያ አየጠየቁ አለመሆኑን አብራርተዋል፡፡ ‹‹ለጊዜው  ከመቶ በላይ መድኃኒት ቤቶች ከኛ ጋር ለመሥራት ተመዝግበዋል፡፡ እነዚህ መድኃኒት ቤቶች አዲስ መድኃኒት ሲያስገቡም ሆነ ነባር መድኃኒቶችን ሽጠው ሲጨርሱ በኛ ሲስተም እየገቡ አሁናዊ መረጃን ለኅብረተሰቡ ያቀብላሉ፡፡ ሌሎችንም ለማሳመን እየሞከርን ነው››  ይላሉ ዶ/ር ሲሳይ፡፡ በኢትዮጵያ ከ60 ሚሊዮን የሚልቅ ሞባይል ተጠቃሚ ቢኖርም፣ የኢንተርኔት ተደራሽነቱና ዘመናዊ ስልክ ተጠቃሚው ቁጥር የዚህ ሲሶውን እንኳ አይሞላም፡፡ እርግጥ በአሁን ዘመን ብዙ አገልግሎቶች ወደ ሞባይል እየገቡ ነው፡፡ ገንዘብ ዝውውርም ከወረቀት ወደ ሞባይል እየተሸጋገረ ነው፡፡ ይሁንና የሕዝብን እምነት ማግኘት በቀላል የሚገኝ እሴት አይደለም፡፡ ዶ/ር ሲሳይም ይህን አይክዱም፤ ‹‹ወደ ዲጂታል ሽግግር ጉዞው ቀላል እንደማይሆን አውቀን ነው የተነሳነው፤ በኛ አገር ዲጂታል ቴክኖሎጂ ገና እያደገ ነው፡፡ ሰዎች እምነት ገና አላዳበሩም፡፡ ይህ ነገር ጊዜ ሊወስድ ይችላል›› ብለዋል፡፡ ይህን ለማገዝም ነው የሚመሩት ድርጅት ለሁሉም አገልግሎቶቻቸው ለጊዜው ክፍያን ላለመጠየቅ የወሰነው፡፡ ፈውስን ፍለጋ ወጥቶ በሽታን መሸመት ወደ ዲጂታል ዓለም ለመግባት እዚያ እዚህም የሚታዩት ሙከራዎች ከብዙ በጥቂቱ ይሁንታን ያገኛሉ፡፡ በኢትዮጵያ ካየነው ሁሉ ለጊዜው በትራንስፖርት ዘርፍ የሰመረ ይመስላል፡፡ በፋይናንስ ዘርፍም ከቅርብ ጊዜ ወዲህ ተስፋ ሰጪ ምልክቶች ታይተዋል፡፡ በጤና ዘርፍ ግን እምብዛም አይደለም፡፡ እርግጥ የሰዎች የጤና ሰነድ ከገንዘብም በላይ ከለላን ይሻል፡፡ ደኅንነቱ የተጠበቀ የመረጃ አያያዝን መከተል ይፈልጋል፡፡ በዚህ ረገድ ብዙ ከተሠራ ከብዙ ትዕግስት ጋር ወደፊት መንፏቀቅ ይቻል ይሆናል፡፡ በተለይ የኅብረተሰብን ችግር ለመፍታት ያለሙ፣ መፍትሄ ላይ መሠረት ያደረጉ መተግበሪያዎች ሲሳኩም የዛኑ ያህል ሕይወት ዘዋሪ ናቸው፡፡ የኬ.ኤም.ኤስ ሄልዝ ዋና ሥራ አስኪያጅ ዶ/ር ሲሳይ አበበ ደጋግመው እንደሚሉት፣ ሰዎች ፈውስ ፍለጋ ወጥተው፣ በሽታን ሸምተው መመለስ የለባቸውም፡፡ ‹‹ጤናዎ ሁለገብ መተግበሪያ›› የጤናው ዘርፍ ዲጂታል ሽግግር ረዥሙ ጉዞ አንድ እርምጃ ይሆን?","answer":"በእርግጥ፣ ለተሰጠው ጽሑፍ ርዕስ ይኸውና - በኢትዮጵያ የጠፋ መድኃኒት የሚያፈላልገው መተግበሪያ"},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:التعايش بأماناعتبارا من عام 2019، صار ربع أنواع الثدييات غير الأليفة في العالم مهددة بالانقراض، وفقا للقائمة الحمراء، وهي لائحة تدرس وتصنف حالة حفظ الأنواع النباتية والحيوانية التي يصدرها الاتحاد العالمي لحفظ الطبيعة.في حين أن التحضر والنشاط البشري قد قللا","answer":"بالتأكيد، في حين أن التحضر والنشاط البشري قد قللا من تنوع الحيوانات على الأرض، فقد أصبحت بعض الأنواع وفيرة للغاية، وهذه هي الأنواع التي تتكيف بشكل جيد مع السلوك البشري، مثل الفئران."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ በ ሀመስ ውስጥ ዋናው ንጥረ ነገር ምንድን ነው? መልስ፦ ","answer":"ሽምብራ"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਚਾਰੇ ਕੁੰਡਾ ਦੇਖਿ ਅੰਦਰੁ ਭਾਲਿਆ ॥ਸਚੈ ਪੁਰਖਿ ਅਲਖਿ ਸਿਰਜਿ ਨਿਹਾਲਿਆ ॥ਉਝੜਿ ਭੁਲੇ ਰਾਹ ਗੁਰਿ ਵੇਖਾਲਿਆ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਸਚੇ ਵਾਹੁ ਸਚੁ ਸਮਾਲਿਆ ॥ਪਾਇਆ ਰਤਨੁ ਘਰਾਹੁ ਦੀਵਾ ਬਾਲਿਆ ॥ਸਚੈ ਸਬਦਿ ਸਲਾਹਿ ਸੁਖੀਏ ਸਚ ਵਾਲਿਆ ॥ਨਿਡਰਿਆ ਡਰੁ ਲਗਿ ਗਰਬਿ ਸਿ ਗਾਲਿਆ ॥ਨਾਵਹੁ ਭੁਲਾ ਜਗੁ ਫਿਰੈ ਬੇਤਾਲਿਆ ॥੨੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 149 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਚਾਰੇ ਤਰਫਾਂ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ (ਭਾਵ, ਬਾਹਰ ਚਵੀਂ ਪਾਸੀਂ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ) ਆਪਣਾ ਅੰਦਰ ਭਾਲਦਾ ਹੈ(ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਦਿੱਸ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਸੱਚੇ ਅਲੱਖ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਨੇ (ਜਗਤ) ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਸੰਭਾਲ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ) ।ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਭਟਕ ਰਹੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਰਸਤਾ ਦਿਖਾਇਆ ਹੈ (ਰਾਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਵਿਖਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ),ਸੱਚੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਾਬਾਸ਼ੇ ਹੈ (ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਸੱਚੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਗਿਆਨ ਦਾ) ਦੀਵਾ ਜਗਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਹੀ (ਨਾਮ-) ਰਤਨ ਲੱਭ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ ।(ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਰਨ ਆ ਕੇ) ਸੱਚੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਸੁਖੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਖਸਮ ਵਾਲੇ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।(ਪਰ) ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਡਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਹੋਰ) ਡਰ ਮਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਪਏ ਗਲਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਭੁੱਲਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਗਤ ਬੇ-ਤਾਲ (ਬੇ ਥਵ੍ਹਾ) ਫਿਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨੪।\\""},{"question":"Akẹkọọ bii ọgọrun-un daku nileewe ijọba n’Ijero-Ekiti","answer":"Nnkan daru patapata nileewe ti wọn ti n kọ nipa eto ilera nipinlẹ Ekiti, iyẹn College of Health and Technology, nigba ti bii ọgọrun-un awọn akẹkọọ ileewe naa daku lọ gbọnrangandan l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, nitori oorun kẹmika ti wọn fin sileewe naa ti awọn akẹkọọ ohun fa simu. Eyi lo mu ki awọn akẹkọọ naa bẹrẹ ija, ti wọn si ba ọpọ nnkan jẹ nileewe naa.ALAROYE gbọ pe iṣẹlẹ naa waye nigba ti ileeṣẹ panapana waa fin ọgba ileewe naa.Lasiko ti awọn akẹkọọ naa jokoo lati ṣedanwo ni wọn ri i pe niṣe ni bii ọgọrun ninu wọn ti daku lọ, oju-ẹsẹ ni wọn si sare gbe wọn lọ si ọsibitu ijọba to wa ni Ijereo-Ekiti. A gbọ pe ọpọ awọn akẹkọọ tiṣẹlẹ naa ṣẹlẹ si ni wọn ni aisan seeemi-seeemi ti awọn oloyinbo n pe ni (Athsma), eyi to lewu fun iru ẹni to ba ni aisan bẹẹ lati fa awọn kẹmika tabi oorun to ba ti le ju simu.Oorun yii lawọn akẹkọọ naa fa simu to ṣakoba fun ilera wọn.Ibinu ni iṣẹlẹ naa lawọn akẹkọọ yooku fi ya lọ si ọọfiisi awọn alaṣẹ ileewe naa, ti wọn si beere ohun to fa wahala naa. Wọn ko tiẹ duro gbesi ti wọn fi bẹrẹ si i ba oriṣiiriṣii nnkan jẹ nileewe naa. Bi wọn ṣe n ba awọn yara ikẹkọọ jẹ ni wọn n ba mọto atawọn nnkan olowo iyebiye mi-in jẹ, o si pẹ diẹ ki wọn too pana wahala naa.Kọmiṣanna fun eto ẹkọ nipinlẹ Ekiti, Dokita Banji Filani, fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ, o ni loootọ ni iṣẹlẹ naa waye, ṣugbọn awọn ti ṣe amojuto to yẹ, alaafia si ti n pada sileewe naa. Kọmiṣanna ni awọn akẹkọọ bii mẹrinlelọgọta ni wọn ti gbadun, ti wọn ti pada sile, beẹ ni awọn mẹrinlelọgbọn ṣi wa ni ibi ti wọn ti n gba itọju. O fi kun un pe awọn ti pe awọn eleto ilera mọra lati le fun awọn akẹkọọ naa ni itọju to peye.Nigba to n ṣalaye bi iṣẹlẹ naa ṣe ṣẹlẹ, Filani ni ọga ileewe naa pe oun lati ṣalaye pe awọn ileeṣẹ pana pana fẹẹ wa fi kẹmika si ileewe naa. Wọn si wa loooto, wọn waa fin in. Afi bi wọn ṣe fin in tan ti wahala ṣẹlẹ. Oorun kẹmika naa lo gbodi lara awọn akẹkọọ kan ti wọn fi daku, ti aọn si sare gbe wọn lọ si osibitu ijọba to wa ni Ijero-Ekiti.O fi kun un pe wọn ti mu diẹ ninu awọn oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ panapana to waa fin kẹmika naa lati wadii ọrọ lẹnu wọn. Bẹẹ lo sọ pe ara awọn akẹkọọ naa ti n ya, ki awọn araalu fọkan balẹ."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي بنى سفينة؟","answer":"الجواب: نوح عليه السلام."},{"question":"اذكر ثلاث مواقع شهيرة للسوشيال ميديا. ","answer":"جوجل، فيسبوك، يوتيوب."},{"question":"கேள்வி : காய்கறி செடிகளில் பூச்சிக்கொல்லி மருந்துகளை பயன்படுத்துவதால் என்ன தீமைகள் விளையும்?","answer":"பதில் :முன்பெல்லாம், அறுவது, எழுவது வயதை தாண்டினால் தான் கண் பார்வை குறைபாடு ஏற்படும். ஆனால், இன்றோ ஐந்து வயது, பத்து வயது குழந்தைகளே போதிய ஊட்டச்சத்து இன்றி பார்வைக் குறைபாடினால் பாதிக்கப்படுகின்றனர். பூச்சிக்கொல்லி அடிக்கப்பட்டு தயாரிக்கப்படும், பாதுகாக்கப்படும் உணவுகளை கர்ப்பிணி பெண்கள் சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால், அது கருவை பாதிக்கும் என்றும். இதனால்,  கருவில் வளரும் குழந்தைக்கு குறைபாடுகள் ஏற்படும் அபாயம் இருப்பதாகவும் கூறப்படுகிறது.தொடர்ந்து நெடுங்காலமாக பூச்சிக்கொல்லி அடிக்கப்பட்ட உணவுப் பொருள்களை உட்கொண்டு வந்தால், நினைவாற்றல் குறைபாடு, மூளையின் செயல்திறன் குறைபாடு, மூளையில் சேதம் ஏற்படுதல் போன்றவை ஏற்பட வாய்ப்புகள் அதிகம் இருக்கின்றன.கீரை வகைகள், உருளைக்கிழங்கு, கேரட், வெள்ளரிகள், பச்சை பீன்ஸ், காலிபிளவர், தக்காளி, சர்க்கரைவள்ளி, கத்திரிக்காய், ப்ராக்கோலி, காளான் மற்றும் குளிர்காலத்தில் ஸ்குவாஷ் போன்ற அன்றாடம் பயன்படுத்தும் உணவுகளில் தான் அதிகம் பூச்சிக்கொல்லி பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. பூச்சிக்கொல்லிகள் அடிக்கப்படாத ஆர்கானிக் காய்கறிகள் தான் உங்கள் உடல் நலத்திற்கு மிகவும் நல்லது. முக்கியமாக குழந்தைகளுக்கு. எனவே, முடிந்தவரை காய்கறிகள் வாங்கும் போது, உழவர் சந்தை போன்ற இடங்களில் சென்று வாங்குங்கள். கண்ணாடி சுவர்களுக்குள் விற்கப்படும் பெரும்பாலான காய்கறிகள் பல நாட்கள் கெட்டுப் போகாமல் இருக்க, கூடுதலாக பதப்படுத்தி வைக்க இரசாயனங்கள் சேர்க்கப்படுகிறது. இதில் இருந்து தப்பிக்க, ஒரே வழி வீட்டு தோட்டம் தான். மொட்டை மாடியில் எளிதாக வீட்டுத் தோட்டம் அமைப்பது எவ்வாறு என அறிந்து செயல்படுத்தலாம்."},{"question":"चलचित्रमा नेपालको सांस्कृतिक विविधताको प्रतिनिधित्व र समावेशीतातर्फ उद्योगको प्रयासबारे छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नेपाली चलचित्र उद्योगमा समावेशीताको प्रयासमा नेपालको सांस्कृतिक विविधताको प्रतिनिधित्व गर्ने कुरामा ध्यान केन्द्रित हुन्छ। चलचित्र निर्माताहरूले विभिन्न जातजाति, भाषाहरू र क्षेत्रीय पहिचानहरू मनाउने कथाहरूको खोजी गरिरहेका छन्।"},{"question":"கேள்வி : தக்காளியில் எத்தனை சதவீதம் நீர் உள்ளது ? ","answer":"பதில் : 95%கங்கை."},{"question":"Afi ki Buhari fọwọ mu ọkan ninu ominira Yoruba ati ijọba ẹlẹkun-jẹkun- Iba Gani Adams","answer":"Bi ẹbiti ko ba pa eku, o yẹ ko fi ẹyin fẹlẹyin. Bijọba Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari yii ko ba ni i yee fiya jẹ Yoruba, o di dandan ki wọn gba iran naa laaye lati ni ilẹ Olominira tiẹ, tabi ki ijọba ẹlẹkun-jẹkun tawọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba n beere fun waye.Eyi lohun ti Aarẹ-Ọna- Kakanfo ilẹ Yoruba, Iba Gani Adams, sọ nibi eto kan ti wọn ṣe fawọn aṣiwaju APC, l’Oṣogbo l’Ọjọbọ to kọja yii.Aarẹ tẹsiwaju pe iran Yoruba ko le maa jiya lọ bayii labẹ akoso Buhari. O ni iran yii ko le maa gbe ninu oṣi ati ipọnju nilẹ ibi ti wọn ti bi wọn. Ko sohun meji ti yoo si ṣẹlẹ ju pe ki Buhari fi ọwọ mu ọkan ninu ki Yoruba da duro laaye tiẹ, tabi ko si jẹ ijọba ẹlẹkun-jẹkun la oo fi yanju ẹ.“Mo fara mọ ohun ti Akintoye n wi, nitori bi ẹ ba wo bi wọn ṣe n dari Naijiria yii, eeyan yoo fẹ kijọba ṣe atunto orilẹ-ede yii ni, pe kijọba di ẹlẹkun-jẹkun tabi ki kaluku da duro lominiria tiẹ gẹgẹ bii ẹya.  A o le maa jiya lọ bayii,  a o le maa da bii ajoji nilẹ baba wa” Bẹẹ ni Aarẹ wi.Iba Gani Adams fi kun alaye naa pe awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ OPC to wa loke okun yoo darapọ mọ iwọde ti Ọjọgbọn Banji Akintoye yoo ṣiwaju lọ sọdọ awọn Ajọ Agbaye (United Nations), eyi ti yoo waye loṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun yii, nibi ti wọn yoo ti beere fun ominira ilẹ Yoruba.Nigba to n gboriyin fawọn gomina ẹkun Guusu Naijiria ti wọn dide lati beere fun ijọba ẹlẹkun-jẹkun, Adams sọ pe oun fara mọ ohun ti wọn n beere yii.O ni ẹgbẹ OPC gẹgẹ bii eyi to n ja fun ominira yoo maa tẹsiwaju ninu ojuṣe rẹ. Awọn naa n beere fun ominira Yoruba, tabi ijọba ẹlẹkun-jẹkun, ọkan ni Buhari fọwọ gbọdọ fọwọ mu ninu mejeeji."},{"question":"வரலாற்றின் தந்தை?","answer":"வரலாற்றின் தந்தை எரோடோட்டசு.  அனதோலியாவில் உள்ள ஆலிகார்னாசசைச்  சேர்ந்த ஒரு கிரேக்க வரலாற்றறிஞா் மற்றும் புவியியலாளர் ஆவார். கிரேக்க பாரசீகப் போர்கள் குறித்த வரலாறை எழுதியதற்காக குறிப்பாக இவர் அறியப்படுகிறார். கிமு 5 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் (கிமு 484 - கிமு 425) வாழ்ந்த இவர் மேற்கு நாடுகளின் பண்பாட்டில் வரலாற்றின் தந்தை எனப்படுகிறார். இது பண்டைய உரோமானிய சொற்பொழிவாளர் சிசெரோவால் இவருக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது. தேவையான தகவல்களை முறைப்படியாகச் சேகரித்து, ஓரளவுக்கு அவற்றின் துல்லியத்தைச் சோதித்து, ஒழுங்கான அமைப்பில் அவற்றைத் தெளிவாக விளக்கிய முதல் வரலாற்றாளர் இவராவார். உலக வரைபடங்களை வரைந்த முதல் நபர் ஆவார்.இவரின் வரலாறுகள் முதன்மையாக மாரத்தான், தேமோபைலே, ஆர்ட்டெமிசியம், சலாமிஸ், பிளாட்டீயா, மைக்கேல் போன்ற புகழ்பெற்ற சமர்களையும் முக்கிய மன்னர்களின் வாழ்க்கையையும் உள்ளடக்கியது. வரலாற்றின் இன்றியமையாத பகுதியை உள்ளடக்கி, வாசகர்களுக்கு கூடுதல் தகவல்களை வழங்குவதாக பண்பாட்டு, இனவரைவியல், புவியியல், வரலாற்றுவரைவியல் போன்றவற்றின் பின்னணியையுடன் வழங்க அவரது பணி உள்ளது.எரோடோட்டசு தனது படைப்பில் \\"தொன்மங்கள் மற்றும் கற்பனை தகவல்களை\\" சேர்த்ததற்காக விமர்சிக்கப்பட்டார். சக வரலாற்றாசிரியர் துசிடிடீஸ் அவர் பொழுதுபோக்கிற்காக கட்டு்க்கதைகளை உருவாக்கியதாக குற்றம் சாட்டினார். எவ்வாறாயினும், எரோடோட்டசு தான் \\"பார்த்ததையும், தனக்குச் சொல்லப்பட்டதையும்\\" தெரிவித்ததாக விளக்கினார். இவரின் வரலாறுகளின் கணிசமான பகுதி நவீன வரலாற்றாசிரியர்கள் மற்றும் தொல்லியல் ஆய்வாளர்களால் உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"न द्विषन्ति न याचन्ते परनिन्दां न कुर्वते। अनाहूता न चायान्ति तेनाश्मानोऽपि देवताः","answer":"दगड कुणाचा द्वेष करत नाहीत, ते कुणाकडे भीक मागत नाहीत, कुणाची निंदा करत नाहीत, कुणाकडे न बोलावता अचानक जात नाहीत (त्यांच्यात माणसांचे हे दुर्गुण नसतात) यामुळे तेसुद्धा देव असतात."},{"question":"Awọn ọdọ tinu n bi le olori awọn Fulani ati ẹran rẹ kuro ni Ojoku-Ikọtun, ni Kwara","answer":"Ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ owurọ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ni awọn ọdọ tinu n bi, le olori awọn Bororo darandaran, Alhaji Muhammadu, ati maaluu rẹ tefetefe kuro ni agbegbe Ojoku-Ikọtun, níjọba ibilẹ Ọyun, nipinlẹ Kwara.Iroyin to tẹ ALAROYE lọwọ ni pe lati ilu Isẹyin, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, lawọn Bororo ọhun ti n bọ, ti wọn si n gbero lati fi Ilu Ojoku-Ikọtun ṣe ibujoko, sugbọn awọn ọdọ ilu fariga, wọn lawọn o le gba awọn ọdaran siluu, ni wọn ba le wọn danu patapata.Ohun ti a ri gbọ ni pe ikọ ẹṣọ alabo aabo ara ẹni laabo ilu (Civil Defence) ni wọn da si ọrọ naa ti ko fi dogun, dọtẹ laarin awọn Bororo darandaran ati awọn ọdọ Ojoku-Ikọtun.Agbẹnusọ ikọ ṣifu difẹnsi, Babawale, sọ pe olori awọn Bororo darandaran ọhun, Alhaji Muhammadu, ni ilu Lọkọja lawọn yoo mori le, nibi ti awọn mọlẹbi awọn tẹdo si.Babawale ni awọn sin awọn Bororo ọhun atawọn maaluu wọn de Bode Ojoku si Ọfa, awọn si fa wọn le ẹsọ alaabo agbegbe naa lọwọ lati ṣe ohun to tọ pẹlu wọn."},{"question":"Cé hé Hugh Doherty? ","answer":"Polaiteoir Éireannach ab ea Hugh Doherty. Bhí sé ina bhall d'Fhianna Fáil. Rugadh sé sa bhliain 1903. Fuair sé bás ar an 13 Deireadh Fómhair 1972. "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਅਸਟਪਦੀ ॥ਸੰਤ ਜਨਾ ਮਿਲਿ ਕਰਹੁ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ਏਕੁ ਸਿਮਰਿ ਨਾਮ ਆਧਾਰੁ ॥ਅਵਰਿ ਉਪਾਵ ਸਭਿ ਮੀਤ ਬਿਸਾਰਹੁ ॥ਚਰਨ ਕਮਲ ਰਿਦ ਮਹਿ ਉਰਿ ਧਾਰਹੁ ॥ਕਰਨ ਕਾਰਨ ਸੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸਮਰਥੁ ॥ਦ੍ਰਿੜੁ ਕਰਿ ਗਹਹੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਹਰਿ ਵਥੁ ॥ਇਹੁ ਧਨੁ ਸੰਚਹੁ ਹੋਵਹੁ ਭਗਵੰਤ ॥ਸੰਤ ਜਨਾ ਕਾ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਮੰਤ ॥ਏਕ ਆਸ ਰਾਖਹੁ ਮਨ ਮਾਹਿ ॥ਸਰਬ ਰੋਗ ਨਾਨਕ ਮਿਟਿ ਜਾਹਿ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 288 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸੰਤਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ) ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰੋ, ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰੋ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ (ਲਵੋ) ।ਹੇ ਮਿਤ੍ਰ! ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀਲੇ ਛੱਡ ਦਿਉ ,ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਕਮਲ (ਵਰਗੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ) ਚਰਨ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾਉ ।ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਆਪ) ਕਰਨ (ਤੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਪਾਸੋਂ) ਕਰਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਤਾਕਤ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰੂਪੀ (ਸੋਹਣਾ) ਪਦਾਰਥ ਪੱਕਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਸਾਂਭ ਲਵੋ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) (ਨਾਮ-ਰੂਪ) ਇਹ ਧਨ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰੋ ਤੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਣੋ, ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਇਹੀ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਉਪਦੇਸ਼ ਹੈ ।ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ) ਆਸ ਰੱਖੋ, ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਸਾਰੇ ਰੋਗ ਮਿਟ ਜਾਣਗੇ ।੧।\\""},{"question":"Ndingaita sei kuti vanhu vandide?","answer":"\\"Zvakakosha kuyeuka kuti havasi vese vachakuda munyika ino, nyangwe wakakura sei. Saka usaore moyo kana ukawana munhu asingakudi sezvaunofunga kuti anofanira.Heano mamwe matipi ekuti vanhu vakufarire:- Vabvunze mibvunzo pamusoro pavo: Vanhu vanofarira kutaura nezvavo uye ukavabvunza mibvunzo ine musoro vanozoona kuti uri munhu ane hanya anovateerera.- Verenga zvinyorwa zvemagariro: Zvakakosha kukwanisa kunzwisisa kana mumwe munhu asingafariri zvauri kutaura nezvazvo. Kana ukaona mumwe munhu wauri kutaura naye achitarisa-tarisa mumba achikupa mhinduro pfupi, unofanira kuedza nekuendesa nhaurirano kune rimwe divi kuti uone kana uchikwanisa kuvabata.- Iva nekuseka: Kuseka nevamwe vanhu inzira yakanaka yekugadzira zvisungo. Iwe unogona kuedza kuzvizvidza zvishoma kana kungoita majee asina mhosva pamusoro pemamiriro ako ezvinhu. Asi chenjera kuti usabvisa vanhu nekuseka kana iwe usingavazivi zvakanaka. Majee pamusoro pechitendero, zvematongerwo enyika, uye vamwe vanhu vangasafamba zvakanaka nevamwe vanhu. \\""},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Megan Ellison akaberekerwa muSanta Clara County, California semwanasikana wemabhiriyoniire Oracle Corporation - Sachigaro Larry Ellison uye Aimbova Mudzimai wake Barbara Boothe Ellison. Mutsara 2: Megan Ellison akaberekerwa muSanta Clara County, California, mwanasikana wemabhiriyoniire Oracle Corporation sachigaro Larry Ellison uye aimbova mudzimai wake, Barbara Boothe Ellison. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hungu kana kuti Aiwa?","answer":"Hongu mutsara 1 ne mutsara 2 unoreva zvakafanana wose."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 香川県宇多津町の四国水族館で、いつもは見ることができないタコやイカなどの子どもを見ることができます。世話をしている人が、自分が好きな小さい生き物を見てほしいと考えて紹介しました。イイダコの子どもは体の長さが2cmぐらいで、貝に隠れているところを見ることができます。7月に生まれたばかりのカミナリイカの赤ちゃんは、足を使って砂の上を動きます。今は体の長さが1cmから2cmぐらいですが、1年以内に30cmから40cmに大きくなります。ほかにクラゲやカニ、メダカもいます。水族館に来た人は「いつもは見ることができない赤ちゃんを見て、不思議な気持ちになりました」と話していました。この子どもたちは、8月27日まで見ることができます。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。- タコ: 1）海にすむ、骨のない、やわらかな動物。物に吸いつくいぼ〔＝吸盤〕のついた足が八本ある。食用にする。- イカ: 1）海にすむ動物。スルメイカ・ヤリイカ・ホタルイカなど種類が多い。胴は細長いふくろの形で、10本の足が頭の部分から出ている。敵にあうと、すみをはいてにげる。- 生き物: 1）生きているもの。生物。特に、動物のこと。- 貝: 1）水の中にすみ、体を硬いからでつつんだ動物。アサリ・ハマグリなどの二枚貝、サザエ・タニシなどの巻き貝がある。- 隠れ: 1）物の後ろに入って見えなくなる。2）人目につかないようにする。3）世の中に名前が知られていない。- クラゲ: 1）海などの水面の近くを、ふわふわと泳いでいる動物。体がやわらかく、かさのような形をしている。- カニ: 1）かたいこうらでおおわれた動物。海にすむタカアシガニ・ケガニや、谷川にすむサワガニなどがいる。足が十本あり、そのうちの二本がはさみになっている。- メダカ: 1）池や川などにすむ小さな魚。体長三センチメートルぐらい。目が大きく、水面近くを群れをなして泳ぐ。近年、数が減っている。- 水族館: 1）水にすむ生物を集め、ガラス張りの大きな水槽に入れて、生きたままのようすを見せるようにした所。すいぞっかん。- 不思議: 1）ふつうでは考えられないこと。あやしいこと。不可思議。"},{"question":"Ity misy lahatsoratra iray : «Nataon’ny razana koa fa ny mety , na dia tsy maintsy ho faty aza any am-parany, dia ny mitandrina izay rehetra hampaharitra ny aina. « Fa ny mahery tsy maody tsy ela velona ». Nefa misy fetrany io hakanosana na fitandreman-tena io. Raha tonga amin’ny zavatra inoany ho ambony vidy noho ny ainy, mahay mihenjana izy hanao vy very ny ainy ary tsy mataho-maty. »Arak’io lahatsoratra io, amin’ny fotoana oviana ny Malagasy no tsy mataho-maty ?","answer":"Tsy mataho-maty ny Malagasy rehefa misy zavatra inoany fa ambony noho ny ainy."},{"question":"ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ : ਵਾਰ ੧ ਪਉੜੀ ੧੪ ਪੰ. ੧ਨਾਗ-ਸ਼ੇਸ਼ਨਾਗ, ਪਾਤੰਜਲਸੇਖਨਾਗ ਪਾਤੰਜਲ ਮਥਿਆ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਨਾਗਿ ਸੁਣਾਈ।ਵੇਦ ਅਥਰਬਣ ਬੋਲਿਆ ਜੋਗ ਬਿਨਾ ਨਹਿ ਭਰਮੁ ਚੁਕਾਈ।ਜਿਉ ਕਰਿ ਮੈਲੀ ਆਰਸੀ ਸਿਕਲ ਬਿਨਾ ਨਹਿ ਮੁਖਿ ਦਿਖਾਈ।ਜੋਗੁ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਨਿਰਮਲਾ ਅਨਹਦ ਧੁਨਿ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਲਿਵਲਾਈ।ਅਸਟਦਸਾ ਸਿਧਿ ਨਉ ਨਿਧੀ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਜੋਗੀ ਚਰਨ ਲਗਾਈ।ਤ੍ਰਿਹੁ ਜੁਗਾ ਕੀ ਬਾਸਨਾ ਕਲਿਜੁਗ ਵਿਚਿ ਪਾਤੰਜਲਿ ਪਾਈ।ਹਥੋ ਹਥੀ ਪਾਈਐ ਭਗਤਿ ਜੋਗ ਕੀ ਪੂਰ ਕਮਾਈ।ਨਾਮ ਦਾਨ ਇਸਨਾਨੁ ਸੁਭਾਈ ॥੧੪॥","answer":"ਗੁਰਮੁਖ ਪਤੰਜਲੀ ਸੇਸਨਾਗ ਦਾ (ਮੰਨਿਆ) ਅਵਤਾਰ, ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਸੋਚ-ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਪਾਠ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ, ਨਾਗ-ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ, ਯੋਗ ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ (ਪਤੰਜਲ-ਯੋਗਸੂਤਰ)।ਉਸਨੇ ਅਥਰਵਵੇਦ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਕੂਲ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਯੋਗ ਦੇ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਭਰਮ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਟਾਇਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ।ਇਹ ਇਸ ਤੱਥ ਦੇ ਸਮਾਨ ਹੈ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਅਸੀਂ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਸ਼ੀਸ਼ੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਫ਼ ਕੀਤੇ ਬਿਨਾਂ, ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਚਿਹਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ।ਯੋਗਾ ਸ਼ੁੱਧ ਅਭਿਆਸ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਸੁਰਤੀ ਅਟੁੱਟ ਧੁਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੀਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਅਠਾਰਾਂ ਸਿੱਧੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਨੌ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਗੁਰਮੁਖ ਯੋਗੀ ਦੇ ਪੈਰੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ।ਕਲਿਯੁਗ ਵਿੱਚ, ਪਤੰਜਲੀ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਇੱਛਾਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਪੂਰਤੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਗੱਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਜੋ ਤਿੰਨ ਯੁਗਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਧੂਰੀਆਂ ਰਹਿ ਗਈਆਂ ਸਨ।ਯੋਗਿਕ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਪੂਰਨ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਹਰ ਚੀਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਹੱਥ-ਪੈਰ ਨਾਲ ਜੋੜਦੇ ਹੋ।ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਯਾਦ, ਦਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ਼ਨਾਨ (ਅੰਦਰੂਨੀ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਹਰੀ) ਦੇ ਸੁਭਾਅ ਨੂੰ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"4: රෝග ලක්ෂණ මතුවීමට පෙර ඇල්සයිමර් රුධිර පරීක්ෂණ (2019)","answer":"2019 වර්ෂයේදී දී විද්‍යාඥයින් පැවසුවේ රෝග ලක්ෂණ මතුවීමට පෙර ඇල්සයිමර් රෝගය වර්ධනය වීමට නියමිත පුද්ගලයින් නිවැරදිව හඳුනාගත හැකි බවයි.Drawing blood into a syringe from an armඡායාරූප මූලාශ්‍රය,GETTY IMAGESඡායාරූප ශීර්ෂ වැකිය,නිවැරදි රුධිර පරීක්ෂාව ඩිමෙන්ශියාව සඳහා ඖෂධ ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා පර්යේෂණ වේගවත් කළ හැකියමෙය ඖෂධ අත්හදා බැලීම්වල ප්‍රගතියට උපකාරී විය හැකි බව ඔවුහු විශ්වාස කළහ. එක්සත් ජනපද විද්‍යාඥයින්ට රුධිරයේ ඇති ඇමයිලොයිඩ් මට්ටමින් මොළයේ රෝගය පිරිහීම පිළිබඳව සොයා ගත හැකි බව පවසා ඇත.එක්සත් ජනපදයේ මිසූරි ප්‍රාන්තයේ වොෂින්ටන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාලයේ පර්යේෂකයන් ස්නායු විද්‍යාව ගැන අදහස් දක්වමින්, වයස අවුරුදු 50 ට වැඩි පුද්ගලයින් 158 දෙනෙකුගේ රුධිරයේ ඇති ඇමයිලොයිඩ් බීටා ප්‍රෝටීන් මට්ටම මනිනු ලැබීය. ඔවුන්ට මොළයේ ස්කෑන් පරීක්ෂණ වලට සමාන මට්ටම් පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ දැයි බැලීමට අවශ්‍ය විය.ස්කෑන් මගින් සමාන මට්ටම් පෙන්නුම් කර ඇති නමුත් එය ප්‍රතිශතයක් වශයෙන් සටහන් වුයේ 88% ක් ලෙස පමණි. එය රෝග විනිශ්චය පරීක්ෂණයක් සඳහා ප්‍රමාණවත් නොවේ.පර්යේෂකයන් මෙම තොරතුරු රෝගය සඳහා තවත් අවදානම් සාධක දෙකක් වන වයස අවුරුදු 65 ට වැඩි සහ APOE4 නම් ජානමය ප්‍රභේදයක් ඇති පුද්ගලයින් සමඟ එක් කළ විට එම පරීක්ෂණයේ නිරවද්‍යතාවය 94% දක්වා වැඩි දියුණු විය.2019 දී එක්සත් රාජධානියේ විශේෂඥයින් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ එම පරීක්ෂණයේ ප්‍රතිඵල බලාපොරොත්තු සහගත වන අතර ඩිමෙන්ශියා පර්යේෂණ වේගවත් කිරීම සඳහා ඇල්සයිමර් සඳහා විශ්වාසදායක රුධිර පරීක්ෂාවකට පියවරක් ගන්නා බවයි.Analysing blood samples in the labඡායාරූප මූලාශ්‍රය,GETTY IMAGESඡායාරූප ශීර්ෂ වැකිය,රුධිර සාම්පල රසායනාගාර පරීක්ෂණ මගින් ඇල්සයිමර් රෝගය හඳුනා ගත හැකිද යන්න විද්‍යාඥයින් පර්යේෂණ කරමින් සිටීකෙසේ වෙතත්, දැනට රුධිර පරීක්ෂණ කෙරෙහි විශ්වාසය තැබීමෙන් වළකින ලෙස වෛද්‍ය විශේෂඥයින් ද අනතුරු අඟවා ඇත.එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ඇල්සයිමර් සංගමය පවසන්නේ ඩිමෙන්ශියා පරීක්ෂා කිරීමේ පරීක්ෂණ ගණනාවක් පාරිභෝගිකයින් වෙත සෘජුවම අලෙවි කර ඇති නමුත් මෙම පරීක්ෂණ කිසිවක් නිවැරදි බව විද්‍යාත්මකව ඔප්පු කර නොමැති බවයි.සාධක ගණනාවක් තක්සේරු කරමින් වෛද්‍යවරයෙකුගෙන් රෝග විනිශ්චය නිර්දේශ කරයි: වෛද්‍යවරයෙකු සාධක ගණනාවක් තක්සේරු කරමින් රෝග විනිශ්චයක් කල යුතු බව නිර්දේශ කෙරේ.\\"මෙවැනි හේතුන් සහ වෙනත් හේතූන් නිසා, ඇල්සයිමර් සංගමය විශ්වාස කරන්නේ, දක්ෂ වෛද්‍යවරයෙකුගේ පරිපූර්ණ පරීක්ෂණයක් සඳහා ආදේශකයක් ලෙස නිවසේ පරීක්ෂා කිරීමේ පරීක්ෂණ භාවිතා කළ නොහැකි බවත් එසේ නොකළ යුතු බවත්ය.\\"සාරාංශයක් ලෙස, ඇල්සයිමර් රෝගය හඳුනා ගැනීම සඳහා රුධිර පරීක්ෂාවන් සාර්ථක භාවයක් පෙන්වා ඇත, නමුත් රෝග ලක්ෂණ තිබේද යන්න තීරණය කිරීම සඳහා රෝගියාගේ හැසිරීමෙන් වෛද්‍යවරයෙකු රෝග විනිශ්චය කිරීම තීරණාත්මක ක්‍රමයකි.Amyloid plaques shown on axons of neurons affected by Alzheimer's diseaseඡායාරූප මූලාශ්‍රය,GETTY IMAGESඡායාරූප ශීර්ෂ වැකිය,ඇල්සයිමර් රෝගයෙන් පීඩාවට පත් වූ නියුරෝන මත ඇමයිලොයිඩ් ඵලක දක්නට ලැබේ"},{"question":"ماهو العنوان المناسب للنص التالي: قال كريم سوس، رئيس قطاع مخاطر التجزئة المصرفية بالبنك الأهلي المصري، أن مصرفه قام بضخ تمويلات بقيمة 258.5 مليون جنيه لتمويل نحو 3450 وحدة سكنية لمحدودى الدخل خلال عاميين من إطلاق مبادرة المركزي للتمويل العقاري. أضاف ل'أموال الغد' ان الشهر العقاري وافق علي إنتداب ممثلين لتسهيل عمليات تسجيل الوحدات وتنشيط مبادرة البنك المركزي لمحدودى ومتوسطي الدخل، موضحا أن البنك يجري حصر الفروع التى سيتم توفير موظفين الشهر العقاري بها. أشار إلى أن البنك يقوم بتقديم تمويلات بمعدل من 500 الي 600 قرض شهريا خلال الفترة الأخيرة مقارنة ب 200 قرض خلال الشهور الأولي من المبادرة. أوضح إن محفظة تمويلات الأفراد بالبنك سجلت نحو 33.8 مليار جنيه بنهاية العام ويستهدف الوصول بها ل 40 مليار جنيه بنهاية 2015/2016 من خلال التنوع فى طرح منتجات جديدة وتعديل شروط بعض المنتجات وأضافة بطاقات إئتمانية URL البنك المركزي قد أطلق مبادرة بداية 2014 لدعم التمويل العقاري من خلال تخصيص مبلغ 10 مليارات جنيه للتمويل العقاري لصالح محدودي ومتوسطي الدخل لمدة 20 سنة بأسعار تصل إلي 7% لمحدودى الدخل. يذكر أن بنوك 'البنك الأهلي المصري و بنك مصر وبنك القاهرة وبنك التعمير والإسكان' كانوا من أوائل البنوك التى وقعت بروتوكلات تعاون مع صندوق دعم التمويل العقاري بقيمة إجمالية تصل إلى 8.5 مليار جنيه. المصدر: اموال الغد.","answer":"حسناً قد يكون العنوان: ''الاهلي' يضخ 258.5 مليون جنيه لتمويل 3450 وحدة لمحدودى الدخل خلال عامين' ، مناسباً."},{"question":"THE THORN IN MY FLESHCHAPTER 7","answer":"THE THORN IN MY FLESHCHAPTER 7Here's my account details, send the money as fast as possible.. Anny said smiling to herselfIt's fine I'll do that but leave my house first,I'll send the money before you get home.. Stan replied knowing fully well he doesn't have a million naira in his accountStan! Do I look like a normal human being to you? If I don't get that money right now I'll frustrate your life.. Anny shouted as Stan's girlfriend enteredWhat's happening here and who is this Stan? She asked dropping her purseBaby I know her not, it's fine I'll explain..You know me not right? After spending my money on you bah,Anny barked slapping his faceDon't dare try that again, are you insane? You slapped my boyfriend in my presence, is something wrong with your ugly brain huh? Stay out of this young lady,Stan your useless and che...Stop it madam, don't call my boyfriend a useless being again if not..Stan's girlfriend interruptedOkay,Stan we shall see..Anny said and leftShe got home sat in the parlour sipping her juice while Steve massaged her feetYou want to injure me right? Common sense did not tell you that what you just did now hurts bah? Anny screamed pouring the juice on his faceI'm sorry Anny, I have to go now,someone is waiting for me..Who's that? Anny questionedSomeone knocked and she dropped her feet on the floor immediately, her mother came inGood evening mum..she greetedGood evening my darling, how are you doing? Her mum asked touching her daughter's skinI'm fine mum,how's everyone?Fine my daughter..Good evening mum.. Steve greetedShe sighed, looked at him from head to toe and spat on his faceThis should be the very last time you dare open your gutter to call me mum, useless son..Mrs Ify saidSteve wiped off the spit on his face,he cried, went upstairs to meet his mumMum,the charm is really working oh..Anny said hugging her motherI told you, Ichaka never fails,where's the mother? Mrs Ify asked opening the fridge"},{"question":"شكرًا لك ، أندريه.'' \`\` أنت مرحبًا بك. اعتني بنفسك وطفلك الأمريكي الجميل.'' واصلت أنظر إلى خريطة الولايات المتحدة لأعرف أين كنت عايز أن أنتقل.","answer":"معذرة، صياغتك مش مبينة ايه المطلوب مني بالظبط. ربما لو عدلت طلبك بصياغة تكون مفهومة أكتر و مهمة محددة هقدر أساعدك أفضل.لكن فى الوقت الحالي، هل في حاجة تانية أقدر أساعدك بيها؟"},{"question":"Jis – anksčiausias Lietuvos kunigaikštis, žinomas vardu ir minimas patikimuose šaltiniuose. Jis žuvo 1205 m., kai jo armiją, grįžtančią iš Estijos su grobiu, užpuolė ir sunaikino jungtinės kalavijuočių ir žiemgalių pajėgos. Kas jis?","answer":"Žvelgaitis – lietuvių kunigaikštis, žuvęs 1205 m. Jis yra pirmasis žinomas lietuvių kunigaikštis, minimas patikimuose šaltiniuose. Apie jo žygį ir mirtį rašoma Henriko Latvio kronikoje. Joje Žvelgaitis vadinamas \\"turtingu ir galingu\\", tačiau jis nebuvęs vyriausias kunigaikštis, o kito nežinomo kunigaikščio armijos vadas.1205 m. Žvelgaitis su dviejų tūkstančių raitelių armija patraukė iš Lietuvos į šiaurę, per Rygą link Estijos. Viduržiemį grįžtančią armiją su karo grobiu ir vergais estais užpuolė jungtinės kalavijuočių ir Viesturo vadovaujamų žiemgalių pajėgos. Žvelgaitis buvo nukautas ietimi vokiečio Teodoro Šilingo. Taip pat žuvo ~1200 lietuvių karių, išžudyti ir vergai. Pasakojama, kad nesulaukusios sugrįžtant karių iš skausmo nusižudė 50 jų moterų."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Hélio Castroneves, egentligen Hélio Castro Neves, född den 10 maj 1975 i Ribeirão Preto, är en brasiliansk racerförare. Han har vunnit Indianapolis 500 fyra gånger, 2001, 2002, 2009","answer":"och 2021. Han kör för Acura Team Penske i Weathertech Sportscar Championship."},{"question":"لدينا النص التالي: القطاع في بداية السنة الماضية تباطؤا غير مسبوق اذ لم ينجح في النصف الأول سوى في بيع 24 شقة وذلك تأثرا بالإجراءات الواردة في قانون المالية 2018. يقول فهي شعبان رئيس الغرفة النقابية للباعثين العقاريين في تصريح ل«المغرب» إن الأوضاع مازالت على ماهي عليه فهي معطلة الى اليوم نتيجة عديد العوامل وأهمها تأثر القطاع بالترفيع في نسبة الفائدة المديرية وإجراءات أخرى على غرار معلوم حق التسجيل وتأثير ارتفاع المحروقات بالإضافة إلى تأثر القطاع أيضا بالانزلاق الذي يشهده الدينار الأمر الذي اثر في ارتفاع تكلفة المواد الموردة مبينا أن أسعارها تضاعفت ومازالت في منحى تصاعدي. وعن برنامج المسكن الأول قال فهمي شعبان أن البرنامج لم يكن في مستوى الآمال المعلقة عليه وفسر المتحدث هذا الأمر بضعف المقدرة الشرائية للتونسيين. وأشار المتحدث إلى أن معدل المبيعات السنوية في الظروف العادية يقدر ب10 آلاف مسكن. وبين شعبان أن التزامات الباعثين العقاريين تجاه البنوك تقدر ب 5200 مليون دينار وهو رقم ثقيل أمام التراجع الذي يشهده نشاطهم وأضاف المتحدث ان الغرفة تطالب الحكومة باتخاذ قرارات من قبيل وضع نسبة فائدة تفاضلية للمواطن والباعث العقاري بهدف تنشيط المبيعات. كما لفت المتحدث إلى أن التراجع في المبيعات يشمل كل أصناف المساكن من المسكن الأول إلى الشقق الفاخرة والرفيعة. من جهة أخرى شهد مؤشر أسعار العقارات ارتفاعا بنسبة URL خلال الثلاثي الرابع من سنة 2018 مقارنة بالثلاثي الثالث من نفس السنة بعد أن سجل تراجعا بنسبة URL خلال الثلاثي الثالث من سنة 2018 .ويعز ى ذلك بالأساس لتسجيل إرتفاع في أسعار الشقق بنسبة URL والمنازل بنسبة URL بعد أن انخفضت الأسعار خلال الثلاثي الثالث لسنة 2018 بنسبة URL وكان مؤشر الأسعار لشهر افريل المنقضي المتعلق بالسكن والطاقة المنزلية قد ارتفع بنسبة URL في مقارنة بالفترة نفسها من العام المنقضي.. قم بإنشاء عنوان مناسب.","answer":"اسفله بعض العناوين:\\"5200 مليون دينار التزامات الباعثين العقاريين تجاه البنوك وبرنامج السكن الأول دون المأمول.\\"\\"تحليل الوضع الراهن للقطاع العقاري في تونس: تأثير السياسات المالية وتحديات برنامج المسكن الأول\\"\\"تراجع ملحوظ في مبيعات العقارات بتونس: التحديات التي تعوق التعافي\\"\\"تأثير ارتفاع التكاليف والتشريعات على القطاع العقاري التونسي: دراسة حول الوضع الحالي\\"\\"تحليل ارتفاع أسعار العقارات في تونس وتأثيرها على مشروع المسكن الأول\\""},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Tamta Goduadze föddes i dåvarande Georgiska SSR, där hon växte upp och började sjunga vid 5 års ålder. När Tamta var 22 år gammal flyttade hon tillsammans med sin familj till Grekland, där hon beslöt sig för att delta i musiktävlingen \\"Super Idol\\", ett program baserat på Idol-formatet. Tamta lyckades ta sig ända fram till finalen, där hon dock förlorade mot Stavros Konstantinou. I januari 2007 meddelade Ellinikí Radiphonikí Tileórassi (ERT) att Tamta var en av deltagarna i Greklands nationella uttagning till Eurovision Song Contest 2007. Hon","answer":"slutade trea av de tre deltagarna med sin låt \\"With Love\\". Vann gjorde Sarbel, som fick åka till Helsingfors. Kort därefter släppte hon sin debutskiva, \\"Tamta\\". Tamtas andra album, \\"Agapise Me\\", släpptes den 16 maj 2007 och innehöll bland annat den populära låten \\"Agapise Me\\". I mars 2010 släppte Tamta sitt tredje och senaste album, \\"Tharros I Alitheia\\". I december 2018 meddelade Cyprus Broadcasting Corporation (CyBC) att Tamta kommer att representera Cypern vid Eurovision Song Contest 2019 i Tel Aviv med låten \\"Replay\\". Tamta tog sig till finalen och slutade på en trettonde plats."},{"question":"“金屋藏嬌”的故事與哪一位皇帝有關？","answer":"漢武帝"},{"question":"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸਮ੍ਰਿਤੀ ਇਰਾਨੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ?","answer":"ਸਮ੍ਰਿਤੀ ਜੁਬੀਨ ਇਰਾਨੀ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 23 ਮਾਰਚ 1976 ਨੂੰ  ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਟੀ.ਵੀ. ਮਹਿਲਾ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਹੈ। ਸਮ੍ਰਿਤੀ ਜੁਬੀਨ ਇਰਾਨੀ ਰਾਜਨੀਤਿਕ ਅਤੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਅੰਰਗਤ ਮਾਨਵ ਸੰਸਾਧਨ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ ਦੀ ਕੈਬਨਿਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਟੈਕਸਟਾਇਲ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਸੇਵਾ ਨਿਭਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਮਈ 2019 ਤੋਂ ਮੋਦੀ ਦੀ ਦੂਜੀ ਕੈਬਨਿਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਔਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਲ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਵਾਧੂ ਚਾਰਜ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਭਾਰਤੀ ਜਨਤਾ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਨੇਤਾ,  ਅਮੇਠੀ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਨਿਧਤਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਸੰਸਦ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਹੈ।ਸਾਲ 2019 ਦੀਆਂ ਆਮ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਗਾਂਧੀ - ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਆਗੂ ਅਤੇ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ - ਨੂੰ ਸੀਟ ਜਿੱਤਣ ਲਈ ਹਰਾਇਆ। ਗਾਂਧੀ ਦੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੇ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਚਾਰ ਦਹਾਕਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਇਸ ਹਲਕੇ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਨਿਧਤਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ, ਉਹ ਗੁਜਰਾਤ ਲਈ ਰਾਜ ਸਭਾ ਦੀ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਕਈ ਪੋਰਟਫੋਲੀਓ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਸੀ।ਦੂਜਾ ਮੋਦੀ ਮੰਤਰਾਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਫਿਰ 30 ਮਈ, 2019 ਨੂੰ ਕੈਬਨਿਟ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਸਹੁੰ ਚੁਕਾਈ। ਉਹ ਇਸ ਸਮੇਂ 43 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮੰਡਲ 'ਚ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਛੋਟੀ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਹੈ। 31 ਮਈ 2019 ਨੂੰ, ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਮੰਤਰੀਆਂ ਲਈ ਪੋਰਟਫੋਲੀਓ ਅਲਾਟਮੈਂਟ ਜਾਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਟੈਕਸਟਾਈਲ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਆਪਣਾ ਅਹੁਦਾ ਬਰਕਰਾਰ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਮੇਨਕਾ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਦੀ ਔਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਲ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇਵਾਰੀ ਵੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ।== ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ==ਸਮ੍ਰਿਤੀ ਜੁਬੀਨ ਇਰਾਨੀ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 23 ਮਾਰਚ 1976 ਨੂੰ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ, ਅਤੇ ਉਹਨਾ ਨੇ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਰਾਜਧਾਨੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਲਈ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਇੱਕ ਬੰਗਾਲਣ ਅਤੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਮਹਾਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸੀ। ਉਹ 3 ਭੈਣਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਹੈ।ਉਹ ਬਚਪਨ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਸਵੈਮ ਸੇਵਕ ਸੰਘ (ਆਰਐਸਐਸ) ਦਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਦਾਦਾ ਆਰ.ਐਸ.ਐਸ. ਦਾ ਸਵੈਮ ਸੇਵਕ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਜਨ ਸੰਘ ਦੀ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਹੋਲੀ ਚਾਈਲਡ ਆਕਸਿਲਿਅਮ ਸਕੂਲ, ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਿਖੇ ਹੋਈ। ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਵਿਖੇ ਸਕੂਲ ਆਫ਼ ਓਪਨ ਲਰਨਿੰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲਾ ਲਿਆ। ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ 2019 ਵਿੱਚ, ਇੱਕ ਪੋਲ ਹਲਫਨਾਮੇ ਵਿੱਚ, ਈਰਾਨੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਗ੍ਰੈਜੂਏਟ ਹੈ। ਆਰ.ਟੀ.ਆਈ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਆਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਖੁਲਾਸਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਬੀ.ਕਾਮ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰੀਖਿਆ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ। ਪਹਿਲਾ ਸਾਲ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਦੇ ਸਕੂਲ ਆਫ਼ ਓਪਨ ਲਰਨਿੰਗ ਤੋਂ ਕੀਤਾ, ਪਰ ਤਿੰਨ ਸਾਲਾ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਕੋਰਸ ਪੂਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ। ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਚਾਂਦਨੀ ਚੌਕ ਤੋਂ 2004 ਦੀਆਂ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਉਮੀਦਵਾਰ ਵਜੋਂ, ਈਰਾਨੀ ਨੇ ਐਲਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਬੀ.ਏ. ਦੀ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਰ.ਟੀ.ਆਈ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਇਹ ਖੋਜਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਬੀ.ਕਾਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ। ਪਰ ਉਹ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਕੋਰਸ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਪੂਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ।== ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਕਰੀਅਰ ==ਈਰਾਨੀ ਮਿਸ ਇੰਡੀਆ 1998 ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਭਾਗੀਆਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਸੀ ਜੋ ਗੌਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਤੇਜਵਾਨੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਚੋਟੀ ਦੇ 9 'ਤੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਸਕੀ। 1998 ਵਿੱਚ, ਈਰਾਨੀ ਮੀਕਾ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਐਲਬਮ \\"ਸਾਵਨ ਮੇਂ ਲਗ ਗਈ ਆਗ\\" ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਗਾਣੇ \\"ਬੋਲੀਆਂ\\" ਵਿੱਚ ਦਿਖਾਈ ਦਿੱਤੀ। ਸੰਨ 2000 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਟੀ.ਵੀ. ਸੀਰੀਜ਼ ਆਤੀਸ਼ ਅਤੇ \\"ਹਮ ਹੈਂ ਕਲ ਆਜ ਔਰ ਕਲ\\" ਨਾਲ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਬਣੀ। ਇਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਨਾਟਕ ਸਟਾਰ ਪਲੱਸ 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਿਤ ਹੋਏ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਡੀਡੀ ਮੈਟਰੋ 'ਤੇ ਕਵਿਤਾ ਸੀਰੀਅਲ 'ਚ ਵੀ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ। ਸਾਲ 2000 ਦੇ ਅੱਧ ਵਿੱਚ, ਈਰਾਨੀ ਨੇ ਸਟਾਰ ਪਲੱਸ 'ਤੇ ਏਕਤਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਕਸ਼ਨ \\"ਕਿਊਂਕੀ ਸਾਸ ਭੀ ਕਭੀ ਬਹੁ ਥੀ\\" ਵਿੱਚ ਤੁਲਸੀ ਵਿਰਾਨੀ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਰਬੋਤਮ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ - ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ, ਚਾਰ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਟੈਲੀ ਅਵਾਰਡਾਂ ਲਈ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਪੰਜ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਟੈਲੀਵਿਜ਼ਨ ਅਕੈਡਮੀ ਪੁਰਸਕਾਰ ਜਿੱਤਣ ਦਾ ਰਿਕਾਰਡ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ। ਇਰਾਨੀ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਏਕਤਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਨਾਲ ਮਤਭੇਦ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਜੂਨ 2007 ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਛੱਡ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਸੀ । ਉਸ ਦੀ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਗੌਤਮੀ ਕਪੂਰ ਨੇ ਲੈ ਲਈ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਮਈ 2008 ਵਿੱਚ ਕਪੂਰ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਲ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਹੋਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਇੱਕ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਐਪੀਸੋਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਕੀਤੀ। 2001 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਜ਼ੀ ਟੀ.ਵੀ ਦੇ ਰਮਾਇਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਹਾਂਕਾਵਿ ਪਾਤਰ ਸੀਤਾ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। 2006 ਵਿੱਚ, ਈਰਾਨੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੈਨਰ ਉਗਰਾਇਆ ਐਂਟਰਟੇਨਮੈਂਟ ਤਹਿਤ ਸ਼ੋਅ \\"ਥੋੜੀ ਸੀ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਥੋਡਾ ਸਾ ਅਸਮਾਨ\\" ਦਾ ਸਹਿ-ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਲਾਜੀ ਟੈਲੀਫਿਲਮਜ਼ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸਹਿ-ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕੀਤਾ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਮਾ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਵੀ ਨਿਭਾਈ। 2007 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸੋਨੀ ਟੀ.ਵੀ. ਲਈ ਟੀਵੀ ਸੀਰੀਅਲ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਸੁਧਾ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਦਰਸਾਇਆ। ਉਸ ਨੇ 9 ਐਕਸ ਲਈ ਮੇਰੇ ਅਪਨੇ ਵੀ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਨੋਦ ਖੰਨਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਨਾਇਕਾ ਵਜੋਂ ਤਸਵੀਰ ਬਨਵਾਈ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਜ਼ੀ ਟੀਵੀ ਦੇ ਤਿੰਨ ਬਹੁਰਾਣੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਸਹਾਇਕ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ। 2008 ਵਿੱਚ, ਇਰਾਨੀ ਨੇ ਸਾਕਸ਼ੀ ਤੰਵਰ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਸ਼ੋਅ 'ਯੇ ਹੈ ਜਲਵਾ' ਦੀ ਮੇਜ਼ਬਾਨੀ ਕੀਤੀ, ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਡਾਂਸ ਅਧਾਰਤ ਰਿਐਲਿਟੀ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਹਸਤੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਫੌਜਾਂ 9X ਐਕਸ 'ਤੇ ਦਿਖਾਈਆਂ ਗਈਆਂ।  ਉਸੇ ਸਾਲ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਜ਼ੀ ਟੀਵੀ'ਤੇ ਵਾਰਿਸ  ਇੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਵੀ ਬਣਾਇਆ, ਜੋ ਕਿ 2009 ਵਿੱਚ ਖਤਮ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। 2009 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਹ ਐਸ.ਏ.ਬੀ ਟੀ.ਵੀ.' ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਤ ਹੋਏ ਇੱਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਮਨੀਬੇਨ ਡਾਟ ਕਾਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਈ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕਾਂਟੀਲੋ ਐਂਟਰਟੇਨਮੈਂਟ ਦੇ ਸਹਿਯੋਗ ਨਾਲ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਵੀ ਕੀਤਾ। 2012 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਬੰਗਾਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਅਮ੍ਰਿਤਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ।== ਰਾਜਨੀਤਿਕ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ==ਸਮ੍ਰਿਤੀ ਜੁਬੀਨ ਇਰਾਨੀ ਦਾ ਰਾਜਨੀਤਿਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਸਾਲ 2003 ਤੋਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਇਆ। ਜਦੋਂ ਉਨਾ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਜਨਤਾ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੀ ਮੈਬਰ ਬਣੀ ਅਤੇ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਚਾਦਣੀ ਚੋਂਕ ਲੋਕਸਭਾ ਨਿਰਵਾਚਨ ਖੇਤਰ ਦੇ ਚੁਨਵ ਲੜੇ।== ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ==ਸਾਲ 2001 ਵਿੱਚ ਸਮ੍ਰਿਤੀ ਜੁਬੀਨ ਇਰਾਨੀ ਨੇ ਸ਼ਾਦੀਸ਼ੁਦਾ ਜੁਬੀਨ ਇਰਾਨੀ ਪਾਰਸੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ। ਉਸ ਹੀ ਸਾਲ ਉਨਾ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਮੁੰਡਾ ਹੋਇਆ। ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਜੋਹਰ ਹੈ। 6 ਸਿਤੰਬਰ 2003 ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨਾ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਕੁੜੀ ਹੋਈ ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਜੋਇਸ਼ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Kí ni orúkọ gómínà àkọ́kọ́ ní ìpínlẹ̀ Edo?","answer":"Colonel John Ewerekumoh Yeri ni."},{"question":"Summarise the article:(CNN) -- Javier Hernandez has had to be patient this season. Robin van Persie's arrival at Manchester United was followed by a glut of goals that justified Alex Ferguson's 38 million investment in the former Arsenal striker. Hernandez also made a big impact two years ago as a relatively little-known signing from Guadalajara, being named player of the season as United won a record 19th league title. But last season was a different story as the Mexico international played a bit-part role and the club's Premier League crown was snatched by crosstown rivals Manchester City. The 24-year-old came into the 2012-13 campaign fresh after Ferguson demanded he miss Mexico's successful Olympic campaign, but he has started only five matches out of 16 in all competitions. However, a run of seven goals in his last five games means \\"Chicharito\\" will be one of the first names on the team sheet next weekend for United's trip to Norwich. \\"When he came to us two years ago, that's what we're seeing again today and, when you score a hat-trick, you pick yourself. I think he'll be playing next week,\\" Ferguson said after Hernandez inspired another comeback victory against Aston Villa on Saturday to put United four points clear at the top of the table. The \\"Little Pea\\" scored three goals in the two come-from-behind wins against Braga that sealed United's place in the last 16 of the Champions League, and he came off the bench to rescue the team from 2-0 down against struggling Villa. It was the eighth time United have won this season after going behind. Hernandez is claiming a hat-trick, though his equalizing goal appeared to be off-target before it deflected into the net off Villa defender Ron Vlaar. Ferguson had to change his preferred attacking formation at halftime, taking off England winger Ashley Young, after Villa took a shock lead with two goals from young Austrian forward Andreas Weimann. \\"We do prefer that one striker with one playing behind,\\" the 70-year-old manager said. \\"It didn't work today in the first half but when...","answer":"Javier Hernandez comes off the bench as a substitute player to help bring Manchester United to victory. Hernandez scored twice against Aston Villa  and has another effort deflected in by Aston Villa player. The 3-2 win put United four points clear at the top of the Premier League."},{"question":"السؤال: كم كان تعداد جيش المسلمين في غزوة أحد؟","answer":"الجواب: ألف مسلم وقد انسحب منهم ثلث الجيش من المنافقين فبقوا سبعمائة مقاتل."},{"question":"洋口港的发展状况如何？","answer":"答：近年来，洋口港的发展迅速，港口吞吐量持续增长，已经成为中国重要的海上门户。"},{"question":"Iza ilay mpikaroka Viking fantatra fa nahita an'i Amerika Avaratra tamin'ny taona 1000, ela be talohan'i Christopher Columbus?","answer":"Leif Erikson, mpikaroka Viking, dia fantatra fa nahita an'i Amerika Avaratra."},{"question":"Temel yetenekler nelerdir?","answer":"Temel yetenekler, rakiplerce bilinmeyen, taklidi zor, kaynak, süreç ve yeteneklerin karışımıdır. (Macmillan, s. 2) Bu ifade oldukça önemlidir. İşletmenin sahip olduğu yeteneklerden birinin temel yetenek olabilmesi için rakip firmalarca elde edilemeyen, taklit veya kopya edilemeyen bir yetenek olması lazımdır."},{"question":"Ìfọmọdéṣaṣẹ́wó ní Orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà ","answer":"Ìfọmọdéṣaṣẹ́wó ní Orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà  jẹ́ ọ̀nà ìgba fífi àwọn ọmọdé ṣiṣẹ aṣẹ́wó. Iṣẹ́ aṣẹ́wo ti di iṣẹ́ tí ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn ènìyàn rí gẹ́gẹ́ bí iṣẹ́ ọ̀ọ̀jọ́ wọn. Kódà tọmọdé àti tàgbà ló ní ṣíṣe yíì gẹ́gẹ́ bí ohun to ń fún wọn ní jíjẹ àti mímu. Àmọ́ èyí kì í ṣe ọ̀nà tó dára. Yorùbá bọ̀ wọ́n ní ọ̀nà kan ò wọjà. Tí ó mú èyí túmọ̀ sí wí pé ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ iṣẹ́ ló wà tí ènìyàn lè fí wá jíjẹ àtì mímu. Ìṣe Aṣẹ́wo àwọn ọmọdé nílẹ̀ Nàìjíríà ní ó jẹ́ wá lógún ní iṣẹ́ yìí.IṢẸ́ AṢẸ́WOIṣẹ́ yìí ní bíba jẹ́ndà kejì ní àṣepọ̀. Tí ó lè jẹ́ mímọ̀ọ́mọ̀ fún ara rẹ̀ tàbí wí pé wọn lọ ẹ̀tàn àti ipá fún un làti lè bá ẹlòmíràn ní àṣepọ̀. Tí a bá sọ mímọ̀ọ́mọ̀ ọmọdé náà, a ma sọ wí pé ó ń ṣiṣẹ́ yìí fún owó ni. Ṣùgbọ́n tí a bá sọ ti ẹ̀tàn àti ipá, èyí lè túmọ̀ sí wí pé ọmọ tí wọ́n mú lọ sókè òkun àìtọ́ niÌTÀNNí ọdún 2019, àjọ tí ń gbógun tí kíkó àwọn ènìyàn lọ sókè òkun lọ́nà àìtọ́ sọ fún CNN wí pé ó tó ọ̀kẹ́(20,000) obìnrin tí wọ́n tí fì ẹ̀tan àbí ipá mú lọ sí orílé-èdè Mali. Àwọn àjọ yìí sọ fún CNN wí pé àwon ní ẹ̀rí tó dájú lórí ọ̀rọ̀ yii.Gẹ́gẹ́ bí ìtàn tí àwọn Àjọ̀ tó ń gbógun tí ìwà ìbàjé ṣe sọ, nípa ti wọn má mú àwọn obìnrin náà ní Nigeria, wọ́n sọ wí pé ìlú Malaysia ni àwọn tí má ṣíṣe pẹ̀lú owó tọ pọ̀ ṣùgbọ́n awọn ò mọ bí àwọn ṣe bá ara àwọn ni Málì. Ní Málì yẹn ní àwọn ọdaran yii ti ta ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn obìnrin yíì. Àwọn yòókù tí wọn ní kó ṣíṣe ní ilé ìtura ní Mali náà di títa lati mọ̀ wí pé wọ́n tí tá àwọn fún ilé ìtura náà. Ohun tó yẹ ka ṣe àkíyèsí rẹ̀ nínú wo pé obìnrin ló sáábà máa ń jẹ́ awon. Àwọn ohun tó ń fa èyí, ohun tó má dá sílẹ̀ àti ọ̀nà àbáyọ la ma mẹ́nubà nínu iṣẹ́ yìí.ÀWỌN OKÙNFÀ RẸ̀Gẹ́gẹ́ bí a ti ṣe mọ̀ wí pé kò sí nǹkan ni àwùjọ tí kò ní ohun tí ó hún fà á. Lára àwọn ohun tí ó fa Iṣẹ́-aṣẹ́wó ọmọdé ni: iṣẹ́, àwọn ọ̀rẹ́, Àìnímọ̀ nípa àwọn àrùn tí ó lè fà, Àdúgbo ẹni àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ. Iṣẹ́ Aṣẹ́wo ní ọ̀nà mímú ọmọdé lọ sókè òkun lọ́nà àìtọ́ ni a ma fẹ́ ẹ̀ mújútó nínu iṣẹ́ yìí.Ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn ọmọdé ni ò nímọ̀ nípa àwọn àrùn tí gbóògùn tí wọ́n ma kó tí àwọn bá ń ṣe Aṣẹ́wo àti wí pé tí ó bá jẹ́ mímú wọn lọ́nà àìtọ́ lọ sí ibòmíràn ni, èyí jẹ́ wí pé ipá lọ ma lò láti fi jẹ́ kí wọ́n ṣiṣẹ́ Aṣẹ́wo yìí. Tí a bá wo ará àdúgbò àti àwọn ọ̀rẹ́, a ma ri wí pé àwọn méjèèjì yìí wà lára àwọn nǹkan tó máa bá ìhùwàsí àwọn ènìyàn lọ rè é. Kò sí ẹnì kankan tí a lè sọ wí pé àpẹẹrẹ àwọn méjèèjì ò hàn nínu ìhùwàsí rẹ̀. Tí ó bá jẹ́ wí pé àwọn ọ̀rẹ́ àwọn ọmọdé yìí bá ń ṣe iṣẹ́ yìí, àyè wà wí pé àwọn náà má ṣe é.Iṣẹ́ àti àìríṣẹ àwọn ọmọdé náà máa ń fà á. Yorùbá bọ̀ wọ́n ní ọwọ́ tó bá dilẹ̀ ni Èṣù ń bẹ̀wò.ÀWỌN OHUN TÍ Ó MÁA Ń DÁ SÍLẸ̀Àrùn kògbóògùn jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára wọn. Àwọn àrùn bí i HIV/AIDS àti àwọn àrùn mìíràn tí ó jẹ́ wí pé ènìyàn má á kó látara ìbáṣepọ̀. Àwọn àrùn yìí ò kògbóògùn tó túmọ̀ sí wí pé bẹ́ẹ̀ àwọn ọmọdé yìí ṣe ma bá ara wọn láíláí.Ó tún lè fa ìrònú ọkàn àti ìrẹ̀wẹ̀sí fún àwọn ọmọdé. Bí àpẹẹrẹ tí ó bá jẹ́ ọmọdé tí wọ́n fi ẹ̀tan àti kíkọpá mú lọ sí ilẹ̀ mìíràn lọ́nà àìtọ́, èyí ma jẹ́ ìrònú ọkàn àti ìrẹ̀wẹ̀sí fun lẹ́yìn tí ó bá rí àwọn ènìyàn gbà á lè. Kódà ó tún lè fa àbámọ̀ fún wọn lẹ́yìn tí wọn ba ti ko àwọn àrùn tán.ÀWỌN Ọ̀NÀ ÀBÁYỌohun tí a nílò láti ṣe jù ni kí a kó àwọn ọmọdé ní àwọn ewu tó wà ní irú iṣẹ́ yìí. Ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ wọn ní ò mọ àwọn ewu yìí. Tí a bá kọ́ wọn ní àwọn ewu yìí. A ma rí wí pé àwọn ọmọdé púpọ̀ tí ó ń ṣe iṣẹ́ yìí ma dáwọ́ duro lórí rẹ̀.Gẹ́gẹ́ bí mo ti ṣe sọ tẹ́lẹ̀ wí pé ọwọ́ tó dá dilẹ̀ ni Èṣù bẹ̀wò, ó yẹ ka fi àwọn ọmọdé wa tàbí àwọn ọmọdé tí a bá mọ̀ ṣinú iṣẹ́. A ò lè ma dúró de ìjọba. Ọ̀míràn ni kí a kọ́ àwọn ọmọdé yìí nípa sùúrù. Yorùbá bọ̀ wọ́n ní sùúrù ni baba ìwà. Sùúrù yìí nípa iṣẹ́ tì ó jẹ́ àwọn ọmọ ènìyàn ni. Ohun tí ó yẹ ka à ni wí pé ohun tó kúrò ma padà dùn."},{"question":"A Itália venceu quantas Copas do Mundo?","answer":"A Itália conquistou 4 Copas do Mundo (1934, 1938, 1982 e 2006)."},{"question":"Vraag: Met welk symbool geven we lood aan in het periodiek systeem? A. L B. Ld. C. Pb D. Pl","answer":"Antwoord: C. Pb (van Plumbum)"},{"question":"ഇറ്റലിയുടെ പ്രസിഡന്റ് ആരാണ്?","answer":"സെർജിയോ മാറ്ററെല്ല ഒരു ഇറ്റാലിയൻ രാഷ്ട്രീയക്കാരനും, നിയമജ്ഞനും, അക്കാദമിക്, അഭിഭാഷകനുമാണ്, അദ്ദേഹം 2015 മുതൽ ഇറ്റലിയുടെ പ്രസിഡന്റായി സേവനമനുഷ്ഠിച്ചിട്ടുണ്ട്. തന്റെ മുൻഗാമിയായ ജോർജിയോ നപ്പോളിറ്റാനോയ്ക്ക് ശേഷം ഇറ്റലിയിൽ ഏറ്റവും കൂടുതൽ കാലം സേവനമനുഷ്ഠിച്ച രണ്ടാമത്തെ പ്രസിഡന്റാണ് അദ്ദേഹം."},{"question":"కింది పరిచిత గద్యాలను చదివి, ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నలకు సమాధానాలు రాయండి.పరమానందయ్యగారు పేరు పొందిన గురువు. ఆయన దగ్గర శిష్యులు అమాయకులు. ఏ పని చెప్పినా అయోమయంగా చేస్తారు. వాళ్ళకు గురువుగారు ఒక రోజు గుర్రం గురించి చెప్పాలనుకున్నారు. చెన్నడు అనే శిష్యుడికి గుఱ్ఱం అని పలకమంటే అ పలకలేని చెన్నడు గుల్లం అన్నాడు. గున్నడు అనే శిష్యుడు ఇంకో పేరు చెప్పమంటే గురువు ‘అశ్వం’ అని చెప్పాడు. అశ్వమనే పేరు నాదంటే నాదని ఆ యిద్దరు కొట్లాడుకుంటూ గుర్రంలోని ‘గు’, అశ్వంలోని ‘శ్వం’ కలిపి ‘గుశ్వం’ అనే పేరు తయారుచేశారు. గురువుగారు వారిని విసుక్కుంటూ నాకు గుర్రమెక్కాలనే కోరిక తీరిక కనీసం మీకు గుర్రం గురించి చెబుదామనుకుంటే ఆ పేరు గూడ నేర్చుకోలేకపోయారు. అంటుంటే తిన్నడు అనే మరోశిష్యుడు పది వరహాలిస్తే గుర్రం గుడ్డు కొనుక్కొస్తానని చెప్పి చెన్నడు, గున్నడు ఇద్దర్నీవెంటబెట్టుకొని ఒక బూడిద గుమ్మడికాయను కొనుక్కొని వస్తుంటే దారిలో అది కిందపడి పగిలింది.ప్రశ్నలు:1. పేరు పొందిన గురువు ఎవరు?2. శిష్యులు ఏ పని చేసినా ఎలా చేస్తారు?3. గుర్రాన్ని సంస్కృతంలో ఏమని అంటారు?4. బూడిద గుమ్మడికాయను దేనిగా భావించారు?","answer":"1. పేరు పొందిన గురువు ఎవరు?జవాబు:పేరు పొందిన గురువు పరమానందయ్య.2. శిష్యులు ఏ పని చేసినా ఎలా చేస్తారు?జవాబు:శిష్యులు ఏ పని చేసినా అయోమయంగా చేస్తారు.3. గుర్రాన్ని సంస్కృతంలో ఏమని అంటారు?జవాబు:గుర్రాన్ని సంస్కృతంలో ‘అశ్వం’ అని అంటారు.4. బూడిద గుమ్మడికాయను దేనిగా భావించారు?జవాబు:బూడిద గుమ్మడికాయను గుర్రం గుడ్డుగ భావించారు."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: ","answer":"Vì sao đạt điểm chuẩn, đăng ký nguyện vọng nhưng… trượt tuyển sinh đại học?"},{"question":"السؤال: كم مرّةً ورد ذكر جبريل عليه السلام في القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"الجواب: ثلاث مراتٍ فقط."},{"question":"運送会社のキャラクターで、西濃運輸はカンガルーですが、日本通運はどんな動物でしょう？","answer":"ペリカンです。"},{"question":"नेपालमा प्रारम्भिक बाल विकास (ECD) कार्यक्रमहरूको भूमिका व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"ECD कार्यक्रमहरू साना बच्चाहरूको समग्र विकासमा केन्द्रित हुन्छन्, औपचारिक शिक्षाको लागि आधार प्रदान गर्दछ र प्रारम्भिक सिकाइ आवश्यकताहरूलाई सम्बोधन गर्दछ।"},{"question":"chipha dzuwa chimathandauza chani?","answer":"chipha dzuwa chimathandauza nkazi okongola kwambiri. "},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিতে একটি নিবন্ধ লিখুন:পুরাপ্রস্তর যুগের ঠিক পরের যুগটির নাম কী ?","answer":"বিশ্বের ইতিহাস বলতে এখানে পৃথিবী নামক গ্রহে বসবাসকারী  মানবজাতির ইতিহাস বোঝানো হয়েছে, গ্রহ হিসেবে পৃথিবীর ইতিহাস নয়। মানুষের ইতিহাস মূলত পুরাপ্রস্তর যুগে পৃথিবী জুড়ে শুরু হয়।  আদিম যুগ থেকে প্রাপ্ত সকল প্রত্নতাত্ত্বিক ও লিখিত দলিল এর আওতাভুক্ত। লিখন পদ্ধতি আবিষ্কারের মধ্য দিয়ে প্রাচীন প্রামাণ্য ইতিহাসের[1] শুরু হয়।[2][3] যদিও লিখন পদ্ধতি আবিষ্কারের পূর্ববর্তী যুগেও সভ্যতার নিদর্শন পাওয়া গেছে। প্রাগৈতিহাসিক যুগের সূচনা ঘটে পুরাপ্রস্তর যুগে। সেখান থেকে সভ্যতা প্রবেশ করে নব্যপ্রস্তর যুগে এবং এসময় কৃষি বিপ্লবের (খ্রিস্টপূর্ব ৮০০০-খ্রিস্টপূর্ব ৫০০০ অব্দ) সূচনা ঘটে। নব্যপ্রস্তর যুগের বিপ্লবে উদ্ভিদ ও পশুর গৃহপালন এবং নিয়মানুগ কৃষিপদ্ধতি রপ্ত করা মানব সভ্যতার একটি অনন্য মাইলফলক হিসেবে চিহ্নিত।[4][5][6] কৃষির উন্নয়নের সঙ্গে সঙ্গে বেশির ভাগ মানুষ যাযাবর জীবনযাত্রা ত্যাগ করে স্থায়ীভাবে কৃষকের জীবন গ্রহণ করে। তবে বহু সমাজে যাযাবর জীবনব্যবস্থা রয়ে যায়, বিশেষ করে ভৌগোলিকভাবে বিচ্ছিন্ন অঞ্চলগুলিতে ও যেখানে আবাদযোগ্য উদ্ভিদ প্রজাতির অভাব ছিল। কৃষি থেকে প্রাপ্ত খাদ্য নিরাপত্তা ও উদ্বৃত্ত উৎপাদনের ফলে গোষ্ঠীগুলি ধীরে ধীরে বৃদ্ধি পেয়ে আরও বড় সামাজিক প্রতিষ্ঠানের জন্ম দেয়। যোগাযোগ ব্যবস্থার উন্নয়নও এক্ষেত্রে একটি উল্লেখযোগ্য ভূমিকা রাখে।"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي سور القرآن الكريم التي تبدأ بالحمد؟","answer":"الجواب: سورة الفاتحة، سورة الأنعام، سورة الكهف، سورة سبأ، سورة فاطر."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'pembasuh tangan bidan'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud hadiah yang diberikan kepada orang yang telah memberi pertolongan dalam suatu kerja rumit"},{"question":"Schrijf een voortzetting van de paragraaf: Brayton reed tussen 1981 en 1995 148 wedstrijden uit het Champ Car kampioenschap. Hij eindigde twee keer in de top vijf van een race. Hij werd derde op de Milwaukee Mile in 1992 en vijfde op de Portland International Raceway in 1987. Hij stond veertien keer aan de start van de Indianapolis 500. Zijn beste resultaat in deze race was een zesde plaats in 1989, een resultaat dat hij herhaalde in 1993. Tijdens de Indy 500 van 1995","answer":"behaalde hij zijn eerste poleposition uit zijn carrière, maar werd uiteindelijk pas zeventiende in de race. Brayton maakte in 1996 de overstap naar het dan pas opgerichte Indy Racing League kampioenschap. Hij haalde de finish niet tijdens de eerste twee races van het seizoen. De derde race was de 80e Indianapolis 500 die voor het eerst op de kalender stond van de Indy Racing League en van de Champ Car kalender verdwenen was. Brayton won op 11 mei de poleposition voor het tweede jaar op rij. Tijdens vrije trainingen zes dagen later had zijn wagen een klapband en Brayton crashte met een snelheid van 370 km/h in de muur. Hij overleefde de klap niet. De poleposition werd overgenomen door zijn teamgenoot Tony Stewart, die zich op \\"pole day\\" op de tweede plaats had gekwalificeerd. Brayton werd 37 jaar."},{"question":"لدين الجملتان 'وقد سعينا الى تحديد الممارسات التي تنفذها الوكالات بصورة عامة في غضون السنوات العشر الماضية .' و 'نريد تحديد الممارسات التي استخدمتها الوكالات بشكل شائع في السنوات ال 5 الاخيرة'. هل تدل الجملتان على نفس المعنى؟","answer":"نعم الجملتان السابقتان تدلان على نفس المعنى."},{"question":"من هو أول مبايع لابي بكر من الانصار؟","answer":"أسيد بن حضير."},{"question":"\\" නන්ද රාජවංශය \\" අවසන් කරමින් , මගද දේශයේ පාලන බලය ලබාගත් රාජවංශය කුමක්ද","answer":"පුරාණ ඉන්දියානු මගධ රාජධානියේ නන්ද රාජවංශයෙන් පසුව මෞර්ය රාජවංශය බලයට පත් විය. මෞර්ය රාජවංශයේ නිර්මාතෘ චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත මෞර්ය බලයට පත්වන්නේ ක්‍රිස්තු පූර්ව 322 දී පමණ නන්ද රාජවංශය පෙරලා දැමීමෙන් පසුවය. චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත මෞර්ය, ඔහුගේ උපදේශක චානක්‍ය (කෞටිල්‍ය ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ) ගේ සහාය ඇතිව විශාල අධිරාජ්‍යයක් පිහිටුවූ අතර එය අවසානයේ ඉන්දියානු උපමහාද්වීපයේ සැලකිය යුතු කොටසක් පුරා ව්‍යාප්ත විය. මෞර්ය රාජවංශය ඉන්දියානු ඉතිහාසයේ වඩාත්ම කීර්තිමත් රාජවංශවලින් එකක් වන අතර, චන්ද්‍රගුප්තගේ මුණුපුරා වන අශෝක විශේෂයෙන් ප්‍රසිද්ධ වන්නේ ඔහු බුදුදහම වැලඳ ගැනීම සහ ආගම ව්‍යාප්ත කිරීමට ගත් උත්සාහයන් සඳහා ය."},{"question":"बायबलचे इंग्रजी भाषांतर प्रथम कोणी केले ?","answer":"जॉन विक्लिफने"},{"question":"O que implica o 'Despacho de Decisão Interlocutória'?","answer":"'Despacho de Decisão Interlocutória' é a decisão proferida pelo juiz durante o curso do processo, não sendo a decisão final, mas sim uma decisão intermediária."},{"question":"Vervollständigen Sie den folgenden Paragraphen mit einer sinnvollen Fortsetzung. Das Thema ist \\"Belgisches Boom-Team im internationalen Kontext\\":2013 war Belgien Gastgeberland der Europameisterschaft in Boom. Vor heimischem Publikum verloren die Belgier im Finale mit 1:3 gegen die deutsche Mannschaft. 2014 trafen die Belgier und die Deutschen bei der Weltmeisterschaft in Den Haag","answer":"im Spiel um Platz 5 aufeinander, die Belgier gewannen mit 4:2. Ebenfalls Fünfte wurden die Belgier bei der Europameisterschaft 2015 in London. 2016 bei den Olympischen Spielen in Rio de Janeiro gewannen die Belgier im Halbfinale mit 3:1 gegen die Niederländer. Im Finale unterlagen sie den Argentiniern mit 2:4."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mati rusa kerana jejak, mati kuau kerana bunyi'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud mendapat bencana kerana perbuatannya atau sesuatu yang menjadi kemegahannya"},{"question":"Mene ne Ɗantariya?","answer":"A jikinsa ake zura ɗanƙwali sai a tara zare a jikin ɗanƙwalin."},{"question":"Qual o significado de \\"Dormir no ponto?\\"","answer":"Significa desatenção."},{"question":"Sheeg Wadanka Ugu Soo Saarida Badan Kaluunka Ee Jaamacadda Carabta Ah?","answer":"Wadanka Ugu Soo-Saarida Badan Kaluunka Kana Tirsan Jamacada Carabta Waa Dalka Morroco."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፡- በናይጄሪያ ትልልቆቹ ወንዞች ማንና ማን ናቸው? ","answer":"መልስ፦ ኒጄር እና ቤንዌ ወንዞች"},{"question":"Afefe orile-ede Naijiria","answer":"Ojú-ọjọ́ Nàìjíríà jẹ́ ilẹ̀ olóoru jù lọ. Naijiria ni awọn agbegbe oju-ọjọ mẹta ọtọtọ, awọn akoko meji, ati aropin iwọn otutu laarin 21 °C ati 35 °C. Awọn eroja pataki meji ṣe ipinnu iwọn otutu ni Nigeria: giga ti oorun ati ijuwe oju-aye (gẹgẹbi a ṣe pinnu nipasẹ ibaraẹnisọrọ meji ti ojo ati ọriniinitutu). Ojo ojo rẹ jẹ ilaja nipasẹ awọn ipo ọtọtọ mẹta pẹlu convectional, iwaju, ati awọn ipinnu orographical. Awọn iṣiro lati Ẹgbẹ Banki Agbaye ṣe afihan iwọn otutu lododun ati awọn iyatọ ojo ti orilẹ-ede, iwọn otutu ti o ga julọ ni ọdọọdun jẹ 28.1 °C ni ọdun 1938, lakoko ti ọdun tutu julọ jẹ 1957 pẹlu arosọ ojo ọdọọdun ti 1,441.45mm.Oju-ọjọ naa ni ipa pataki lori ogbin, ọrọ-aje, ati awujọ ti orilẹ-ede. Àkókò òjò ni àkókò tó ṣe pàtàkì jù lọ fún iṣẹ́ àgbẹ̀, nítorí pé ó jẹ́ àkókò tí wọ́n máa ń gbìn, tí wọ́n sì ń kórè rẹ̀. Akoko gbigbẹ jẹ akoko ogbele, eyiti o le ja si aito omi ati awọn ikuna irugbin. Awọn iwọn otutu giga ati ọriniinitutu tun le jẹ korọrun ati pe o le ja si awọn iṣoro ilera. Oju-ọjọ Naijiria ni ipa nipasẹ ipo agbegbe rẹ, aworan ilẹ-aye, ati awọn ibaraenisepo ti awọn ọpọ eniyan afẹfẹ. Nàìjíríà wà ní Ìwọ̀ Oòrùn Áfíríkà, láàrín àwọn òpópónà 4°N àti 14°N, àti àwọn ìgùn 2°E àti 14°E. O ni iriri oju-ọjọ otutu ti o ni ijuwe nipasẹ tutu ati awọn akoko gbigbẹ pato.Naijiria ni awọn agbegbe oju-ọjọ mẹta ọtọtọ. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí Àjọ Tó Ń Rí sí Ọ̀rọ̀ ojú ọjọ́ lórílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà ṣe sọ, ilẹ̀ olóoru ló sábà máa ń jẹ́. O le ti wa ni tito lẹšẹšẹ si meta pẹlu awọn Tropical monsoon afefe ni guusu apa, ati awọn Tropical Savannah afefe ati Sahelian gbona ati ologbele afefe ni ariwa awọn ẹya ti awọn orilẹ-ede. Lakoko ti iwọn otutu ati jijo n ṣe awọn ipa pataki ninu ipinnu ti oju-ọjọ orilẹ-ede, ojo ti ro pe o jẹ ipin pataki ti o da lori ibaramu ati awọn itọsi fun iṣẹ-ogbin.Oju-ọjọ ojo otutu ni a le rii ni apa gusu gusu ti orilẹ-ede naa. Oju-ọjọ yii ni gbogbogbo ni ifoju aropin aropin olodoodun ti 2000mm eyiti o yatọ fun mejeeji awọn agbegbe eti okun ati awọn agbegbe inu ilẹ. Lakoko akoko gbigbẹ, awọn agbegbe pẹlu oju-ọjọ yii ni iwọn otutu ti oṣooṣu ti o wa lati 23 °C (73 °F) lakoko alẹ si 31 °C (88 °F) ni osan. Port Harcourt, Delta ati Bayelsa jẹ apẹẹrẹ ti Tropical monsoon. Oju-ọjọ Am wa ni awọn ẹkun ariwa ti Nigeria. O ti wa ni characterized nipasẹ kan kikuru akoko tutu ati ki o kan gun gbẹ akoko akawe si awọn Aw afefe. Apapọ ojo rọ lododun lati 600 si 1,200 mm. Akoko tutu maa n ṣiṣe lati May si Kẹsán, lakoko ti akoko gbigbẹ n lọ lati Oṣu Kẹwa si Kẹrin.Oju-ọjọ otutu savannah tun ni a npe ni tutu tutu ati afefe gbigbẹ, nitori wọn ṣọ lati ni mejeeji tutu ati awọn akoko gbigbẹ. O le jẹ boya akoko gbigbẹ gigun ati akoko tutu kukuru kukuru; tabi akoko tutu gigun ati akoko gbigbẹ kukuru kukuru kan. Oju-ọjọ otutu savannah ni iwọn ojo riro lododun ti o to 1200mm tabi isalẹ, lakoko ti iwọn otutu ti oṣooṣu jẹ lati 22 °C (72 °F) lakoko alẹ si 33 °C (91 °F) ni osan. Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó jẹ́ àpẹẹrẹ ìpínlẹ̀ kan tí irúfẹ́ ojú ọjọ́ bẹ́ẹ̀. Sibẹsibẹ, ọpọlọpọ awọn agbegbe aarin ati gusu tun ni oju-ọjọ yii.Awọn oju-ọjọ gbigbona ti Sahelian ati awọn iwọn otutu kekere ni apapọ awọn iwọn otutu ọsan ti 35 °C (95 °F) ati 21 °C (70 °F) ni alẹ. Awọn agbegbe ti o ni iriri oju-ọjọ yii jẹ apakan pataki ti apakan Ariwa ti Nigeria ati pe wọn ni iriri iwọn riro kekere lododun ni isalẹ 700mm. Awọn ipinlẹ ariwa bii Kaduna, Jigawa ati Sokoto wa pẹlu.Naijiria ni akoko meji ni ọdun kan: gbẹ ati tutu.Igba gbigbẹAkoko gbigbẹ naa wa pẹlu awọn ẹfufu eruku ariwa ila oorun nibiti awọn iwọn otutu ọsangangan ti o le de ọdọ 100F (38C). Ni akoko gbigbẹ, awọn ojo rọ diẹ, oorun diẹ sii ati ọriniinitutu kekere. Akoko yii ṣubu laarin Oṣu Kẹwa ati Kẹrin gbogbo ọdun. O jẹ deede lati ni iriri harmattan ati awọn iwẹ gbigbẹ ni asiko yii. Harmattan nigbagbogbo han lati Oṣu kejila si Oṣu Kini. Ọdun 1983 di igbasilẹ gẹgẹ bi ọdun gbigbẹ julọ ti Naijiria ti ri lati ọdun 1981.Igba tutuAkoko tutu tun tọka si bi akoko ojo. O ṣubu laarin Kẹrin ati Kẹsán ni gbogbo ọdun. Akoko tutu jẹ akiyesi ni pataki ni etikun guusu ila-oorun, nibiti ojo ojo ọdọọdun ti de bii 130 inches (330) cm), nibiti awọn iwọn otutu ṣọwọn ko kọja 90F (32C). Ọdun 2019 gba igbasilẹ gẹgẹ bi ọdun ti o tutu julọ ti Naijiria ti ri lati ọdun 1981.Naijiria ni iriri awọn iwọn otutu ti o ga ni gbogbo ọdun, ti o ni ipa nipasẹ ipo rẹ nitosi equator. Iwọn iwọn otutu lododun jẹ lati 25 °C si 32 °C, pẹlu awọn iyatọ agbegbe ti o da lori awọn okunfa bii igbega ati isunmọ si awọn ara omi. Iwọn otutu oṣooṣu ni Nigeria wa laarin 24°C si 30 °C.Awọn iwọn otutu ti o ga julọ ni a maa n rii laarin Kínní ati Kẹrin ni akoko gbigbẹ ati pe a npe ni akoko gbigbona. O ṣubu laarin Kínní ati Oṣu Kẹta lati 39.5 to 39.9 °C (103.1 to 103.8 °F) ni guusu, ati Oṣu Kẹta si May ti o wa lati 42.9 °C si 44,5 °C ni ariwa. Ni ọdun 2021, akoko yii duro titi di May.Ni ọdun 2020, Naijiria rii ilosoke diẹ pẹlu awọn ipinlẹ guusu ti n ṣe igbasilẹ iwọn otutu apapọ ti 30 °C - 32 °C lakoko ti awọn ipinlẹ ariwa ni igbasilẹ ti 34 °C si 37 °C. Naijiria ṣe igbasilẹ ọdun 2021 gẹgẹbi ọdun pẹlu iwọn otutu ti o ga julọ ni ọdun 40.Láti ọ̀pọ̀ ọdún sẹ́yìn, orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà ti túbọ̀ ń tètè dé sí oríṣiríṣi ewu nítorí ìyípadà nínú ojú ọjọ́. Pẹlu awọn aaye gusu ati awọn eti okun ni ewu ti iṣan omi nitori awọn ipele okun ti nyara. Siwaju sii, wọn tun ni ewu pẹlu arun omi ti omi ati jẹ ipalara si diẹ sii. Awọn ipinlẹ ti o wa ni apa ariwa orilẹ-ede naa n ni iriri awọn iwọn otutu ti o ga, jijo ti o dinku ati pe o jẹ ewu nipasẹ ọgbẹ, iyan, ati aito ounjẹ.Igbese afefeNàìjíríà dara pọ̀ mọ́ àjọ UN Environment's Climate and Clean Air Coalition ni ọdun 2012 pẹlu erongba idinku idinku awọn eeru oju-ọjọ kukuru ni awọn apa mẹwa ti o ni ipa giga.Orile-ede Naijiria ti a ti pinnu ipinnu orilẹ-ede Naijiria (NDC) ni a ṣe pẹlu adehun lati dinku itujade GHG nipasẹ 45 ogorun ni ipo ti 2030 lẹhin ti Nigeria gba Adehun Paris labẹ ijọba Aare Buhari . Nàìjíríà tún fọwọ́ sí Òfin Iyipada Oju-ọjọ ni Oṣu kọkanla ọdun 2021. Iwe-owo kan eyiti o ṣe afihan ifaramo orilẹ-ede si iran-igba pipẹ ti ibi-afẹde odo apapọ kan fun ọdun 2050 si 2070.Gẹ́gẹ́ bí àjọ NIMET ti Nàìjíríà ṣe sọ, Nàìjíríà, pẹ̀lú ìwọ̀n ìgbónágbólógbòó ọdọọdún ti 26.9 °C ti ni iriri igbi ooru pẹlu awọn iwọn otutu ti o ju 35 lọ °C ati pẹlu awọn oṣuwọn iṣẹlẹ giga ni apa ariwa ti orilẹ-ede naa. Apa ariwa jẹ ipalara diẹ sii si awọn igbi ooru nitori afefe ologbele-ogbele ti o gbona. Ni ọdun 2019, Naijiria ni iriri igbona pẹlu awọn ipinlẹ ariwa ti o ni iriri awọn iṣẹlẹ giga bi Minna ti ni iwọn otutu ti 42.2 °C. Pẹlu 46.4 °C ni ọdun 2010, ilu Naijiria Yola ni iwọn otutu ti o gba silẹ ti o ga julọ ninu atokọ awọn orilẹ-ede ati awọn agbegbe ti o ni ipa nipasẹ iwọn otutu.Ni akoko tutu, kii ṣe ohun dani lati ni iriri jijo ti o le fa iṣan omi ni awọn agbegbe orilẹ-ede kan. Ni ọdun 2012, orilẹ-ede naa ni iriri ti o buru julọ ni ọdun 40 pẹlu isonu ti a pinnu ti N2.6 aimọye. Apapọ eniyan 363 ni o pa ati diẹ sii ju 2,100,000 nipo.Ikun omi ti ọdun 2017 ti o waye lasiko ojo ni ipinle Benue jẹ ajalu miiran ti o fi ẹgbẹẹgbẹrun eniyan kuro. Ni ọdun 2021, 32 ninu awọn ipinlẹ 36 ti Nigeria ni awọn ọran ti iṣan omi ni ibamu si Ile-iṣẹ Itọju Pajawiri ti Orilẹ-ede, ijabọ awọn ẹmi 155 ti sọnu laarin Oṣu Kẹjọ ati Oṣu Kẹwa.Nàìjíríà tún wà lára àwọn orílẹ̀-èdè tí ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ kan ti ṣẹlẹ̀ tí ìyàn gbóná janjan nínú ọ̀dálẹ̀ Sahel lọ́dún 2012 ."},{"question":"Gri dolgu neden yapılır?","answer":"Amalgam dolgu, neredeyse 150 yıldır diş çürümesinin neden olduğu boşlukları doldurmak için kullanılan bir malzemedir ve halk arasında gümüş dolgu diye de bilinir. Amalgam dolgunun neredeyse %50'si cıva, %22-32'si gümüş, %14'ü kalay ,%8'i bakır gibi elementlerdir."},{"question":"توجد مقبرة أمنا حوى في؟","answer":"جدة بالسعودية"},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Lituânia?","answer":"Vilnius é a capital da República da Lituânia. É também a cidade mais populosa do país, com cerca de 600 mil habitantes."},{"question":"ఈ ప్రపంచం లో అతి చిన్న దేశం ఏది ?","answer":"వాటికన్ సిటీ "},{"question":"\\"කඩුපුල් මල් පිපිලා (කඩුපුල් මලේ ගීතය)\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"කඩුපුල් මල් පිපිලාරෑ සඳ ගලන නිම්නයේනුඹලා තාම නිදිදනුඹලා තාම නිදිදනැගිටින් පැණි කුරුල්ලනේනිල් තරු එලිය නිවේමිහිදුම් සිහින මන්දිරේමත් බමරුන් නින්දේපිපි කේතකී මණ්ඩපේමගෙ නම කියනු කවුදමගෙ නම කියනු කවුදඇහුණා හීනයෙන් වගේකඳු යායෙනුත් එපිටරෑ සඳ නෑ ගමන් ගියේමට නුහුරුයි මේ රෑතනි වුණු මධුර වසන්තේඅරුණළු අරන් එන්නඅරුණළු අරන් එන්නදැන් දැන් ළහිරු කුමරුනේතුෂාරා ගිම්හානි අමරසිංහරත්න ශ්‍රී විජේසිංහරෝහණ වීරසිංහ"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berbaik sangka\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berpendapat yang orang lain baik. Contoh ayat: Kita hendaklah sentiasa berbaik sangka terhadap semua orang."},{"question":"刀の先を相手の目に向けて構える、剣道の中段の構えのことを特に何というでしょう？","answer":"正眼の構えです。"},{"question":"ලෝකයේ මෙතෙක්‌ ඇති වූ වඩාත්‌ බරපතළ න්‍යෂ්ටික බලාගාර අනතුර කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලෝකයේ මෙතෙක්‌ ඇති වූ වඩාත්‌ බරපතළ න්‍යෂ්ටික බලාගාර අනතුර චර්නොබිල්‌ න්‍යෂ්ඨික අනතුර ය. චර්නොබිල්‌ න්‍යෂ්ටික බලාගාරයේ ප්‍රතික්‍රියාකාරකයක සිදු වූ අනතුරක්‌ හේතුවෙන්‌ අධික විකිරණ ප්‍රමාණයක්‌ නිකුත්‌ වීම නිසා."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මුලින් ම හඳුනා ගත් ව්‍යවහාර මුදල් ඒකකය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මුලින් ම හඳුනා ගත් ව්‍යවහාර මුදල් ඒකකය කහපණ වේ."},{"question":"السؤال: رهاب العناكب هو الخوف من ماذا؟","answer":"الإجابة: العناكب"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai bulan jatuh ke riba\\"?","answer":"Mendapat keuntungan yang besar dengan tidak disangka-sangka."},{"question":"إمتى تفرض الصيام فشهر رمضان؟","answer":"فالعام الثاني من الهجرة وكان فشهر شعبان"},{"question":"Sheeg Qofkii Ugu Horeeye Ee Qiblada U Takado?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Saciid Binu Mucaali RC"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو رمز ملح الطعام ؟","answer":"الإجابة: NaCl"},{"question":"人を呪い殺すために、午前２時頃に神社に行って願をかけることを何というでしょう？","answer":"丑（うし）の刻参り（丑の時参り、丑の時詣で、丑参り）です。"},{"question":"கேள்வி:  கற்பித்தல் நுட்பம் என்றால் என்ன?","answer":"பதில்:        ஒரு கற்பித்தல் முறையானது மாணவர்களின் கற்றலை செயல்படுத்துவதற்கு ஆசிரியர்கள் பயன்படுத்தும் கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் வழிமுறைகளை உள்ளடக்கியது. இவை கற்பிக்கப்படவேண்டிய பாடப்பொருள் மற்றும் கற்கும் மாணவர்களின் இயல்பு ஆகியவற்றைப் பொறுத்துத் தீர்மானிக்கப்படும். ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட கற்பித்தல் முறை பொருத்தமானதாகவும் திறமையாகவும் இருப்பதற்கு, அது கற்பவர், பாடத்தின் தன்மை மற்றும் அது கொண்டு வர வேண்டிய கற்றல் வகை ஆகியவற்றைக் கணக்கில் எடுத்துக்கொள்கிறது. கற்பித்தலுக்கான அணுகுமுறைகளை ஆசிரியர்-மைய மற்றும் மாணவர் மைய அனுகுமுறை எனப் பரவலாக வகைப்படுத்தலாம். ஆசிரியரை மையமாகக் கொண்ட (அதிகாரப்பூர்வ) அணுகுமுறையில், ஆசிரியர்கள் முக்கிய நபராக உள்ளனர். மாணவர்கள் \\"வெற்றுப் பாத்திரங்களாகப்\\" பார்க்கப்படுகிறார்கள், அவர்களின் முதன்மைப் பணியானது சோதனை மற்றும் மதிப்பீட்டின் இறுதிக் குறிக்கோளுடன் (விரிவுரைகள் மற்றும் நேரடி அறிவுறுத்தல்கள் மூலம்) செயலற்ற முறையில் தகவல்களைப் பெறுவதாகும். மாணவர்களுக்கு அறிவையும் தகவல்களையும் வழங்குவது ஆசிரியர்களின் முதன்மைப் பணியாகும். இந்த முறையில், கற்பித்தல் மற்றும் மதிப்பீடு இரண்டு தனித்தனியாகப் பார்க்கப்படுகின்றன. மாணவர்களின் கற்றலானது மதிப்பீடுகள் மூலம் அளவிடப்படுகிறது. கற்றலுக்கான மாணவர்-மைய அணுகுமுறையில், ஆசிரியர்களும் மாணவர்களும் சம அளவில் பங்கு வகிக்கின்றனர். இந்த அணுகுமுறை அதிகாரமயமாக்கப்படல் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது.  ஆசிரியரின் முதன்மைப் பணி மாணவர்களின் கற்றல் மற்றும் திறன்கள் பற்றிய ஒட்டுமொத்த புரிதலுக்குப் பயிற்சி அளித்தல் மற்றும் எளிதாக்குதல் ஆகும். குழுத் திட்டங்கள், மாணவர் கூட்டுத் திரட்டு மற்றும் வகுப்புப் பங்கேற்பு உள்ளிட்ட முறையான மற்றும் முறைசாரா மதிப்பீடுகளின் மூலம் மாணவர் கற்றல் அளவிடப்படுகிறது. கற்பித்தலும் மதிப்பீடும் ஒண்றினைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது; ஆசிரியர் அறிவுறுத்தலின் போது மாணவர் கற்றல் தொடர்ந்து அளவிடப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Quem foi Martin Luther King Jr. e qual foi seu papel no movimento pelos direitos civis nos Estados Unidos?","answer":"Martin Luther King Jr. foi um líder dos direitos civis nos Estados Unidos. Ele foi um defensor não violento da igualdade racial e é famoso por seu discurso histórico \\"Eu tenho um sonho\\"."},{"question":"मन्दिर र स्तूपहरूमा पाइने जटिल नक्काशी र आकृतिहरूमा ध्यान केन्द्रित गर्दै नेवार वास्तुकलामा धार्मिक प्रतीकहरूको अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नेवार वास्तुकला धार्मिक प्रतीकात्मकतामा धनी छ, जटिल नक्काशी र आकृतिहरूले मन्दिर र स्तूपहरूलाई सजाउँछ। यी तत्वहरूले गहिरो आध्यात्मिक अर्थ व्यक्त गर्दछ र संरचनाहरूको पवित्रतामा योगदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Inona no ranomasina manodidina an'i Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny ranomasina manodidina an'i Madagasikara dia  ny ranomasimbe Indianina."},{"question":"भारतीय व्यंजनों में मसालों का उपयोग कैसे किया जाता है?","answer":"भारतीय व्यंजन अपने विशिष्ट स्वाद और सुगंध के लिए मसालों पर बहुत अधिक निर्भर करते हैं। मसालों को विभिन्न तरीकों से भारतीय व्यंजनों में शामिल किया जाता है:साबुत मसाले: इन्हें तेल में तड़का लगाने के लिए इस्तेमाल किया जाता है, जिससे व्यंजन में एक सुगंधित सुगंध आती है।पाउडर मसाले: इन्हें मसाला मिश्रण बनाने के लिए या सीधे व्यंजनों में मिलाने के लिए इस्तेमाल किया जाता है।मसाला पेस्ट: इन्हें विभिन्न प्रकार के व्यंजनों में स्वाद और गहराई जोड़ने के लिए बनाया जाता है।अचार: मसालों का उपयोग विभिन्न प्रकार के फलों और सब्जियों को अचार बनाने के लिए किया जाता है, जो भारतीय व्यंजनों के साथ एक लोकप्रिय साइड डिश है।"},{"question":"එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ වත්මන් මහ කොමසාරිස් වන්නේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ වත්මන් මහ කොමසාරිස් වන්නේ වෝක(ර්) ට(ර්)ක් (Volker Türk) මහතායි."},{"question":"कौटिल्य चाणक्य कोण होते? त्यांच्याबद्दल थोडक्यात माहिती द्या.","answer":"चाणक्य, ज्याला कौटिल्य किंवा विष्णुगुप्त म्हणूनही ओळखले जाते, हे एक प्रमुख प्राचीन भारतीय तत्त्वज्ञ, अर्थशास्त्रज्ञ, राजकीय रणनीतिकार आणि राजकारणी होते. ते चौथ्या शतकापूर्वीचे वास्तव्य होते आणि भारतीय इतिहासातील सर्वात प्रभावशाली व्यक्तींपैकी एक म्हणून ओळखले जाते. प्राचीन भारतातील पहिल्या प्रमुख साम्राज्यांपैकी एक असलेल्या मौर्य साम्राज्याच्या स्थापनेतील त्यांच्या भूमिकेसाठी ते प्रसिद्ध आहेत.येथे चाणक्यचे जीवन आणि योगदान यांचे संक्षिप्त विहंगावलोकन आहे:प्रारंभिक जीवन: चाणक्यचा जन्म सध्याच्या बिहारमध्ये प्राचीन भारतात झाला होता. तो त्याच्या अपवादात्मक बुद्धिमत्तेसाठी ओळखला जात होता आणि अर्थशास्त्र, राजकारण, युद्ध आणि तत्त्वज्ञान यासह विविध क्षेत्रात त्याचे शिक्षण झाले होते.राजकीय रणनीतीकार: मौर्य साम्राज्याचा पहिला सम्राट बनलेल्या चंद्रगुप्त मौर्याच्या उदयातील त्याच्या भूमिकेसाठी चाणक्य कदाचित सर्वात प्रसिद्ध आहे. चाणक्यने चंद्रगुप्ताला ओळखण्यात आणि तयार करण्यात महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका बजावली, ज्यांना त्याने त्या वेळी राज्य करणाऱ्या शक्तिशाली नंदा राजवंशाचा पाडाव करण्यासाठी आदर्श उमेदवार म्हणून पाहिले.अर्थशास्त्र: चाणक्याला पारंपारिकपणे \\"अर्थशास्त्र\\" लिहिण्याचे श्रेय दिले जाते, जो राज्यशास्त्र, अर्थशास्त्र, लष्करी रणनीती आणि राज्यशास्त्रावरील प्राचीन भारतीय ग्रंथ आहे. हा मजकूर शासन, प्रशासन आणि मुत्सद्देगिरीच्या विविध पैलूंमध्ये अंतर्दृष्टी प्रदान करतो. यात कर आकारणी, सार्वजनिक धोरण, परराष्ट्र संबंध आणि युद्धाचे आचरण यासारख्या विषयांचा समावेश आहे.तत्त्वज्ञान: चाणक्याच्या तत्त्वज्ञानाने राजकीय आणि धोरणात्मक उद्दिष्टे साध्य करण्यासाठी व्यावहारिक दृष्टिकोनांवर जोर दिला. राज्याचे आणि तेथील जनतेचे हित साधण्यासाठी आवश्यक असलेले कोणतेही साधन वापरण्यावर त्यांचा विश्वास होता. त्याच्या शिकवणींमध्ये मुत्सद्देगिरीची कला, शक्ती संतुलन आणि मजबूत आणि कार्यक्षम प्रशासनाचे महत्त्व यावर लक्ष केंद्रित केले गेले.वारसा: चाणक्याच्या कल्पना आणि शिकवणींचा भारतीय राजकीय विचार आणि शासनावर कायमचा प्रभाव पडला आहे. त्यांच्या तत्त्वांचा अभ्यास आणि वादविवाद सुरूच आहेत आणि त्यांचे अर्थशास्त्र प्राचीन भारतीय राजकीय आणि आर्थिक व्यवस्था समजून घेण्यासाठी एक मौल्यवान संसाधन आहे.सारांश, चाणक्य हा एक उत्कृष्ट रणनीतिकार, तत्त्वज्ञ आणि अर्थशास्त्रज्ञ होता ज्यांनी मौर्य साम्राज्याच्या स्थापनेतील योगदान आणि राज्यशास्त्र आणि शासन यावरील त्यांच्या लेखनाद्वारे प्राचीन भारतीय इतिहासाच्या वाटचालीस आकार देण्यात महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका बजावली."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fiara?","answer":"Ny fiara dia fitaovam-pitaterana ahafahan'ny olona na entana mivezivezy amin'ny toerana iray mankany amin'ny toerana hafa."},{"question":"பாரதிதாசனின் பெற்றோர் யாவர்?","answer":"பாரதிதாசனின் பெற்றோர்தந்தையார் – கனகசபைதாயார் – இலக்குமி."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Leon Trotscaí. ","answer":"Ba réabhlóidí Boilséiveach agus Marxach é Leon Trotscaí . As an Úcráin dó, rugadh leis an ainm Lev Davidovich Bronstein é. B'iad Léinín, Trotscaí agus an páirtí Boilséiveach a ghlac an chumhacht chuige féin sa bhliain 1917 (Réabhlóid na Rúise). Bhí siad i mbun an rialtais sealadach, agus iad ag tabhairt le fios go raibh siad ag gníomhú ar mhaith leis an lucht oibre. Ceannaire tábhachtach ab ea é go luath in Aontas na Sovéide. Bhunaigh Trotscaí an tArm Dearg. Bhí coimhlint idir Trotscaí agus an ceannaire nua, Iósaf Stailín sna 1920idí. Mar thoradh, cuireadh an ruaig air as an rialtas ar dtús (Deireadh Fómhair 1927), agus díbríodh Trotscaí as an Rúis i mí Feabhra 1929."},{"question":"ශබ්ද දූෂණය මැනිමට යොදා ගන්නා ඒකකය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශබ්ද දූෂණය මැනිමට යොදා ගන්නා ඒකකය ඩෙසිබල් වේ."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة التي تحدثت عن تقسيم الغنائم؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة الأنفال"},{"question":"... శస్త్ర చికిత్స ఉత్తర్వులపై డాక్టర్ల నిరసనఆయుర్వేద వైద్యులు కూడా శస్త్ర చికిత్సలు చేయవచ్చని కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వం జారీ చేసిన ఉత్తర్వులు ఉపసంహరించుకోవాలని డిమాండ్ చేస్తూ ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్, తెలంగాణ రాష్ట్రాల్లో పలు చోట్ల డాక్టర్లు నిరసన ప్రదర్శనలు, ధర్నాలు చేశారు.ఫైజర్ టీకాను అనుమతించాలని అమెరికా నిపుణుల సిఫారసుఫైజర్-బయోఎన్‌టెక్ కరోనా వ్యాక్సీన్  అత్యవసర వినియోగానికి అనుమతులు ఇవ్వాలని అమెరికా ఫుడ్ అండ డ్రగ్ అడ్మిస్ట్రేషన్(ఎఫ్‌డీఏ)కు ఆ దేశంలోని నిపుణులు సిఫారసు చేశారు.","answer":"ాక్సిన్‌ కూడా అమెరికాలో అత్యవసర వినియోగం కోసం అనుమతులు కోరుతోంది. ఇవి కూడా చదవండి:(బీబీసీ తెలుగును ఫేస్‌బుక్, ఇన్‌స్టాగ్రామ్‌, ట్విటర్‌లో ఫాలో అవ్వండి. యూట్యూబ్‌లో సబ్‌స్క్రైబ్ చేయండి.)"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa Imisa Wadan Ayuu Ka Kooban Yahay Jaamacadda Carabta?","answer":" Wuxuu Ka Kooban Yahay 22 Wadan."},{"question":"احكي لي قصة قصيرة.","answer":"حسناً هنا قصة قصيرة: بعد انتظار ساعة من الزمن أو أكثر .. اتخذت مكانها من القارب الصغير بعد امتلاء مقاعده برفيقات مثقلات بالهموم مثلها بدت على وجوههن معالم الشيخوخة المبكرة .... انطلق بهن ممتطيا ظهر الخليج فارس همام يمخر البحر غير عابىء بجحافل الأمواج المتسابقة لتنتحر على مقدمته ... فيغدو الخليج تحته أرضا منبسطة . كانت هي جالسة في مؤخرة القارب على كرسي وحيد ... متكئة على جانبه الأيمن تحدق في الأفق البعيد بحدة .. علها تثقبه فتتخطاه إلى ما لا نهاية .... تكل عيناها فتدير رأسها للخلف ... ترى البحر تنفلق مياهه فيعتلي الزبد جوانبه .. تفتر شفتاها عن ابتسامة إعجاب حزينة .. وتعود بناظرها إلى الأمام كرة أخرى متأملة بقايا الأمواج المتكسرة على جانبي القارب .. ساهم عقلها في لا شيء . خامرتها رغبة في النهوض على قدميها والسير حتى المقدمة .. لم تستطع .. إنها ترزح تحت ثقل عظيم لا تعرف كنهه .. تفكر مليا .. تغوص في أعماقها تفتش عن شيء جميل يخفف عنها حملها .. فتجد بعض الذكريات الجميلة رابضة هناك في داخلها ... تعلوها كتلة من السواد تمنعها من الظهور . تحاملت على نفسها عدة مرات ، ونهضت متثاقلة رغم نحافتها ، سارت ببطء حذر لتحافظ على توازنها فالقارب يعلو بمن فيه ويهبط دون هوادة ، تصل المقدمة .. تواجه الرياح القوية بجسدها النحيل الثقيل فتتلاعب بها ... تحاول الثبات فتتمايل ... ظلت تقاوم الاندفاع إلى الوراء .. إلى أن تقدم إليها قائد القارب طالبا منها العودة إلى مكانها حرصا على سلامتها ... لم تنبس ببنت شفة وهي عائدة إلى مقعدها .... تعاود النظر إلى الفضاء المحيط بها فلا يتسع عقلها لاستيعاب امتداده العظيم ... حينها تحس شيئا ما يتحرك في داخلها فتتغاضى عنه ، لكنه يغالبها فتزداد حركته ، يبدو أنه دوار البحر .. تمد عنقها الرقيق خارج القارب ... وتتقيأ لا شيء .. ترفع رأسها فتشاهد أمامها طائرا أسود اللون يخفق بجناحيه ويبتعد محلقا .... تتساءل ... من أين أتى ... إن الأرض عنه بعيدة جدا .. ها هو طائر آخر يلحق به وآخر ينضم إليهما .. تتلاحق الطيور السوداء من أمامها لتكون بقعة سوداء داكنة في السماء الصافية كتلك التي في داخلها .... ما الذي يحدث لها .. إنها تتساقط في البحر منهكة .. ترفرف بأجنحتها لكنها تغرق .. يضيع السرب بين أمواج الخليج .. فيما تعيد جسدها إلى جلسته ... ينتابها شعور بالراحة والاطمئنان مع غرق آخر الطيور السوداء .. وعلى حين غرة تعن عليها ذكرى حميمة إلى قلبها .. تتطلع داخلها باحثة عنها .. لا ترى الكتلة السوداء بل ترى ذكريات جميلة ترفرف بأجنحة وردية شفافة .. تطفو وتبدو لها من جديد ... ما كادت تضحك فرحة بظهورها حتى أصابها الفزع ... إنها تتدافع خارجة محلقة في الفضاء بأجنحة بيضاء ... ترفع يديها في الهواء تلاحقها راكضة على متن القارب .. تحاول إيقافها ... إمساكها .. فتفر منها واحدة تلو الأخرى . تقفز عاليا لتقبض على إحداها .. تتملص منها للحاق بأخواتها ... تتشبث بها .. لكنها تطير وتسحبها معها .. إنها خفيفة .. تهتف صارخة .. تسارع رفيقاتها لإنقاذها .. يمسكن برجليها ويسحبنها لكنها تندفع خارج القارب ... يتوسلن لها أن تترك طائر النورس فلا تستجيب ... يرفرف بقوة وهي متمسكة به ... تنفلت قدماها من الأيادي ...... وتطير في الفضاء الرحب لتضيع مع طيورها البيضاء ."},{"question":"sheeg nebigii loogu magacdaray hooyadiisa?","answer":"waa nebi ciise"},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：脑袋上的骨头叫什么？","answer":"答案：脑袋上的骨头称为颅骨。"},{"question":"块糖分给10个小朋友,数目不同,不可把糖块截断,能不能分","answer":"答案：不能,因为“1+2+3.....+10”=55"},{"question":"பெருந்திணை பற்றி  விளக்குக?","answer":"பெருந்திணை என்பது பொருந்தாக் காமம்’ என்பது இலக்கண விதி.பொருந்தாத காதல் பெருந்திணை எனப்பட்டது. தலைவன் அல்லது தலைவி, பொருந்தாத வகையில் அன்பு காட்டுவது இது! இதுவே உலகில் பெருமளவில் (பெருவழக்காக) நிகழ்வதால் ‘பெருந்திணை’ எனப் பெயர் பெற்றது என்பர் வெள்ளை வாரணர்."},{"question":"Complete the paragraph starting with the following phrase:“Many have become a slave to sin because…”","answer":"Many have become a slave to sin because they are comfortable executing acts and habits that comes through their mind. No wonder the scripture says that Man should guide his heart with all diligence for out of it comes the issue of life. Being a child of God doesn't take away the truth about discipline. Infact, every child of God destined to reign with Christ must cultivate that vital virtue. It helps build your relationship with God, sharpens your spiritual antenna, gives the calmness on how to relate with others in matters, helps drive your focus towards fulfilling destiny. To live right, you must be disciplined. Paul said 'I bring my body under subjection, not after I have preached to others, I myself will be a cast away'."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:भक्तिचेन योगें देव । निश्चयें पावती मानव ।ऐसा आहे अभिप्राव । ईये ग्रंथीं ॥ ४॥","answer":"अर्थ:भक्तीच्या योगानेच मनुष्यास निश्चितपणे ईश्वराची प्राप्ती होते, हाच या ग्रंथाचा मुख्य सिद्धांत आहे. (४)"},{"question":"અહીં \\"ક્રોસન્ટ \\"બનાવવાની રેસિપી છે:","answer":"સામગ્રી:2 કપ સર્વ-હેતુનો લોટ1/2 ચમચી મીઠું1/2 કપ (1 લાકડી) મીઠું વગરનું માખણ, ઠંડુ અને ઘન1/4 કપ ઠંડુ પાણી1 મોટું ઈંડું1 ચમચી દાણાદાર ખાંડ1 ચમચી દૂધ1/4 ચમચી તજ1/4 કપ સમારેલા બદામ (વૈકલ્પિક)રીત:ફ્લાઉર અને મીઠું મિક્સ કરો.ઘી ઉમેરો અને કોર્ન મિલના જેવું ભળાવો.પાણી, ઇંડું, ખાંડ, દૂધ અને દાણા ઉમેરો અને મસળીને એકદમ સરસ લોટ બનાવો.લોટને ઢાંકીને 20 મિનિટ ઠંડુ રાખો.લોટને 4 સમાન ભાગોમાં વહેંચો.દરેક ભાગને એક ચપટી પાડો અને 16 ઇંચ લાંબી પેસ્ટ્રી બનાવો.પેસ્ટ્રીને અડધા ભાગમાં વળો અને તેને રેફ્રિજરેટરમાં 15 મિનિટ સુધી ઠંડુ કરો.આ પ્રક્રિયાને 3 થી 4 વખત પુનરાવર્તન કરો.પેસ્ટ્રીને 350 ડિગ્રી ફેરનહીટ તાપમાને પેક્ડ કન્વેકશન ઓવનમાં 12-15 મિનિટ સુધી બેક કરો.ટિપ્સ:લોટને સખત બાંધો જેથી તે પાતળી પેસ્ટ્રીમાં વિતરણ થઈ શકે.પેસ્ટ્રીને ઠંડુ કર્યા પછી તેને ફરીથી નાંખો જેથી તે સ્પ્રેડ ન થાય.બેકિંગ પહેલા પેસ્ટ્રીને ચાકુથી છાપવી પડશે જેથી તે ફૂલી ન જાય.ક્રોસન્ટને ઠંડુ કરો અને તેનો આનંદ માણો!"},{"question":"Warona Setshwaelo","answer":"Warona Masego Setshwaelo (tí wọ́n bí ní ọdún 1976/1977 ) jẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin àti olóòtú fíìmù ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Bòtswánà.Wọ́n bí Setshwaelo ní ìlú Gaborone, orílẹ̀-èdè Botswana, ṣùgbọ́n ó lo àwọn ìgbà ayé rẹ̀ ní àwọn orílẹ̀-èdè bíi Ethiópíà, Swaziland, Gúúsù Áfríkà, àti Bòtswánà. Ìyá rẹ̀ jẹ́ onímọ̀-ìjìnlẹ̀ nípa ìhùwàsí àwọn ènìyàn, bàbá rẹ̀ síì jẹ́ olóṣèlú tí orúkọ rẹ̀ n ṣe Ephraim Setshwaelo. Setshwaelo lọ sí orílẹ̀-èdè Amẹ́ríkà láti kàwé ni ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga Virginia Tech. Ó gba oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ̀ eré ìtàgé. Ó ṣiṣẹ́ atọ́kùn ètò rédíò àti olóòtù fíìmù. Setshwaelo jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn tí wọ́n kọ́kọ́ kópa nínu ètò Big Brother Africa ní ọdún 2003, ó síì jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn tí wọ́n fìdí rẹmi nígbẹ̀yìn níbi ètò náà.Ní ọdún 2007, Setshwaelo kó lọ sí ìlú Montreal láti tẹ̀síwájú nínu iṣẹ́ òṣèré rẹ̀. Ó kópa nínu ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn eré tó fi mọ́ Nutmeg Princess àti New Canadian Kid. Ó ní ipa kékeré kan nínu fíìmù ti ọdún 2013 tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ White House Down. Ní ọdún 2015, Setshwaelo kópa nínu eré tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ The Waiting Room, èyí tí wọ́n ṣe ní ilé-ìṣeré Tarragon Theatre ní ìlú Toronto. Ní Oṣù Kẹẹ̀wá ọdún 2015, o ́kópa gẹ́gẹ́ bi Odette nínu eré State of Denial. Setshwaelo tún kópa nínu Quantico ní ọdún 2016, àti ní ọdún 2018, nínu eré tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ On the Basis of Sex. Ní ọdún 2019, ó kópa gẹ́gẹ́ bi ìyá òṣìṣẹ́ agbófinró kan tí n ṣe Lila Hines nínu eré Bang Bang.Ó fẹ́ràn kí ó ma dáná óúnjẹ àti kí ó máa ka ìwé. O ́n gbé pẹ̀lú ọkọ rẹ̀ tí n ṣe Mike Payette, àti ọmọ rẹ̀ obìnrin tí orúkọ rẹ̀ n ṣe Khaya.Àwọn àṣàyàn eré rẹ̀2003: Big Brother Africa (TV Series, as herself)2009: Enemy Combatant (Short film, as Amy Dyer)2011: Jack of Diamonds (as Receptionist Kala)2012: Deadfall (as Female Paramedic)2013: White House Down (as School Teacher)2014: 19-2 (TV series, as Depanneur Owner)2014: Northpole (as Jasmine)2016: Quantico (TV Series, as Trauma Counselor)2016: This Life (TV Series, as Registrar Employee)2017: The Disappearance (TV Mini-Series, as Obstetrician)2018: Death Wish (as Nurse Carla)2018: Birthmarked (as TV Talk Show Host)2018: The Death & Life of John F. Donovan (as Mother)2018: The Detectives (as Sylvie Teague)2018: On the Basis of Sex (as Gladys)2019: Deadly Secrets (TV Series, as DeCynda)2020: Transplant (TV Series, as Lavondra Kelly)"},{"question":" د اداري اصلاحاتو او ملکي خدمتونو د کمېیسیون دندي څه شی دي ؟","answer":"ځواب: ۱ – د سالمي ، بېطرفه ، له سیاسي مداخلوپاکي او کار ته د اهل کار سپارلو ادارې د رامنځته کولو په موخه د دولت د اداري پاليسي طرح او تطبیق .۲ – د دولت په مشرۍ د لیاقت او ک فایت د معیارونو په اساس د لوړ پوړیو مامورینو تشخيص ، پیشنهاد او ځای پر ځای کول . ۳ – د لیاقت او شایسته ګي پر اساس د ټیټ رتبه ملکي مامورینو له تعیناتو نظارت . ۴ – په وزارتونو او دولتي ادارو کي د اداري اصلحاتو د پروګرام له تطبیق څخه نظارت ۵ – له وزارتونو او دولتي ادارو سره د سالمي ادارې د جوړولو په موخه همکاري کول ."},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ કહે છે: \\"આશ્રમવૃક્ષો પછી આ વનવૃક્ષો છે. મનુષ્યજીવન અને વનસ્પતિજીવન એકબીજાનાં કેવી રીતે સહાયક છે અને કુદરતનું ડહાપણ કેવું અદ્‌ભૂત છે એની ખબર કુદરતના અભ્યાસમાંથી પડે છે. વનવૃક્ષો માત્ર વૃક્ષોની યાદી નથી કે તેનાં વર્ણનો નથી. પક્ષીઓ પેઠે વૃક્ષો પણ અભ્યાસ કરવા યોગ્ય છે, અને એ રસિક અભ્યાસની દિશા ઉઘાડવા માટે આવાં પુસ્તકોની યોજના છે.\\"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાએ \\"આમળી\\" વિષે વર્ણન કરતા નીચે મુજબ ની વાતો કહી છે:\\"એક હતું ઝાડ; એનું નામ પછી કહીશ. એ ઝાડ ઊંચું હતું; એનાં પાન ખીજડાનાં પાન જેવાં હતાં.દિવાળી ગઈ ને કારતક મહિનો બેઠો. આમળી ઉપર નાનાં નાનાં આંબળાં આવ્યાં, ને થોડા દિવસમાં મોટાં થયાં.ઝાડે ઝાડે આંબળાં વીણનાર પહોંચ્યા ને ટોપલેટોપલા ભરી આંબળાં બજારે લાવ્યા.“લેવા છે કોઈને ધોળાં મોટાં આંબળાં ?”એક જણ આવ્યો ને શેર આંબળાં લીધાં; બીજો જણ આવ્યો ને બશેર લીધાં; ગાડીમાંથી વાણિયો ઊતર્યો ને પાંચ શેર આંબળાં ખરીદ્યાં; મોટરમાંથી કોક મોટું માણસ ઉતર્યું ને બધાં ય આંબળાં ખરીદી લીધાં.બેચાર પગે ચાલતા સાધારણ માણસો આવ્યા ને આંબળા માગ્યાં. આંબળાંવાળાએ કહ્યું : “ભાઈ ! આજ તો આંબળાં ખપી ગયાં; પેલા મોટરવાળાએ બધા લઈ લીધાં. કાલે આવજો; કાલે આવવાનો છું.આંબળાં ખરીદાઈને કેટલે ય ઘરે પહોંચી ગયાં એક ઘરે એનું શાક કર્યું; કાચી કેરીનું શાક થાય એમ આંબળાંનું પણ શાક કર્યું. આંબળાને બાફવું પડ્યું, વઘારમાં વઘારાવું પડ્યું અને પછી મીઠું મરચું વગેરે મસાલાથી મશાલાવું પડ્યું. હોંશેહોંશે આંબળાંના શાકને ઘરના બધા લોકોએ ખાધું.બીજા ઘરમાં આંબળાનો મુરબ્બો થવા લાગ્યો. ચાસણીમાં બાફેલાં આંબળાંને નાખ્યાં, ને ખાટાં આંબળાંને ગળ્યાં બનાવ્યાં. જરા જરા તાજા મુરબ્બાને ચાખી બાકીનો મુરબ્બો શેઠાણીએ કાચની બરણીમાં ભરાવ્યો. શેઠાણી કહે : “જરા ગળશે, એટલે પછી છોકરાઓ ને ખવરાવીશું.”\\"તેમનું આગળ \\"આમળી\\" વિષે નું વર્ણન શું હશે?","answer":"ત્રીજા ઘરમાં આંબળાંની ત્રીજી દશા થઈ. એ ઘર જીવન બનાવનારનું હતું. જાતજાતની દવાઓ સાથે આંબળાંને મેળવી તેનું ‘આંબળાંનું જીવન’ બનાવ્યું ને વેચવા માટે બાટલીઓમાં ભર્યું. બાટલીઓ ઉપર ચિઠ્ઠી મારી : “શુદ્ધ આંબળાંનું જીવન.”એક જ જંગલનાં આંબળા અને ઝાડઝાડનાં આંબળાં ટોપલામાં ભેગાં થયાં હતાં ને ભેગાં બેઠાં આરામ કરતાં હતાં; ત્યાંથી તે છુટાં પડયાં ને જાતજાતની દશા પામ્યાં.પણ હજી એની વાત અધૂરી છે. ચોથું ઘર વૈદનું હતું. વૈદે આંબળાંને સૂકવ્યાં. સૂકાં આંબળાંને ખાંડીને ભૂકો કર્યો ને ‘આંબળાનો અવલેહ’ બનાવ્યો.પણ નાનાં નાનાં સૂકાં આંબળાંના તો માત્ર કટકા જ કર્યા ને ઘણા દિવસ સુધી તે વૈદનાં છોકરાંએ મુખવાસ તરીકે ખાધા.લીલું આમળું કે સૂકું આંબળું ખાધા પછી પાણી પીવાની મજા પડે છે. પાણી મીઠું મીઠું ને ગળ્યું ગળ્યું લાગે છે. છોકરાંઓને તો આવું જ ગમે, એટલે આંબળાં ખાતાં જાય ને પાણી પીતાં જાય.વૈદરાજે સૂકાં આંબળાંનો ભૂકો કરાવ્યો ને હરડાં ને બહેડાંના ભૂકા સાથે સરખે ભાગે મેળવીને ત્રિફળાં બનાવ્યા. ત્રિફળાં એટલે ત્રણ જાતનાં ફળ.વૈદની દુકાને કોઈ આવ્યું ને ત્રિફળાં માગ્યાં. ત્રિફળાંને પાણીમાં પલાળી રાત આખી રાખી બીજે દિવસે ગળેલ પાણીને આંખ ઉપર છાટ્યું. એ બિચારાની આંખ નબળી હતી.આંબળાનું ઝાડ હતું; આપણા દેશમાં થતું હતું. વરસે વરસે શિયાળો આવતો હતો; ઝાડે ઝાડે આંબળાં થતાં હતાં અને આંબળે આંબળે એનું નસીબ માંડ્યું હતું. એક ઉપર મુરબ્બો, બીજા ઉપર શાક, ત્રીજા ઉપર જીવન, ચોથા ઉપર આંખે છંટાવું, ને પાંચમાં ઉપર મુખવાસ."},{"question":"Материалдык эмес маданий мурас деген эмне?","answer":"“Материалдык эмес маданий мурас» белгилүү бир маданияттын физикалык эмес аспектилеринен турат, көбүнчө тарыхтын белгилүү бир мезгилиндеги коомдук үрп-адаттар тарабынан колдоого алынат. Концепция коомдогу жүрүм-турумдун ыкмаларын жана ошондой эле белгилүү бир маданий климатта көп учурда формалдуу иш-аракеттердин эрежелерин камтыйт. Аларга коомдук баалуулуктар жана каада-салттар, үрп-адаттар жана практикалар, эстетикалык жана рухий ишенимдер, көркөм сөз, тил жана адам ишмердүүлүгүнүн башка аспектилери кирет. Физикалык артефакттардын маанисин адамдардын белгилүү бир тобунун социалдык-экономикалык, саясий, этникалык, диний жана философиялык баалуулуктарынын фонунда иштөө катары чечмелесе болот. Албетте, материалдык эмес маданий мурастарды сактоо материалдык объекттерге караганда кыйыныраак."},{"question":"Ke eng seo se ka fokotšago go fetogafetoga ga leratadima mo e lego gore go hlolega dilo tša go swana le tšhikintšhego ya lefase, meetsefula, komelelo bjalobjalo?","answer":"Ke mešongwana ya batho yeo ba e dirago lefaseng go swana le tšhilafalo ya moya ka menkgo, mello ya lešoka, mmuši wa diintastereng tša peterole, malahla le tše dingwe."},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng:Thiên tai nào sau đây không phải là hậu quả do biến đổi khí hậu trên Trái đất hiện nay?A. Động đất, sóng thầnB. Lũ lụt, hạn hánC. Triều cường, xâm nhập mặn","answer":"Đáp án đúng là: A. Động đất, sóng thầnĐộng đất, núi lửa có nguyên nhân từ hoạt động kiến tạo mảng của vỏ Trái đất. Động đất và núi lửa thường xảy ra ở khu vực gần ranh giới giữa các mảng kiến tạo, các dải đứt gãy của lớp vỏ Trái đất.Khi các lớp địa chất dịch chuyển tương đối với nhau gây ra biến dạng đàn hồi, nếu biến dạng vượt quá giới hạn cho phép thì năng lượng được giải phóng ra dưới dạng sóng địa chấn, nhiệt do ma sát và làm nứt vỡ đất đáo, gây ra một trận động đất.Sóng địa chấn lan truyền đến đâu thì nền đất khu vực đó bị dao động, gây ra rung lắc nhà cửa. Động đất, núi lửa hoặc va chạm thiên thạch xảy ra ở đại dương thường sẽ gây ra sóng thần. Tùy thuộc vào cường độ động đất, mức độ phun trào của núi lửa, kích thước của thiên thạch va chạm... mà sóng thần sinh ra có sức tàn phá mạnh yếu khác nhau.Lũ lụt, hạn hán... và nhiều hình thái thời tiết cực đoan khác có thể diễn biến phức tạp hơn do biến đổi khí hậu. Nhiệt độ Trái đất tăng dẫn đến băng ở các cực tan ra, làm mực nước biển dâng cao. Nhiều khu vực ven biển có thể biến mất do nằm dưới mực nước biển, triều cường và xâm nhập mặn cũng diễn biến phức tạp hơn."},{"question":"ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ : ਵਾਰ ੧ ਪਉੜੀ ੧੬ ਪੰ. ੧ਕਲਿਜੁਗ ਤੇ ਨਾਮਕਲਿਜੁਗ ਕੀ ਸੁਣ ਸਾਧਨਾ ਕਰਮ ਕਿਰਤ ਕੀ ਚਲੈ ਨਾ ਕਾਈ।ਬਿਨਾ ਭਜਨ ਭਗਵਾਨ ਕੇ ਭਾਉ ਭਗਤਿ ਬਿਨ ਠੌਰ ਨਾ ਥਾਈ।ਲਹੇ ਕਮਾਣਾ ਏਤ ਜੁਗਿ ਪਿਛਲੀ ਜੁਗੀਂ ਕਰੀ ਕਮਾਈ।ਪਾਇਆ ਮਾਨਸ ਦੇਹਿ ਕਉ ਐਥੌ ਚੁਕਿਆ ਠੌਰ ਨ ਠਾਈ।ਕਲਿਜੁਗ ਕੇ ਉਪਕਾਰ ਸੁਣਿ ਜੈਸੇ ਬੇਦ ਅਥਰਬਣ ਗਾਈ।ਭਾਉ ਭਗਤਿ ਪਰਵਾਣ ਹੈ ਜਗ ਹੋਮ ਤੇ ਪੁਰਬ ਕਮਾਈ।ਕਰਿ ਕੇ ਨੀਚ ਸਦਾਵਣਾ ਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਲੇਖੈ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਪਾਈ।ਕਲਿਜੁਗਿ ਨਾਵੈ ਕੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ॥੧੬॥","answer":"ਹੁਣ ਕਲਿਯੁਗ ਦਾ ਅਨੁਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਸੁਣੋ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਕਰਮਕਾਂਡ ਦੀ ਪਰਵਾਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦਾ।ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੇ ਬਾਝੋਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਤੇ ਥਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲੇਗੀ।ਪੂਰਬਲੇ ਯੁਗਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਨੁਸ਼ਾਸਿਤ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਕਲਿਯੁਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਸਰੂਪ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ।ਹੁਣ ਜੇਕਰ ਇਹ ਮੌਕਾ ਖਿਸਕ ਗਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਮੌਕਾ ਅਤੇ ਥਾਂ ਉਪਲਬਧ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ।ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਅਥਰਵਵੇਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਕਲਿਯੁਗ ਦੀਆਂ ਮੁਕਤੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ਤਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਣੋ।ਹੁਣ ਫੀਲਿੰਗ ਭਗਤੀ ਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਨ ਹੈ; ਯੱਗ, ਹੋਮ ਬਲੀ ਅਤੇ ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਪੂਜਾ ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਯੁੱਗਾਂ ਦੀ ਅਨੁਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਸੀ।ਜੇਕਰ ਕੋਈ ਹੁਣ ਕਰਤਾ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਬਾਵਜੂਦ ਵੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਇਸ ਭਾਵ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਟਾ ਕੇ ਨੀਚ ਅਖਵਾਉਣ ਨੂੰ ਤਰਜੀਹ ਦੇਵੇ, ਤਾਂ ਹੀ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀਆਂ ਚੰਗੀਆਂ ਪੁਸਤਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।ਕਲਯੁਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੇਵਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਣ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਮਹਾਨ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਪੰਚਮਿ ਪੰਚ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਤੇ ਜਿਹ ਜਾਨਿਓ ਪਰਪੰਚੁ ॥ਕੁਸਮ ਬਾਸ ਬਹੁ ਰੰਗੁ ਘਣੋ ਸਭ ਮਿਥਿਆ ਬਲਬੰਚੁ ॥ਨਹ ਜਾਪੈ ਨਹ ਬੂਝੀਐ ਨਹ ਕਛੁ ਕਰਤ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ਸੁਆਦ ਮੋਹ ਰਸ ਬੇਧਿਓ ਅਗਿਆਨਿ ਰਚਿਓ ਸੰਸਾਰੁ ॥ਜਨਮ ਮਰਣ ਬਹੁ ਜੋਨਿ ਭ੍ਰਮਣ ਕੀਨੇ ਕਰਮ ਅਨੇਕ ॥ਰਚਨਹਾਰੁ ਨਹ ਸਿਮਰਿਓ ਮਨਿ ਨ ਬੀਚਾਰਿ ਬਿਬੇਕ ॥ਭਾਉ ਭਗਤਿ ਭਗਵਾਨ ਸੰਗਿ ਮਾਇਆ ਲਿਪਤ ਨ ਰੰਚ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਬਿਰਲੇ ਪਾਈਅਹਿ ਜੋ ਨ ਰਚਹਿ ਪਰਪੰਚ ॥੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 297 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਉਹ ਸੰਤ ਜਨ ਸੇ੍ਰਸ਼ਟ ਮੰਨੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਜਗਤ-ਪਸਾਰੇ ਨੂੰ (ਇਉਂ) ਸਮਝ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ (ਕਿ ਇਹ) ਫੁੱਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੁਗੰਧੀ (ਵਰਗਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਭਾਵੇਂ) ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਰੰਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ (ਫਿਰ ਭੀ) ਸਾਰਾ ਨਾਸਵੰਤ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਠੱਗੀ ਹੀ ਹੈ ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ (ਸਹੀ ਜੀਵਨ-ਜੁਗਤਿ) ਸੁੱਝਦੀ ਨਹੀਂ, ਇਹ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਤੇ (ਸਹੀ ਜੀਵਨ-ਜੁਗਤਿ ਬਾਰੇ) ਕੋਈ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦਾ ।ਜਗਤ (ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ) ਅਗਿਆਨ ਵਿਚ ਮਸਤ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਸੁਆਦਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮੋਹ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਰਸਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵਿੱਝਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਹੋਰ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਕਰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ, ਉਹ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆ ਰਿਹਾ, ਉਹ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਜੂਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਭਟਕਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ।ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਸਿਰਜਣਹਾਰ ਕਰਤਾਰ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ, ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕੇ (ਭਲੇ ਬੁਰੇ ਕੰਮ ਦੀ) ਪਰਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਉਤੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਆਪਣਾ ਰਤਾ ਭਰ ਭੀ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾ ਸਕਦੀ, ਤੇ ਜੇਹੜੇ ਭਗਵਾਨ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਭਗਵਾਨ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਅਜੇਹੇ ਬੰਦੇ) ਵਿਰਲੇ ਹੀ ਲੱਭਦੇ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਇਸ ਜਗਤ-ਖਿਲਾਰੇ (ਦੇ ਮੋਹ) ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਫਸਦੇ ।੫।\\""},{"question":"ਵਿਸ਼ਾਃ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ 'ਚ ਅੱਧੀ ਰਾਤ ਨੂੰ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨੇ ਸੜਕਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਦੌੜਾਈ ਗੱਡੀ।","answer":"ਪਾਬੰਦੀ ਹਟਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਸਾਬੀਕਾ ਹਬੀਬ ਖੋਬਰ ਸਿਟੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੱਧੀ ਰਾਤ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਗੱਡੀ ਚਲਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਇਹ ਪਾਬੰਦੀ ਹਟਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਐਲਾਨ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਸਾਲ ਸਤੰਬਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਲਾਈਸੈਂਸ ਵੰਡੇ।ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਹੀ ਇਕੱਲਾ ਦੇਸ ਰਹਿ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਡਰਾਈਵ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਮਹਿਲਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇਦਾਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਡੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਫਰ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੀ ਸੀ।ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਇਹ ਫੈਸਲਾ ਉਦੋਂ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂ ਗੱਡੀ ਚਲਾਉਣ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਲਈ ਮੁਹਿੰਮ ਚਲਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਮਹਿਲਾ ਕਾਰਕੁੰਨਾ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਕਾਨੂੰਨੀ ਕਾਰਵਾਈਆਂ ਹੋ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ।ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਅਧਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਸਥਾ ਅਮੈਨਸਿਟੀ ਇੰਟਰਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ 8 ਮਹਿਲਾ ਕਾਰਕੁੰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਿਰਾਸਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਾਉਂਟਰ-ਟੈਰੇਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੇਸ਼ ਹੋਣਾ ਪੈ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇੰਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਈ ਸਾਲ ਜੇਲ੍ਹ ਦੀ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਵੀ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ।ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਵੀ ਹੋਈ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਗ੍ਰਿਫ਼ਾਤਾਰੀ :1990 ਵਿੱਚ ਰਿਆਧ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਰਜਨਾਂ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਗ੍ਰਿਫ਼ਤਾਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੈਠ ਕੇ 2008, 2011 ਅਤੇ 2014 ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀਡੀਓਜ਼ ਪੋਸਟ ਕਰਨੀਆਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ।ਹਜ਼ਾਰਾਂ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਹੁਣ ਜਲਦੀ ਹੀ ਸੜਕਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਗੱਡੀ ਦੌੜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆ ਸਕਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ।ਸਾਊਦੀ ਟੀਵੀ ਦੀ ਐਂਕਰ ਸਾਬਿਕਾ ਨੇ ਏਐੱਫ਼ਪੀ ਨਿਊਜ਼ ਏਜੰਸੀ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ, \\"ਇਹ ਹਰ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਔਰਤ ਲਈ ਇਤਿਹਾਸਕ ਪਲ ਹੈ।\\"ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪਾਬੰਦੀ ਹਟਣ ਤੋਂ ਕੁਝ ਪਲਾਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਹੀ ਉਹ ਅੱਧੀ ਰਾਤ ਨੂੰ ਗੱਡੀ ਚਲਾ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ।ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਦੀਆਂ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਹੁਣ ਗੱਡੀ ਤਾਂ ਚਲਾ ਸਕਣਗੀਆਂ ਪਰ ਪੰਜ ਹੋਰ ਅਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਹਨ ਜਿਹੜੀਆਂ ਉਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਣਗੀਆਂ।1. ਬੈਂਕ ਖਾਤੇ ਲਈ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਮਰਦ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਬੈਂਕ ਖਾਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹਵਾ ਸਕਦੀਆਂ। ਇਸਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੈ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਦਾ ਗਾਰਡੀਅਨਸ਼ਿਪ ਸਿਸਟਮ।ਜਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ ਇਹ ਸਿਸਟਮ ਬਣਿਆ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਦੇਸ ਵਾਹਾਬੀ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਇਸਲਾਮ ਦੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਬ੍ਰਾਂਚ ਹੈ।ਡਰਾਈਵਿੰਗ ਵਰਕਸ਼ਾਪ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਟੈਸਟ ਡਰਾਈਵ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਾਰੀ ਦੀ ਇੰਤਜਾਰ ਕਰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ।ਵਾਹਾਬੀ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਹਰ ਔਰਤ ਦੇ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਿਆ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਪੁਰਸ਼ (ਮੇਲ ਗਾਰਡੀਅਨ) ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਲਈ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਲਵੇ।ਇਸ ਗਾਰਡੀਅਨਸ਼ਿਪ ਸਿਸਟਮ ਦਾ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਵਿਰੋਧ ਵੀ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। 'ਹਿਊਮਨ ਰਾਈਟਸ ਵਾਚ' ਸੰਸਥਾ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਨਿਖੇਧੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਲਈ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੈ ਸਕਣਗੀਆਂ।2. ਪਾਸਪੋਰਟ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਨ ਲਈਗਾਰਡੀਅਨਸ਼ਿਪ ਸਿਸਟਮ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਉਦਹਾਰਣ ਹੈ।ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਦੀਆਂ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਸਪੋਰਟ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਨ ਜਾਂ ਫੇਰ ਦੇਸ ਛੱਡਣ ਲਈ ਮਰਦਾਂ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਲੈਣੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ।ਇਸ ਸਿਸਟਮ ਤਹਿਤ ਕਈ ਹੋਰ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਵੀ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਲਈ ਮਰਦਾਂ  ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'buah masak merah belum tentu manis rasanya'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang elok rupanya tetapi belum tahu baik buruk hatinya"},{"question":"biology-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"உயிரியல்"},{"question":"O que é a Renner?","answer":"A Lojas Renner é uma das maiores redes de lojas de departamentos do Brasil, vendendo roupas, acessórios e produtos de beleza."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--धार्याला (मोरीला) बोळा व दरवाजा मोकळा","answer":"छोट्या गोष्टीची काळजी घेणे परंतु मोठी कडे दुर्लक्ष करणे."},{"question":"இன்றைய சிற்பக்கலை குறித்து எழுதுக?","answer":"• இன்று சுதை சிற்பங்களும், கல்சிற்பங்களும் அமைக்கப்பட்டு வருகின்றன.• செங்கல், பைஞ்சுதை (சிமெண்ட்) ஆகியவற்றைக் கொண்டும் கலைநயமிக்க சிற்பங்களை வடிக்கின்றனர்.• வெண்கலம் மற்றும் செயற்கை இழைகள் மூலமாகவும் உருவங்கள் உருவாக்கப் படுகின்றன.• இன்றைய சிற்பக்கலை கோவில்களைக் கடந்து, பலதுறைகளில் தன் இடத்தை நிறைவு செய்கிறது."},{"question":"Nginikeze isibonelo sezinto eziwubala kulesi sigaba: ezombusazwe","answer":"Hangazi."},{"question":"sheeg ama keen tusaale labo saxaabi muhaajiriin iyo ansar oo la walaaleeyey?","answer":"waa tusaale waxaa nooga filan walaaleyntii cabdiraxmaan binu coof oo muhaajirahaa iyo sacad binu rabiica oo ansaar ahaa11sheeg inta sano ay dhisaneyd boqortooyadii nebi suleymaan"},{"question":"السؤال: مجموعة من الغزلان تعرف باسم؟","answer":"الإجابة: قطيع"},{"question":"“Mampiroborobo ny torimaso ve ny fisotroana ronono alohan’ny hatoriana?”","answer":"Eny, ny ronono dia afaka mandrisika ny torimaso noho ny fananany \\"tryptophan\\"."},{"question":"Mention any four features of the Russian society of the 20th century.","answer":"The vast majority of Russia’s people were agriculturists. About 85 percent of the Russian Empire’s population earned their living from agriculture.Workers were a divided social group. Some had strong links to the villages from which they came. Others had settled in cities permanently.Women made up 31 percent of the factory labour force by 1914, but they were paid less than men (between half and three-quarters of a man’s wage).In the countryside, peasants cultivated most of the land. But the nobility, the crown, and the Orthodox Church owned large properties. Nobles got their power and position through their services to the Tsar, not through local popularity."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ɗari biyu da talatin da ɗaya a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 231"},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Chiều 31-7, Cơ quan chức năng tỉnh Đắk Lắk đang tổ chức khám nghiệm hiện trường, khám nghiệm tử thi để làm rõ vụ tại nạn giao thông khiến 1 bé gái tử vong.  Hiện trường vụ tại nạn giao thông khiến bé gái tử vong tại chỗ Theo thông tin ban đầu, khoảng 15 giờ cùng ngày, anh Lê Thành Nam (35 tuổi, ngụ huyện Ea H'leo, tỉnh Đắk Lắk) điều khiển xe tải mang BKS: 47H - 008.71 lưu thông trên quốc lộ 27 theo hướng tỉnh Đắk Lắk - Lâm Đồng.  Cơ quan chức năng điều tra nguyên nhân vụ tai nạn Khi xe chạy đến Km 43 + 300, đoạn qua thị trấn Liên Sơn, huyện Lắk, tỉnh Đắk Lắk thì tông vào xe đạp điện lưu thông cùng chiều, do 1 bé gái khoảng 12 tuổi điều khiển. Vụ tai nạn khiến bé gái ngã ra đường, tử vong tại chỗ. ","answer":"\\"Vụ tai nạn giao thông làm bé gái tử vong tại Đắk Lắk: Cơ quan chức năng điều tra nguyên nhân\\""}]`),I={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:T},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:M,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},B={class:"search-container"},C={class:"card-container"},L=["disabled"],O={key:0},K={key:1};function P(e,a,s,m,o,u){const d=b("PoemCard");return i(),t("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",B,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>o.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[c,o.searchQuery]])]),n("div",C,[(i(!0),t(w,null,p(u.filteredPoems,(r,k)=>(i(),v(d,{key:k,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),t("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:o.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[o.isLoading?(i(),t("span",K,"Loading...")):(i(),t("span",O,"See more"))],8,L)):f("",!0)])}const D=g(I,[["render",P],["__scopeId","data-v-aa77ba23"]]),G=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/14.md","filePath":"chatai/14.md"}'),H={name:"chatai/14.md"},R=Object.assign(H,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),t("div",null,[j(D)]))}});export{G as __pageData,R as default};
